<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Text-based discussion interactions and engagement with three different text types</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2025 08:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2423177?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring students’ conceptual understanding through mathematical problem solving: students’ use of and shift between different representations of rational numbers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2025 05:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2025.2456840?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teacher educators’ instructional modifications: A cultural-comparative study using a Czech mathematics classroom video</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this cultural-comparative study, we examined the recommendations for instructional modifications made by 12 Czech and 12 non-Czech mathematics teacher educators (MTEs). The non-Czech MTEs were selected from countries culturally distinct from Czechia, including Costa Rica, Japan, Kosovo, Türkiye, the UK, and the USA, with two MTEs from each country. The participants were invited to provide written feedback on a part of a video lesson (teaching segment) in which a Czech elementary mathematics teacher handled student errors. The results demonstrated that the Czech MTEs emphasized individual learning and content, while the non-Czech MTEs’ feedback was more diverse, advocating a more collaborative and reflective learning environment. Drawing on the limitations of our study, implications for future research are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-025-00518-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Feasibility and Comparability of Using Artificial Intelligence for Qualitative Data Analysis in Equity-Focused Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this essay, we explored the feasibility of utilizing artificial intelligence (AI) for qualitative data analysis in equity-focused research. Specifically, we compare thematic analyses of interview transcripts conducted by human coders with those performed by GPT-3 using a zero-shot chain-of-thought prompting strategy. Our results suggest that the AI model, when provided with suitable prompts, can proficiently perform thematic analysis, demonstrating considerable comparability with human coders. Despite potential biases inherent in its training data, the model was able to analyze and interpret the data through social justice perspectives. We discuss the applications of integrating AI into qualitative research, provide code snippets illustrating the use of GPT models, and highlight unresolved questions to encourage further dialogue in the field.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 11:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X251314821?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We are born mentors … It’s in our DNA”: Exploring Indigenous Australian kinship mentoring practices</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 11:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2025.2459944?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Turnover, Social Capital, and Improvement: How Instability Disrupts Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher turnover is a persistent policy concern in public education. Researchers have documented negative impacts of turnover on student outcomes; yet we know little about the causal mechanisms by which turnover influences, or disrupts, schools’ efforts to improve. In our longitudinal qualitative study, we examined how turnover affects relationships, trust, and shared knowledge in organizations—that is, organizational social capital—in ways that can impede school improvement efforts. We found that teacher turnover depletes organizational social capital by disrupting networks and relationships between teachers working in teams, weakening shared meanings and goals in schools, and impeding teachers’ ability to collectively engage in problem-solving and learning. We illuminate the hidden ways in which instability undermines improvement efforts and strains organizations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 07:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241311304?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the knowledge structure of coping strategies in teacher education research using bibliometric analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2025.2458496?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emotions in mathematics learning: a systematic review and meta-analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Academic emotions play a crucial role in mathematics learning, significantly influencing motivation, academic achievement, and career aspirations in mathematics. With the notable increase in research on emotions in recent years, our review uses Pekrun’s control-value theory with two primary objectives: to systematically describe the characteristics of emotions in recent research through a systematic review, and to synthesize evidence on the relationships between specific emotions, control-value antecedents, and mathematics achievement via a meta-analysis. The systematic review of 112 studies revealed that more than 100 specific emotions have been addressed in recent research, which we analyzed based on key emotion characteristics: valence and activation, type of object, temporal stability, and social context. The findings from the systematic review provide an overview of mathematics-specific objects that emotions have referred to in the most recent research. The subsequent meta-analysis demonstrated that mathematics achievement (e.g., test scores and grades) was positively related to enjoyment, hope, and pride (&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\overline{r}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; = .247, .224, and .344, respectively) but negatively related to anger, boredom, frustration, hopelessness, and shame (&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\overline{r}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt;= − .322, − .187, − .207, − .378, and − .291, respectively). Theoretical and practical implications of these results are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01651-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The complexity of mathematics teacher educator expertise</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics teacher education is now a well-established field of research, but it is only in recent years that research attention has turned towards the learning and development of mathematics teacher educators themselves. In this special issue, interest centres on mathematics teacher educator expertise and how this can be represented, developed, and studied. The research studies published in this issue aim to move beyond category-based descriptions of mathematics teacher educator knowledge and explore the broader complexity of expertise as blend of knowing, doing, believing, and being. In doing so they capture the dynamic and interconnected nature of expertise. In this commentary article, I reflect on what we can learn from these studies about the complexity of MTE expertise and use these insights to suggest directions for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-025-09679-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Communities of Practice for Canadian University Mathematics Instructors</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Communities of practice (CoPs) that support the teaching and learning of mathematics in Canada are discussed. In particular, why CoPs are needed for mathematics instruction in Canadian universities, as well as some examples of these CoPs and what they offer, their target audience, and how they benefit mathematics education. CoP examples aimed to reach nationwide include the Canadian Mathematics Society, Canadian Mathematics Education Study Group, and First Year Mathematics and Statistics in Canada. There are also examples of regional and institutional-specific CoPs, such as the Fields Math Ed Forums located in Toronto and online, that are discussed. We conclude with some comparisons of these CoPs and what may lie ahead for CoPs and their impact on university mathematics instructors in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00341-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nurturing preservice teachers’ metacognitive pedagogies through Lesson Study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-02-2025 10:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2025.2451880?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Obstacles to in-service Chinese high school mathematics teachers’ implementation of mathematical modelling in classrooms: an empirical investigation of teachers’ perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This mixed-method study uses interviews and an online questionnaire to investigate the obstacles that hinder teachers’ implementation of mathematical modelling in everyday classrooms in China. Thirty high school mathematics teachers were interviewed, and 200 teachers completed an online questionnaire regarding their perceived obstacles. We identified six critical obstacle groups: missed opportunities to learn mathematical modelling education in professional development and/or teacher education; students’ lack of knowledge and interests; lack of examples in textbooks; lack of suitable teaching materials; non-favourable curricula tradition and school policies; and a strong traditional focus on examination culture. The obstacles identified and their relationship to and role in current in-service teachers’ practices are explored and interpreted from a sociocultural perspective considering, among other factors, the significance of central examinations in China and the historical prevalence of pure, structurally oriented mathematics in school.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-02-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01660-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>To Whom Do These Results Apply? Assessing Evidence for the Generalizability of Social and Emotional Learning Programs Among Specific Racial and Ethnic Groups</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Social and emotional learning (SEL) programs are widely used, yet concerns have arisen about whether the evidence for these programs extends to students of color (SOC). The data in this study include published articles (n = 158) of trials (n = 97) of SEL interventions (n = 32) from the CASEL SELect list of evidence-based SEL programs. Using racial frames common in intervention research, we examined the extent of SOC representation in SEL intervention trials, how authors attend to race/ethnicity in their analyses, and whether and how these analyses show evidence that these programs benefit specific racial/ethnic groups. While doing so, we discuss the complex nature of race and racism in SEL research. Eight interventions provided some evidence that they benefit Black students and four showed some evidence that they benefit Hispanic/Latiné students. No trials provided evidence of benefit to any other groups of SOC. Findings suggest that while representation of SOC in SEL trials has improved, additional research is needed to understand to whom the evidence for SEL program effectiveness applies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 09:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241310184?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘We’re not taught the full story’: Black students’ mistrust of secondary school U.S. history curricula</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 04:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2025.2459946?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Social innovation in the making: Action research on relationship building and role understanding in the co-development of a Participatory Guarantee System in Argentina</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Social innovation (SI) is gaining attention to explore how multistakeholder initiatives create new social practices for local food system development. Participatory Guarantee Systems (PGS) is a group-based certification scheme for sustainable farming, comprising new social practices that require changes in relationships and roles. Research highlights potentials of PGS to produce SI; however, without providing insights into the innovation process, needed to learn how relationship and role building occur and how SI can be facilitated through action research. We addressed these gaps in a four-year action research that co-developed a PGS in Argentina. The overall aim of studying relationship and role building required to establish PGS was operationalized by i) analysing ambitions for change of relationships of involved groups; ii) examining how relationship building evolved and how it was facilitated; and iii) exploring changes in role understanding and performance. Therein, we reflected on how action research can enhance SI and transformation in local food system development. The processual analysis showed that SI was facilitated when narratives of change were shared across stakeholder environments and a socially constructed facilitation mandate was created. Critical role reflection was stimulated, while performance was constrained when individual benefits were uncertain, underscoring the need to elaborate on role expectations in the initiation phase.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 02:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503251316368?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Noticing in the midst of building on a critical event</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research on teachers’ noticing of student mathematical thinking has typically focused on how a teacher attends to, interprets, and determines a response to an individual student contribution in isolation from the broader mathematical classroom context. This research focus is not nuanced enough, however, to fully account for the complex noticing required of a teacher engaged in responsive teaching. To support teachers in enacting responsive teaching, it is important to have a way to distinguish high-leverage student contributions from among the many contributions available to a teacher. We draw on a previously developed framework to help teachers identify such contributions, those referred to as a mathematically significant pedagogical opportunity to build on student thinking (MOST) (Leatham in Journal for Research in Mathematics Education 46:88–124, 2015). We conceptualized a productive response to a MOST—what we call building on a MOST—that involves the teacher using a coordinated combination of moves to engage the class in collaboratively developing a sense-making argument about the significant mathematics inherent in the MOST. Rather than a single act of noticing, building requires the teacher to engage in an iterative, dynamic, and relational noticing process as students contribute their ideas to the sense-making discussion. It is this ongoing noticing that allows the teacher to keep the discussion focused on making sense of the MOST. In this article, we use this responsive teaching practice and the iterative noticing it entails to unpack a nuance of teacher noticing—what we call noticing with respect to.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09675-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Re-conceptualising mathematics teacher noticing through critical events from an enactivist perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this theoretical article, we propose a conceptualisation of noticing, drawing on our enactivist perspective, which takes account of what is now known about human cognition, and from which we draw out implications for how noticing develops. We review past work on mathematics teacher noticing and note the dominance of a paradigm of taking noticing to comprise: attending, interpreting, and deciding. We argue this framework draws from a computing model of mind, which is outdated. We use a vignette, from a lesson and stimulated recall interview, to elaborate an alternative. We suggest that noticing is: embodied; layered; mutual; and meta. We then further exemplify these characteristics by showing how they can be used to analyse a vignette from a teacher discussion of a video recording (of the first vignette). From these ideas, we then consider how it is possible to educate teacher noticing, and how it can develop through a focus on critical events.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09676-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Volume 13: Issue 2 (Feb 2025): February 2025</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/13/2/mte.13.issue-2.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On the Promises and Pitfalls of Editorial Care</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 13&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 82-90
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/13/2/article-p82.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Traffic Stops to Engage Preservice Teachers in Thinking About Systemic Racism</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 13&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 91-107
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/13/2/article-p91.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Elementary Preservice Teachers’ Flexible Use of Strategies for Solving Linear Relationship Problems Using Strip Diagrams</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 13&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 108-121
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/13/2/article-p108.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Based on Books: Leveraging Children’s Literature to Guide Social Justice Mathematics Lessons in Early Childhood</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 13&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 122-135
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/13/2/article-p122.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics Teacher Educator Activism: A Framework for Making Visible Mathematics Teacher Educators’ Justice-Oriented Work</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 13&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 136-157
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/13/2/article-p136.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reconsidering task classification systems for situations that can be modelled with multiplication</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;To effectively teach modeling, instructors need to select tasks that allow students to learn which mathematical operations are appropriate for modeling different scenarios. Naturally, instructors might select tasks using a priori task classification systems—ones that group real-world problems for a given operation based on mathematical formalisms (e.g., as reported by Vergnaud (in: Hiebert (ed) Number concepts and operations in the middle grades, National Council of Teachers of Mathematics, 1988). In this paper, we critique the robustness of a priori task classifications systems for guiding the selection of modeling tasks. We investigated the meanings undergraduate STEM majors attributed to multiplication while modeling a predator–prey system using differential equations. Through analysis of task-based clinical interviews with 23 participants, six distinct justifications for &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; multiplication was an appropriate operation for modeling the scenario were identified. These six justifications confirm that learners’ assimilation of scenarios to operations may differ from how educators classify problems using a priori classification schemes. Our findings challenge the use of a priori task classification systems for guiding the pedagogical selection of real-world scenarios to model because classifying real-world scenarios using a priori systems can overlook nuances in modelers’ &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;structuring&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;validating&lt;/em&gt;. We highlight the importance of these nuances for generating task trajectories that would leverage learners existing meanings for mathematical operations to build new associations between mathematical operations and novel problems. We end by suggesting a shift towards reasoning-based classification systems for selecting real-world scenarios to model—ones that are based on students reasoning about and within a scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-31-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01657-4</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
