<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The First-Grade Outcomes of Pre-K Attendees: Examining Benefits as a Function of Skill Type, Environments, and Subgroups</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examined whether pre-K benefits persist through the end of first grade and the extent to which persistence differs based on outcome domains, subsequent classroom environments, and key subgroups of children. Data from 2,351 children living in a large and diverse county in Virginia revealed that the initial benefits of pre-K for academic and executive function persisted through the end of first grade but were 75% to 80% smaller than at kindergarten entry. Kindergarten and first-grade classroom environments did not sustain pre-K benefits. Although the initial benefits of pre-K were larger for dual language learners and children in poverty relative to English speakers and low-income children, there were no differential benefits by the end of first grade.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2023 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231195559?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I don’t like to ask for charity”: The possibilities of social inclusion among immigrant low-income Latina mothers via feminist action research</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This Feminist Action Research (FAR) examines the impact of economic and societal exclusion on low-income Latina mothers. The study, conducted in an urban community in the Northeast U.S., aimed to foster social inclusion among low-income Latina mothers via a financial intervention. Data were collected from 12 participants, and the intervention emphasized curriculum negotiation and critical thinking. Descriptions and roles of positionality are considered and contextualized. Findings exemplified economic and societal exclusion in the form of economic deprivation and experiences of discrimination, along with experiences of personal agency, solidarity, and social inclusion. Conclusions include a discussion on the potential of FAR within poverty research, along with practical implications in developing community change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 11:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231199846?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Errybody Sayin ‘No New Friends’?: The Proverbs of Rap and Why Young People Recite Them</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 06:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2240460?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional digital competence beliefs of student teachers, pre-service teachers and teachers: Validating an instrument based on the DigCompEdu framework</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 02:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2251663?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing the views of the theory of objectification and the onto-semiotic approach on the school algebra nature and learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The theoretical reflection on the nature of school algebra and the development of algebraic thinking from the first educational levels is a relevant topic in mathematics education. In this paper, we first summarize and clarify the positions held on this topic by two theoretical frameworks: the Theory of Objectification and the Onto-semiotic Approach. We identify concordances and complementarities in the respective conceptions of algebra and of the processes of developing algebraic thinking, as a result of applying these frameworks to analyse some students’ responses to a task on numerical patterns. We also analyse and compare the didactic models proposed in both theoretical frameworks for developing algebraic thinking. The analysis of the algebraic thinking and learning episodes is also used to illustrate a general discussion on the identity and boundaries of these theoretical frameworks and the possibilities of coordination and integration.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00400-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring units-locating in enumerating units of 3D arrays: linking units-locating to units-representation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of the present study is to explore strategies in enumerating units of three dimensional (3D) arrays. We analyse enumeration strategies of students in grade 3 (ages 8 to 9) in situations of cubical and spherical representations of units of 3D arrays. By exploring students’ strategies in these two situations, we find that difficulties in enumerating units in 3D arrays can be traced to difficulties in units-locating, with the consequence of applying double and triple counting. Our results also indicate that spherical units can serve as perceptual clues in units-locating and in assembling units into relevant composites. With input from our findings, we suggest research to investigate the following three hypotheses: (i) spherical units can turn students away from double and triple counting, (ii) spherical units can support students’ units-locating process and their ability to assemble units into relevant composites and (iii) teaching of enumerating 3D arrays should start with spherical units before cubical units.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00405-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impact of teachers’ professional learning on students’ learning of multiplicative thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The shift from additive to multiplicative thinking is challenging for students. A professional learning program was developed that focused on an identified area of need by teachers, namely multiplicative thinking. Program content focused on concepts underpinning multiplicative thinking, pedagogical approaches, challenging tasks, and application to classroom practice. It was delivered via six 90-min modules in 13 participating schools across terms 2–4, as part of regular after school professional learning. Whilst all staff participated, the research focus was year 3–4 teachers. Students’ historical data were collected across four years (2016–2019) to determine mean growth over time, in participating and non-participating schools. National Assessment Program Literacy and Numeracy (NAPLAN) and Mathematics Assessment Interview (MAI) data were used to determine the impact of the learning, as both assessments are administered annually. Analysis of year 4 students’ longitudinal data showed greater mean growth in student learning over a 2-year period in schools involved in the learning and additional in-class coaching support, than students in non-participating schools. Our findings showed that targeted school-based professional learning, with in-class support from a knowledgeable other, leads to teachers’ improved understanding of multiplicative thinking and subsequent pedagogical content knowledge to support student learning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00408-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Draw yourself doing mathematics: developing an analytical tool to investigate the nature of young children’s attitudes towards mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Understanding children’s attitudes towards mathematics provides insights into their lived mathematical experience and engagement. Despite the considerable amount of research into students’ attitudes toward mathematics, limited research has been conducted into &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;young children’s&lt;/em&gt; attitudes toward mathematics (YCATM). Within this limited research, investigating YCATM has certain challenges. From a methodological perspective, limitations exist regarding the type of research techniques that can be employed to study the nuances of the issue. The foci of this paper are to present and evaluate a methodological approach that used children’s drawings (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 106) and interview responses as the primary sources of data. Findings indicate that the strategy of “&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus internal-ref refid-sec11&quot;&gt;Draw yourself doing mathematics&lt;/span&gt;”, when used with other research methods, generated rich attitudinal data in the form of personal stories about YCATM.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00399-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collective noticing: teachers’ experiences and reflection on a mathematics video club</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Video clubs have been used for more than a decade to support teachers’ professional noticing. Accordingly, numerous studies have evaluated video use as a tool for professional learning, concentrating on aspects such as video selection, club meetings, and teacher interviews. Yet, few researchers have considered noticing as a result of repeated experiences in video clubs, over time, or teachers’ perceptions of video clubs. In this study, we explored individual and collective teacher noticing and teachers’ perceived value of video club participation, incorporating multiple data sources. The study was conducted over one academic year with elementary teachers. Our results reveal that teachers noticed broad aspects of teaching as well as specifics of students’ mathematical thinking. Additionally, teachers perceived video club participation as prompting deeper thinking and reflection and encouraging application of learned pedagogical practices. Of interest, participant noticing appeared to converge over time, suggesting social construction of meaning based on collective experiences. Thus, we introduce the notion of collective noticing–a term we coin to describe the convergence of noticing that may result from repeated engagement and discourse between a group of teachers focused on the same videos over time. We encourage teacher educators to consider the specific foci of video clubs and the ramifications of collective, repeated experiences through the video club process.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00403-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The community mathematics project: Using a parent tutoring program to develop sense-making skills in novice mathematics educators</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Programs that provide underserved populations with access to high-quality mathematics through workshops, clubs, and classroom observations (Civil, Stoehr, &amp;amp; Salazar, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r16&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/span&gt;; Civil &amp;amp; Bernier, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r15&quot;&gt;2006&lt;/span&gt;; Diaz-Palomar, Menendez, &amp;amp; Civil, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r24&quot;&gt;2011&lt;/span&gt;; Jimenez-Castellanos, Ochoa, &amp;amp; Olivos, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r35&quot;&gt;2016&lt;/span&gt;; Muir,  &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r49&quot;&gt;2011&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r50&quot;&gt;2012&lt;/span&gt;; Quintos, Civil, &amp;amp; Bratton, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r56&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/span&gt;) are vital. The community mathematics project (CMP) is one such program that takes a holistic approach to transforming mathematics education. Through partnerships with local institutions, the CMP pairs a prospective teacher (PT) with a parent for online mathematics tutoring sessions. This study describes how PTs in the CMP supported parents’ mathematics development of sense-making (Odden &amp;amp; Russ, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r53&quot;&gt;2017&lt;/span&gt;) in mathematics by providing relevant tasks, employing multiple strategies, using virtual manipulatives, and questioning in one–one-one tutoring sessions. Findings suggest that this type of field experience with an explicit focus on a sense-making approach supported PTs in learning mathematics, engaging in partnerships with parents and members of the community, and attending broader issues of social contexts of learning. Further, PTs attended to individual considerations such as sequencing and scaffolding, relevancy of the content, task development, and building towards common mathematical practices. Finally, onsite coaching and tutoring experiences were formative in developing essential skills for teaching mathematics in elementary school in the following areas: content and pedagogical content knowledge, development of core pedagogical practices, funds of knowledge approaches and collaboration with families, and dispositions toward (teaching) mathematics such as reframing mistakes, emphasis on sense-making, and co-construction of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00401-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating students’ geometrical proofs through the lens of students’ definitions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The current study is part of a comprehensive research on linking visualization, students’ construction of geometrical concepts and their definitions, and students’ ability to prove. The aim of the current study is to investigate the effect of learners’ understanding of definitions of geometrical concepts on their understanding of the essence of geometrical proofs and their ways of proving. By “understanding” (geometrical definitions and/or proofs), we mean knowing the definition’s and/or proof’s meaning and their role within the logic structure of geometry and also the ability to define and/or prove in “geometrically correct” ways. Ninety grade 11 students from an Arab high school in Israel participated in the comprehensive study in geometry of which the current study forms a part. Research tasks for the investigation of the current study’s aim were designed, constructed, and used in a questionnaire to the whole research population and in interviews with about 10% of the population. The findings point clearly to effects of elements within the students’ understanding of definitions on their understanding of proofs and on their ability to prove. These elements are as follows: (a) The difficulty to internalize that an incomplete definition is an incorrect definition and may lead to an incomplete proof. (b) The difficulty to deal with non-economical definitions forms the basis to non-economical proofs. (c) Students have difficulties to accept equivalent definitions to the same geometrical concept. (d) The students’ lack of understanding the origin of a constructive definition of geometrical concept.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00406-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Factors that promote interest and engagement in learning mathematics for low-achieving primary students across three learning settings</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study explored the mathematics engagement of Australian primary students who currently struggle with mathematics learning and who participated in an intervention program. The research aimed to identify the elements that facilitated their engagement across three learning settings that they experienced concurrently: their &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Extending Mathematical Understanding&lt;/em&gt; (EMU) intervention lessons, classroom mathematics lessons, and home mathematics learning. A model of mathematics engagement comprising facilitators, indicators, and consequences of engagement was used to guide the data analysis process. By examining variation in results for these three categories of engagement, we draw tentative conclusions about how the settings contribute to the students’ motivation to learn mathematics and their interest and engagement. The findings identified several key facilitators of mathematics engagement for students who struggle with mathematics. These included tasks and mathematical games, using number lines to represent whole numbers, and being offered a range of mathematics content beyond the number domain. Also important was the social aspect of learning including having supportive family members, peers, and teachers during mathematics learning activities, working with others, and being helped. Each of the three settings explored through the study differed with respect to the factors that most promoted the students’ interest and engagement. The findings provide teachers and researchers with a deeper understanding of the contextual features that facilitate engagement for students who currently struggle with learning mathematics. These facilitators of engagement can assist teachers to design more effective classroom practices and small group interventions, as well as help families to support their children’s mathematics learning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00402-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Design-based research in mathematics education: trends, challenges and potential</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Originating from the learning sciences community, design-based research (DBR) is attracting interest from many educational researchers including those focused on mathematics. Beyond its research role, it is being seen as a collaborative way to engage teachers in deep professional development leading not only to changes in skill but also in purpose. Previous reviews of the approach, however, have offered only cautious optimism for the capacity of DBR to support widespread or scalable change. This paper will use methods drawn from the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;digital humanities and social sciences&lt;/em&gt; to explore patterns relating to regional differences, theoretical underpinnings, practical implementation and methodological choice in recent DBR research in the domain of mathematics education. The findings suggest that much of the work presented as DBR might be better characterized as ‘implementation studies’ as they contain only limited commitment to theoretical development capable of supporting the scaling of innovation. The exceptions appear to occur in settings with well-developed research capacity which recognizes the need for ontological innovation of theory whilst iteratively and comprehensively exploring the complexities of authentic learning interventions. An example of a rich mathematical research study using DBR is provided to point to the potential for this methodology to achieve its overarching aims more fully.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00407-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Natural number bias on evaluations of the effect of multiplication and division: the role of the type of numbers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Over the last years, there is a growing interest in studying students’ difficulties with rational numbers from a cognitive/developmental perspective, focusing on the role of prior knowledge in students’ understanding of rational numbers. The present study tests the effect of the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;whole&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;natural number bias&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., the tendency to count on natural number knowledge to interpret information about rational numbers and deal with rational number tasks), on students’ expectations about the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;size&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., bigger or smaller) and the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;type&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., natural number or decimal) of the results of multiplication and division. Items that were congruent and incongruent with students’ assumed expectations were administered to 91 seventh and eighth graders, asking them to evaluate equalities presenting multiplication and division between given and missing numbers. The results showed that besides the already well-documented effect of the size of results (i.e., &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;multiplication makes bigger&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;division makes smaller&lt;/em&gt;), students tended to think that the numbers involved in multiplication and division should be of the same type (i.e., natural or non-natural, e.g., decimals). Both size and type of the numbers involved in the operations were significant factors affecting students’ evaluations, with size being stronger than type.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00398-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Phronesis in teacher education: a critical reexamination</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 12:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2253495?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning programming for mathematical investigations: an instrumental and community of practice approach</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 11:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2239195?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Wealth-Based Inequalities in Higher Education Attendance: A Global Snapshot</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study provides a comprehensive global snapshot of wealth-based inequalities in higher education attendance. We draw on data from 117 countries to describe cross-national patterns in higher education attendance rates, disaggregated by wealth quintile and country income group. We then calculate four different indicators to quantify the size of wealth-based inequality in higher education attendance and completion for each country. Our findings point to large wealth-based inequalities in higher education attendance cross-nationally, which are: substantially larger than inequalities in secondary completion, larger in low- and middle-income countries than high-income countries, and negatively associated with national wealth. The results serve as a foundation for future studies on how country-level factors and policies exacerbate or reduce wealth-based inequalities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 10:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231194307?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating Psychometric Differences Between Fast Versus Slow Responses on Rating Scale Items</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Some previous studies suggest that response times (RTs) on rating scale items can be informative about the content trait, but a more recent study suggests they may also be reflective of response styles. The latter result raises questions about the possible consideration of RTs for content trait estimation, as response styles are generally viewed as nuisance dimensions in the measurement of noncognitive constructs. In this article, we extend previous work exploring the simultaneous relevance of content and response style traits on RTs in self-report rating scale measurement by examining psychometric differences related to fast versus slow item responses. Following a parallel methodology applied with cognitive measures, we provide empirical illustrations of how RTs appear to be simultaneously reflective of both content and response style traits. Our results demonstrate that respondents may exhibit different response behaviors for fast versus slow responses and that both the content trait and response styles are relevant to such heterogeneity. These findings suggest that using RTs as a basis for improving the estimation of noncognitive constructs likely requires simultaneously attending to the effects of response styles.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231195260?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching rational number concepts and skills to students receiving tier two interventions</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 04:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2248046?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identifying school-based teacher educators’ professional learning needs: an international survey</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 05:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2251658?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>My brother’s keeper: two Black men navigating the tenure-track experience</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 05:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2248892?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Proof and proving in school and university mathematics education research: a systematic review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This systematic review aims to provide a complementary to existing synopses of the state-of-the-art of mathematics education research on &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;proof&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;proving&lt;/em&gt; in both school and university mathematics. As an organizing framework, we used Cohen et al.’s triadic conceptualization of instruction, which draws attention not only to the main actors of the didactical process (i.e., the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teacher&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students&lt;/em&gt;) and the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Content&lt;/em&gt; around which the actors’ work is organized (herein, content related to proof and proving), but also to the relationships among the actors and the content. Out of the 103 papers we reviewed, almost half fell in the Student-Content category, which is consistent with the existence of a substantial number of frameworks, methods, and research findings related to students’ engagement with proof and proving. About a quarter of the papers fell in the Student–Teacher-Content category, which reflects an emphasis on viewing instructional practice in proof and proving in a holistic, systemic way. Only few papers fell in the categories that did not include Content in them, namely, the categories of Student, Teacher, and Student–Teacher; this suggests mathematics education research on proof and proving has a strong disciplinary identity, which potentially differentiates it from other mathematics education research strands. About a fifth of the papers were oriented towards ‘breaking ground’ through making an explicit theoretical and/or methodological contribution (Student–Teacher-Content and Content were the main categories where such contributions appeared), whilst the majority of the papers were focused on ‘building ground’ through elaborating or employing existing methodological and/or theoretical approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01518-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing how college mathematics instructors and high-school teachers recognize professional obligations of mathematics teaching when making instructional decisions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper investigates how mathematics instructors&#39; recognition of the professional obligations of mathematics teaching varies based on their institutional environment, specifically whether they teach high school or college mathematics. Using an instrument that measures instructors’ recognition of four hypothesized professional obligations, we surveyed 471 US high school mathematics teachers and 239 university mathematics instructors to measure the extent to which they recognized professional obligations when evaluating the appropriateness of certain instructional actions. After testing measurement invariance of four item sets, each of which measures one of the four hypothesized professional obligations—disciplinary, institutional, interpersonal, and individual obligations-, we compared the instructors’ recognition of each of the four obligations between the two groups. We found that university instructors recognized the institutional obligation more than high school teachers, while recognizing the individual and interpersonal obligations significantly less. This investigation provides insight into the variation in the nature of mathematics teaching practice across different levels of schooling.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09595-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Magnifying the Scope of Nature of Science (NOS) Toward the Whole: An Investigation of NOS Representation in Early Childhood Science Education Standards</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Effective teaching and learning of Nature of Science (NOS) has been a curriculum goal for decades and its inclusion into the science education from K-12 is becoming commonplace worldwide, regardless of the differences in the adapted science curricula. However, less attention, if any, has been paid to the holistic representation of NOS at kindergarten schooling level. This study utilizes the Family Resemblance Approach (FRA) on NOS to investigate how NOS is represented in the United Arab Emirates (UAE) science curriculum documents for the kindergarten school years, and the extent of its alignment with the international benchmarks and educational research evidence. Findings from the FRA-based curriculum analysis have demonstrated that the standards include “the nature of science” as one of the key domains of science education in the kindergarten stage. However, the cognitive-epistemic dimensions of NOS appeared to be more dominant than the social-institutional system dimensions. Specifically, the majority of the standards and learning outcomes emphasize learning of scientific methods, scientific practices, and scientific knowledge, alongside very few NOS aspects related to scientific ethos, social values, professional practices, and social organization. Pedagogical and practical implications of these results for science education are presented, along with recommendations to help structure NOS account into the UAE science standards that is more progressive, holistic, and interactive, all which can be of interest to a broader audience for purposes of curriculum policy reform both locally and internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00282-1</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
