<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptualizing White-Ability Saviorism: A Necessary Reckoning With Ableism in Urban Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;White saviorism is a well-documented phenomenon in the education literature. Particularly, researchers have made connections between white saviorism and teacher preparation for urban contexts serving Students of Color negatively impacted by legacies of systemic racism. Scholars are increasingly taking an intersectional lens to understand the ways in which racism and ableism intersect, yet much of the literature on white saviorism does not critically examine the role of ableism. In this meta-ethnography, we review extant qualitative research on urban teacher preparation in an effort to extend the analysis to include a robust examination of ableism and deepen our understandings of white supremacy in these spaces. To this end, we conceptualize white-ability saviorism as a more comprehensive and precise way to understand the dynamics at play in urban teacher preparation that contribute to white supremacy and perpetuate educational inequities for urban Communities of Color.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2024 04:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241241336?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ and principals’ views on interdisciplinary teaching and learning in the humanities</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-02-2024 11:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2337646?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 5Ps of Holistic Policy Development: A Way Forward for Engaging Teacher Educators?</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/75/3&quot;&gt;Volume 75, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 253-260, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-02-2024 08:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241236001?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Closing the Gap: A Conceptual Replication of an Early Reading Intervention</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-02-2024 08:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2333734?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Coding and Computational Thinking Across the Curriculum: A Review of Educational Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teaching coding and computational thinking is an emerging educational imperative, now embedded in compulsory curriculum in the United States, Finland, the UK, Germany, Belgium, the Netherlands, New Zealand, and Australia. This meta-synthesis of 49 studies critically reviews recent international research (2009–2022) of coding and computational thinking as core and integrated across the curriculum. It addresses four essential problems: (a) What are the key features of learning environments that successfully develop students’ coding and computational thinking? (b) What is the impact of student engagement in coding and computational thinking on learning outcomes across curriculum areas? (c) What pedagogical constraints are evident for coding and computational thinking, including across curriculum areas? and (d) Which conceptual frameworks support coding and computational thinking, and what has been marginalized or excluded? The review advances knowledge of coding and computational thinking—vital to guide and develop future AI-based solutions to real-world problems that challenge disciplinary boundaries.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-02-2024 04:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241241327?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race(ism), Power, Intimidation, &amp; Domestic Terrorism: A Critical Content Analysis of HBCU Bomb Threats on Social Media</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-02-2024 01:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2331939?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Book Review: Humanizing Disability in Mathematics Education: Forging New Paths. Paulo Tan, Alexis Padilla, Erica N. Mason, and James Sheldon (Eds.)</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00486-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A practice turn in teacher education in Turkey: is a balanced practicum at risk?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 11:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2337631?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preschool teachers’ beliefs about children, self-efficacy, classroom quality and children’s early language</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 08:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2329581?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Shortages: A Framework for Understanding and Predicting Vacancies</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We develop a conceptual framework for understanding and predicting teacher shortages at the state, region, district, and school levels. We then empirically examine how teacher shortages vary geographically and by subject using data on unfilled teaching positions in Tennessee traditional public schools during Fall 2019. We find that teacher staffing challenges are highly localized, causing shortages and surpluses to coexist. Aggregate descriptions of staffing challenges mask considerable variation between schools and subjects within districts. Schools with fewer local early-career teachers, smaller district salary increases, worse working conditions, and higher historical attrition rates have higher vacancy rates. Our findings illustrate why viewpoints about, and solutions to, shortages depend critically on whether one takes an aggregate or local perspective.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 04:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241235224?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Next Chapter of Critical Educational Policy Research: Research Informing Policy Design</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Drawing on the special issue’s collection of articles, the following commentary examines the racial biases in K-12 and higher education policies and products revealing their seemingly neutral and objective facades to be inherently racialized and, at times, explicitly racist. The article also highlights the damaging effects of race-evasive language in K-12 and higher education, advocating for the prioritization of the most vulnerable students in policy and product design. Rooted in prior research and the author’s experiences as a Latina, a first-generation college student, and a former K -12 educator, the article argues for the abolition of harmful practices like corporal punishment and school resource officers. The author suggests that effective policy design for racial justice may require both mainstream and alternative approaches and highlights successful programs like Freedom Schools and ethnic studies programs. Lastly, the article emphasizes the need for educational policies to reflect a deep understanding of systemic racial inequities and for the research community to directly influence policy design towards equity and inclusion.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 04:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241239916?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CTE Mechanisms: The Effects of Career and Technical Education Center Admissions Offers in Baltimore</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;While there is a growing body of literature related to the benefits of participation in career and technical education (CTE) in high school, there remains a dearth of causal work in this area. Relying on administrative data from Baltimore City Public Schools, which uses a ranking system with a strict cut score to assign students into CTE-focused high schools, we employ a regression discontinuity design to estimate the causal effects of attending one of these high-quality CTE schools on attendance, career pathway completion, high school GPA, and SAT scores. We find that students who are offered admission to a program within one of the CTE centers are significantly more likely to complete a CTE pathway, though they present significantly lower GPAs. Implications are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241239299?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Race Matters: Black Men and Authority Figures</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 03:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2331934?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cultural Mistrust: Comparing Black Student and Faculty Experiences at HBCUs and HWCUs</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 02:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2331932?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strategies for solving multiplicative problems using a conceptual model-based problem-solving approach. A case study with a student with autism spectrum disorder</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study examines the multiplicative problem-solving strategies used by a 14-year-old student with autism spectrum disorder and intellectual disabilities during an instructional process based on the Conceptual Model-based Problem Solving (COMPS) approach. The instruction aimed to enhance conceptual comprehension of problem-solving by the use of model diagrams representing mathematical relations involved in word problems. These diagrams aid in selecting the appropriate operation for each type of multiplicative problem, including equal-groups, multiplicative comparison, and combination problems. We further discuss how the instructional process promoted conceptual understanding for the three problem types, highlighting the development of strategies (modeling, counting, and operations) and the pivotal role of the COMPS methodology components in this progression. The results indicate that the student adeptly adopted the COMPS approach, facilitating the transition from informal modeling to written operations, with his choice of strategies varying depending on the type of problem. While there was a higher utilization of modeling strategies in equal-groups and combination problems, modeling was not as frequently employed in comparison problems. We speculate how this differentiated strategy preference could be associated with certain characteristics of the disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01568-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interrogating the equity promise for Black immigrant students in reformed mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As increasing numbers of Black immigrant students attend schools in Chile, we examine classroom practices to consider the limits of the mathematics education equity promise for this student population. We focus on the practices of a third-grade teacher who participated in professional development for enhancing reform-based mathematics teaching in a racially diverse classroom. Drawing on Stuart Hall’s approach to race, our analysis shows how two technologies of race-power fabricate the Black immigrant child as an uneducable and impossible mathematics learner. We contend that rather than enhancing the inclusion of Black immigrant students, reform-based mathematics teaching might maintain and reinforce racial hierarchies of mathematics ability.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10314-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional development and teacher agency in Mathematics Teacher Education for Sustainability</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In-service primary school teachers’ professional development and, more specifically, their teacher agency, are analyzed regarding the integration of mathematical education and sustainability. To achieve this, based on semi-structured interviews, several questions involving Education for Sustainable Development (ESD) and links between mathematics education and sustainability are considered, which yielded 44 answers. The analysis of these answers is based on four sub-aspects: knowledge of sustainability and its connection to the SDGs; sustainability practices; links between mathematics education and sustainability; and obstacles and challenges. The results show that teachers exhibit a significant lack of knowledge about sustainability and its connection to the SDGs, making a single association with issues related to the environmental crisis, which is the main focus of the sustainability practices carried out in schools. As pertains to the links between mathematics education and sustainability, most accept the importance of this connection, but point out various obstacles and challenges, such as the lack of knowledge and time, the curriculum itself, and others. It is concluded that it is necessary to design training programs focused on these aspects, in order to contribute to the development of teacher agency, i.e. the appropriation and reconstruction of new resources to face the challenges that mathematics education for sustainability implies in teaching practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00488-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A study of the teaching of action research in an online setting</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2024 01:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2336038?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional development through collaborative action research for early career academics - a collaborative auto-ethnography during the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2024 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2333911?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Novice Teachers and Student Attendance in Early Elementary School</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Student absenteeism in the earliest years of elementary school has been linked to a range of negative outcomes. Though the literature has examined numerous factors that are associated with children missing school, the role of teachers—especially at the early elementary level—has not been well understood. Given that students spend the majority of their time in elementary school with one teacher in a single classroom, a large component of early elementary school is underexplored, and our understanding of absenteeism remains incomplete. In this vein, we looked into whether having novice versus more experienced teachers was linked to the frequency of student absenteeism in the earliest years of school. Using a national dataset including repeated observations of students in grades K-2, we found that novice teachers have students with fewer absences and a lower probability of being chronically absent. There were no differences in the outcomes of novice teachers as a function of child nor classroom characteristics. Implications for policy and practice are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2024 11:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241231952?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Shift in School Reform: Examining Site-Level Spending and Student Academic Growth</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Accountability efforts under the Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) has brought greater attention to school-level processes and practices and their impact on student outcomes. This has pushed states to report more school-level inputs, including per-pupil expenditures. Grounded in an open systems theory (OST) framework, we identify the association between school-level per-pupil spending and academic growth on statewide assessments for seventh graders in Michigan. Overall, our findings suggest an overall positive association between school-level per-pupil expenditure and student growth.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 10:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241243066?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Education Experiments in Latin America: Empirical Evidence to Guide Evaluation Design</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Randomized experiments involving education interventions are typically implemented as cluster randomized trials, with schools serving as clusters. To design such a study, it is critical to understand the degree to which learning outcomes vary between versus within clusters (schools), specifically the intraclass correlation coefficient. It is also helpful to anticipate the benefits, in terms of statistical power, of collecting household data, testing students at baseline, or relying on administrative data on previous cohorts from the same school. We use data from multiple cluster-randomized trials in four Latin American countries to provide information on the intraclass correlations in early grade literacy outcomes. We also describe the proportion of variance explained by different types of covariates. These parameters will help future researchers conduct statistical power analysis, estimate the required sample size, and determine the necessity of collecting different types of baseline data such as child assessments, administrative data at the school level, or household surveys.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 08:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241241354?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>State Goals, Institutional Social Constructions, and Utah’s Postsecondary Education Governance Reform Efforts</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;State-level postsecondary education governance has experienced a lull in successful reform efforts since the turn of the century. However, in 2020, the Utah System of Higher Education and Utah System of Technical Colleges were formally merged following a multi-year effort by state legislators and higher education officials. Framed by the theory of social construction and policy design, this study considers underlying institutional considerations and statewide goals that led to Utah’s governance merger and how these changes impacted the public higher education sectors in the state, offering insights for research examining higher education governance and reform efforts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 06:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241243082?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nuancing the narrative: understanding Asian American opposition to NYC’s selective high school admissions reform</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 05:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2334459?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
