<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Testing the potency of ethnoscience instruction on biology students’ critical thinking ability</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2024 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2373464?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unraveling high-quality mathematics teaching in algebra: insights from overlaying domain-specific and content-specific observation instruments</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When analyzing instructional quality in mathematics, observational measures can consider domain-specific instructional approaches (e.g., effective teaching of mathematics) and content-focused practices (e.g., effective teaching of a specific mathematical topic). In this study, we analyze lesson videos from secondary algebra classrooms using two different instruments—one focused on ambitious mathematics teaching practices and one focused on instructional features that support students’ learning opportunities in algebra specifically. We consider the information provided by overlaying these instruments to raise implications for instructional improvement efforts, particularly related to how information from the instruments might inform formative feedback to teachers. We consider how alignment between instrument and instructional emphasis can influence the strengths and areas of instructional improvement identified in a given lesson. We further model a collaborative process for looking across observation instruments to deepen understanding of the information provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01606-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inside the Black Box: Detecting and Mitigating Algorithmic Bias Across Racialized Groups in College Student-Success Prediction</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Colleges and universities are increasingly turning to algorithms that predict college-student success to inform various decisions, including those related to admissions, budgeting, and student-success interventions. Because predictive algorithms rely on historical data, they capture societal injustices, including racism. In this study, we examine how the accuracy of college student success predictions differs between racialized groups, signaling algorithmic bias. We also evaluate the utility of leading bias-mitigating techniques in addressing this bias. Using nationally representative data from the Education Longitudinal Study of 2002 and various machine learning modeling approaches, we demonstrate how models incorporating commonly used features to predict college-student success are less accurate when predicting success for racially minoritized students. Common approaches to mitigating algorithmic bias are generally ineffective at eliminating disparities in prediction outcomes and accuracy between racialized groups.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241258741?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do quality criteria of instructional explanatory videos in algebra influence student choice? A feasibility study using conjoint analysis to assess implicit reasoning in educational contexts</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 04:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2377423?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Heterogeneity of Item-Treatment Interactions Masks Complexity and Generalizability in Randomized Controlled Trials</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 03:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2361337?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teaching, learning, and assessment in the digital age</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The role of teaching, learning, and assessment with digital technology has become increasingly prominent in mathematics education. This survey paper provides an overview of how technology has been transforming teaching, learning, and assessment in mathematics education in the digital age and suggests how the field will evolve in the coming years. Based on several decades of research and educational practices, we discuss and anticipate the multifaceted impact of technology on mathematics education, thus laying the groundwork for the other papers in this issue. After a brief introduction discussing the motivations for this issue, we focus our attention on three lines of research: teaching mathematics with technology, learning mathematics with technology, and assessment with technology. We point to new research orientations that address the issue of teaching with technology, specifically describing attempts to conceptualise teachers’ mathematical and digital competencies, perspectives that view teachers as designers of digital resources, and the design and evaluation of long-term initiatives to support teachers as they develop innovative teaching practices enhanced by digital technologies. Our examination shows that learning with technology is still marked by new conceptualizations raised by researchers that can further our understanding of this complex issue. These conceptualizations support the recognition that multiple resources, ranging from paper and pencil to augmented reality, participate in the learning process. Finally, assessment with technology, especially in the formative sense, offers new possibilities for offering individualised support for learners that can benefit from adaptive systems, though more tasks for conceptual understanding need to be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01612-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Patterning strategies in grade 1 students with low and high number sense proficiency</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Repeating patterning proficiency predicts students’ later mathematical proficiency. A comparative multi-case design enabled the present study to compare patterning success and strategy use for repeating patterns of 75 Norwegian 6-year-old grade 1 students. We provided the students with duplicate, extend, transfer, and unit isolation activities in a semi-structured, task-based interview that was video-recorded. The students’ number sense was also measured using a digital assessment. In-depth analysis of 52 students (divided evenly into two groups based on their number sense scores, lowest and highest) was performed. A statistically significant group difference was found for extend activities. Multimodal video analysis of strategies employed revealed that both student groups used recursive and different strategies and only students with high number sense used relational strategies. The students with low number sense used more variants of recursive patterning strategies. Our findings also demonstrated that attention to pattern features may both hinder identification of a pattern’s underlying structure and reflect advanced strategy use rather than not showing pattern awareness. We discuss group differences in terms of decomposition and awareness of mathematical pattern and structure and emphasise the need for scaffolding awareness of mathematical pattern and structure through communication.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10341-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating the Complexity in Elementary Teachers’ Noticing of Children’s Mathematical Thinking in Written Work</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-09-2024 08:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2372977?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race, racism, and racialization in mathematics education: global perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10346-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice Secondary Teachers’ Mathematical Knowledge for Teaching: Focus on Reflective Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 09:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2373653?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Intertwining of Children’s Interests and Micro-Practices at a Science Museum: Case Study of Three Children</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 06:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2374705?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cooperation in primary school children: The role of cardiac vagal tone and cognitive control</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 04:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2366347?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming teaching through cooperative inquiry: meaningful research for university teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 01:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2374745?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Learner-Centered Teaching and Learning Goes Online: Zooming into Linear Algebra Tutorials During the Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic shifted higher education online, drawing attention to synchronous learning and instruction on digital communication platforms. Learner-centered teaching practices in the tertiary level, such as mathematical discussions, have been shown to benefit student learning. The interactions involved in online synchronous mathematical discussions have been studied less. Most research taps into these aspects drawing on students’ academic outcomes and reflective interviews. This study explores instructional practices as they unfold online, with a focus on student-instructor and student-student interactions. We zoom-in to online synchronous teaching and learning processes on a popular communication platform by analyzing Linear Algebra tutorials in the first pandemic year. Using the commognitive framework, we characterize instructional interactions with the construct of a learning-teaching agreement. The analysis resulted in three interactional patterns, where in all cases, the tutorial transformed at some point to the one dominated by the instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00244-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analyzing Teacher-Designed Tasks Through the Lens of Procedural and Conceptual Knowledge</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Literature suggests that “current characterizations of the terms procedural knowledge and conceptual knowledge are limiting and are, in fact, impediments to careful investigation of these constructs” (Star, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r31&quot;&gt;2005&lt;/span&gt;, p. 405). We examined secondary mathematics teachers’ understanding of procedural and conceptual knowledge at superficial and deep levels through the design of mathematical tasks. For this purpose, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;=55 secondary mathematics teachers were asked to design a procedural and a conceptual task on a given topic and explain why they think the task they designed is a procedural and/or conceptual task. The study results showed that 78% of teachers were able to design and correctly explain procedural tasks. However, only 5.5% of teachers were able to design conceptual tasks correctly. Teachers’ narratives were examined to categorize emerging characteristics of procedural and conceptual tasks as well as to address teachers’ (mis)conceptions about procedural and conceptual knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00319-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning models and achievements of the most gifted students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2024 08:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2364690?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Heading for new shores? Longitudinal participation patterns in teacher professional development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2024 07:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2370891?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: How can university mathematics overcome Klein&#39;s second discontinuity? Specific course design</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01611-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Task potential in relation to teaching quality and teacher competence in secondary mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The potential of tasks to foster mathematical learning and understanding is an important aspect of instruction and their implementation in teaching is thus often viewed to be positively related to the quality of instruction. Both the selection of tasks as well as their implementation in the classroom depend on many factors, with teachers’ knowledge and skills as one of the most important ones. The present study aims to analyze the relations between different aspects of task potential, the quality of instruction, and teachers’ competence in order to investigate whether task potential can be seen as an indicator for teaching quality, for teacher competence, or as an independent construct in models of educational effectiveness. To this end, we draw on data from the TEDS-Validate study, namely tests of mathematics teachers’ competence (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 31) observations in their classrooms (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 60), and an in-depth analysis of all tasks used in the respective lessons (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 2490). Multiple regression analysis suggests that while some facets of task potential are related to either teaching quality or teacher competence, the potential of tasks emerges as an independent construct with some characteristics predicting the teaching quality of the respective lessons. Implications of these results for the role of tasks in educational effectiveness research are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01596-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Epistemological justification</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Epistemological justification&lt;/em&gt; is a way of thinking that manifests itself through perturbation-resolution cycles revolving around the question &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;why and how was a piece of mathematical knowledge conceived&lt;/em&gt;? The paper offers a conceptual framework for constituent elements of epistemological justification. The framework provides: (a) a theoretical basis for epistemological justification, (b) criteria for its occurrence, and (c) analysis of its relation to &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;mathematical explanation&lt;/em&gt;. The criteria are illustrated by a series of learning-teaching events taken from teaching experiments aimed at investigating the learning and teaching in linear algebra. The contribution of the proposed framework is three-fold: (a) it addresses a critical aspect of proof understanding not explicitly addressed in the literature; (b) it goes beyond the traditional treatment of mathematical understanding and production into questions about learners’ conceptualization of the origins of mathematical knowledge; and (c) it theorizes instructional approaches that can advance this conceptualization among students.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01603-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Towards an advanced mathematical language task for the early primary school years: preliminary results on reliability and validity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical language (or the content-specific words in mathematics) has repeatedly shown to be related to mathematical abilities in preschool and in the early grades of primary education. Research in this field has predominantly focused on young children’s quantitative and spatial language. At the same time, recent research has discovered that children in the early years of primary education already possess advanced mathematical skills such as reasoning about patterns, proportions and probabilities. In this study we developed an advanced mathematical language task to measure children’s understanding of mathematical language proper of the domains of patterning, proportionality, and probability, specifically aimed at first, second, and third graders (ages 5 -8). To develop a valid test instrument, our task was substantiated by a review of relevant literature and previously conducted studies. Further, the task was optimized based on the feedback received from expert professionals and a pilot study with 36 children. After administering the advanced mathematical language task to 236 first, second, and third graders, the results suggest that the task provides reliable scores in these grades. The internal consistency is excellent (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;α&lt;/em&gt; = .993). In addition, the test–retest reliability was checked in 49 children (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; = .704; &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; .001), and shows that the test also produces stable results over time.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10342-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Political conocimiento in teaching mathematics: mathematics teacher candidates enacting their ethical identities</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09646-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Units Coordination in Preservice Elementary Teachers&#39; Mathematical Knowledge for Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2024 11:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2370178?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher education for mathematical modelling: exploring the experiences of secondary school teachers in two courses</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper focuses on in-service teacher education as a crucial agent in driving educational paradigm shifts for the teaching and learning of mathematical modelling. Our paper presents empirical research based on two case studies, examining training courses for in-service secondary school mathematics teachers. The first course integrates different modelling approaches, while the second one is based on the anthropological theory of the didactic and uses the proposal of the study and research paths for teacher education. Both experiences conclude with teachers working on the design of modelling tasks to be implemented in secondary schools. Both courses are analysed through the lenses of how teachers progress on the collective identification of conditions and constraints for modelling, when teachers deal with the design of modelling tasks and analyse their implementations. First, the results show the kind of modelling tasks teachers design and the level of disciplinary specificity at which they plan modelling to be implemented. Second, we analyse how teachers address the “ecological analysis”, that is, the identification of conditions and constraints that facilitate or hinder the integration of modelling in secondary school classrooms after their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01609-4</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
