<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impact of service learning supported by the ePortfolio on the development of professional competencies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-02-2024 01:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2281396?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Differential effects of private tutoring on groups of students’ mathematics achievements: a longitudinal study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Supplementary private tutoring (PT) is commonly implemented worldwide, particularly among countries with highly competitive school systems and high-stakes examinations. Families often consider PT to promote their children’s skills and address any gaps in children’s learning. However, PT generally requires a considerable amount of family resources, and whether PT effectively increases students’ academic achievement remains subject of debate. This study examined student-report questionnaires and school reports of mathematics achievement from approximately 1500 secondary school students in China to track retrospective longitudinal variations of PT over a year. The study involved an analysis of the differential effectiveness of regular mathematics PT participation on the mathematics achievement of students from different quantiles at four hierarchical cognitive levels. The results indicated that only the lower-quantile students benefited from PT for their lower cognitive level achievement. Further, it was observed that among the higher-quantile students there was a reduction in high cognitive level achievement. These results raise questions concerning the role and effectiveness of PT. This study provides an evidence-based assessment of the effectiveness of PT and highlights the implications for educational practice and future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10282-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects and Local Implementation of School Finance Reforms on Teacher Salary, Hiring, and Turnover</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Knowing how policy-induced salary schedule changes affect teacher recruitment and retention will significantly advance our understanding of how resources matter for K–12 student learning. This study sheds light on this issue by estimating how legislative funding changes in Washington state in 2018–2019—induced by the McCleary court-ordered reform—affected teacher salaries and labor market outcomes. By embedding a simulated instrumental variables approach in a mixed-methods design, we observed that local collective bargaining negotiations directed new state funding allocations to substantially increase certificated base salaries, particularly for senior teachers with 16 years or more of teaching experience. Variability in political power, priorities, and interests of both districts and unions led to greater heterogeneity in teacher salary schedules. Suggestive evidence shows that state average teacher turnover rate was significantly reduced in the first year of reform. The McCleary-induced salary increase particularly reduces mid-career teachers’ (8–15 years of teaching experience) mobility rate and late-career teachers’ (23+ years of teaching experience) leaving rate. The McCleary-induced base salary increase has mostly null effects on teacher hiring in the first 2 years of implementation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231213880?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking teacher education in/for challenging times: reconciling enduring tensions, imagining new possibilities</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-31-2023 02:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2299926?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analyse didactique d’une reprise d’étude de la multiplication de deux nombres entiers dans un suivi orthophonique en France</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In France, when a student has persistent and recurring difficulties in mathematics, he or she may be cared for by a healthcare professional, a speech-therapist, outside of school. The social security reimbursed this support. Our research aims to objectify the effects of such monitoring on school learning. This article presents seven sessions on the theme of multiplying two integers of a speech therapy follow-up for a 10 to 11-year-old child. The didactic analysis of this sequence, based on a naturalistic observation, without intervention of researchers, is carried out to answer the question: what is the mathematical knowledge worked? Our study highlights a networking of different types of tasks, potentially due to a work of reversibility (Apostel et al. in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Logique et équilibre,&lt;/em&gt; Presses Universitaires de Francein, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r1&quot;&gt;1957&lt;/span&gt;) and the epistemic role of the material, omnipresent during the sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-31-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00304-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Charles Hohensee and Joanne Lobato (Eds.). Transfer of learning: progressive perspectives for mathematics education and related fields</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-29-2023 01:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2299062?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Demonstrating mathematics learning as the emergence of eye–hand dynamic equilibrium</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper combines recent developments in theories of knowledge (complex dynamic systems), technologies (embodied interactions), and research tools (multimodal data collection and analysis) to offer new insights into how conceptual mathematical understanding can emerge. A complex dynamic system view models mathematics learning in terms of a multimodal agent who encounters a set of task constraints. The learning process in this context includes destabilizing a systemic configuration (for example, coordination of eye and hand movements) and forming new dynamic stability adapted to the task constraints. To test this model empirically, we applied a method developed to study complex systems, recurrence quantification analysis (RQA), to investigate students’ eye–hand dynamics during a touchscreen mathematics activity for the concept of proportionality. We found that across participants (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 32), fluently coordinated hand-movement solutions coincided with more stable and predictable gaze patterns. We present a case study of a prototypical participant’s hand–eye RQA and audio–video data to show how the student’s cognitive system transitioned out of prior coordination reflective of additive thinking into a new coordination that can ground multiplicative thinking. These findings constitute empirical substantiation in mathematics education research for cognition as a complex system transitioning among dynamic equilibria.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-29-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10279-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Recasting Race-Conscious Admissions: Sylvia Wynter and Higher Education Policy After “Man”</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-28-2023 10:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231218207?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing student-researchers in primary schools through inclusive inquiry</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-28-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2298418?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An analysis of prospective primary school teachers’ action research: the case of Lithuania</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-28-2023 01:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2298744?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fictionalizing and researching: An approach from collaborative ethnography</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article describes the process of making a radio soap opera with Stop Desahucios Granada 15M, a movement fighting for the right to decent housing in southern Spain. The production of the radio soap opera has allowed us to: (i) investigate the affective and political implications of the problem of evictions after the financial crisis of 2008; (ii) reflect on how to produce meanings through co-research (using collaborative ethnography and fiction); (iii) experiment with the use of fiction as a research device, to “do” research and not only to transmit its results; and (iv) investigate the potential of fiction to facilitate new creative forms of knowledge construction.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-28-2023 01:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231225090?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ mathematical thinking of the tree concept: an integration of APOS with Tall’s three worlds of mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-27-2023 11:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2292260?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Grandmother Cedar as Educator: Teacher Learning Through Native Knowledges and Sovereignty Curriculum</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;As Indigenous-led education mandates proliferate globally, understanding how educators teach Indigenous perspectives and sovereignty remains urgent. Learning and integrating such knowledge proves difficult for non-Native teachers, given their lengthy participation in settler colonial schooling and society. What does learning to implement Native sovereignty curriculum entail? Codesigned with eight Native education leaders, this qualitative study examines five non-Native K–12 teachers’ learning processes with Washington’s Since Time Immemorial curriculum across three schools, using interviews, observations, and other data. Findings indicate six themes of learning supporting meaningful implementation, one potential catalyst for overall growth, and two distinct learning trajectories that suggest outward, rather than inbound, directionality. Implications for teacher education and educational leadership clarify needed steps for teacher learning and curriculum implementation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-27-2023 11:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231214455?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effective Teacher Professional Development: New Theory and a Meta-Analytic Test</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Multiple meta-analyses have now documented small positive effects of teacher professional development (PD) on pupil test scores. However, the field lacks any validated explanatory account of what differentiates more from less effective in-service training. As a result, researchers have little in the way of advice for those tasked with designing or commissioning better PD. We set out to remedy this by developing a new theory of effective PD based on combinations of causally active components targeted at developing teachers’ insights, motivating change, developing teaching techniques, and then embedding these changes in teachers’ practice. We test two important implications of the theory using data identified through a systematic review and meta-analysis of 104 randomized controlled trials, finding qualified empirical support for the theory. The main contribution of the article is to provide a testable theory of what makes PD more effective, which can be used to guide future empirical research on this topic.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-27-2023 06:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231217480?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to identify actions to improve in the practices of a professional learning community: a study of an action research project</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-26-2023 12:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2298424?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why teacher education matters even more</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-26-2023 10:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2298631?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career-related concerns and opportunities in the times of COVID-19 pandemic among preservice teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-26-2023 10:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2296351?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Postsecondary Future Selves of Black and Latinx Boys: A Case for Cultivating More Expansive Supports in College-Going Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Black and Latinx adolescent boys from economically stratified communities face pervasive societal inequities and, therefore, deserve more responsive school supports to determine and actualize postsecondary pathways. For insights into how such students conceptualize their futures and their school’s role in facilitating this process, this ethnographic study investigated one urban school’s college-going culture and its impact on shaping what the author calls participants’ postsecondary future selves. This theoretical approach encompasses three domains: college (i.e., postsecondary education), career (i.e., post-college employment trajectory), and condition (i.e., expected financial stability, relational and familial prospects, future living arrangements, happiness, and joy). Implications suggest that college-going school practitioners widen supports so students can imagine and envision how college ambitions align with career and condition goals.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-26-2023 09:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231214477?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Calibrating Items Using an Unfolding Model of Item Response Theory: The Case of the Trait Personality Questionnaire 5 (TPQue5)</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Unfolding item response theory (IRT) models are important alternatives to dominance IRT models in describing the response processes on self-report tests. Their usage is common in personality measures, since they indicate potential differentiations in test score interpretation. This paper aims to gain a better insight into the structure of trait personality, by investigating whether the dominance or alternatively the unfolding IRT model are better descriptors of the response processes on a personality measure constructed under the dominance response theorem. For the assessment of the dominant model, the Graded Response Model (GRM) is used; while for the unfolding model, the Generalized Graded Unfolding Model (GGUM) was examined. All analyses are conducted with the freely available R. A sample of 1340 Greek adults, employed in private and public organizations, fulfilled the Trait Personality Questionnaire 5 short-form (TPQue5). Findings contradict previous research on trait personality. In accordance to the construction method employed, the TPQue5 items are best understood by monotonically increasing item response functions (IRFs). Individuals responding to the TPQue5 increase their probability of endorsing its items as their trait level increases; this stands for all personality dimensions, although Openness to Experience exhibited mixed type of item response patterns. Further research directions, implications and limitations are also discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-26-2023 07:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231223374?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prospective mathematics secondary teachers’ perceptions of their pedagogical content knowledge: an approach in the educational context of Zambia</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-26-2023 05:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2281942?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Effective Teachers for Students With Disabilities Effective Teachers for All?</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The success of students with disabilities (SWDs) depends on access to high-quality general education teachers. Yet, teacher value-added measures (VAMs) generally fail to distinguish between effectiveness in educating students with or without disabilities. Using data from the Los Angeles Unified School District, we create two VAMs: one focusing on teachers’ effectiveness for SWDs and one for non-SWDs. We find that many top-performing teachers for non-SWDs have relatively lower VAMs for SWDs and vice versa, and that on average SWDs have teachers with lower scores in both VAMs than non-SWDs. Overall, SWD-specific VAMs may be more suitable for identifying which teachers have a history of effectiveness with SWDs and could play a role in informing student assignment to teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-25-2023 08:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231214555?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modern mathematics: an international movement?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2023 07:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2298119?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical tools for real-world applications: a gentle introduction for students and practitioners</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2023 07:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2298118?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Students to the Role of Assumptions in Mathematical Activity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-22-2023 01:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2293695?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
