<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Marketing a culture of achievement to Black and Brown students: TNTP and neoliberal multiculturalism</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2024 12:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2419133?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing initial notions of variability when learning about box plots</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2024 05:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2421412?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘We are changed yet the same…we can make a difference’: using a critical, creative, collaborative inquiry process to understand and develop professional artistry in nursing</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2024 02:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2420331?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Edgar H. Schein’s Process Consultation: the book that changed my life</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2024 02:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2421971?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Workplace Inclusion in Academia: The Relationship between Diversity Climate and Engineering Faculty Turnover Intentions</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The purpose of this study is to examine the relationship between engineering faculties’ perception of the diversity climate and their turnover intentions at R1 (Research 1) universities across the U.S. We sampled 1,101 tenure-track engineering faculty for this purpose. Data analysis showed that an engineering faculty’s demographic characteristics (i.e., sex, race/ethnicity, professor rank, age, engineering areas, marriage status, and tenure-track status) are associated with their perceptions of the diversity climate. Furthermore, results from structural equation modeling analyses show that faculty with higher perceptions of organizational fairness and inclusion reported a lower desire to turn over. Implications for the results are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-31-2024 08:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241290741?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tracking Procedures and Criteria and the SES Bias in Teacher Track Recommendations</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The allocation of students to ability tracks is often based on teacher recommendations. These recommendations tend to be biased in favor of students from higher socioeconomic status (SES) backgrounds. While tracking procedures and criteria have been proposed to play a role herein, empirical research is lacking. Using a survey experiment and information from 221 teachers in 69 Dutch schools, I find that teachers in the same school vary in their interpretation of their school’s procedure and (relatedly) their own tracking criteria. Teachers who perceive the school procedure to put more weight on students’ home environment, and/or (relatedly) put more weight on this themselves, show a stronger SES bias in track recommendations in the survey experiment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-31-2024 08:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241288212?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inclusive Strategies for Children With Developmental Disabilities in Mainstream Classrooms in African Countries: A Systematic Review of Stakeholder Experiences, Attitudes, and Perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;African children with developmental disabilities (DD), including autism and intellectual disability, are often excluded from mainstream schools. We systematically reviewed 28 qualitative studies conducted in Africa, aiming to synthesize stakeholders’ perspectives on inclusive teaching strategies for supporting children with DD in mainstream classes. Six interrelated themes were developed using thematic analysis. Teachers strived to meet learners’ needs through teaching and task adaptations (Theme 1) and provide targeted support, reinforcement, and feedback (Theme 2). Teachers’ inclusive pedagogies, while sometimes creating divisions, often reflected a whole-class approach (Theme 3), especially in promoting inclusive environments (Theme 4) and engaging teaching (Theme 5). Authors of reviewed studies often discussed how teachers’ strategies fit in with the evidence base (Theme 6). While teachers’ inclusion efforts appeared progressive, they were mostly based on Western pedagogies and challenged by limited resources and training. Training efforts based on indigenous pedagogies could improve use and outcomes of inclusive strategies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-31-2024 01:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241288247?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Rise and Fall of the Teaching Profession: Prestige, Interest, Preparation, and Satisfaction Over the Last Half Century</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We examine the state of the U.S. K–12 teaching profession over the last half century by compiling nationally representative time-series data on four interrelated constructs: occupational prestige, interest among students, the number of individuals preparing for entry, and on-the-job satisfaction. We find a consistent and dynamic pattern across every measure: a rapid decline in the 1970s, a swift rise in the 1980s extending into the mid-1990s, relative stability, and then a sustained decline beginning around 2010. The current state of the teaching profession is at or near its lowest levels in 50 years. We identify and explore a range of hypotheses that might explain these historical patterns including economic and sociopolitical factors, education policies, and school environments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-31-2024 01:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241276856?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Progression in units coordination: initial counterevidence for a transition that transcends mathematical domains</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2024 12:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2421055?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Need-Based Promise Programs, Performance Funding Bonuses, and the Enrollment of Low-Income Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Certain statewide promise programs require students to demonstrate financial need, while state performance funding policies sometimes incorporate a financial bonus that incentivizes colleges to enroll or graduate low-income students. We use data on public, 4-year colleges from 2007–2008 to 2019–2020, and incorporate difference-in-differences analyses and event studies. We find that colleges affected by promise programs in Louisiana, New York, and Washington observed no changes to the number and percent of first-time, full-time (FTFT) Pell grant recipients. Colleges in states subject to a performance funding bonus experienced no changes to the number and percent of FTFT Pell grants recipients, and colleges in Louisiana subject to both policies experienced no changes to either outcome.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2024 07:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241287410?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CritSEM: Advancing QuantCrit to Examine Racialized Resegregation in Special Education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2024 04:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2408538?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dreaming a better future: irreverent beings who say what we cannot</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2024 01:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2421962?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Attendance Practices in High-Absenteeism Districts</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Though researchers have documented the consequences and causes of chronic absenteeism, there is limited empirical evidence about what schools and districts are actually doing to improve attendance. This study presents evidence about the types of attendance practices that forty-seven high-absenteeism districts in Michigan are planning and implementing, using data from principal surveys, case studies, observations, and school improvement plans. In 2022-2023, principals reported using communication practices, incentives, and to an extent providing resources to address barriers to attendance. In improvement plans, districts planned to create new organizational infrastructure and hire new personnel, with less emphasis on specific practices. These findings highlight frequent use of communication-based strategies and limited existing organizational infrastructure for addressing attendance. It is unclear whether planned practices will address social and economic inequalities at the root of high absenteeism rates. I conclude with recommendations for monitoring new attendance practices, addressing root causes, and avoiding counterproductive practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 09:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241288504?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under the Law: Virtually an education</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 52-53, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The closure of school buildings during the pandemic made virtual instruction necessary. Since schools have reopened, its use has become more normalized than it was pre-COVID. Bob Kim discusses some of the civil rights issues education leaders and policy makers must consider if they choose to assign certain students to virtual instruction. Some students, particularly students from low-income families, students with disabilities, and English learners, may have difficulty accessing virtual instruction or receiving the full benefit of instruction when it is delivered virtually.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295433?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Person: The Happy Farm: Igniting the flame of knowledge in children</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 48-49, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher Shanshan Wang took the opportunity to transform an empty area near her school into a vegetable and fruit garden with her students, which they dubbed the Happy Farm. Students planted the seeds and tended the plants. They kept journals about the growing plants and worked together to solve problems when they arose. The produce from the garden is served in the school cafeteria. Wang writes that the students value being out in nature and learning through activities rather than just in their classrooms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295431?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Backtalk: Where are the teachers of color? Getting cut out and lured away</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 54-55, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research has shown that having a diverse teacher workforce benefits students, but the population of teachers remains predominantly white, even as the student population becomes increasingly diverse. Andrew Kwok and Brendan Bartanen analyzed data from college applications in Texas and found that interest in teacher certification has declined in the past decade more than interest in other professions. Promisingly, the racial makeup of college applicants interested in teaching is relatively diverse. However, at every stage in the process toward becoming a teacher, the diversity decreases. They recommend that education leaders and schools of education make intentional efforts to reach out to students of color early about the possibility of becoming a teacher.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295434?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: The case for sensory civics education</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 50-51, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Civics education should include ways for students to experience civic life and to understand how voting affects their lives. Jonathan E. Collins writes that civics education is currently perceived as a luxury. It is, instead, a societal necessity that will help build and maintain our civic infrastructure.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295432?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Employing School Librarians: What Decision-Makers Tell Us</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 42-46, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Although research has shown that having a school librarian benefits students, librarian positions are being cut in schools across the U.S. SLIDE — The School Librarian Investigation: Decline or Evolution? — examined federal data on school library staffing and interviewed 49 district leaders about their decisions to eliminate or add librarian positions. Keith Curry Lance, Debra E. Kachel, and Caitlin Gerrity report that of 54 total decisions leaders made related to changes in librarian staffing, 28 resulted in librarian increases and 26 resulted in librarian decreases. Decisions to add or eliminate positions were generally related to changes in district priorities. Although leaders expressed that they value librarians’ role in providing information literacy instruction and support and had positive experiences with librarians, some had to allocate resources to other positions. Others had trouble finding librarians with the necessary qualifications. When making staffing decisions, leaders need to consider what benefits librarians offer and how to meet student and staff needs for information and media literacy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295430?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: Organizational news about PDK International</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-63, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this month’s PDK Connection, CEO James F. Lane highlights a visit to a new Educators Rising site in Pennsylvania by U.S. Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona. Lane also addresses AI in the classroom and promotes new lesson assessments for Education Rising Curriculum users. Elsewhere in this regular department, PDK members share the one change they’d like to see in today’s schools and recount this summer’s trip to Vietnam with the PDK International Travel Program.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295437?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: Veteran educator wonders, ‘Is it too late to start over?’</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 56-57, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Educator Starr Sackstein gives workplace advice to educators. In this month’s column, an experienced teacher is feeling bored and wonders if it’s time to make a career pivot.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295435?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Poll Points: Public opinion on AI in schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 64-64, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;PDK International, Educators Rising, AI, PDK International Travel Program.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295438?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 7-7, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this regular column, Kappan authors recommend books that have influenced their thinking about education. In this issue, James Paul Gee recommends The Ignorant Schoolmaster: Five Lessons in Intellectual Emancipation by Jacques Rancière, and Ayesha Hashim recommends Suddenly Diverse: How School Districts Manage Race and Inequality by Erica O. Turner.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295422?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: Why come to school?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Workplace advice, Advice for educators, Career change, Student motivation, Teacher burnout
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295436?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editor’s Note: Nationwide problems, local solutions</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Kappan’s editor-in-chief shares highlights from the November 2024 issue, which focuses on student attendance and absenteeism.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295420?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
