<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race, ethnicity, and stratification within the first-generation student experience</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-08-2024 07:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2386954?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student-perceived parents’ and teachers’ expectancies and feedback influence homework motivation and effort</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-08-2024 07:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2385405?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Two-Stage Regression Approach to Detecting Section Score Inconsistency</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;For an assessment with multiple sections measuring related constructs, test takers with higher scores on one section are expected to perform better on the related sections. When the sections involve different test designs, test takers with preknowledge of an administration may score unusually high on some sections but not on others. To address such inconsistency, regression approaches have been successfully applied to compare section scores for many years in operational settings. With a focus on outlier analysis, we propose a new two-stage regression approach to detecting score inconsistency among different sections of a test. It is designed to leverage rich historical information from large-scale assessments to help detect unusually high scores on the easier-to-cheat sections based on the scores on the harder-to-cheat sections in new administrations. This paper presents a statistical framework for the two-stage regression procedure and develops analytical results under a null model of no exposure. It also describes an analysis procedure to guide applications. An empirical example is provided to illustrate the proposed method, to evaluate the performance and robustness of the analytical results in real settings, and to compare with two other methods for the detection of inconsistent section scores.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-08-2024 05:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241263974?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Protest and Resistance: Conceptualizing a Blackamerican Institutional Schema and the Contemporary Relevance of Pre-Brown Educators</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In the century following emancipation, Blackamericans developed robust and effective schools despite limited resources. Unfortunately, their successes and contributions to the education system are often overlooked. This interdisciplinary theoretical paper draws on historiographies of segregated school systems, examining the struggles of Blackamerican educators within segregated education systems through the lenses of coloniality and institutional work. This examination reveals a distinct Blackamerican institutional schema rooted in community, guiding educators in navigating structural and systemic dynamics that shape educational opportunities and successfully challenge dominant white education standards. We discuss the coloniality of schooling, a structural framework, and a mindset that continues to undergird our contemporary education system and then draw attention to an alternative perspective. Our goal is to work toward more inclusive and equitable education systems by recognizing and acknowledging the protest and resistance of Blackamerican educators, their contributions to alternative epistemologies, and the mindsets that guided their actions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 09:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241269812?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unequal City and Inequitable Choice: The Neoliberal State’s Development of School Choice and Marketization in the Publicly Funded Catholic School Board in Toronto, Canada</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 06:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2381394?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating insight and rigour as separate constructs in mathematical proof</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 03:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2379301?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting early career teachers’ self-regulation and goal pursuit through online coaching during a professional development programme</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 03:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2382820?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impostor phenomenon among racially minoritised university students: ‘who knows how to get rid of this?’</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 02:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2386949?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interference of prototypical geometry representations in students’ construction of concepts and development of proofs</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-06-2024 06:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2386619?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“If I bring my whole self to school, I am opening myself up to hurt”: A case study and (re)humanizing counterstory of an early career, multiply-marginalized multiracial teacher with justice commitments</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-06-2024 02:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2386952?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The algebraic learning of middle school students’ evolution during a school year: a statistical large-scale study based on results in mathematics didactics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This large-scale study characterizes the algebraic learning of a cohort of nearly 800 French students during the last year of middle school (9th grade, 14–15 years old) and examines their evolution in relation to the composition of the classes to which the students belong. Based on the Anthropological Theory of the Didactic (ATD), the study is founded both on a reference model of elementary algebra and on technological-theoretical levels characterizing the students’ reasoning and their knowledge regarding institutional expectations. These are used to code the data and define the statistical variables on which multivariate descriptive analyses are carried out. Students’ learning is analyzed through &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Pépite&lt;/em&gt;, an algebra test given at the beginning and at the end of the year. A cluster analysis resulted in three distinct clusters of similar classes and of similar students both at the beginning and end of the grade 9 school year. They are interpreted didactically and could be useful for a teacher who has to manage the heterogeneity of learning in a class. Some classes and students move from one cluster to another between the beginning and the end of the year, showing a wide variety of ways in which students’ algebra learning progresses or regresses over a school year.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-06-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10347-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Potential for Race Discrimination in Voucher Programs in a Post-Carson World</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-05-2024 04:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2381370?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning Inside the School, but Outside the Curriculum: An Extreme Case of Interest-Driven Learning in Alternative STEAM Learning Infrastructure for Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-05-2024 01:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2386956?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Errors and misconceptions of secondary school students in absolute values: a systematic literature review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Although absolute value is of interest to mathematics teaching researchers, since many students face problems with it, there does not seem to be an integrated record of students’ errors. The present study attempts to conduct a systematic review to identify and categorize errors and misconceptions of secondary school students aged 12–18 concerning the concept of absolute value. Following the PRISMA method, empirical studies published in English later since 1990 studying the errors and misconceptions of secondary school students with absolute value were looked up through the databases Scopus and Web of Sciences as well as through the Google Scholar search engine. From the 11 empirical studies that were eventually found, a categorization of misconceptions and corresponding errors arose. The first main category concerns the transition from the arithmetic to the algebraic domain while the second main category concerns the definition of absolute value in the form of a piecewise function. It is noteworthy that these two categories sometimes interact and are linked. Based on these findings, practical implications are discussed that strengthen the understanding of mathematical literacy.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00499-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hot Leadership, Cool Leadership: How Education Policies are Implemented (and Ignored) in Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The article advances an emergent framework for conceptualizing the relationship between principal leadership and education policy implementation. Based on a qualitative study of school principals and policy implementation in Region X of the Philippines, findings suggested that the way in which policies were interpreted and implemented at the school level was influenced by a variety of intrinsic and extrinsic dynamics and these were shaped in situ by individual, school and community inhibitors and facilitators. These motivations and localized contexts were critical to implementation, and compelled principals to ignore, monitor, or implement education policies as a priority.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2024 11:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241268309?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>E-Learning for the Public Good? The Policy Trajectory of Online Education in Ontario, Canada</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Our critical historiography of e-learning policy in Ontario, Canada, traces the policy’s trajectory through three settlements (2006-2022) and shows how successive governments have mobilized neoliberal discourses of personalization, access, and choice to justify new arrangements with private actors, within a broader sociopolitical context that includes increased privatization and commodification of public institutions, cuts to public spending, and imagines individuals as rational subjects driven to maximize their economic potential. This context exacerbates challenges students marginalized by schooling already face. Findings from our critical discourse analyses of government documents and news media reports also demonstrate that online learning in Ontario is neither personalized nor customizable but instead is centralized, standardized and, by design, operates independent of rather than interdependent with community. Further, our findings highlight the interdependence of schools – online and in-person – with social processes that create and perpetuate inequality, including gendered and racialized poverty, locally and abroad.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2024 11:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241267953?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward Race-Conscious Care-Based Healing to Support Latino Immigrant Youth</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This longitudinal convergent mixed-methods study sheds light on how school-based personnel such as educators, counselors, and district leaders perceive the needs of immigrant youth. Additionally, we explore how immigrant youth experience belonging and well-being in school and community spaces to advance a conceptual framework for ecosystems of care. The research questions ask how school-personnel manage the welcome of immigrant youth and how youth perceive belonging and well-being in schools. This study uses survey data from school and district personnel (N = 80) and qualitative data such as interviews and participant-observations with 41 Latino immigrant youth from school districts on the east coast. The study reports adult perceptions of immigrants’ needs and school climates as well as professional role constraints in fostering belonging for youth. The qualitative data shows the individual and structural level factors that impact Latino immigrant youth belonging and well-being. We theorize what we term race-conscious care-based healing in nested educational systems for Latino immigrant youth. We urge school systems, as an important nested context of reception, to consider forms of care-based healing to improve well-being, belonging and educational mobility for immigrant youth. We expand educational policy and sociological literature about schools as important contexts of reception for mitigating inequality. Implications for policy and practice are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2024 11:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241265509?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Core practices in teacher education: A global perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2024 08:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2386229?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Paying for School Finance Reforms: How States Raise Revenues to Fund Increases in Elementary-Secondary Education Expenditures</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study investigates how individual states raise revenue to pay for elementary-secondary education spending following school finance reforms (SFRs). We identify states that increased and sustained education expenditures after reform, search for legislative statutes that appropriated more education spending, and assess how policymakers funded the SFRs. Our results show that state legislatures increase investments in education by increasing tax revenue streams, such as sales and excise taxes, and by taking over property tax collections. Considering these results, we discuss that increased state investment in education should be accompanied by a policy mechanism to distribute state aid equitably to districts. Moreover, policymakers should consider local voters’ preferences when implementing SFR policies, as tax increases may reduce local fiscal effort for education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2024 04:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241264320?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The evaluation of computational modelling performance within the context of rationality theory: finding the area between two curves</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2024 02:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2382459?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School mathematics as context: examining discourses about the subject in district policymaking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;School subjects differ in their histories, epistemologies, and relations to state and federal policies. Though educational policymaking is shaped by how education leaders view school mathematics—what mathematics is, how mathematics is learned, and what counts as equitable and high-quality mathematics education—policy research often takes a subject-neutral perspective, ignoring the ways in which policymaking is rooted in the subject-matter. In this article, I report the ways in which systems of meaning or &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;discourses&lt;/em&gt; about school mathematics penetrate the policymaking of two school districts. Based on a discourse analysis of interviews, observations, and artifacts, I found five main discourses about school mathematics reflected in district policymaking: (1) mathematics is a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;core&lt;/em&gt; school subject; (2) mathematics is &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;sequential&lt;/em&gt;, where mastery of prior learning is necessary for future learning; (3) mathematics is &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;well-defined&lt;/em&gt;, with agreement over the content; (4) there are competing perspectives of high-quality mathematics pedagogy, between conceptually-oriented instruction and direct instruction focused on procedures; and (5) equity in mathematics is access and achievement. These discourses about school mathematics were written in formal policy texts, institutionalized in district-wide practices for assessment, intervention, and tracking, and reflected in leaders’ personal views and social narratives from teachers, parents, and the community. By making visible the taken-for-granted meanings about school mathematics shaping educational policymaking, it becomes possible to interrupt and challenge them with alternative discourses.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10348-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Un hiver long</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00328-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Same Arguments, Different Outcomes: Struggles Over Private School Funding in Alberta and Ontario, Canada</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2024 06:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2381388?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: Mathematics education research on language and on communication including some distinctions: where are we now?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01618-3</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
