<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Action research for transforming the poverty field special issue editorial team in cooperation with the authors</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2024 02:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231221078?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Teacher’s Role in Discourse and Social Regulation of Learning: Insights from Collaborative Sessions in High-School Physics Classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/hcgi20/42/1&quot;&gt;Volume 42, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, January-March 2024, Page 92-123&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2024 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2266847?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Debugging as a Platform for Transdisciplinary Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/hcgi20/42/1&quot;&gt;Volume 42, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, January-March 2024, Page 124-158&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2024 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2270094?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Doing research: a new researcher’s guide</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2024 01:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2291716?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Alan J. Bishop 1937–2023</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10302-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interactional practices of inviting minoritized students to whole-class mathematics discussions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Distributing opportunities to participate in talk-in-interaction during whole-class mathematics discussions is an important equity issue, with multiple studies reporting pervasive inequitable participation patterns in mathematics classrooms. Less attention, however, has been given to the underlying interactional practices that can initiate and support minoritized students’ participation. This article examines how and what kinds of opportunities for participation are interactionally generated for minoritized students in whole-class mathematics discussions in two US high school classrooms. Through the lenses of turn-taking organizations and epistemic dimensions from conversation analysis, this study details the interactional features of turn-taking by three Black students in predominantly White classrooms. The analysis shows the importance of establishing epistemic congruence about the nature of students’ knowledge before inviting them to take up the conversational floor. The findings imply that locally achieved, mutual understanding of what minoritized students know in the moment-by-moment classroom interaction is an important interactional feature for making minoritized students’ brilliance more visible during whole-class discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10292-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Slow emergencies of racism in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper adopts a biopower lens to examine emergency declarations that posit race or racism as problems to be addressed through mathematics education. We argue that attending to “slow emergencies” of racism must avoid sustaining mathematics education as a self-evident cause and cure for societal problems. We analyze how declarations of emergency reanimate racializing hierarchies by reordering spaces, temporalities, and subjectivities. To explore these concerns, we compare three race-explicit emergency declarations in US mathematics education during World War II with recent emergency declarations of pandemic-related learning loss, disengagement, and a racial reckoning. We juxtapose past and present to spotlight what we outline as distinct biopolitical working arrangements. The analysis maps how emergency declarations rearrange hopes, fears, diagnostic techniques, and intervention strategies—sometimes inadvertently reracializing students in attesting to damage or demanding redress. Our purpose is to foster deliberation over paradoxes and possibilities of addressing racialization and racism in mathematics education transnationally.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10293-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From development work to research publication: a case of Norwegian teacher educators developing research literacy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2024 10:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2298197?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Use of Reparametrization and Constraints on Linear Models to Parse Qualitative and Quantitative Information for a Set of Predictors</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The following study shows how reparameterizations and constraints of the general linear model can serve to parse quantitative and qualitative aspects of predictors. We demonstrate three different approaches. The study uses data from the High School Longitudinal Study of 2009 on mathematics course-taking and achievement as an example. Results show that all mathematics courses are not equally predictive of math achievement. Thus, taking into account qualitative aspects of mathematics courses is useful. The study ends with a justification of quantifying qualitative aspects of predictors relative to a criterion with extensions to other linear models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2024 07:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231223769?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CRToP: toward a critical race theory of power in higher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2024 06:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306380?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the foundations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/32/1&quot;&gt;Volume 32, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, February 2024, Page 1-6&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2024 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2301257?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The underlying beliefs in Pirkko’s narrative about implementing collaborative learning in mathematics - ‘my job is to give individual instruction’</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2024 12:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2298359?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transferability of Lessons From Program Evaluations: Iron Laws, Hiding Hands and the Evidence Ecosystem</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Assessing the transferability of lessons from social research or evaluation continues to raise challenges. Efforts to identify transferable lessons can be based on two different forms of argumentation. The first draws upon statistics and causal inferences. The second involves constructing a reasoned case based on weighing up different data collected along the causal chain from designing to delivery. Both approaches benefit from designing research based upon existing evidence and ensuring that the descriptions of the programme, context, and intended beneficiaries are sufficiently rich. Identifying transferable lessons should not be thought of as a one-off event but involves contributing to the iterative and learning of a scientific community. To understand the circumstances under which findings can be confidently transferred, we need to understand: (1) How far and why outcomes of interest have multiple, interacting and fluctuating causes. (2) The program design and implementation capacity. (3) Prior knowledge and causal landscapes (and how far these are included in the theory of change). (4) New and relevant knowledge; what can we learn in our ‘disputatious community of truth seekers’.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2024 11:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241228332?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cluster Randomized Trials Designed to Support Generalizable Inferences</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;When planning a cluster randomized trial, evaluators often have access to an enumerated cohort representing the target population of clusters. Practicalities of conducting the trial, such as the need to oversample clusters with certain characteristics in order to improve trial economy or support inferences about subgroups of clusters, may preclude simple random sampling from the cohort into the trial, and thus interfere with the goal of producing generalizable inferences about the target population. We describe a nested trial design where the randomized clusters are embedded within a cohort of trial-eligible clusters from the target population and where clusters are selected for inclusion in the trial with known sampling probabilities that may depend on cluster characteristics (e.g., allowing clusters to be chosen to facilitate trial conduct or to examine hypotheses related to their characteristics). We develop and evaluate methods for analyzing data from this design to generalize causal inferences to the target population underlying the cohort. We present identification and estimation results for the expectation of the average potential outcome and for the average treatment effect, in the entire target population of clusters and in its non-randomized subset. In simulation studies, we show that all the estimators have low bias but markedly different precision. Cluster randomized trials where clusters are selected for inclusion with known sampling probabilities that depend on cluster characteristics, combined with efficient estimation methods, can precisely quantify treatment effects in the target population, while addressing objectives of trial conduct that require oversampling clusters on the basis of their characteristics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2024 05:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231169557?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating a Hypothetical Learning Trajectory for nets of rectangular prisms: A teaching experiment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2024 04:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2303505?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strategy flexibility in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this article we review the research on the flexible or adaptive use of solution strategies in school mathematics, with a focus on the most recent work in the field. After a short introduction, we provide an overview of the various ways in which strategy flexibility has been conceptualized and investigated in the research literature. Then we review the research that has looked at the relationship between strategy flexibility and task proficiency, followed by studies that analyzed the association of strategy flexibility and other learner variables, including learners’ age, general mathematical ability, prior knowledge, executive functions, gender, and affect. Studies addressing the socio-cultural and educational embeddedness of strategy flexibility are reviewed next, and, finally, we discuss the intervention studies that have tried to stimulate learners’ strategy flexibility by means of various instructional approaches. While this review reveals that strategy flexibility is increasingly recognized as an important and valuable construct in research and practice of mathematics education, and that recently substantial progress has been made in our understanding of this construct, there are many aspects of it that are still not well-understood and that need further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 23:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01491-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Dakota Cultural Intervention’s Influence on Native Students’ Sense of Belonging: A CBPR Case Study</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;This community-based participatory research case study demonstrates how Dakota Wicoḣaƞ utilized Indigenous and feminist epistemologies to create, implement, and evaluate a cultural intervention, the Mni Sota Makoce: Dakota Homelands Curriculum, to increase Native 6th- and 10th-grade social studies students’ peoplehood sense of belonging (Tachine et al., 2017). Findings demonstrate Native students liked the curriculum and reported an increase in support and a decrease in invalidation of their sense of belonging. While the curriculum provided a source of racial-ethnic socialization, some European American students criticized the curriculum, which likely negatively impacted 6th-grade students psychological sense of school membership (Goodenow, 1993). Results indicate Indigenous culture, epistemologies, and pedagogies should be infused throughout all curricula, teachers need to be prepared to effectively deal with racist and discriminatory behavior, and Indian education is important to Native students’ belonging. Implications and recommendations for funders, schools, researchers, teacher education programs, and Native communities are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 07:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231221793?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“No me dejaran ir porque they needed me here”: spatializing corrective representatives by critiquing latinx teacher role model discourse</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 01:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306413?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>(Re)presenting race: an analysis of special education textbooks for engagement with race and ethnicity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 01:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306409?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Structure sense in students’ quantity comparison and repeating pattern extension tasks: an eye-tracking study with first graders</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;There is growing evidence that the ability to perceive structure is essential for students’ mathematical development. Looking at students’ structure sense in basic numerical and patterning tasks seems promising for understanding how these tasks set the foundation for the development of later mathematical skills. Previous studies have shown how students use structure sense in enumeration tasks. However, little is known about students’ use of structure sense in other early mathematical tasks. The main aim of this study is to investigate the ways in which structure sense is manifested in first-grade students’ work across tasks, in quantity comparison and repeating pattern extension tasks. We investigated students’ strategies in quantity comparison and pattern extension tasks and how students employ structure sense. We conducted an eye-tracking study with 21 first-grade students, which provided novel insights into commonalities among strategies for these types of tasks. We found that for both tasks, quantity comparison and repeating pattern extension tasks, strategies can be distinguished into those employing structure sense and serial strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10290-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Seeing number relations when solving a three-digit subtraction task</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The decomposition of numbers when solving subtraction tasks is regarded as more powerful than counting-based strategies. Still, many students fail to solve subtraction tasks despite using decomposition. To shed light upon this issue, we take a variation theoretical perspective (Marton, 2015) seeing learning as a function of discerning critical aspects and their relations of the object of learning. In this paper, we focus on what number relations students see in a three-digit subtraction task, and how they see them. We analyzed interview data from 55 second-grade students who used decomposition strategies to solve 204 − 193 = . The variation theory of learning was used to analyze what number relations the students experienced and how they experienced them, aiming to explain why they made errors even though they used presumably powerful strategies in their problem-solving. The findings show that students who simultaneously experienced within-number relations and between-number relations when solving the task succeeded in solving it, whereas those who did not do this failed. These findings have importance for understanding what students need to discern in order to be able to solve subtraction tasks in a proficient way.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10287-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>There’s ‘learning in that struggle’: journey mindsets and agency in action research and culturally responsive education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2024 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2304807?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Predicted Academic Performance to Identify At-Risk Students in Public Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Measures of student disadvantage—or risk—are critical components of equity-focused education policies. However, the risk measures used in contemporary policies have significant limitations, and despite continued advances in data infrastructure and analytic capacity, there has been little innovation in these measures for decades. We develop a new measure of student risk for use in education policies, which we call Predicted Academic Performance (PAP). PAP is a flexible, data-rich indicator that identifies students at risk of poor academic outcomes. It blends concepts from emerging early warning systems with principles of incentive design to balance the competing priorities of accurate risk measurement and suitability for policy use. In proof-of-concept policy simulations using data from Missouri, we show PAP is more effective than common alternatives at identifying students who are at risk of poor academic outcomes and can be used to target resources toward these students—and students who belong to several other associated risk categories—more efficiently.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2024 05:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231212163?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emergent mathematical worlds from teacher knowing in whole-class discourse: using an enactivist lens on the teaching of exponential functions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reports findings related to the pursuit of describing a lived knowing for teaching mathematics. Specifically, we used an enactivist perspective to describe the knowing exhibited by three experienced high school teachers in their instructional actions while leading whole-class instruction on the topic of the equations of exponential functions. From classroom observations, we constructed maps of the emergent mathematical worlds of ideas and collective mathematical activity. Three major categories of ideas emerged in all three teachers’ classrooms relating to the recursive multiplicative nature of exponential functions, the role of the independent variable, and the definition of exponential. Findings of this study suggest attending to teacher knowing for mathematical whole-class instruction must include describing the role of the mathematical activity in the emergence of the ascribed mathematical ideas. When teachers facilitated the collective mathematical activity as the means by which the mathematical ideas and justifications emerge, the mathematical worlds were diverse and complex, and connections among ideas were more robust in their comprehensibility.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09610-6</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
