<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging AI to enhance learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 40-45, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) technologies, such as ChatGPT, have ushered in a new digital era that presents formidable challenges related to cheating and plagiarism in the classroom. Although many school systems have reacted by banning AI language models and related applications, these technologies present opportunities to leverage formative assessment practices to enable students to demonstrate more complex and valued learning outcomes. Using the ICE (Ideas, Connections, Extensions) model, Louis Volante, Christopher DeLuca, and Don A. Klinger offer educators a research-informed pathway, based on best practices and policy, to promote critical, creative, and higher order thinking in secondary schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197475?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher expertise isn’t enough</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 46-50, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In recent research with classroom teachers on their personal pedagogical trajectories, Jeremy Glazer found teachers expressing concerns that their teaching practice was getting worse and they were not able to do the best teaching they knew how to do. The accounts of these teachers suggest that, when thinking about strategies for improving teachers’ practice, education leaders need to expand their focus beyond the knowledge, skills, and experience of teachers themselves and begin to look at the contexts in which teachers do their jobs. Specifically, teacher development initiatives need to include advocacy for sustainable workloads and teacher autonomy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197476?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why teachers leave: It isn’t what you think</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 51-55, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;With all the talk of turnover and shortages, it would be easy to think that many teachers have simply given up on education. Yet, despite the myriad challenges teachers have faced recently, this is not the case: Teachers care about their work as much as ever. Andrew Pendola, David Marshall, Tim Pressley, and Deja Trammell present a new narrative suggesting that there is no shortage of teacher dedication, even if some are leaving. They provide strategic, school-level changes that can not only help keep our best teachers, but also enrich their core purpose and dedication.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197477?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emerging stronger</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 24-28, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Pentucket Regional School District serves three small suburban communities north of Boston. Historically, its student performance had been quite high, but had been declining steadily for about a decade. The district had started reversing those losses, but the pandemic set it back. Now, however, the district has emerged even stronger; in most cases, student achievement already exceeds pre-pandemic levels. The reasons: new, high-quality curricula in multiple areas; a strong system of implementation supports; and a data-driven approach to help teachers address the specific needs of individual students. Assistant Superintendent Brent Conway explains how they did it.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197471?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A design course for every student</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 29-33, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Integrating STEAM with human-centered design is one way to transform the teaching of high school mathematics. Susanna Kemp described how this was done at Evanston Township High School in Illinois through a project-based learning class called STEAM Design Thinking &amp;amp; Innovation. The course equips students with real-world skills like critical thinking, creativity, communication, curiosity, collaboration, and empathy. Kemp describes the creation of the course as well as the design thinking process, shares how the course addresses critiques of design thinking, and encourages educators to develop curricula that focus on process over outcome and that de-emphasize competition.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197473?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Continued support for teachers; growing support for four-day school week: Findings from the 55th annual PDK poll</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 34-39, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The 55th Annual PDK Poll finds that a wide majority (66%) of adults say teachers should have a substantial say in what’s taught in public schools, more than say so about school boards, local residents, or lawmakers. Support for teachers also is apparent in another result from the 2023 PDK Poll: 67% of respondents support increasing local teacher salaries by raising property taxes. That result reflects the public’s broad sense that public school teachers are undervalued, underpaid, and overworked. At the same time, more than half of Americans support shifting to a four-day school week in their community, nearly twice as many as said so two decades ago. And structurally, beyond a four-day week, the poll finds that about six in 10 adults support other changes in how schools operate — longer school days and/or a longer school year — as ways to try to improve student learning outcomes. On another topic, results show widespread support for schools conducting mental health assessments of students. The survey was produced by Langer Research Associates for PDK International, with data collected June 16-25, 2023, in English and Spanish, among a representative, random national sample of 1,002 adults.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197474?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: PDK International appoints new CEO</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 69-71, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;News from PDK International: The Board of Directors of PDK International and the Board of Governors of the PDK Foundation announce the appointment of James F. Lane as CEO of PDK International. The 2023 Educators Rising conference featured the first-ever student delegate meeting and selection of new national officers. Student leader Milan Aranda, scholarship winner Kaitlyn Hannah, and emerging leader Kathryn Wiley are spotlighted.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197490?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Poll Points: Digging deeper into 2023 PDK Poll results</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 72-72, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The 2023 PDK Poll showed a sharp increase in the percentage of Americans who support the idea of a four-day school week since the question was last asked in 2003. A slim majority in 2023 (53%) said they would support a four-day school week, with longer school days, as a means of saving money. This infographic gives a snapshot of who supports this idea.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197491?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>One good thing, one day at a time: A conversation with Rebecka Peterson</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 8-12, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The 2023 National Teacher of the Year Rebecka Peterson is a high school math teacher in Tulsa, Oklahoma. Union High School serves more than 3,000 students, 72% of whom qualify for free and reduced-price lunch, and 62 languages are represented. Peterson, an immigrant to the U.S. whose parents were medical missionaries, builds trust in her classroom through stories—her stories and those of her students. During her first year of teaching, she discovered the “One Good Thing” blog founded by math teachers. It encouraged teachers to post their own stories of good things that happened during the day. The practice of scanning her day for one good thing that had occurred changed her mindset, allowing her to see more good things and finally persuading her to be the “one good thing” for her students each day.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197468?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Local success in the standards era</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 18-23, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The Common Core State Standards and Next Generation Science Standards were adopted in the early 2010s in most U.S. states with high hopes of improving educational achievement and equity. Almost a decade later, there is little evidence of the hoped-for improvements at the state and national level. However, state and national averages obscure gains that occurred in particular schools and districts. Elaine Allensworth, Laura M. Desimone, and Latrice Marianno share findings from studies of successes in multiple states and in Chicago. Their research shows that improvement was most likely when teachers engage in professional learning that is both flexible and specific, incorporates collaboration, focuses on practice, and offers guidance in using resources.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197470?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: The power of the bright side</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The September 2023 issue of Kappan focuses on “What’s going well in schools?” But it’s being published in a time when the news about schools seems to be nothing but bad. Teresa Preston, Kappan’s editor-in-chief, explains that there are lots of good things going on in individual districts, schools, and classrooms. Seeing the good takes time and mental discipline, but forming the habit of looking for good things makes it easier to recognize them when they appear.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197465?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How change-making teachers create bottom-up reforms</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 13-17, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Within our schools are change-making teachers who innovate and find ways to make their schools better for students. Rose Sebastian shares the stories of two change-making teachers who taught at high schools where integration within the school stopped at the classroom doors. With perseverance, a strong sales pitch, and a willingness to compromise, both teachers were able to create new, more integrated courses at their schools. By looking closely at their paths to change, we can gain new insights into how bottom-up reforms are created and into how we can support more teachers in becoming change-makers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197469?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Backtalk: ChatGPT: A powerful technology tool for writing instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 66-67, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Responding to widespread concern about the potential for artificial intelligence tool ChatGPT to enable cheating and discourage students from developing writing skills, authors Sarah W. Beck and Sarah R. Levine discuss how this latest and most powerful digital writing tool can help, rather than harm, developing writers. Drawing on research about the writing process and effective writing instruction, they outline ways that teachers can teach students to assess ChatGPT’s output with a critical eye and use the tool to overcome writers’ block and other obstacles to writing.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197487?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Browsing: Further thoughts on this month’s theme</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 5-6, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;News, quotes, and insights from the past related to the theme of the September 2023 issue of Kappan on “What’s going well in schools?”
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197466?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 7-7, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt; Kappan authors recommend favorite books that have inspired them. In this issue, Andrew Pendola recommends The Schooled Society by David Baker. Latrice Marianno recommends Teaching to Transgress by bell hooks.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197467?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Person: Our students want to volunteer. We can show them the way.</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 56-57, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Students want to volunteer, but they may not know how to find appropriate opportunities that will motivate them to participate regularly. Jamey Melcher writes about how she harnessed he students’ desire to volunteer by talking about volunteer opportunities in the classroom, doing some of the activities with students, and posting a current list organizations and events.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197482?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: What helped you learn last year?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 68-68, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Educators Rising students share some of the positive learning experiences they’ve had in the past year.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197489?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: Should we abolish school boards?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;News about violence and dysfunction at school board meetings may shape the impressions most people have of the public school governing body. While school boards have their flaws, Kappan columnist Jonathan E. Collins argues that they are worth preserving. School boards offer localized decision making and a way for a community to choose their representatives. School board meetings by law are open to the public and allow children under the age of 18 to speak and participate. Importantly, school boards are able to address student needs on a systemwide scale.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197483?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under The Law: Affirmative retraction</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-62, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Robert Kim and Kevin Welner discuss Students for Fair Admissions, Inc. v. Harvard College, in which the U.S. Supreme Court decreed that the admissions systems at the University of North Carolina (UNC) and Harvard College were unconstitutional. This ruling effectively banned the use of race-based admissions policies (i.e., affirmative action) in higher education. Kim and Welner explore what the ruling might mean for colleges and universities and the students seeking admission to them, implications for preK-12 education, and the larger context of social inequity.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197484?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: New teacher wants a mentor</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 64-65, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Phyllis Fagell gives career advice to educators. In this month’s column, a teacher asks if it’s acceptable to Google the names of students who are struggling to see if she can undercover underlying issues. A beginning teacher wants a mentor but isn’t sure how to go about building that relationship. A teacher who’s always willing to pitch in when the principal asks for help wants to get better at saying no.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197485?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An investigation of eighth-graders’ mathematical communication competency and mathematical literacy performance</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-26-2023 12:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2250752?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Edgar H. Schein 1928-2023: A Reflective Appreciation by David Coghlan</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-26-2023 04:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231199535?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Integrating Theory and Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-26-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00288-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>En intégrant la théorie et la pratique</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-26-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00287-w</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
