<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impacts of maker technologies on classroom learning outcomes: A mixed methods explanatory study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 11:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2239185?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>ebct: Using entropy balancing for continuous treatments to estimate dose–response functions and their derivatives</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 709-729, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Interest in evaluating dose–response functions of continuous treatments has been increasing recently. To facilitate the estimation of causal effects in this setting, I introduce the ebct command for the estimation of dose–response functions and their derivatives using entropy balancing for continuous treatments. First, balancing weights are estimated by numerically solving a globally convex optimization problem. These weights eradicate Pearson correlations between covariates and the treatment variable. Because simple uncorrelatedness may be insufficient to yield consistent estimates in the next step, higher moments of the treatment variable can be rendered uncorrelated with covariates. Second, the weights are used in local linear kernel regressions to estimate the dose–response function or its derivative. To perform statistical inference, I use a bootstrap procedure. The command also provides the option of producing publication-quality graphs for the estimated relationships.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196291?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>cntraveltime: Travel distance and travel time in China</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 730-753, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce the command cntraveltime, which can calculate both the travel distance and the travel time between two locations in China with respect to different modes of transportation (driving, public transport, and cycling). Existing commands such as georoute, traveltime, and mqtime have difficulties in parsing Chinese locations. cntraveltime solves this outstanding challenge via a feature that enables it to call route-planning services from the Baidu Maps Open Platform. The results of rigorous testing on the features of the command show that, relative to similar existing commands, cntraveltime has the highest capacity in terms of functionality and precision. This suggests that it can be regarded as a useful complement to other existing commands, especially when calculating travel distance and time for locations within China.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196292?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Robit regression in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 658-682, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Logistic and probit models are the most popular regression models for binary outcomes. A simple robust alternative is the robit model, which replaces the underlying normal distribution in the probit model with a Student’s t distribution. The heavier tails of the t distribution (compared with the normal distribution) mean that model outliers are less influential. Robit regression models can be fit as generalized linear models with the link function defined as the inverse cumulative t distribution function with a specified number of degrees of freedom; they have been advocated as being particularly suitable for estimating inverse-probability weights and propensity scoring more generally. Here we describe a new command, robit, that implements robit regression in Stata.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231195288?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mpitb: A toolbox for multidimensional poverty indices</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 625-657, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I present mpitb, a toolbox for multidimensional poverty indices (MPIs). The package mpitb comprises several subcommands to facilitate specification, estimation, and analyses of MPIs and supports the popular Alkire– Foster framework to multidimensional poverty measurement. mpitb offers several benefits to researchers, analysts, and practitioners working on MPIs, including substantial time savings (for example, because of lower data management and programming requirements) while allowing for a more comprehensive analysis at the same time. Aside from various convenience functions, mpitb also provides low-level tools for advanced users and programmers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231195286?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Review of Environmental Econometrics Using Stata, by Christopher F. Baum and Stan Hurn</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 897-900, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I review Environmental Econometrics Using Stata, by Christopher F. Baum and Stan Hurn (2021, Stata Press).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196497?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Facilities for optimizing and designing multiarm multistage (MAMS) randomized controlled trials with binary outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 774-798, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We introduce two commands, nstagebin and nstagebinopt, that can be used to facilitate the design of multiarm multistage (MAMS) trials with binary outcomes. MAMS designs are a class of efficient and adaptive randomized clinical trials that have successfully been used in many disease areas, including cancer, tuberculosis, maternal health, COVID-19, and surgery. The nstagebinopt command finds a class of efficient “admissible” designs based on an optimality criterion using a systematic search procedure. The nstagebin command calculates the stagewise sample sizes, trial timelines, and overall operating characteristics of MAMS designs with binary outcomes. Both commands allow the use of Dunnett’s correction to account for multiple testing. We also use the ROSSINI 2 MAMS design, an ongoing MAMS trial in surgical wound infection, to illustrate the capabilities of both commands. The new commands facilitate the design of MAMS trials with binary outcomes where more than one research question can be addressed under one protocol.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196295?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>iefieldkit: Commands for primary data collection and cleaning (update)</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 875-883, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Data collection and cleaning workflows implement highly repetitive but extremely important processes. In this article, we describe an update to iefieldkit, a package developed to standardize and simplify best practices for high-quality primary data collection across the World Bank’s Development Impact Evaluation department. The first release of iefieldkit provided workflows to automate error checking for Open Data Kit-based survey modules, duplicate management, data cleaning, and codebook creation. This update to the package includes improved commands to document and implement data point corrections, verify the structure or contents of data using codebooks, and create replicationready data through automated variable subsetting.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196496?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cluster randomized controlled trial analysis at the cluster level: The clan command</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 754-773, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce a new command, clan, that conducts a cluster-level analysis of cluster randomized trials. The command simplifies adjusting for individual- and cluster-level covariates and can also account for a stratified design. It can be used to analyze a continuous, binary, or rate outcome.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196294?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Speaking Stata: Replacing missing values: The easiest problems</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 884-896, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Missing values are common in real datasets, and what to do about them is a large and challenging question. This column focuses on the easiest problems in which a researcher is clear, or at least highly confident, about what missing values should be instead, implying a deterministic replacement. The main tricks are copying values from observation to observation and using the ipolate command. Both may often be extended simply to panel or longitudinal datasets or to other datasets with a group structure, such as data on individuals within families or households. This column includes how to satisfy constraints that interpolation is confined to filling gaps between values known to be equal or to observations moderately close to a known value in time or in some other sequence or position variable.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196519?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Review of Multilevel and Longitudinal Modeling Using Stata, Fourth Edition, by Sophia Rabe-Hesketh and Anders Skrondal</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 901-904, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This article reviews Multilevel and Longitudinal Modeling Using Stata, Fourth Edition, by Rabe-Hesketh and Skrondal (2022, Stata Press).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196518?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>hdps: A suite of commands for applying high-dimensional propensity-score approaches</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 683-708, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Large healthcare databases are increasingly used for research investigating the effects of medications. However, a key challenge is capturing hard-to-measure concepts (often relating to frailty and disease severity) that can be crucial for successful confounder adjustment. The high-dimensional propensity score has been proposed as a data-driven method to improve confounder adjustment within healthcare databases and was developed in the context of administrative claims databases. We present hdps, a suite of commands implementing this approach in Stata that assesses the prevalence of codes, generates high-dimensional propensity-score covariates, performs variable selection, and provides investigators with graphical tools for inspecting the properties of selected covariates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196288?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Iterative intercensal single-decrement life tables using Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 813-834, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;One way to estimate mortality in countries with incomplete data is to utilize intercensal methods, which do not require model life tables and provide accurate results even in the presence of age distortions and death underregistration. In this article, I revisit three of these techniques (census based, death distribution, and an iterative procedure) and introduce ilt, a command to calculate singledecrement life tables and the net flow of migrants by age. The required inputs are two age-specific population distributions and the average number of deaths between them. The empirical example draws on data from Vietnam, but the methods are extendable to any context and period.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196441?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estimating text regressions using txtreg_train</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 799-812, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I introduce new commands to estimate text regressions for continuous, binary, and categorical variables based on text strings. The command txtreg_train automatically handles text cleaning, tokenization, model training, and cross-validation for lasso, ridge, elastic-net, and regularized logistic regressions. The txtreg_predict command obtains the predictions from the trained text regression model. Furthermore, the txtreg_analyze command facilitates the analysis of the coefficients of the text regression model. Together, these commands provide a convenient toolbox for researchers to train text regressions. They also allow sharing of pretrained text regression models with other researchers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196349?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>winratiotest: A command for implementing the win ratio and stratified win ratio in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 835-850, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The win ratio is a statistical method most commonly used for analyzing composite outcomes in clinical trials. Composite outcomes comprise two or more distinct “component” events (for example, myocardial infarction or death) and are typically analyzed using time-to-first-event methods ignoring the relative importance of the component events. When using the win ratio, component events are instead placed into a hierarchy from most to least important; more important components can then be prioritized over less important outcomes (for example, death can be prioritized over myocardial infarction). Furthermore, the win ratio enables outcomes of different types (for example, time-to-event, continuous, binary, ordinal, and repeat events) to be combined. We present winratiotest, a command to implement the win-ratio approach for hierarchical outcomes in a flexible and user-friendly way.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196480?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>synth2: Synthetic control method with placebo tests, robustness test, and visualization</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 597-624, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The synthetic control method (Abadie and Gardeazabal, 2003, American Economic Review 93: 113–132, Abadie, Diamond, and Hainmueller, 2010, Journal of the American Statistical Association 105: 493–505) is a popular method for causal inference in panel data with one treated unit that often uses placebo tests for statistical inference. While the synthetic control method can be implemented by the excellent command synth (Abadie, Diamond, and Hainmueller, 2011, Statistical Software Components S457334, Department of Economics, Boston College), it is still inconvenient for users to conduct placebo tests. As a wrapper program for synth, our proposed synth2 command provides convenient utilities to automate both in-space and in-time placebo tests, as well as the leave-one-out robustness test. Moreover, synth2 produces a complete set of graphs to visualize covariate or unit weights, covariate balance, actual or predicted outcomes, treatment effects, placebo tests, ratio of posttreatment mean squared prediction error to pretreatment mean squared prediction error, pointwise p-values (two-sided, right-sided, and left-sided), and the leave-one-out robustness test. We illustrate the use of the synth2 command by revisiting the classic example of California’s tobacco control program (Abadie, Diamond, and Hainmueller 2010).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231195278?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>blandaltman: A command to create variants of Bland–Altman plots</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 851-874, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Bland–Altman plots can be useful in paired data settings such as measurement-method comparison studies. A Bland–Altman plot has differences, percentage differences, or ratios on the y axis and a mean of the data pairs on the x axis, with 95% limits of agreement indicating the central 95% range of differences, percentage differences, or ratios. This range can vary with the mean. We introduce the community-contributed blandaltman command, which uniquely in Stata can 1) create Bland–Altman plots featuring ratios in addition to differences and percentage differences, 2) allow the limits of agreement for ratios and percentage differences to vary as a function of the mean, and 3) add confidence intervals, prediction intervals, and tolerance intervals to the plots.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196488?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcements</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 906-907, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196522?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Connecting mathematics to STEM education: interdisciplinary teaching and learning facilitation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In interdisciplinary Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics (STEM) education, empirical evidence is required that points to the educational contribution of mathematics. Specifically, researchers are not clear how mathematics weaves itself through the STEM education meta-discourse. This article contributes to pedagogical practices in educational institutions where STEM has been newly introduced - What are the perceptions and experiences of South African teachers on interdisciplinary STEM education, and how do mathematics and interdisciplinary STEM discourses leverage each other at schools of specialisation (SoS) in South Africa? Participant teachers were drawn from ten SoS in South Africa. SoS are STEM-dense schools in South Africa’s Gauteng Province, the country’s industrial and commercial hub. Interview data was collected on teachers’ experiences and practices to explore the affordances of Mathematics and other STEM disciplines to influencing curriculum advancement. Situated cognition, mathematics as explorations and flow theory informed this qualitative study. In the findings, technology was regarded as raising learner motivation and mathematical achievement. Important to the study is that participants have a high regard for mathematics’ role in interdisciplinary STEM education. In the study, teachers had no autonomy to pursue the STEM agenda, as they were bound to adhere to a prescribed curriculum, which hardly refers to implementation of interdisciplinary STEM education. Various recommendations are proffered, such as maintaining the positive perceptions participants have on the role of mathematics in STEM curricula. The research calls for equality and equity of all the STEM disciplines, as one STEM curricula cannot succeed without the other.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01522-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Everybody’s talking about doing co-design, but to really truly genuinely authentically do it […] it’s bloody hard”: Radical openness in youth participatory action research</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Guided by the work of bell hooks, this study uses her concept of ‘radical openness’ as an innovation for multi-party facilitation teams negotiating different roles, positionalities and understandings of youth participatory action research (YPAR). We explore the challenges we negotiated as facilitators in YPAR as they materialised in weekly reflections. We write as a team of two project leaders, three researchers and a project manager. Data comprised recordings of collaborative meetings, weekly reflections and focus groups. Two themes captured the challenges that we experienced and reflexively negotiated. First, we uncovered our own biases and assumptions through critical reflection and dialogue between comrades. Second, as a facilitation team we were able to negotiate authenticity and accountability in relation to project governance and reporting. Radical openness enabled us to identify and mitigate power relations as a team, collectively deepening our consciousness and research praxis. We all proved willing to acknowledge what we each did not know and use our imaginations to see things from each other’s perspectives. Based on our experiences, we suggest that multi-party facilitation teams consider how radical openness can help to cultivate spaces of dialogue between comrades to disrupt hegemonic and colonised views in YPAR.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-21-2023 10:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231200982?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Critical Examination of the Relationship Between Social and Personal Constructions of Gender and Race and their Impact on Mathematical Identity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-21-2023 06:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2254152?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ participation in mathematics in inclusive classrooms: a study of the enacted mathematical and relational knowing of teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-21-2023 01:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2258485?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers and School Leaders’ Readiness for Parental Engagement: Critical Policy Analysis of Canadian Standards</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher readiness for parental engagement is a vital competence in the context of increased emphasis on engaging parents in K–12 schools. The rise in the standards movement in education led to the inclusion of parental engagement in teacher standards. Here, critical policy analysis of teacher standards shows how teachers’ and school leaders’ readiness for parental engagement is addressed in Canadian policy documents. Teacher readiness is conceptualized as the ability to establish relationships, support communication, and build partnerships with parents and families. Current policy provisions support teachers’ capacity for parental engagement by introducing the asset-based approach to engagement and acknowledging the diversity among parents. Nevertheless, teacher standards fail to distinguish between parental involvement in schooling and parental engagement in education/learning and remain silent on the role of social inequality in parental engagement. Implications for new teacher standards include centering parental engagement on parents and families and tackling inequality in parental engagement.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-20-2023 09:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231199365?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Forced to Choose: Lessons Learned from Families of Students Within Special Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this interview study, we utilize a theoretical framework that combines Bell’s theory of choice sets with DisCrit to explore how parents of students with IEPs (SIEPs) experienced a forced school choice embedded with the 2013 mass school closures in Chicago. We find that a child’s disability was a primary factor in parent’s choices. Further, all parents in our sample had conceptions of ideal schools, but a child’s IEP and other barriers—including safety and transportation—could prevent parents from enrolling their child in an otherwise desired school. In this way a child’s IEP could provide access to needed services while also denying families from desired learning environments. These findings point to the ableist nature of school choice and contribute to the growing body of research that questions the theoretical underpinnings of school choice as an education reform strategy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-20-2023 08:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231198814?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
