<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Extending the Simple View of Reading in Second and Foreign Language Learning: A Meta-Analytic Structural Equation Modeling Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study used a meta-analytic structural equation modeling approach to build extended versions of the simple view of reading (SVR) model in second and foreign language (SFL) learning contexts (i.e., SVR-SFL). Based on the correlation coefficients derived from primary studies, we replicated and integrated two previous extended meta-analytic SVR models, that is, Quinn and Wagner’s (2018) model with an English-speaking population with a cognitive factor and Peng et al.’s (2021) model with Chinese-speaking readers with metalinguistic skills. A total of 180 independent samples (N = 36,235) obtained from 152 empirical studies in SFL contexts were included in our meta-analytic structural equation model. The results revealed that the collected data successfully replicated H. Lee et al.’s (2022) SVR model in SL contexts (SV2R) in terms of overall model fit and moderation effects; in addition, the results confirmed that the data fit well with the extended SVR-SFL models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-25-2023 06:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231186605?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Causal Stories and Problem Definitions: How Policymakers and Superintendents Frame School Turnaround</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This study uses framing theory and the concept of causal stories to examine beliefs about causes and solutions to improving chronically low-performing schools in response to Michigan’s school turnaround policy. Across cases, policymakers and district leaders assigned most responsibility to poor leadership, poverty, and chronic educator turnover as primary causes of problems leading to turnaround identification. These causal stories were most often framed as side effects of policy or practice rather than as intentional actions. However, a notable subset assigned blame more directly to intentional policy action (or inaction) that would help districts counteract the effects of concentrated poverty, such as weighted funding. In terms of solutions, most leaders believed that improved funding was necessary to strengthen and stabilize the workforce and meet the nonacademic needs of children—for instance, attending to the deleterious effects of poverty through wraparound services or efforts to address trauma.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-25-2023 06:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231186425?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of contextual knowledge in noticing students’ strategies in-the-moment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-25-2023 06:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://maa.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2239418?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking Collective Reflection in Teacher Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Collective reflection, which has become a de rigueur activity in teacher training and professional development, is predicated upon Schön’s theory of reflective practice. This concept, according to which people learn to be reflective-in-action through reflection on practice, relates primarily to individual and one-on-one mentorship processes. The shift from individual to collective processes has gone largely unstudied and unproblematized. This study of collective teacher reflection in a professional development workshop calls prevailing assumptions into question by bringing an alternative lens, textual trajectories, to bear on this ubiquitous activity to better account for oft-ignored issues of context and identity. Using linguistic ethnographic methods, it traces textual trajectories of key ideas indexed in a collective reflection event. Key findings include the nonlinearity of the reflective process and the centrality of identity-work in collective teacher reflection. This study thus reveals functions of this ritual that belie its ostensible purposes and suggest a rethinking of this practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-24-2023 08:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231188702?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Plantation “All Charter” Model and the Long Durée of Resistance for Black Public High Schools in New Orleans</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Education research has often overlooked how the long durée of resistance for Black education has shaped current educational policy. We complicate notions of Black public school closures in two case studies from extensive ethnographic research in post-Katrina New Orleans through our reading of the plantation. Findings suggest these institutions have served as linchpins for the transferal of the blues. Data analysis also indicates that traditional public school closures have functioned as a plantation management device. We encourage future inquiries into portfolio governance models, school “choice,” and school closures to consider the plantation complex and to recognize that post-Katrina education reforms were not isolated policy enactments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-24-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231182751?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bayesian Change-Point Analysis Approach to Detecting Aberrant Test-Taking Behavior Using Response Times</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/48/4&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 490-520, August 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Change-point analysis (CPA) is a method for detecting abrupt changes in parameter(s) underlying a sequence of random variables. It has been applied to detect examinees’ aberrant test-taking behavior by identifying abrupt test performance change. Previous studies utilized maximum likelihood estimations of ability parameters, focusing on detecting one change point for each examinee. This article proposes a Bayesian CPA procedure using response times (RTs) to detect abrupt changes in examinee speed, which may be related to aberrant responding behaviors. The lognormal RT model is used to derive a procedure for detecting aberrant RT patterns. The method takes the numbers and locations of the change points as parameters in the model to detect multiple change points or multiple aberrant behaviors. Given the change points, the corresponding speed of each segment in the test can be estimated, which enables more accurate inferences about aberrant behaviors. Simulation study results indicate that the proposed procedure can effectively detect simulated aberrant behaviors and estimate change points accurately. The method is applied to data from a high-stakes computerized adaptive test, where its applicability is demonstrated.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-24-2023 01:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231151961?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Improved Inferential Procedure to Evaluate Item Discriminations in a Conditional Maximum Likelihood Framework</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A modified and improved inductive inferential approach to evaluate item discriminations in a conditional maximum likelihood and Rasch modeling framework is suggested. The new approach involves the derivation of four hypothesis tests. It implies a linear restriction of the assumed set of probability distributions in the classical approach that represents scenarios of different item discriminations in a straightforward and efficient manner. Its improvement is discussed, compared to classical procedures (tests and information criteria), and illustrated in Monte Carlo experiments as well as real data examples from educational research. The results show an improvement of power of the modified tests of up to 0.3.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-20-2023 05:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231183335?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Latent Trait Item Response Models for Continuous Responses</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A general framework of latent trait item response models for continuous responses is given. In contrast to classical test theory (CTT) models, which traditionally distinguish between true scores and error scores, the responses are clearly linked to latent traits. It is shown that CTT models can be derived as special cases, but the model class is much wider. It provides, in particular, appropriate modeling of responses that are restricted in some way, for example, if responses are positive or are restricted to an interval. Restrictions of this sort are easily incorporated in the modeling framework. Restriction to an interval is typically ignored in common models yielding inappropriate models, for example, when modeling Likert-type data. The model also extends common response time models, which can be treated as special cases. The properties of the model class are derived and the role of the total score is investigated, which leads to a modified total score. Several applications illustrate the use of the model including an example, in which covariates that may modify the response are taken into account.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-20-2023 05:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231184147?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Over-Tourism to Under-Tourism via COVID-19: Lessons for Sustainable Tourism Management</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;With various strains of the novel coronavirus emerging during the last few years, there is a need to reinvent and manage the tourism industry by engaging various stakeholders. Industry and policymakers need to observe the shift and curate tourism-related products and offerings accordingly. In light of the increasing demand for innovations and future directions in the post-COVID-19 period, this article conducts a bibliometric analysis for sustainable tourism studies spanning the years 1990–2021. This paper presents an integrative review of tourism, environment and sustainable tourism to reveal geographical, contextual, and methodological directions for future research. The comprehensive analysis includes contributions on topics and methods, country collaborations, and thematic analysis. The findings are consistent with the Sustainable Development Goals of sustainable production and consumption (SDG-12), with a particular emphasis on sustainable tourism to promote local culture and create jobs (SDG-12.b) and on sustainable growth (SDG-13). The study’s findings can be used to inform future policies and directions; for example, the findings indicate that the hospitality industry is facing challenges that necessitate new regulations to address its socioeconomic and environmental impacts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-20-2023 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231189805?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strengthening mathematical orientation: how university mathematics courses can gain relevance for pre-service teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of the article is to discuss how university mathematics courses can become more relevant for pre-service teachers (PSTs). We therefore introduce a concept we call mathematical orientation and develop an analytical framework based on Felix Klein’s pervasive approach to elementary mathematics from a higher standpoint and the work of the practical philosopher Stegmaier on orientation. This framework is used to analyze the mathematical orientation of PSTs on two mathematics courses in Norway and Switzerland. In a qualitative empirical approach, we analyzed 85 reflections written by PSTs on the topic of decimal expansions and reconstructed aspects of their individual mathematical orientation. Our results show that mathematical orientation varies across PSTs to a certain extent. In particular, different points of reference, perspectives, standpoints, and types of links between the mathematical content and teaching situations could be identified. We therefore propose that mathematical orientation can be considered a key variable in addressing the mathematical needs of PSTs in university courses.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2023 16:28</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01492-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Puzzle identification in action research in initial teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2023 09:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2238003?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Evidence Clearinghouses Can Avoid the Winner’s Curse</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2023 07:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2194298?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Nudging Mentors Weaken Student Support? Experimental Evidence from a Virtual Communication Intervention</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2023 07:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2186291?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Chain as Strong as Its Strongest Link? Understanding the Causes and Consequences of Biases Arising from Selective Analysis and Reporting of Research Results</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-18-2023 05:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2219673?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inquiry-based mathematics education and attitudes towards mathematics: tracking profiles for teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research on the relationships between the main constructs underlying inquiry-based learning is rarely reported in mathematics education research. Considering this as a complex problem which is worth to be investigated, the present study aims to provide some empirical evidences that might serve as an insight to support further investigations on the relationships between attitudes towards mathematics and inquiry-based learning approaches. Thus, this study adopts a descriptive research design where no variables are manipulated but observed and measured in order to identify changes depicted in data collection. An instructional design focusing on the nature of mathematical inquiry is carried out with the participation of 304 secondary and high school students, and a clustering approach is used to look at how participants are grouped around certain attitudinal profiles before and after such mathematical practice. The results show how the heterogeneity of attitudinal profiles present in the classroom evolves positively in terms of perceived usefulness of mathematics and mathematical self-concept as perception of competence in mathematics. This fact provides some basis that might be used for further research on the idea that certain forms of development in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;inquiry-based mathematics education (IBME)&lt;/em&gt; based on greater immersion in the nature and culture of mathematics can help students to improve their attitudes towards mathematics.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-18-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00468-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cream Skimming and Pushout of Students Participating in a Statewide Private School Voucher Program</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A pervasive issue in the school choice literature is whether schools of choice cream skim students by enrolling high-achieving, less-challenging, or less-costly students. Similarly, schools of choice may “push out” low-achieving, more-challenging, or more-costly students. Using longitudinal student-level data from Indiana, we created multiple measures to examine whether there is evidence consistent with the claims of voucher-participating private schools cream skimming the best students from public schools or pushing out voucher-receiving students. We do not find evidence consistent with the claim of cream skimming. However, we find evidence consistent with the claim of private schools pushing out the lowest-achieving voucher students. This is the first study to examine these two issues within a statewide private school voucher program.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-17-2023 04:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231183397?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cultivating Stronger Coaching in Clinical Mentors: An Experimental Evaluation of the Mentors Matter Professional Development Initiative</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Despite the critical role of mentors in the preparation of preservice teachers, very little causal quantitative research has explored the effects of offering mentors professional development (PD) around how to coach and support their candidates. We conduct an experimental evaluation of a PD opportunity randomly offered to mentors within six different Tennessee programs over the course of 3 years to investigate its impacts on the perceptions and practices of both the mentors themselves and their candidates. PD significantly increased the frequency of coaching provided by mentors and mentors’ own instructional effectiveness but did not impact their candidates’ satisfaction or feelings of preparedness, though candidates of mentors assigned to treatment were marginally significantly more likely to find employment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-17-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231183414?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Interest to Entry: The Teacher Pipeline From College Application to Initial Employment</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Strengthening teacher supply is a key policy objective for K–12 public education, but understanding of the early teacher pipeline remains limited. In this descriptive analysis, we leverage the universe of applications to a large public university in Texas from 2009 to 2020 to examine the pipeline into teacher education and employment as a K–12 public school teacher. A unique feature of Texas’s centralized higher education application is that it solicits potential interest in teacher certification. We document sharply declining interest in teaching over the period. Further, we show that students of color, men, and students with higher SAT scores are substantially underrepresented in teacher education. Particularly for race/ethnicity, these disparities are only partially explained by differences in interest at application.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-15-2023 07:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231185733?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Undergraduate students’ attitudes towards mathematical proving in an introduction to proof course</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, we investigated undergraduate mathematics students’ (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 267) attitudes towards proving. The students were taking an introduction-to-proof type course that was situated at the beginning of the mathematics curriculum and lasted for one term. Four attitude variables were measured at the beginning and at the end of the course with a new self-report instrument: self-efficacy, anxiety, appreciation and motivation. The instrument was based on two existing instruments on mathematics attitudes and proof-related self-efficacy. We studied how these four attitude variables were related to the students’ prior skills and their gender at the beginning of the course, how the attitude variables changed during the course, and how they affected the students’ performance in the final course project. Our results indicate that students’ prior performance is linked to their proof-related self-efficacy, anxiety and motivation at the beginning of the course. Female students exhibited lower efficacy and motivation levels than male students. During the focus course, students’ self-efficacy increased and anxiety decreased. The gender gaps in self-efficacy and motivation persisted throughout the course. In addition, high motivation in the beginning of the course predicted good performance in the final project. Based on our results, we conclude that an introductory course on proving can enhance students’ attitudes, and we suggest that these attitudes are taken into account in teaching as they can affect students’ performance. Finally, we urge researchers and professionals to earnestly consider ways to mitigate gender differences in mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-15-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10239-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Role-play experience’s effect on students’ 21st century skills propensity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/vjer20/116/3&quot;&gt;Volume 116, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, 2023, Page 159-170&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-14-2023 04:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2227596?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Historical influences, present problems, and futuristic solutions in African countries. Brantina Chirinda, Kakoma Luneta, and Alphonse Uworabayeho (Eds.). (2022). Mathematics education in Africa: the fourth industrial revolution</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-14-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10249-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing Geometric Reasoning of the Relationship of the Cauchy Riemann Equations and Differentiation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigates the embodied, symbolic, and formal reasoning of two fourth-year university students while exploring geometric reasoning about the Cauchy-Riemann equations with the aid of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Geometer’s Sketchpad (GSP)&lt;/em&gt;. These students participated in a teaching activity designed to encourage shifts between embodied, symbolic, and formal reasoning of the Cauchy-Riemann equations as they relate to the amplitwist concept. This research extends previous work related to the complex derivative which only makes use of the limit definition. The Cauchy-Riemann equations naturally integrate notions from linear algebra and multi-variable calculus, which have their own embodied and symbolic interpretations and introduce different challenges in developing a geometric/embodied understanding of the C-R equations. Our work also illustrates how conversations expressed through utterances served as a catalyst for teasing out and connecting the symbolic representations such as the Jacobian and partial derivatives inherent in the Cauchy-Riemann equations. As such, taking part in conversations via utterances with &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;GSP&lt;/em&gt;, inscriptions, and other students can create opportunities for students to connect concepts and recognize contradictions across multiple forms of reasoning. We offer potential anticipatory knowledge for complex analysis instructors to facilitate similarly rich conversations within the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-14-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00223-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Two-Eyed Seeing Teaching and Learning Framework for Science Education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Worldwide, education jurisdictions are looking for authentic ways to address First Nations perspectives in the K-12 curriculum, including science education. At the same time, there have been ongoing efforts to integrate authentic and engaging approaches to teaching science, including those that are student-centred, inquiry-based, multimodal, and linked to meaningful contexts. Both goals may be realised through the principle of Two-Eyed Seeing (TES), which seeks to integrate the strengths of Indigenous ways of knowing with one eye, and Western ways of knowing with the other eye, for the benefit of all students. This theoretical paper presents a Two-Eyed Seeing for Science Education (TESSE) Framework, which brings together two pedagogical models. One is from a contemporary science perspective, the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;5Es&lt;/em&gt; representation-rich inquiry approach, which scaffolds authentic student-centred conceptually focused learning experiences. The other is from an Indigenous perspective, the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;8 Aboriginal Ways of Learning, which&lt;/em&gt; illustrates different ways of knowing—many of which are familiar with First Peoples across the world (e.g., place-based, visual, holistic). The TESSE Framework aims to act as a strengths-based interface between the two knowledge systems to support a culturally responsive approach to teaching and learning science. It is designed to support meaningful connections through curriculum and pedagogy in ways that are contextually relevant to place. Through empirical investigation and in collaboration with local communities, the Framework has the potential to inform current approaches to science education in schools and universities and provide a pathway towards decolonisation and reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-14-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00276-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Self-Care Mandates as Institutional Gaslighting in a Neoliberal System</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this manuscript, I argue that narratives of self-care for educators in the midst of pandemic teaching are a form of gaslighting, supported and exacerbated by a neoliberal school system that reinforces individualist, White-normed conceptions of teaching and learning. To make this argument, I use several excerpts from practicing teachers’ writing to illustrate the deep sense of frustration and betrayal that teachers felt when inundated with self-care messages without regard for more systemic support and change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-13-2023 02:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231174804?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
