<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Action research with sociodrama in a healthcare institution</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article presents an action research study initiated in 2021, which employed the sociodrama method within a medical institution with healthcare assistants to improve their situation. The study discusses firstly the implications of the deepening and broadening nature of action research knowledge generation within that specific context. Secondly, it delves into the sociodrama method, emphasizing its compatibility with both the fundamental elements and the core principles of action research. Lastly, the study presents various project outcomes, categorized based on their focus: direct effects on individuals and groups, actions and action plans implemented at the group and institutional levels, and identified issues concerning the institutional and cultural context.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-08-2024 03:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241258875?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ripple Effect of Managerial Behavior: Exploring Post-experimental Impact of Leading by Example on Small Firms’ Cooperation and Performance</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Cooperation between employees in a company is an important input to firm performance. This study examines how a manager’s cooperative behavior and the visibility of this behavior affect the cooperation amongst employees, and subsequently firm performance. To do so, we conducted a field experiment with managers and their employees from 320 Vietnamese small and micro firms to determine the impact of a manager’s leading by example (LBE) on employees’ behavior, corporate culture, and firm performance. Both managers and employees participated in a Public Good experiment which aimed to elicit an individual cooperative behavior. Noteworthy is that the decision made by a manager in the experiment was given as an example to employees before they made decision in that same experiment. We considered that the example of cooperation by managers in the Public Good experiment communicated a powerful signal to the employees regarding the importance of fostering cooperation in the workplace. Such a signal by the manager, who is at the top in the organizational hierarchy, would impact their employees’ behavior in the workplace and firm’s outcomes beyond the experiment. Interestingly, we found that concealing a manager’s identity from their employees enhances the impacts of LBE.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-08-2024 02:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241260466?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Education Research-Practice Partnerships: Impacts and Dynamics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-07-2024 12:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357033?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ beliefs on integrating children’s literature in mathematics teaching and learning in Indonesia</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The integration of children’s literature, specifically mathematical story picture books, in mathematics education has demonstrated significant benefits. Nevertheless, its actual implementation largely hinges on teachers’ beliefs. This exploratory mixed-methods study examines the beliefs of 78 teachers regarding the integration of children’s literature into mathematics teaching and learning, with a focus on identifying its barriers and enablers. Data were collected through an open-ended survey and semi-structured interviews and analyzed using thematic analysis framed by the concept of belief indication. The study identifies 15 barriers (across five themes) and 16 enablers (across six themes) that, teachers believe, affect their decisions to integrate children’s literature into mathematics teaching and learning. This paper contextualizes the findings within the Theory of Planned Behavior (TPB), a framework from social psychology, to provide actionable recommendations and compare findings from studies conducted in Asian and Western countries. Ultimately, this research offers a broader understanding of teachers’ behaviors and their receptiveness to educational reforms, such as the integration of children’s literature, across diverse cultural and international settings.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-07-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10334-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Mathematics Teacher Education Partnership: The Power of a Networked Improvement Community to Transform Secondary Mathematics Teacher Preparation: A Review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;A review of Martin, W. G., Lawler, B. R., Lischka, A. E., &amp;amp; Smith, W. M. (&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r1&quot;&gt;2020&lt;/span&gt;). &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The Mathematics Teacher Education Partnership: The Power of a Networked Improvement Community to Transform Secondary Mathematics Teacher Preparation&lt;/em&gt;. Charlotte, North Carolina: Information Age Publishing, xix + 412 pp., $62.04 (paperback), ISBN 978–1-64,113–931-1, $89.24 (hardcover), ISBN 978–1-64,113–932-8.&lt;/p&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This book offers a thorough overview of a 7-year initiative by the Mathematics Teacher Education Partnership (MTE-Partnership), a national consortium uniting over 90 universities and 100 school systems. Focused on preparing secondary mathematics teachers, the MTE-Partnership operates as a Networked Improvement Community (NIC), merging improvement science with networking for accelerated progress. Addressing key challenges in teacher preparation, such as content knowledge development, impactful clinical experiences, recruitment, and equity considerations, the book explores existing knowledge and initiatives by Research Action Clusters (RACs). These collaborative clusters iteratively refine processes and products to enhance secondary mathematics teacher preparation. The book outlines successful RAC approaches and specific products, offering insights for educators and policymakers. Reflecting on the NIC model, it provides valuable considerations for research design, with explicit references to the Standards for Preparing Teachers of Mathematics (Association of Mathematics Teacher Educators, 2017), enhancing practical applicability. This resource is essential for advancing the field of secondary mathematics teacher preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-07-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00316-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Documenting the Distribution of Instructional Coaching Programs</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We present data from the Schools and Staffing Survey and the National Teacher and Principal Survey to document the prevalence of instructional coaching programs (ICPs) and consider how ICPs are distributed by school level, urbanicity, new teachers in a school, student enrollment, school poverty levels, student achievement levels, and state. We show that ICPs are most common in elementary schools, schools located in cities, schools with larger proportions of new teachers, larger schools, schools enrolling larger fractions of economically disadvantaged students, and schools with lower student achievement levels. Additionally, more affluent and higher achieving schools experienced the sharpest increase in ICPs over time.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-06-2024 06:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241256935?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Integrating subject-generic and subject-specific teaching frameworks: searching for stages of teaching in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Currently there is an attempt to combine subject-generic and subject-specific teaching frameworks to comprehensively capture teaching quality. This study explores the possibility of integrating two widely used and validated frameworks, the subject-generic Dynamic Model of Educational Effectiveness (DMEE) and the subject-specific Mathematical Quality of Instruction (MQI). Toward this end, we drew on data from 38 upper-grade primary school teachers, each observed in six mathematics lessons, which were coded using both frameworks. Data were analyzed using the Extended Logistic model of Rasch to explore whether a common scale of teaching quality with good psychometric properties could be developed. Saltus was then utilized to investigate the possibility of forming levels of effective teaching in mathematics. A common scale encompassing both subject-generic and subject-specific teaching aspects, which had good psychometric properties, was developed. The subject-generic and subject-specific teaching aspects of these frameworks were clustered in five distinct levels. With the exception of the top level that included only subject-generic aspects, all other levels included teaching aspects from both frameworks, thus providing support to the assumption that it is possible to develop levels of effective teaching that combine related subject-generic and subject-specific aspects. In discussing the study findings, we consider their implications for developing an integrated framework of teaching quality and for developing professional development programs that combine subject-generic and subject-specific teaching aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-06-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01591-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Being a Workforce to Agents of Change: An Interpretive Meta-ethnography of Different Approaches to Participatory Research With Young People</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A growing amount of educational research employs participatory methods in which young people actively gather and analyze data in collaboration with the investigators. Considering the diverse use of the label “participatory,” we examined participatory studies with young people to understand how researchers justify using this approach and conceptualize its purposes and goals, as well as these studies’ contributions to scholarship and youth’s civic learning. We conducted an interpretive meta-ethnography of 95 studies, identifying four distinct types of participatory studies with youth: technical, capacity building, justice-oriented, and transformative. We conclude that research that labels itself “participatory” but does not benefit the participants and their communities puts the approach’s credibility at risk. To challenge structural inequalities and power relations between participants and researchers, academic studies should better align with the transformative approach that has the potential to support youth in becoming agents of change by engaging them in self-directed civic learning and activism.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-05-2024 11:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241255625?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining the elements of culturally relevant pedagogy captured and missed in a measure of high-quality mathematics instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics instruction is not race or culture neutral. For students who have been historically marginalized in mathematics classrooms, high-quality mathematics instruction, instruction that helps students build conceptual understanding, on its own might not be enough to disrupt inequities. These students might also need instruction that is culturally relevant, with teachers who demonstrate cultural competence, build critical consciousness, and support student learning. Our goal in this study was to understand which components of culturally relevant pedagogy (CRP) are captured and which are missed in a typical U.S. framework of high-quality mathematics instruction. To find the overlaps and gaps, we analyzed the mathematics lessons of three elementary teachers through both the lens of CRP and the Mathematics-Scan, a mathematics observation tool. We found the strongest overlap between the two frameworks in the patterns of strengths and weaknesses in the teachers’ lessons. When the teachers were delivering high-quality instruction, they were also often supporting students’ learning or showing cultural competence. When the teachers were delivering lower quality instruction, they were also often missing opportunities to enact CRP. At the same time, key elements of CRP including linguistic support for students, high expectations, critical consciousness, and nuances within cultural competence, were missed by the high-quality instruction framework. High-quality instruction was the foundation for CRP in the teachers’ classrooms, but CRP was more than just high-quality instruction. We conclude with recommendations for increasing the alignment between the frameworks and implications for international educators also grappling with equity in their own frameworks of mathematics instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01595-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptualizing functional relationships in an augmented reality environment: connecting real and virtual worlds</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper describes how students conceptualize real-life phenomena in which two or more quantities are covarying in an augmented reality environment. With this technology, real-world phenomena and virtual representations may be connected simultaneously. We aim to investigate how students connect elements of the two worlds when conceptualizing functional relationships. We relied on Zindel’s conceptual facet model for functional relationships to achieve this goal, specifically focusing on the covariational approach. Three 11th-grade students participated in two real-life experiments (Galileo and Hooke’s law experiments) at the heart of this study. The qualitative analysis of selected episodes revealed how students relate the two worlds and how covariational reasoning is reflected in such connections. The findings show that students frequently related elements of the real and virtual worlds while engaging in several forms of covariational reasoning. The theoretical contribution resulting from this study is expanding Zindel’s model to address the conceptualization of families of functions indexed by a parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01594-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Boardrooms to Classrooms: How Interorganizational Networks Influence Education Policy Adoption</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper examines how relationships among government and “outside” organizations influenced policy implementation of new dropout prediction data systems. Using comparative historical and network analyses of three cities, I suggest the concept of interorganizational coupling—highlighting how the dependence and (in)formal collaborations among local school improvement organizations affected implementation speed, variation, and constraint. In Chicago, the loosely coupled system influenced slow and varied implementation, sustained by interpersonal relations and challenged by unclear division of labor. In Philadelphia, the tightly coupled system shaped swift and uniform changes, constrained by questions of sustainability. In New York, the tightening system led to fast yet variable transformations, limited by competition among organizations. Broadly, the article contributes to studies of education policies, interorganizational networks, and school improvement.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-04-2024 12:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241254791?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Choice, Socioeconomic Status, and Stratified Enrollment in Urban Districts: Evidence From Detroit</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Researchers and policymakers have often debated whether urban schools of choice enroll students who are relatively advantaged compared to their traditional public school peers. Existing research has not adequately answered this question due to a reliance on inadequate quantitative measures of socioeconomic status and an emphasis on differences between racial or class groups rather than within them. This mixed-methods study contributes new evidence based on novel survey data and interviews with parents and educational leaders in Detroit. Detroit charter schools enroll significantly fewer students living in deep poverty than neighborhood schools, and selective schools enroll a distinctly advantaged population. These stratified enrollment patterns result from differences in geographic constraints, the influence of social networks, school type reputations, and school practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-04-2024 11:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241254783?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptualizing political knowledges needed to teach inclusive mathematics: theorizing through counterstories</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;How do teachers develop and use political knowledge to create equitable and inclusive conditions for and with disabled students, particularly disabled students of color? In this essay, we build on concepts of political teacher knowledge in mathematics education, critical inclusive mathematics education and disability studies to explore teacher knowledges that support disabled students’ mathematical learning. We focus on four aspects of political knowledge for teaching mathematics: (1) knowledge as relational and unfolding over time, (2) understanding and negotiating the political contexts in which we teach mathematics, (3) deconstructing deficit discourses about marginalized students, and (4) learning to creatively resist the systems for and with our students. To develop our theoretical analysis, we use a counterstory of a middle school Latino student named Luis and his Latina mathematics teacher, Ms. Marquez. Our aim is to open up discussions in mathematics teacher educational research about the politics at play in teaching inclusive mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01598-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student visual attention during group instruction phases in collaborative geometry problem solving</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teacher gestures support mathematics learning and promote student collaboration. Aligned with speech, gestures can help students to notice the important visual information of geometry tasks. However, students’ visual attention to the teacher’s gestural cues during collaborative problem solving remains a largely unexplored field in mathematics education research. This mixed-method case study investigated relations between students’ visual attention, teacher gestures, and students’ collaborative problem-solving process on a geometry task. The data were collected with video cameras and mobile gaze trackers on four students simultaneously in two Finnish 9th-grade mathematics lessons with the same teacher. The findings show that the students attended to their own papers most of the time during the teacher&#39;s gestures, but differences in student attention between the gesture types emerged. The qualitative analysis showed that the teacher’s tracing, pointing, and representational gestures helped in directing student attention to targets relevant to the situational learning process. We conclude that teacher gestures can both convey mathematical contents and direct student attention, which intermediates mathematical thinking in problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10337-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ Knowledge and Preparedness for Retirement: Results From a Nationally Representative Teacher Survey</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Adequately preparing for retirement requires planning and knowledge about available savings and investment options. Teachers participate in a complex set of plan designs, and many do not participate in Social Security. While teachers represent a large part of the public workforce, relatively little is known regarding their knowledge and preparation for retirement. We administered a survey to a nationally representative sample of teachers through RAND’s American Teacher Panel and asked teachers about their retirement planning and employer-sponsored retirement plans. We find that while most teachers are taking steps to prepare for retirement, many teachers do not currently possess the basic retirement knowledge necessary to plan effectively. Teachers struggled to identify their plan type, how much they contribute to their plans, retirement eligibility ages, and who contributes to Social Security. These results suggest that better education around teacher retirement plans has the potential to improve teachers’ retirement planning and preparation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-03-2024 12:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241253819?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Synthesisability and optimising exploratory action research for continuing professional development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-03-2024 08:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2362706?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Embedding Racialized Selves into the Creation of Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-03-2024 03:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357031?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Preparation for Culturally Responsive Teaching: Implications for Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-03-2024 03:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2358912?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Broadening our Understanding of how Research-Practice Partnerships Support Educational Improvement and Equitable Transformation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-03-2024 03:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2358696?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing the role of being an advocate in mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics teacher education is often described in terms of the mathematical content and pedagogy that teachers need. However, recent calls for equity in mathematics education demand a broadening of this view. In this article, we articulate a theoretical description of what the role of being an advocate in language-diverse classrooms could involve and some of the practical challenges that mathematics teacher educators may have when introducing it, using empirical examples from our teacher education courses for teachers of Grades 1–7 in Norway. In the theoretical description of the role of being an advocate into mathematics teacher education, we distinguish between in-class advocacy and advocacy beyond the classroom and what these different kinds of advocacy might entail in language-diverse classrooms. The practical issues that we identified in raising different aspects of the role indicate the need for further research into how to raise preservice teachers’ awareness about the role of being an advocate, in and outside of the classroom, in different cultural settings and how this knowledge could be used in teacher education to challenge preservice teachers’ language ideologies and raise non-trivial issues.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09629-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: The new mathematics education of new Europe. Alexander Karp (Ed.) (2020) Eastern European mathematics education in the decades of change</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10269-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical structures of simple and compound interest: An analysis of secondary teachers’ relational thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article proposes an in-depth mathematics analysis of simple and compound interest through an exploration of the mathematical structures underlying these concepts. Financial numeracy concepts (simple and compound interest, interest rates, interest period, present and future value, etc.) have been added to the mathematics curriculum of the Canadian province of Quebec in 2016. Yet, little is known with regards to mathematics teachers’ knowledge of financial concepts. We mobilized the relational paradigm framework in the context of simple and compound interest to construct an assessment instrument of teacher knowledge. Based on 36 teachers’ responses to the questionnaire, we observed that the majority of teachers did not use mathematical structures in problem solving; they were not able to make sense of simple and compound interest in ways that do not involve standard formulas. Such results indicate opportunities for professional development in regard to secondary mathematics teachers’ knowledge of mathematics in the context of simple and compound interest situations.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10308-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I’m a bit out of place here.”—Preservice teachers’ positioning in the figured world of university mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Preservice mathematics teachers are sometimes trained in programs so that they have both their own courses and joint courses with mathematics majors from the beginning of their studies. While this is thought to provide them with both deep mathematical knowledge and teaching-specific content right from the start, many of them report disaffection with and disengagement from mathematics during their very first semester. Current approaches often frame this from an individual’s perspective, investigating cognitive and affective individual differences among students. In contrast, we aim to understand this issue from a sociocultural perspective, examining underlying social processes. In this study, we thus explored preservice teachers’ experiences of the mathematics component of their training, using Holland and colleagues’ theory of figured worlds as a theoretical lens. Three group interviews with 14 preservice higher secondary teachers in a common mixed setting in Germany (one course specific to preservice teachers, one general mathematics course together with major students) were analyzed. Our findings displayed that the preservice teachers experienced two dichotomous figured worlds of mathematics and mathematics teaching. Our further analysis of their positioning between these worlds provided new insights to explain their disaffection, disengagement, and consequent learning behavior. We discuss practical implications, focusing on different teaching systems and interventions in teacher education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10315-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Socio-ecological gestures of mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this theoretical article, we argue that the imminent collapse of earth systems that sustain life forms calls for mathematics education as a field to reflect on and re-evaluate its priorities and thus practices. We consider both what ecological collapse means for mathematics education and whether mathematics education might offer meaningful gestures in response. We explore how the relationship between the social and the ecological is conceptualised in mathematics education (and other relevant) research and what this implies for mathematics education. We read, in this scholarship, a growing focus on the ecological and conceptualisations of socio-ecological relations between existing entities that are dialectical, or mutually dependent. More rarely, are they seen as entangled and monist, and it is in this thought that we locate our contribution of multi-layered gestures of mathematics education. We describe these, in terms of three broad practices: listening for socio-ecological entanglement; attending to the scales of socio-ecological entanglements; and living entanglement as mathematics educators. We exemplify these gestures through examples of curriculum innovation. This article, a socio-ecological gesture in itself, is written in the spirit of opening a conversation into which we invite others.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10318-4</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
