<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reimagining Preservice Experiences for Aspiring Latino Teachers in the United States</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-13-2024 05:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2311421?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of observation mode on ratings of teaching quality in secondary mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In educational research, teaching quality is extensively studied because of its role of a mediator between teacher characteristics and student learning. However, empirical evidence on differences between video and live scoring of teaching quality is rare. In the present study, thirty lessons from 15 secondary mathematics classrooms in a German metropolitan area were observed. Lessons were scored both live in the classroom and using video recordings. Live and video scoring was conducted by (different) trained observers. Ratings were obtained with a “hybrid” observational instrument that covers generic and subject-specific characteristics of teaching quality in mathematics classrooms. Generalizability analysis and paired &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;t&lt;/em&gt; tests were performed to investigate mode effects. The findings showed that in live scoring, classroom management was rated lower, and cognitive activation was rated higher. Rankings of lessons or classrooms were very similar across modes, and reliabilities did not differ to a meaningful extent either, except for classroom management reaching better results for live ratings. This suggests that based on the present findings, classroom observation performed with our hybrid framework of teaching quality generalizes across observation mode only under certain circumstances. Further research is necessary to better understand the relation between observation mode and teaching quality ratings, as well as the impact of the scoring procedures. We discuss the implications of our findings for educational research and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01557-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>More Than One Way: Fifth-Graders’ Varied Digital Reading Behaviors and Comprehension Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Digital reading is ubiquitous, yet understanding digital reading processes and links to comprehension remains underdeveloped. Guided by new literacies and active reading theories, this study explored the reading behaviors and comprehension of thirteen fifth graders who read static digital texts. We coded for the quantity and quality of digital reading behaviors and employed action path diagrams to connect behaviors to comprehension. We used timescape analyses to visualize how behaviors were orchestrated differently across readers. Findings showed no single behavior was related directly to comprehension, indicating varying pathways to digital reading success. Occasional rereading seemed to support active reading and improved comprehension. Instances of students subverting expected digital tools were observed. Minor distractions like mind-wandering did not link to poor performance. This research deepens our understanding of self-monitoring and active reading in static digital contexts, offering insights for future study of more complex digital reading contexts like reading on the internet.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 12:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241226633?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2022 Wallace Foundation Distinguished Lecture Education Reform, Past and Present: Asking Equity Questions and Looking for Hope</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Drawing on a set of studies conducted over 3 decades, this article provides a reflection on what has been learned by centering equity questions in research on educational reform. These studies reveal the need to explore educators’ belief systems, emotions, and agency in relation to reform. They also underscore the co-constructed nature of reform and the importance of attending to context and scale. Although prior research reveals the complex challenges educators, policymakers, and communities face in promoting educational change with social justice aims, it also provides lessons for a hopeful path forward. Pursuing an equity agenda in this pivotal moment requires deep thinking about how we conduct research on educational reform, prepare the next generation of scholars, and work across disciplinary and national boundaries.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241228255?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Critical Quantitative Literacy: An Educational Foundation for Critical Quantitative Research</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Education research has recently seen the emergence of two distinct frameworks guiding the application of quantitative methods through a more critical and equity-oriented lens. These two frameworks are critical quantitative (CritQuant) studies and quantitative critical race theory (QuantCrit). Although different in their intellectual traditions, they both acknowledge the oppressive history of quantitative methods and the need to improve the criticality of quantitative research in education. For applied quantitative research in education to become more critical, it is imperative that learners of quantitative methodology be made aware of its historical and modern misuses. This directive calls for an important change in the way quantitative methodology is taught in educational classrooms. Critical quantitative literacy (CQL) is introduced in this manuscript as a paradigm for teaching, learning, understanding, and applying quantitative methods in a way that supports the application of CritQuant and QuantCrit frameworks in educational research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 07:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241228223?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Preservice Teachers’ Quantitative and Covariational Reasoning in Understanding Climate Change</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 05:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2314499?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Constructing an Educational “Quality” Crisis: (E)quality Politics and Racialization Beyond Target Beneficiaries</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this critical, political discourse analysis, we trace how two concepts, equity and quality, became discursively linked and contested in the administration of postsecondary education policy over time (1968–1994)—a developmental process we refer to as (e)quality politics. By engaging in a historical analysis, we investigate (a) the racialized political origins and discursive processes by which arguments over educational “quality” are advanced as part of an antiequity policy paradigm and (b) how this paradigm reinscribes racial inequity into administrative and organizational action over time. We illustrate how, once an (e)quality politics paradigm is established, racialized policy designs can persist, even in the absence of explicit references to racialized social constructions of target populations in later periods of policy development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 05:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231189478?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher practitioner enquiry: a process for developing teacher learning and practice?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-11-2024 05:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2313085?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Moving beyond reflection and toward disruption in the post-field context of mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Prospective teachers bring countless stories of success and failure from different mathematics classrooms to their post-field teacher education courses. These reflective stories often glorify school mathematics classrooms and dominant traditions within, instead of confronting the marginalization of diverse groups in school environments. Mathematics teacher educators have a significant role to play in teaching prospective teachers to reflect critically on their field experiences and, in doing so, create spaces for &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;disruption&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;disruptive pedagogies&lt;/em&gt;. Drawing on critical and equity-based theories applied within the fields of mathematics education and teacher education research, we propose a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;disruptive pedagogy&lt;/em&gt; analytical framework that enables us to study the roles and practices of mathematics teacher educators as they conduct their work in these post-field contexts of teacher education. In this paper, we introduce our disruptive pedagogy framework and present the results that followed from using it to analyze data from a research study in which mathematics teacher educators from across Canada and Norway were interviewed. We claim that our analytical framework can be used to identify those disruptive and transformative practices initiated by mathematics teacher educators—practices that are necessary to bring about shifts in inequitable and unjust classroom practices of school mathematics and in becoming a teacher. Unfortunately, however, results reported here point to the need for further shifts and growth toward more explicitly disruptive practices initiated by mathematics teacher educators in the post-field context.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01547-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The longing to just be – a belonging body in teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2024 06:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2311709?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preschool teachers’ mathematical questions during shared picture book reading</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;High-quality instruction in preschool is important for children’s mathematical development. To date, the domain-specific elements constituting mathematics instruction quality and the factors associated with this quality are hardly studied, resulting in serious gaps in our insights into the topic. We aimed to address this gap by investigating (a) 43 preschool teachers’ mathematical questioning behavior during shared picture book reading, and (b) its association with picture book and teacher characteristics. We analyzed the number and the level of abstraction of mathematical questions when sharing a mathematical (i.e., written with explicit mathematical aim and content) and a non-mathematical (i.e., written without explicit mathematical aim and content) picture book, and their associations with teachers’ professional competence. For mathematical and non-mathematical picture books, teachers formulated mathematical questions, mainly at lower levels of abstraction. They formulated more, but proportionally less abstract, mathematical questions when sharing a mathematical versus a non-mathematical picture book. We found only limited evidence for associations between teachers’ questioning behavior and their professional competence. Our findings indicate that preschool teachers offer opportunities to engage in mathematical interaction during shared picture book reading, pointing to the potential of this activity to implement high-quality mathematics instruction. They further show that mathematical picture books enable more mathematical interaction than non-mathematical picture books, but not at higher levels of abstraction. Future studies are needed to replicate and complement our findings, with special attention for the contribution of teacher professional competence and the fit to children’s competency level.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01544-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Quantification and the homogeneous representation of urban students in school choice research and politics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2024 02:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306395?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working with an instructional video on mathematical modeling: upper-secondary students’ perceived advantages and challenges</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Many instructional videos in mathematics education target knowledge of procedures and algorithms. To design instructional videos that support students in a non-algorithmic domain, such as mathematical modeling, we developed a framework based on research on heuristic worked examples and instructional videos. Because students’ perceptions play an important role in whether they will engage with a learning resource, our research questions focus on the advantages and challenges students perceive when they work with an instructional video on mathematical modeling and solve a subsequent related modeling problem. Using a video based on the developed framework, we conducted an interview study with 14 pairs of upper-secondary students. The results of the qualitative text analysis showed that the perceived advantages and challenges were related to certain design features and to the processes of self-regulated learning with the video. The students experienced challenges regarding the video’s duration, the transfer to a subsequent related modeling problem, the absence of a teacher, and self-discipline. Hence, further learner support is necessary to guide the transition from working with a video to autonomous modeling, such as combining the video with strategic instruments and teacher support. In addition, interactive video features may be essential, as the students enjoyed how those features involved them in the process of watching the video. Overall, the results indicate that instructional videos are promising for providing heuristic worked examples, offering an innovative approach for teaching and learning mathematical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01546-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Trends, insights, and developments in research on the teaching and learning of algebra</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper addresses the recent body of research in algebra and algebraic thinking from 2018 to 2022. We reviewed 74 journal articles and identified four clusters of content areas: (a) literal symbols and symbolizing, (b) equivalence and the equal sign, (c) equations and systems, and (d) functions and graphing. We present the research on each of these content clusters, and we discuss insights on effective teaching practices and the social processes supporting algebraic reasoning. The research base shows that incorporating algebraic thinking into the elementary grades, emphasizing analytic and structural thinking processes, and emphasizing covariational reasoning supports students’ meaningful learning of core algebraic ideas. We close with a discussion of the major theoretical contributions emerging from the past five years, offering suggestions for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01545-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Education lead(her)ship: Advancing women in K-12 administration</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2024 06:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2311470?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the concept of energy through definitions, drawings, and metaphors</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2024 06:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2308150?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impact of realistic mathematics education on secondary school students’ problem-solving skills: a comparative evaluation study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2024 04:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2306633?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An exploratory study of the relation between teachers’ implicit theories and teacher noticing</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Despite interest in how students’ implicit theories—their growth and fixed mindsets about their own learning—affect students as learners, relatively little research on mindset has looked at &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;teachers&lt;/em&gt; as learners. This study explores elementary teachers’ implicit theories about the malleability of mathematics intelligence and teaching ability. It also examines how implicit theories of learning relate to teacher noticing, a construct that has been linked to teachers’ classroom practice and their students’ learning outcomes. Findings from the present investigation indicate that teachers generally reported growth mindsets concerning mathematics intelligence and teaching ability. For both mathematics intelligence and teaching ability, teachers’ reporting of more growth—compared to more fixed—mindsets was associated with more expert noticing, as measured by comments they wrote about elementary mathematics video clips on the dimensions of mathematics and student thinking. These findings point to intriguing possibilities about whether fostering growth mindsets (of mathematics intelligence and of teaching ability) in professional development settings might be leveraged to promote expert teacher noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09617-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Coaching Teachers in Document-Based History Instruction: Practices That Support Teacher Facilitation of Student Discourse</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Instructional coaching is increasingly regarded as an essential feature of professional development, but no research exists on content-specific instructional coaching for history teachers. The study examines data from a coaching program in which history teacher leaders served as novice coaches for their colleagues. We found that coached teachers, as a whole, improved in discussion facilitation. Case analysis of two successful and two less successful coach–teacher pairings revealed that successful coaches were more likely to focus on eliciting students’ argumentative discourse whereas less successful coach planning sessions focused on discrete historical content knowledge and the disciplinary heuristics of historical thinking. It appears that coaching that emphasized a conceptual redirection toward inquiry and a pedagogical toolkit for fostering student discourse was more closely tied to growth in discussion facilitation and opportunities for student historical reasoning than a coaching approach more narrowly focused on historical concepts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 11:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231223443?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Revealing the Known: The Invisibilized Bias of Commercial Literacy Curricula</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 03:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2309858?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hiding and Seeking: The Educational and Socioemotional Needs of Asylum Seeker and Refugee Students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 03:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2308436?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Marginalization at the Intersection of Language, Culture, and Disability: Systemic Contradictions Perceived by Special Education Teachers in Serving Culturally and Linguistically Diverse Students with Disabilities in South Korea</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 02:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2307800?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modelling individuality but advising universality: ethnography of mentoring pre-service teachers with regard to student diversity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 02:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2311694?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking discourses about the transition from school to university mathematics: an intensive reading</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper has two main goals: first, to analyze current research related with transition to identify the foci being produced and reproduced by research through a literature review and, second, to map the connections between circulating discourses to unfold the discursive network that supports them via an intensive reading. Specifically, we are interested in how social and economic factors, educational background, and cognitive development impact the transition process and the documented potential challenges students may face. In this fashion, the questions that guide the development of the paper are as follows: What are the dominant narratives in mathematics education research about the transition from school to university mathematics? How do dominant narratives entangle particular rationalities to configure a discursive network about the transition from school to university mathematics? As a result, we identify three dominant narratives entangled, which shape a system of reason that regulates what is possible to do, act, and think.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10288-z</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
