<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Classroom profiles of instructional quality: contribution of level and variability of students’ perception</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Different approaches for measuring instructional quality have been debated. Previous studies based on student ratings have primarily used class-average ratings. Beyond this, the high within-classroom variability of students’ ratings might indicate that instruction caters to some, but not all students. Therefore, we investigated student-reported instructional quality in mathematics classrooms by considering the average student ratings and rating heterogeneity within classrooms. Using a case-centered clustering approach, we aimed to detect meaningful configurations of the level and heterogeneity of student-reported instructional quality in terms of the Three Basic Dimensions (TBD): classroom management, cognitive activation, and student support. We analyzed data from &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 973 grade eight students across &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 106 classes. Using Latent Profile Analysis (LPA), we identified four classroom profiles comprising 20% to 28% of the sample. The results indicate that the profile with the lowest average ratings showed consistently high heterogeneity for all indicator variables. However, the profile with the highest average ratings exhibited consistently low heterogeneity. We gained interesting insights into between-class differences in instructional quality by considering rating heterogeneity. Furthermore, we explored how classrooms from the identified profiles differed regarding socio-economic status (SES) and mathematics-related characteristics (interest, intrinsic motivation, self-concept, and achievement).&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01583-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Experts’ intuitive mathematical discourses about integration in complex analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Although complex analysis is part of the study programs of many mathematics undergraduates, little research has been done on how individuals interpret basic concepts from complex analysis. To address this gap, this paper investigates how experts individually think about complex path integrals. For this purpose, the commognitive framework is used to conceptualize experts’ interpretations of mathematical concepts discursively, namely in terms of so-called intuitive mathematical discourses. A total of nine interpretations of complex path integrals, so-called discursive images, as well as eight sets of rules governing their construction, so-called discursive frames, are derived from expert interviews. These interpretations range from a rejection of intrinsic meaning to connections with real and vector analysis, mean values, and individual formulations of theorems. The paper also raises questions for the inclusion of the results into teaching and addresses further research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01610-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racialized teacher tracking: the systematic exclusion of black teachers from advanced-level coursework</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-12-2024 06:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2370763?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Connectivity in resources for teaching graph theory in engineering education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This contribution explores the teaching of graph theory in the context of engineering education. We examine how teachers use collectively designed resources in terms of their backgrounds. After a literature review, we justify the choice to develop an analytical framework for studying the materials in terms of connections to be established in the resources. We suggest developments around the theoretical concept of connectivity, which allows us to analyze the potential connectivity, characterized by the connections enabled by the resources for teaching; and the effective connectivity that develops in teachers’ practices and during the implementation of resources. We study the effective connectivity in terms of each teacher’s personal relationship with graph theory. Graph theory evolves at the interface of mathematics and computer science research. We consider the case of two teachers, a computer scientist and a mathematician in a French Engineering School in France. The data collected consists of resources for teaching graph theory in engineering courses and interviews with teachers. As for results, we characterize how forms of connectivity developed in the use of resources for teaching graph theory are largely determined by the teachers’ backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01613-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Testing the potency of ethnoscience instruction on biology students’ critical thinking ability</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2024 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2373464?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hurdles and Straightaways: Building a Cross-School Community of Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2024 01:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2373126?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unraveling high-quality mathematics teaching in algebra: insights from overlaying domain-specific and content-specific observation instruments</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When analyzing instructional quality in mathematics, observational measures can consider domain-specific instructional approaches (e.g., effective teaching of mathematics) and content-focused practices (e.g., effective teaching of a specific mathematical topic). In this study, we analyze lesson videos from secondary algebra classrooms using two different instruments—one focused on ambitious mathematics teaching practices and one focused on instructional features that support students’ learning opportunities in algebra specifically. We consider the information provided by overlaying these instruments to raise implications for instructional improvement efforts, particularly related to how information from the instruments might inform formative feedback to teachers. We consider how alignment between instrument and instructional emphasis can influence the strengths and areas of instructional improvement identified in a given lesson. We further model a collaborative process for looking across observation instruments to deepen understanding of the information provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01606-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inside the Black Box: Detecting and Mitigating Algorithmic Bias Across Racialized Groups in College Student-Success Prediction</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Colleges and universities are increasingly turning to algorithms that predict college-student success to inform various decisions, including those related to admissions, budgeting, and student-success interventions. Because predictive algorithms rely on historical data, they capture societal injustices, including racism. In this study, we examine how the accuracy of college student success predictions differs between racialized groups, signaling algorithmic bias. We also evaluate the utility of leading bias-mitigating techniques in addressing this bias. Using nationally representative data from the Education Longitudinal Study of 2002 and various machine learning modeling approaches, we demonstrate how models incorporating commonly used features to predict college-student success are less accurate when predicting success for racially minoritized students. Common approaches to mitigating algorithmic bias are generally ineffective at eliminating disparities in prediction outcomes and accuracy between racialized groups.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241258741?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do quality criteria of instructional explanatory videos in algebra influence student choice? A feasibility study using conjoint analysis to assess implicit reasoning in educational contexts</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 04:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2377423?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Heterogeneity of Item-Treatment Interactions Masks Complexity and Generalizability in Randomized Controlled Trials</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 03:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2361337?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teaching, learning, and assessment in the digital age</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The role of teaching, learning, and assessment with digital technology has become increasingly prominent in mathematics education. This survey paper provides an overview of how technology has been transforming teaching, learning, and assessment in mathematics education in the digital age and suggests how the field will evolve in the coming years. Based on several decades of research and educational practices, we discuss and anticipate the multifaceted impact of technology on mathematics education, thus laying the groundwork for the other papers in this issue. After a brief introduction discussing the motivations for this issue, we focus our attention on three lines of research: teaching mathematics with technology, learning mathematics with technology, and assessment with technology. We point to new research orientations that address the issue of teaching with technology, specifically describing attempts to conceptualise teachers’ mathematical and digital competencies, perspectives that view teachers as designers of digital resources, and the design and evaluation of long-term initiatives to support teachers as they develop innovative teaching practices enhanced by digital technologies. Our examination shows that learning with technology is still marked by new conceptualizations raised by researchers that can further our understanding of this complex issue. These conceptualizations support the recognition that multiple resources, ranging from paper and pencil to augmented reality, participate in the learning process. Finally, assessment with technology, especially in the formative sense, offers new possibilities for offering individualised support for learners that can benefit from adaptive systems, though more tasks for conceptual understanding need to be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01612-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Patterning strategies in grade 1 students with low and high number sense proficiency</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Repeating patterning proficiency predicts students’ later mathematical proficiency. A comparative multi-case design enabled the present study to compare patterning success and strategy use for repeating patterns of 75 Norwegian 6-year-old grade 1 students. We provided the students with duplicate, extend, transfer, and unit isolation activities in a semi-structured, task-based interview that was video-recorded. The students’ number sense was also measured using a digital assessment. In-depth analysis of 52 students (divided evenly into two groups based on their number sense scores, lowest and highest) was performed. A statistically significant group difference was found for extend activities. Multimodal video analysis of strategies employed revealed that both student groups used recursive and different strategies and only students with high number sense used relational strategies. The students with low number sense used more variants of recursive patterning strategies. Our findings also demonstrated that attention to pattern features may both hinder identification of a pattern’s underlying structure and reflect advanced strategy use rather than not showing pattern awareness. We discuss group differences in terms of decomposition and awareness of mathematical pattern and structure and emphasise the need for scaffolding awareness of mathematical pattern and structure through communication.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10341-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating the Complexity in Elementary Teachers’ Noticing of Children’s Mathematical Thinking in Written Work</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-09-2024 08:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2372977?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race, racism, and racialization in mathematics education: global perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10346-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice Secondary Teachers’ Mathematical Knowledge for Teaching: Focus on Reflective Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 09:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2373653?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Intertwining of Children’s Interests and Micro-Practices at a Science Museum: Case Study of Three Children</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 06:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2374705?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cooperation in primary school children: The role of cardiac vagal tone and cognitive control</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 04:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2366347?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming teaching through cooperative inquiry: meaningful research for university teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 01:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2374745?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Learner-Centered Teaching and Learning Goes Online: Zooming into Linear Algebra Tutorials During the Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic shifted higher education online, drawing attention to synchronous learning and instruction on digital communication platforms. Learner-centered teaching practices in the tertiary level, such as mathematical discussions, have been shown to benefit student learning. The interactions involved in online synchronous mathematical discussions have been studied less. Most research taps into these aspects drawing on students’ academic outcomes and reflective interviews. This study explores instructional practices as they unfold online, with a focus on student-instructor and student-student interactions. We zoom-in to online synchronous teaching and learning processes on a popular communication platform by analyzing Linear Algebra tutorials in the first pandemic year. Using the commognitive framework, we characterize instructional interactions with the construct of a learning-teaching agreement. The analysis resulted in three interactional patterns, where in all cases, the tutorial transformed at some point to the one dominated by the instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00244-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analyzing Teacher-Designed Tasks Through the Lens of Procedural and Conceptual Knowledge</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Literature suggests that “current characterizations of the terms procedural knowledge and conceptual knowledge are limiting and are, in fact, impediments to careful investigation of these constructs” (Star, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r31&quot;&gt;2005&lt;/span&gt;, p. 405). We examined secondary mathematics teachers’ understanding of procedural and conceptual knowledge at superficial and deep levels through the design of mathematical tasks. For this purpose, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;=55 secondary mathematics teachers were asked to design a procedural and a conceptual task on a given topic and explain why they think the task they designed is a procedural and/or conceptual task. The study results showed that 78% of teachers were able to design and correctly explain procedural tasks. However, only 5.5% of teachers were able to design conceptual tasks correctly. Teachers’ narratives were examined to categorize emerging characteristics of procedural and conceptual tasks as well as to address teachers’ (mis)conceptions about procedural and conceptual knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00319-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning models and achievements of the most gifted students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2024 08:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2364690?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Heading for new shores? Longitudinal participation patterns in teacher professional development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2024 07:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2370891?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: How can university mathematics overcome Klein&#39;s second discontinuity? Specific course design</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01611-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Task potential in relation to teaching quality and teacher competence in secondary mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The potential of tasks to foster mathematical learning and understanding is an important aspect of instruction and their implementation in teaching is thus often viewed to be positively related to the quality of instruction. Both the selection of tasks as well as their implementation in the classroom depend on many factors, with teachers’ knowledge and skills as one of the most important ones. The present study aims to analyze the relations between different aspects of task potential, the quality of instruction, and teachers’ competence in order to investigate whether task potential can be seen as an indicator for teaching quality, for teacher competence, or as an independent construct in models of educational effectiveness. To this end, we draw on data from the TEDS-Validate study, namely tests of mathematics teachers’ competence (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 31) observations in their classrooms (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 60), and an in-depth analysis of all tasks used in the respective lessons (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 2490). Multiple regression analysis suggests that while some facets of task potential are related to either teaching quality or teacher competence, the potential of tasks emerges as an independent construct with some characteristics predicting the teaching quality of the respective lessons. Implications of these results for the role of tasks in educational effectiveness research are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01596-6</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
