<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Context Matters as Racialization Evolves: Exploring Bias in Preservice Teacher Responses to Children</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study explores preservice teacher attributions to children’s behaviors portrayed in specific emotion-laden school scenarios. Participants included 178 preservice teachers from three universities. The preservice teachers viewed video vignettes of Black and White child actors in six different school scenarios. Our team constructed two themes from the preservice teachers’ narratives about what they saw: (a) context matters (i.e., different scenarios activate different preservice teacher attributions), and (b) racialization evolves (i.e., preservice teachers make different attributions about Black and White boys engaged in the same behaviors). Findings underscore the importance of teacher education and professional development for novice teachers that address racial bias in attributions of student behaviors.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2023 10:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231200016?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preparing the Expert Novice: Preservice Teacher Thinking and Efficacy in Inquiry Design</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this study, we share the understandings and the reflections of preservice teachers as they engage in focus group interviews about inquiry in social studies, generally, and their reactions to publicly available Inquiry Design Model blueprints. These preservice teachers first discussed their understanding of inquiry, which was rooted in their university coursework. They then described their self-efficacy for implementing inquiry, generally, and the IDM blueprint, specifically, in their current field placements and future classrooms. This envisioned implementation often involved adaptations of the blueprints. Our goal in this research was to reconsider how preservice teachers experience and learn about social studies inquiry and, as a result of these experiences, whether and how they see themselves implementing social studies inquiry with students. This study can inform teacher educators to proactively address common barriers and better support preservice teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2023 08:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231202956?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The influence of critical friendships on secondary student teachers engaged in collaborative action research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2023 06:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2263492?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Tale of Two Systems: Choice and Equity in the District of Columbia’s Charter Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Advocates often predict that school choice policies will expand access to high-quality schools, particularly for marginalized communities. To interrogate this assumption, we employed a sequential mixed-methods analysis examining the state of charter reform in the District of Columbia. We observed that stakeholders consistently defined equity as uniform processes, evident in data distribution and enrollment practices. We also uncovered persistent disparities in where students live versus learn. We conclude that race-neutral conceptions of equity may hinder attempts to improve school access by ignoring structural inequalities tied to race, place, and income and by overlooking privileged households’ efforts to remain separate.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2023 12:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231198816?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Restorative Justice in Education: A Content Analysis of US State Legislation From 2010 to 2020</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study sought to understand how state-level policies inform and promote the implementation of restorative justice in education (RJE). A content analysis of 60 laws revealed that definitions, structures, and supports varied greatly, causing us to question whether policies support a systematic implementation of RJE and how policies can prevent the misuse of RJE as an alternative system of punishment. We recommend that laws clearly define the paradigm shift underlying RJE, and provide sustained support to promote a realignment of policies and practices with attention to incorporating measures of accountability to larger values surrounding equity and justice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2023 12:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231198813?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2023 10:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2259678?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Utilizing Real-Time Test Data to Solve Attenuation Paradox in Computerized Adaptive Testing to Enhance Optimal Design</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;To solve the attenuation paradox in computerized adaptive testing (CAT), this study proposes an item selection method, the integer programming approach based on real-time test data (IPRD), to improve test efficiency. The IPRD method turns information regarding the ability distribution of the population from real-time test data into feasible test constraints to reversely assembled shadow tests for item selection to prevent the attenuation paradox by integer programming. A simulation study was conducted to thoroughly investigate IPRD performance. The results indicate that the IPRD method can efficiently improve CAT performance in terms of the precision of trait estimation and satisfaction of all required test constraints, especially for conditions with stringent exposure control.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2023 06:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231197666?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Impact of the Corequisite Classroom Climate on Students’ Attitudes Toward Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Many postsecondary institutions across the United States have adopted the corequisite model of academic support to facilitate student learning and the successful completion of introductory mathematics courses within students’ first year of college enrollment. While research have highlighted the benefits of corequisites in terms of academic outcomes, there is little qualitative research on the impact of this model of academic support on students beyond course grades. Through student narratives, this study documents how one university implemented their College Algebra corequisite and investigates the impact of the classroom climate of a corequisite course on students’ attitudes toward mathematics. This study shows that though the classroom climate positively impacted the participants’ attitudes toward mathematics in general, the climate of the corequisite specifically had a greater impact on their beliefs about mathematics and perceptions of themselves as learners of mathematics. However, there were some identified drawbacks to the corequisite course including time-consuming coursework and occasionally unproductive group collaboration. These findings highlight the potential for corequisites to foster positive attitudes toward mathematics, yet it also demonstrated a need for greater intention in the course development to ensure a coherent course structure where course activities and assessments give way to meaningful and productive student engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00226-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Different Methods for Assessing Preservice Teachers’ Instruction: Why Measures Matter</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher preparation programs are increasingly expected to use data on preservice teacher (PST) skills to drive program improvement and provide targeted supports. Observational ratings are especially vital, but also prone to measurement issues. Scores may be influenced by factors unrelated to PSTs’ instructional skills, including rater standards. Yet we know little about how these measurement challenges play out in the preservice context specifically. Here, we investigate the reliability and sensitivity of two observational measures. We find measures collected during student teaching are especially prone to measurement issues; only 3% to 4% of variation in scores reflects consistent differences between PSTs, while 9% to 17% of variation can be attributed to the mentors with whom they work. When high scores stem not from strong instructional skills, but instead from external circumstances, we cannot use them to make consequential decisions about PSTs’ individual needs or readiness for independent teaching.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2023 10:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231200279?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reframing High-Quality Mentoring: Between Teacher Mentoring and Visions of Teaching as a Profession</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Visions of teacher professionalism may shape common conceptualizations of high-quality mentoring, sometimes distortedly. Nevertheless, this relationship is often unnoticed, and studies rarely analyze mentor–teachers’ work according to their interrelating visions. This multiple case study aimed at this literature gap. It examined the goals that accomplished mentor-teachers promoted and their practices and found four mentoring styles that characterized these mentors. After, it interrogated how the mentoring styles interrelated with three distinct visions of teacher professionalism (teachers as intellectuals, craftspeople, or artists). Findings challenge the idea that mentor-teachers’ work can be evaluated as either advancing or degrading teacher professionalism. The study questions this framing of mentoring literature and suggests that a bipolar logic could mislead us to forsake essential aspects of mentoring, for instance, ones associated with apprenticeship relations. The study concludes by offering to replace the bipolar logic with a more balanced consideration of the different aspects of teacher mentoring.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2023 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231200276?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming collaboration between communities and non-governmental organisations: Reflections on learning spaces in Central-Eastern Uganda</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Non-governmental organisations have several mechanisms in place to facilitate learning with and from communities they intend to serve, however these do not always realise authentic participation and meaningful programmatic adjustments. In a participatory research in Central-Eastern Uganda we investigated how the community believes collective learning with NGOs could best be shaped. In this paper we present findings as well as reflections on the learning spaces that emerged in the research and how one could assess whether collective learning is a transformative practice. We offer a conceptual framework NGO practitioners can use to enrich their collective learning toolkit as well as to track and trace small shifts and changes happening in learning trajectories in order to lobby for resources to allow collective learning to happen more authentically, through increased presence and informal interaction with communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2023 09:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231202627?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advocacy Stories: Equity Literacy Practices of White Low Income Mothers Navigating School Reform</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article, based on collaborative ethnography, describes five low income white mothers’ equity literacy practices as they advocated for their children&#39;s diverse “failing” school during a state takeover. Mothers used both hard and soft advocacy. They promoted equity by reinforcing positive aspects of the school community, and resisting and reframing negative stories perpetuated about the school based on stigma at the intersection of race, class, and standardized educational attainment. They shared the ideal of exposing their children to “real life” by staying loyal to their school. However, their advocacy can also be understood as subtly reifying whiteness. These mothers’ stories present possibilities, and challenges, for realizing interracial solidarity that fosters and sustains equitable schooling in the United States long term.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2023 06:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231195805?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An ADVANCE for Whom? A National Study of Initiatives to Improve Faculty Gender Equity</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examines whether the National Science Foundation’s ADVANCE-IT grant program identifies and funds institutions that improve faculty gender equity. By using matching procedures and a two-way fixed-effect event study, we find that when universities received ADVANCE-IT grants, their proportion and headcount of women faculty as full-time new-hire, overall faculty, and tenured and tenure-track faculty are not different from multiple comparison groups of universities—including universities that received other types of ADVANCE grants. Drawing on the concept of intersectionality, we further disaggregate women faculty into subracial/ethnic groups. We did not find consistent evidence supporting that ADVANCE-IT universities increase the proportion or headcount of women faculty in subracial/ethnic groups. We discuss implications for federal grantmaking and diversifying higher education faculty.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231197683?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bringing utopian visioning to educational leadership: participatory action research as professional learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2023 01:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2260845?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impact of a Mathematics Bridging Course on the Motivation and Learning Skills of University Students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The transition from secondary to tertiary education is an exciting and yet challenging event in the educational biography of students. During this transition, students often meet with unexpected challenges, which may cause them to drop out from their degree program. Many universities offer bridging courses or longer-term interventions to support their incoming students in this period. To examine the effect of a bridging course designed to reduce gaps in prior mathematical knowledge, promote social-emotional well-being, and foster learning skills, we implement a repeated-measures intervention study. We analyze the outcomes of the intervention, which features tutors with special training, autonomous choice of topic areas, peer learning, and materials for self-directed learning. We measure the development of motivational beliefs reflecting the will to learn (achievement goals, satisfaction of basic psychological needs, implicit theories, self-efficacy) and the skills to learn (reactions to errors, self-regulated learning) at the secondary-tertiary transition. These aspects are captured at multiple measurement points among students (N = 679) who participate in the bridging course (intervention group) and those who do not (control group). The intervention boosts motivational beliefs related to social embeddedness and learning skills in the short term. The observed decrease in autonomy, competence, and self-efficacy might be explained by higher standards that students use for their self-assessment in the new peer group. In the long term, all aspects of the will to learn, except for social relatedness, show stable to strongly negative developments in both groups. Among those students who do not participate in the bridging course, mostly strongly negative developments are observed. The results suggest that the peer tutoring strategy is highly effective and the need for longer-term interventions to uphold the positive short-term effects.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00224-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Applying ‘merging of knowledge’ in Tanzania: What can we learn about interrupting patterned relationships to reveal hidden dimensions of poverty?</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Merging of Knowledge is a research approach that creates the conditions for people with lived experience of poverty to participate at an equal level with academics and practitioners, in the co-generation of knowledge about poverty. This paper reflects critically on the application of ‘Merging of Knowledge’ to study poverty in Tanzania, assessing its challenges, achievements, and lessons learned about revealing hidden knowledge about poverty. It also provides a brief literature review to place the Merging of Knowledge alongside other participatory approaches. This paper finds that Merging of Knowledge can effectively interrupt patterned social relationships, and empower individuals and peer groups, thereby stimulating transformation of both academics and people and poverty. It does so by addressing imbalances in social status, empowering all groups of participants at each stage of the research, and building trust, confidence, and freedom from fear in a sustainable manner. The conclusion drawn is that Merging of Knowledge holds great promise for future research on topics where strong hierarchies of knowledge exist, and where the physical inclusion of participants in data collection is not readily translated into intellectual inclusivity during analysis and the dissemination of findings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-23-2023 12:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231202628?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acting Upon Student Voice-Based Teaching Assessment Initiatives: An Account of Participatory Action Research for Teacher Professional Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Numerous nations implement Student Perception Surveys (SPS) in their schools to assess teaching for student learning improvement. However, research suggests no significant change in teachers’ practices following such student voice-based assessment initiatives, noting their struggle to act upon it. Utilizing the pyramid of student voice as a key framework, we investigate how a Participatory Action Research (PAR)-based professional development (PD) shapes a group of Australian secondary teachers’ interaction with SPS and professional learning. Analyses of the teachers’ interviews, research projects, and reflective notes about their use of SPS illustrate how the PAR-based PD informed their practice, specifically: (i) transforming ‘survey fatigue’ to increased student voice; (ii) contemplating personal, professional, and political entanglements; and (iii) (re)building teacher agency—employing SPS as collective learning tools of professional empowerment rather than accountability measures of teaching. Implications include pathways to strengthen teachers’ agency—honoring their professionalism—in assessment spaces increasingly shaped by student voices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-23-2023 05:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231200278?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Empirical Research Base of Early Childhood Coaching? A Mapping Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examined the empirical base for early childhood (birth to 8) coaching via a systematic mapping review of the relevant literature, including diverse research designs to represent the full breadth of published studies related to early childhood coaching. The systematic review yielded 374 unique studies published between 1987 and 2019 that were coded for type of study design (e.g., causal; quantitative noncausal; qualitative; single-case design); research populations; and reported content, structure, and processes of early childhood coaching. Descriptive analyses revealed that almost half of the study designs were causal (45.99%); over 75% of the studies were interested in the outcomes or experiences of teachers. The most targeted coaching content domains were social-emotional (44.92% of studies) and language/literacy development (43.58% of studies). Reporting on coaching structure was inconsistent across studies. Observation was the most reported coaching strategy during instruction (73.53% of studies), and provision of evaluative feedback was the most frequently reported coaching strategy outside of instruction (62.83% of studies). The review identified the literature base includes a diversity of study designs, and a great majority of studies occur in preschool settings (70.32%). Findings also suggest that a growing number of coaching studies are focused on child outcomes (60.16%). Results indicate a need for more studies that focus on coaches directly as well as research about coaching in infant/toddler programs and in content domains beyond social-emotional and language/literacy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 12:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231195836?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impacts of maker technologies on classroom learning outcomes: A mixed methods explanatory study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 11:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2239185?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>ebct: Using entropy balancing for continuous treatments to estimate dose–response functions and their derivatives</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 709-729, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Interest in evaluating dose–response functions of continuous treatments has been increasing recently. To facilitate the estimation of causal effects in this setting, I introduce the ebct command for the estimation of dose–response functions and their derivatives using entropy balancing for continuous treatments. First, balancing weights are estimated by numerically solving a globally convex optimization problem. These weights eradicate Pearson correlations between covariates and the treatment variable. Because simple uncorrelatedness may be insufficient to yield consistent estimates in the next step, higher moments of the treatment variable can be rendered uncorrelated with covariates. Second, the weights are used in local linear kernel regressions to estimate the dose–response function or its derivative. To perform statistical inference, I use a bootstrap procedure. The command also provides the option of producing publication-quality graphs for the estimated relationships.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196291?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>cntraveltime: Travel distance and travel time in China</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 730-753, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce the command cntraveltime, which can calculate both the travel distance and the travel time between two locations in China with respect to different modes of transportation (driving, public transport, and cycling). Existing commands such as georoute, traveltime, and mqtime have difficulties in parsing Chinese locations. cntraveltime solves this outstanding challenge via a feature that enables it to call route-planning services from the Baidu Maps Open Platform. The results of rigorous testing on the features of the command show that, relative to similar existing commands, cntraveltime has the highest capacity in terms of functionality and precision. This suggests that it can be regarded as a useful complement to other existing commands, especially when calculating travel distance and time for locations within China.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196292?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Robit regression in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 658-682, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Logistic and probit models are the most popular regression models for binary outcomes. A simple robust alternative is the robit model, which replaces the underlying normal distribution in the probit model with a Student’s t distribution. The heavier tails of the t distribution (compared with the normal distribution) mean that model outliers are less influential. Robit regression models can be fit as generalized linear models with the link function defined as the inverse cumulative t distribution function with a specified number of degrees of freedom; they have been advocated as being particularly suitable for estimating inverse-probability weights and propensity scoring more generally. Here we describe a new command, robit, that implements robit regression in Stata.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231195288?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mpitb: A toolbox for multidimensional poverty indices</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 625-657, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I present mpitb, a toolbox for multidimensional poverty indices (MPIs). The package mpitb comprises several subcommands to facilitate specification, estimation, and analyses of MPIs and supports the popular Alkire– Foster framework to multidimensional poverty measurement. mpitb offers several benefits to researchers, analysts, and practitioners working on MPIs, including substantial time savings (for example, because of lower data management and programming requirements) while allowing for a more comprehensive analysis at the same time. Aside from various convenience functions, mpitb also provides low-level tools for advanced users and programmers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231195286?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Review of Environmental Econometrics Using Stata, by Christopher F. Baum and Stan Hurn</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/3&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 897-900, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I review Environmental Econometrics Using Stata, by Christopher F. Baum and Stan Hurn (2021, Stata Press).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-22-2023 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231196497?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
