<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The research circle: a possible utopia? Possibilities and constraints of knowledge development within a research-circle practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-31-2024 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2359426?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Time in School: A Conceptual Framework, Synthesis of the Causal Research, and Empirical Exploration</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We examine the fundamental and complex role that time plays in the learning process. We begin by developing a conceptual framework to elucidate the multiple obstacles schools face in converting total time in school into active learning time. We then synthesize the causal research and document a clear positive effect of additional time on student achievement typically of small to medium magnitude depending on dosage, use, and context. Further descriptive analyses reveal how large differences in the length of the school day and year across public schools are an underappreciated dimension of educational inequality in the United States. Finally, our case study of time loss in one urban district demonstrates the potential to substantially increase instructional time within existing constraints.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-31-2024 05:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241251857?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing Finnish and Chinese national teacher education frameworks from the teacher competency perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-31-2024 01:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2361108?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to achieve ‘egalitarian’ interaction between student teachers and mentor teachers? A study of a one-school-year teacher practicum in Germany</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-31-2024 01:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2359708?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Response Times in Answer Similarity Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Recent decades have seen a tremendous growth in the development of collusion detection methods, many of which rest on the assumption that examinees who engage in collusion will display unusually similar scores/responses. In this article, we expand the definition of answer similarity to include not only the item scores/responses but also the item response times (RTs). Using detailed simulations and an experimental data set, we show that (a) both the new and existing similarity statistics are able to control the Type I error rate in most of the studied conditions and (b) the new statistics are much more powerful, on average, than the existing statistics at detecting several types of simulated collusion.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 09:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241248770?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Quotas Constructed from Auxiliary Data to Guide the Recruitment of Sites for Randomized Controlled Trials</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 08:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2342852?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The “Who” of Teacher Residencies: Preservice Teachers’ Motivations for Selecting a Teacher Residency Program</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 08:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2358921?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dignity-Affirming Care in Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 05:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357008?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>(Trans)formation of student teachers’ professional identity through problem-based learning in Korea</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 01:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2360555?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/32/3&quot;&gt;Volume 32, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, July 2024, Page 327-331&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-29-2024 11:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2357959?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Any Other Thoughts?”: Establishing Third Space in a Family-School-University STEM Partnership to Center Voices of Parents and Teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-29-2024 03:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357010?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the onto-semiotic approach in mathematics education through the lens of the cultural historical activity theory</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research in mathematics education can be understood as a system of activities addressing the basic and applied problems related to teaching and learning of mathematics. Such a system includes the activities of foundation, planning, implementation, evaluation of mathematics instruction, and teacher professional development, which are supported by different theories. This diversity of theories raises interest in their comparison, coordination, and possible integration. The paper aims to present a case of application of the Cultural Historical Activity Theory (CHAT), in its 3rd and 4th generation versions, to analyze the emergence of the Onto-semiotic Approach to mathematical knowledge and instruction as a theoretical framework that addresses the study of the five partial activities mentioned above. This use of the CHAT can be useful in studies on theory articulation by focusing not only on the subjects, the object, and the instruments but also on the community context, the ecological-normative environment in which these activities take place, and the dilemmas or contradictions between theories.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-29-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01590-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Adapting Habermas’ construct of communicative rationality into a framework for analyzing students’ statistical literacy</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study argues that the works of philosopher Jürgen Habermas can provide useful directions for mathematics education research on statistical literacy. Recent studies on the critical demands posed by statistical information in media highlight the importance of the communicative component of statistical literacy, which involves students’ ability to react to statistical information. By adapting Habermas’ construct of communicative rationality into a framework for statistical literacy, a novel analytical tool is presented that can provide theoretical insights as well as in-depth empirical insights into students’ communication about statistical information. Central to the framework are the four validity claims of comprehensibility, truth, truthfulness, and rightness which interlocutors need to address to engage in statistical communication. The empirical usefulness of the framework is shown by presenting the results of a study that examined Grade 5 students’ responses to fictional arguments about the decline of Arctic sea ice. The Habermas-based framework not only reveals that complex evaluations of statistical arguments can take place even in Grade 5 but also shows that students’ evaluations vary greatly. Empirical results include a content-specific differentiation of validity claims through inductively identified sub-categories as well as a description of differences in the students’ uses of validity claims.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-29-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10325-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Approaches to Statistical Efficiency When Comparing the Embedded Adaptive Interventions in a SMART</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Sequential, multiple assignment randomized trials (SMARTs), which assist in the optimization of adaptive interventions, are growing in popularity in education and behavioral sciences. This is unsurprising, as adaptive interventions reflect the sequential, tailored nature of learning in a classroom or school. Nonetheless, as is true elsewhere in education research, observed effect sizes in education-based SMARTs are frequently small. As a consequence, statistical efficiency is of paramount importance in their analysis. The contributions of this manuscript are twofold. First, we provide an overview of adaptive interventions and SMART designs for researchers in education science. Second, we propose four techniques that have the potential to improve statistical efficiency in the analysis of SMARTs. We demonstrate the benefits of these techniques in SMART settings both through the analysis of a SMART designed to optimize an adaptive intervention for increasing cognitive behavioral therapy delivery in school settings and through a comprehensive simulation study. Each of the proposed techniques is easily implementable, either with over-the-counter statistical software or through R code provided in Supplemental Material.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-28-2024 07:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241251419?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Research-Practice Partnerships Advance Multilingual Learner Equity? A Case Study of Partnership with State-Education-Agency Leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-28-2024 05:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357036?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Unexpected Benefits of a Research-Practice Partnership’s Efforts to Strengthen Budgetary Decision-Making</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-28-2024 05:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357039?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publisher Correction: Professionalisation for inclusive mathematics–teacher education programs and changes in pre-service teachers’ beliefs and self-efficacy</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01592-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inequality in USA mathematics education: the roles race and socio-economic status play</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The recent PISA mathematics results delivered disappointing news for the United States of America (USA). These results underscored the education system’s continuing inequalities. An important question concerns to what extent and to which part of the educational system do these sources of inequality occur? In this paper we use PISA 2012 data merged with district- and school-level variables derived from five additional national databases to explore the way socio-economic status (SES) and race are related to inequalities in student performance as well as to inequalities in other components of schooling at both the system and student-levels, such as the academic ‘zeitgeist’ of the school, the nature of the mathematics curriculum and characteristics of both the teacher and the student. The results demonstrated how race and SES had significant relationships not only to student performance but to other aspects of schooling as well. Those relationships occurred at both the system- and within-school levels but differed in their implications. The policy implications of the research could help determine where the greatest effort could be made to provide all children of all racial and social classes equal opportunities to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01593-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Rising Tide That Lifts All Boats? Effects of Competition on Child Care Quality and Medium-Term Student Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Using administrative data of center-based child care providers in North Carolina from 2005 to 2018, we provide the first direct evidence on the effects of competition on provider quality and student outcomes in the context of early care and education, taking advantage of quality measures from the state’s Quality Rating and Improvement System (QRIS). We found that competition was associated with higher quality ratings and a higher probability to achieve a five-star rating—the highest tier in the QRIS. More competition increased providers’ probability to improve their rating and reduced the time to improve. Compared to public schools, private providers were responsive to competition. However, we did not find any effects of competition on district-level student third-grade academic performance.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 11:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241252413?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Holistic Capital Model: Time and Body Capital as Sources of Inequity</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;We present a model of capital that expands existing models to introduce two new forms of capital (time and body capital) as sources of inequity in education. The aim is to (a) make visible core resources that are relevant to educational outcomes and also (often hidden) sources of inequity, (b) identify commonalities across diverse empirical and theoretical research strands, and (c) reconceptualize existing research from an asset rather than deficit framework. We explain how time and physiological resources can be conceptualized as forms of capital and link this to extant empirical and theoretical research across fields. Then, we describe how students may have different amounts and types of time and body capital, as well as different drains on capital, and how this may lead to educational inequities. We close by describing the affordances of using this theory as a lens for analyzing existing educational structures, policies and practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 06:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241255626?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Individual to Collective Logics of Thriving: Redesigning K–12 Learning Ecosystems to Support Equitable Civic Futures</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 536-567, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The concept of “thriving” in educational policy refers to a loosely defined mix of academic, socioemotional, and civic outcomes associated with youth well-being. In this chapter, we analyze three focus areas in K–12 education—social emotional learning, 21st-century skills, and digital citizenship—and conclude that they are currently built on an individualistic neoliberal paradigm of learning and success. We argue that this paradigm is incommensurate with the personal, social, and civic flourishing necessary to sustain equitable multiracial democratic futures and offer instead an alternative collective logic of thriving. Our critical metasynthesis of the emergent field of social-design-based experimentation offers design principles educators can use to reorganize collective learning environments to support expansive youth thriving in schools and society.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231210257?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Science of Learning and Development: A View of the Issues</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page ix-xviii, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241244741?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Science of Learning and Development: A Commentary</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 155-160, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Transforming difficulties into opportunities for thriving is at the heart of this volume on the science of learning and development. This chapter brings the perspective of European research and the Global North and South and discusses some of the challenges included in the call to create the conditions for promoting sustainable and equitable futures for all. Among others, globalizing transformative knowledge by recreating, replicating, and scaling up success stories in education research can overcome methodological or epistemological limitations. Examples of cocreation and interdisciplinary work are included to produce socially relevant knowledge and be effective in tackling the real problems affecting children and youth. Dialogic learning and successful educational actions illustrate how educational success and transformation can happen.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231218731?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inclusive and Ameliorative Theorizing for Redressing 21st-Century Structural Inequities</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 167-172, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In analyzing the disseminated call, the commentary suggests the need for a consciousness consistent with a quote from Maya Angelou concerning identity. It is applied—in this case—to the situation of social science and specifically developmental science vis-à-vis published scholarship pertaining to communities of color. Questioned is the field’s long-term positionality regarding the persistent marginalization of Blacks. Suggested is the need to be candid in acknowledging the redundant “embracing of the lie of Black inferiority.” Argued is that the field’s positionality when it comes to representations of communities of color (i.e., embodied in “scholarly efforts”) serves as an untoward, incentivized, and under acknowledged contributor to the science of learning and development, which has problematic consequences for all.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231218878?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
