<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Segregating Gotham’s Youngest: Racial/Ethnic Sorting and the Choice Architecture of New York City’s Pre-K for All</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;New York City’s Pre-K for All (PKA) is the nation’s largest universal early childhood initiative, serving over 64,000 four-year-olds annually. Stemming from the program’s choice architecture as well as the city’s stark residential segregation, PKA programs are extremely segregated by child race/ethnicity. Our current study explores the complex forces that influence this segregation, including the interplay between family choices, seat availability, site-level enrollment priorities, and the PKA algorithm that weighs these and other considerations. We find that a majority of PKA segregation lies within local communities, and that areas with increased options and greater racial/ethnic diversity exhibit the most extreme segregation. We also conduct a simulation that leverages family PKA choices to maximize site-level racial/ethnic diversity and reduce between-site segregation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 08:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231190071?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where internationalisation and digitalisation intersect: designing a virtual exchange to enhance student teachers’ professional awareness as European teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 07:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2243644?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading Rural Districts: Research Synthesis of Rural Educational Leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 12:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238519?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participatory pedagogies enhance engineering education for sustainability</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 10:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2240858?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Practicum in ELT: a systematic review of 2010–2020 research on ELT practicum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2242577?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward a Conceptual Understanding of Inclusion as Intersubjective Experiences</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Inclusion has become a global buzzword relating to education policy and practice. Mostly, it is tied to discussions about access and opportunities in education spaces as well as school policies and the curriculum decisions and pedagogical actions of teachers. As part of this critique, we propose defining inclusion as intersubjective experiences associated with feelings of belonging, acceptance, and value that are dynamic, ephemeral, spatial, and in flux. Here, we advocate for centering the experiences and amplifying the voices of disabled children and young people in and about education spaces, while acknowledging the wider social forces that structure those spaces, as only disabled young people can explain how they feel in the educational spaces where they find themselves.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 02:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231176287?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Clustering eye-movement data uncovers students’ strategies for coordinating equations and diagrams of vector fields</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In mathematics education, students are repeatedly confronted with the tasks of interpreting and relating different representations. In particular, switching between equations and diagrams plays a major role in learning mathematical procedures and solving mathematical problems. In this article, we investigate a rather unexplored topic with precisely such requirements—that is, vector fields. In our study, we first presented a series of multiple-choice tasks to 147 introductory university students at the beginning of their studies and recorded students’ eye movements while they matched vector field diagrams and equations. Thereafter, students had to solve a similar coordination task on paper and justify their reasoning. Two cluster analyses were performed including (i) transition and fixation data on diagrams and options (Model 1), and (ii) additionally the number of horizontal and vertical saccades on the diagram (Model 2). In both models, two clusters emerge—with Model 1 distinguishing behaviors related to representational mapping and Model 2 additionally differentiating students according to representation-specific demands. Model 2 leads to a better distinction between the groups in terms of different performance indicators (test score, response confidence, and spatial ability) which also transfers to another task format. We conclude that vertical and horizontal saccades reflect executive actions of perception when approaching vector field coordination tasks. Thus, we recommend targeted interventions for mathematics lessons; these lessons must focus on a visual handling of the vector field diagram. Further, we infer that students’ difficulties can be attributed to covariational reasoning, thereby indicating the need for further investigations. From a methodological perspective, we reflect on the triangulation of eye-tracking and verbal data in (multiple-choice) assessment scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10243-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘I realised it when we played with the doll!’: nursing students’ learning from participation in an action research project that included manikins</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 07:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2242425?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Epistemic Injustice and Legitimacy in U.S. Doctoral Education: A Systematic Review of Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Epistemic injustice is a condition where knowers and knowledge claims are unduly dismissed. Philosophers suggest that epistemic injustice manifests in three forms: testimonial, hermeneutical, and contributory. Although distinct, all forms of epistemic injustice stem from relations of power, privilege, and positionality — where some have the opportunity and authority to legitimize the knowledge contributions of others. The purpose of this study was to explore the presence of epistemic injustice in U.S. doctoral education through a systematic review of literature. We methodically searched hundreds of peer-reviewed journals for studies focused on teaching, advising, peer interaction, doctoral socialization, and other experiences concerning doctoral education across the humanities, social science, and science disciplines. We retained, reviewed, and analyzed 107 manuscripts. Our analysis revealed epistemic injustice in doctoral education as well as rules that foster the conditions for epistemic injustice. Implications for doctoral education and future research are offered.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 06:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231187628?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Trekking Across Some Rough Terrain: Rural Teacher Education for Multilingual Students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 02:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238502?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Recruiting and Retaining Teachers in Rural Schools: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 01:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238491?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making Connections Explicit</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 572-585
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p572.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Translanguaging Pedagogy in Elementary Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 586-591
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p586.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advancing Agency Through Conjecturing</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 592-597
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p592.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing Meaning for Mathematical Expressions</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 598-603
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p598.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making Sense of Algebraic Expressions in Context</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 604-612
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p604.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Harnessing the Power of a Single-Number Number Talk</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 613-616
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p613.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Numbers: A Platform for Conjecture and Exploration</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 617-620
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p617.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Checking Math IDs to Launch the School Year</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 566-569
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p566.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Problems to Ponder</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 621-625
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p621.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GPS: Teaching Shapes Inclusively</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 626-630
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p626.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Revisiting How to Foster and Improve S3D</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 631-632
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p631.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Mathematics: The Universal Language?”</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 633-643
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p633.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Mathematics of Sewing</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 644-644
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p644.xml</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
