<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/edra/52/9&quot;&gt;Volume 52, Issue 9&lt;/a&gt;, Page 590-594, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-29-2023 11:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231216124?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inclusive co-teaching with teachers with intellectual disabilities in teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-29-2023 09:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2288550?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impacts of Viewpoint Diversity Law on Teaching and Learning in Florida’s State Universities</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study explores the impact of Florida House Bill 233 on teaching and learning in Florida’s State University System. This bill purports to promote intellectual freedom and viewpoint diversity by permitting students to record classes and by creating a cause of action for faculty violating these principles. Faculty were invited to share qualitative feedback about the specific impacts of the two provisions. The vast majority of faculty expressed negative views of these provisions, suggesting they would inhibit intellectual freedom and viewpoint diversity by deterring student participation in classes, discouraging faculty from engaging students in discussions of certain topics, and creating an atmosphere of mistrust between faculty and students. Faculty with positive views of the recording provision suggested that these provisions promote intellectual freedom and viewpoint diversity by discouraging faculty from imposing their views and giving students a remedy if they feel that faculty are violating their rights.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2023 10:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231215485?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mixed-Effects Location Scale Models for Joint Modeling School Value-Added Effects on the Mean and Variance of Student Achievement</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;School value-added models are widely applied to study, monitor, and hold schools to account for school differences in student learning. The traditional model is a mixed-effects linear regression of student current achievement on student prior achievement, background characteristics, and a school random intercept effect. The latter is referred to as the school value-added score and measures the mean student covariate-adjusted achievement in each school. In this article, we argue that further insights may be gained by additionally studying the variance in this quantity in each school. These include the ability to identify both individual schools and school types that exhibit unusually high or low variability in student achievement, even after accounting for differences in student intakes. We explore and illustrate how this can be done via fitting mixed-effects location scale versions of the traditional school value-added model. We discuss the implications of our work for research and school accountability systems.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2023 05:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231210808?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Comparison of Latent Semantic Analysis and Latent Dirichlet Allocation in Educational Measurement</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Topic models are mathematical and statistical models used to analyze textual data. The objective of topic models is to gain information about the latent semantic space of a set of related textual data. The semantic space of a set of textual data contains the relationship between documents and words and how they are used. Topic models are becoming more common in educational measurement research as a method for analyzing students’ responses to constructed-response items. Two popular topic models are latent semantic analysis (LSA) and latent Dirichlet allocation (LDA). LSA uses linear algebra techniques, whereas LDA uses an assumed statistical model and generative process. In educational measurement, LSA is often used in algorithmic scoring of essays due to its high reliability and agreement with human raters. LDA is often used as a supplemental analysis to gain additional information about students, such as their thinking and reasoning. This article reviews and compares the LSA and LDA topic models. This article also introduces a methodology for comparing the semantic spaces obtained by the two models and uses a simulation study to investigate their similarities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2023 05:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231209446?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Relationships Between State Higher Education Funding Strategies and College Access and Success</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We compiled the first longitudinal data set with detailed state funding information to examine whether different funding strategies for public higher education correlate with college access and completion, with a focus on outcomes among racially minoritized students. We found no relationships between funding mechanisms and student outcomes at public universities. However, at community colleges, we found that funding strategies that combine base adjustments and enrollment or performance components may increase enrollment, but not completions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-27-2023 12:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231208964?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Promise of Tutoring for PreK–12 Learning: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of the Experimental Evidence</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Tutoring ranks among the most versatile and potentially transformative educational tools available. Dozens of randomized experiments have evaluated preK–12 tutoring programs, varying widely in approaches, contexts, and costs. This article presents results from a systematic review and meta-analysis of tutoring field experiments. We develop a framework for understanding variation in tutoring program impact and examine effect sizes (ESs) across a range of characteristics. We find that tutoring programs yield consistently substantial positive impacts on learning, with an overall pooled ES of 0.288 SD (SE = 0.029, p &amp;lt; .001). ESs tend to be largest for programs that use teachers or paraprofessionals as tutors, are held in earlier grades, occur at least 3 days per week, and are held during school.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-27-2023 12:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231208687?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>AACTE, the Profession, and the Future</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/75/1&quot;&gt;Volume 75, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 5-12, January/February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-27-2023 10:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231212975?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring cultural dynamism of ethnomodelling as a pedagogical action for students from minority cultural groups</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics education is inherent to the discourse of globalization, which often states that mathematical knowledge is universal. Certain global mathematical techniques and procedures found in many mathematics curricula around the world often discourage students to engage in creating their own mathematical knowledge. This suggests that dominant cultural values are defined as universal or at the very least labeled as normative, while peripheral mathematical knowledge is tagged as merely simplistic, primitivistic, folkloristic, and/or as forms of obsolete systems. Our main purpose here is to discuss how ethnomodelling promotes a holistic understanding of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;local&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;global&lt;/em&gt; approaches in mathematics education, which contributes to the development of a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;glocal&lt;/em&gt; comprehension of mathematical practices developed by members of distinct cultures, which means placing them at the center of the educational process. Through the development of ethnomodelling, this pedagogical action promotes connections between day-to-day knowledge and systematized school curricula. Thus, this theoretical article demonstrates how we might consider situating local mathematical practices (margins) at the center (glocal) of the mathematics education process by decentering globalized mathematical knowledge in the search for peace and social justice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-27-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01539-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Family Perspectives of University Reading Clinic/Literacy Lab Experiences: What Matters</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Family partnerships should be a central component of teacher preparation. Although research provides family engagement strategies, little research offers teacher educators guidance from the perspectives of families themselves. The purpose of this convergent mixed-method study was to begin to fill the void in the literature by investigating family perspectives of theirs and their children’s experience in 10 reading clinic/literacy lab literacy specialist preparation programs across the United States and Canada. Through analysis of survey ratings (N = 132) and responses to structured interviews to (N = 84), this study found that families valued clinic/lab tutors building relationships with them, responding to their children’s strengths and needs, promoting self-efficacy, and working together as partners. Methods used in this study can provide a useful model for how teacher educators can intentionally seek input from families. Findings have implications for teacher educators advocating for and centering family engagement in teacher preparation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-25-2023 09:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231211266?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Organizing Possible Futures: A Systematic Review on Dis/ability Justice Frameworks to Design Equity-Oriented Inclusive Teacher Education Programs</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In the U.S. school system, Black, Indigenous, and People of Color (BIPOC) students often experience multiple forms of marginalization at the intersection of racism, ableism, and other forms of subjugation. To reform dysfunctional school systems, teacher education programs must create transformative spaces to nurture future educators committed to equity. These educators then will be equipped to dismantle the (in)visible racist and ableist structures within education systems and envision new alternative futures. Drawing on critical learning sciences and dis/ability justice-oriented theoretical approaches, we conducted a systematic literature review of 11 empirical studies to examine how teacher preparation programs are informed by dis/ability justice theoretical lenses. We synthesized how dis/ability justice-oriented teacher preparation programs organized transformative learning environments aimed at disrupting color-evasive and pathologizing discourses. We discussed the findings on how these programs conceptualized dis/ability, their applications of these conceptualizations in practice, and the transformative learning outcomes for preservice teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-25-2023 05:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231212927?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Peer Relationships and Chinese Adolescents’ Academic Achievement: Selection and Influence</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study applied Simulation Investigation for Empirical Network Analysis to disentangle friendship selection and influence regarding the academic achievement of Chinese adolescents in a 3-year longitudinal study of 880 middle school students (400 girls, Year 1 mean age = 13.33) and 525 high school students (284 girls, mean age = 16.45). Both peer selection and influence effects were obtained. Chinese adolescents preferred friendships with similarly achieving or higher achieving peers but avoided friendships with lower achieving peers. They increased achievement when they befriended high-achieving peers but decreased achievement when they befriended low-achieving peers. Influence but not selection was stronger for middle school students than for high school students. The results may be a function of the importance of academic success for Chinese students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-25-2023 05:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231208675?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What College Freshmen Believe About Themselves: An Investigation of Mathematical Mindset, Identity, Self-Efficacy, and Use of Self-Regulated Learning Strategies in Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Knowing what first-time freshmen in mathematics believe to be true about themselves as they arrive on a college campus provides valuable perspectives about freshman mathematics learners. We investigated how gender, high school mathematics course history, and university mathematics course placement are related to first-time freshmen’s mathematical mindset, identity, self-efficacy, and use of self-regulated learning strategies. A survey was completed by 293 first-time freshmen at a four-year university in the United States. Participants were enrolled in one of three university mathematics courses and completed a survey during the first week of class in Fall 2018. Results found that students’ mean scores for mathematical self-efficacy and use of self-regulated learning strategies were close to 4, and mathematical mindset and identity were close to 3 on a 5-point scale, where larger values corresponded to a more positive response. A multivariate analysis of variance was conducted on mean subscale scores, followed by analyses of variance. Calculus I students expressed significantly stronger mathematical identity than Intermediate Algebra students, and students who took advanced mathematics courses in high school expressed both stronger mathematical identity and self-efficacy than those who had taken only up to Algebra 2. Gender was not a significant differentiator among students, and neither mathematical mindset nor use of self-regulated learning strategies varied significantly across any subgroups.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-24-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00229-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of EthnoSTEM-based mathematics modular instruction on Sama students’ mathematical thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/vjer20/116/6&quot;&gt;Volume 116, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, 2023, Page 349-355&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2023 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2269536?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining students’ mathematical modeling competences in video-based modeling tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/vjer20/116/6&quot;&gt;Volume 116, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, 2023, Page 336-348&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2023 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2269533?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do mathematical thinking processes influence visual estimation skills in students?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/vjer20/116/6&quot;&gt;Volume 116, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, 2023, Page 325-335&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2023 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2269529?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Structure and associations of science vocabulary, general academic vocabulary, and science knowledge</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/vjer20/116/6&quot;&gt;Volume 116, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, 2023, Page 356-370&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2023 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2269545?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Redefining autonomy in low-achieving high-school students: Collaborative learning in Taiwan-context classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/vjer20/116/6&quot;&gt;Volume 116, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, 2023, Page 371-385&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2023 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2278767?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A multidimensional approach to the study of school climate and student engagement</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/vjer20/116/6&quot;&gt;Volume 116, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, 2023, Page 386-395&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2023 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2278771?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sample Size Calculation and Optimal Design for Multivariate Regression-Based Norming</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Normative studies are needed to obtain norms for comparing individuals with the reference population on relevant clinical or educational measures. Norms can be obtained in an efficient way by regressing the test score on relevant predictors, such as age and sex. When several measures are normed with the same sample, a multivariate regression-based approach must be adopted for at least two reasons: (1) to take into account the correlations between the measures of the same subject, in order to test certain scientific hypotheses and to reduce misclassification of subjects in clinical practice, and (2) to reduce the number of significance tests involved in selecting predictors for the purpose of norming, thus preventing the inflation of the type I error rate. A new multivariate regression-based approach is proposed that combines all measures for an individual through the Mahalanobis distance, thus providing an indicator of the individual’s overall performance. Furthermore, optimal designs for the normative study are derived under five multivariate polynomial regression models, assuming multivariate normality and homoscedasticity of the residuals, and efficient robust designs are presented in case of uncertainty about the correct model for the analysis of the normative sample. Sample size calculation formulas are provided for the new Mahalanobis distance-based approach. The results are illustrated with data from the Maastricht Aging Study (MAAS).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2023 06:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231210807?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the cognitive processes of mathematical problem posing: evidence from eye movements</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract  &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study concerns the cognitive process of mathematical problem posing, conceptualized in three stages: understanding the task, constructing the problem, and expressing the problem. We used the eye tracker and think-aloud methods to deeply explore students’ behavior in these three stages of problem posing, especially focusing on investigating the influence of task situation format and mathematical maturity on students’ thinking. The study was conducted using a 2 × 2 mixed design: task situation format (with or without specific numerical information) × subject category (master’s students or sixth graders). Regarding the task situation format, students’ performance on tasks with numbers was found to be significantly better than that on tasks without numbers, which was reflected in the metrics of how well they understood the task and the complexity and clarity of the posed problems. In particular, students spent more fixation duration on understanding and processing the information in tasks without numbers; they had a longer fixation duration on parts involving presenting uncertain numerical information; in addition, the task situation format with or without numbers had an effect on students’ selection and processing of information related to the numbers, elements, and relationships rather than information regarding the context presented in the task. Regarding the subject category, we found that mathematical maturity did not predict the quantity of problems posed on either type of task. There was no significant main group difference found in the eye-movement metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10262-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Joint Exploration: the Epistemic Positioning Underlying Collaborative Activity in a Secondary Mathematics Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study examines how collaborative activity among students and the teacher to investigate disciplinary questions, which we term ‘joint exploration’, is established and maintained in a secondary mathematics classroom. Although collaborative and active learning is increasingly sought after in mathematics classrooms, studies of instances of joint exploration remain relatively rare. In this study, we use the theoretical perspective of positioning to conceptualize joint exploration as involving the negotiation among participants to position students with epistemic authority and agency. Using a constant comparative method, we use classroom video data of two episodes containing joint exploration and closely analyse the shifts in epistemic positioning within them. We find that shifts in epistemic positioning, especially with respect to students positioning one another with epistemic authority and exercising epistemic agency, help to support continued joint exploration. We also find that the teacher can play an important role in decentring themselves as the epistemic authority. In addition to these findings, this study contributes a distinction in epistemic authority and agency, as we explain how the two concepts are related and involved in establishing and maintaining joint exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00295-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Mainstreaming action research”: Olav Eikeland’s legacy for our shared future</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/31/5&quot;&gt;Volume 31, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2023, Page 848-851&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-22-2023 01:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2277562?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial: (Re)searching for integrity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/31/5&quot;&gt;Volume 31, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2023, Page 843-847&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-22-2023 01:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2277557?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
