<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Practicum in ELT: a systematic review of 2010–2020 research on ELT practicum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2242577?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward a Conceptual Understanding of Inclusion as Intersubjective Experiences</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Inclusion has become a global buzzword relating to education policy and practice. Mostly, it is tied to discussions about access and opportunities in education spaces as well as school policies and the curriculum decisions and pedagogical actions of teachers. As part of this critique, we propose defining inclusion as intersubjective experiences associated with feelings of belonging, acceptance, and value that are dynamic, ephemeral, spatial, and in flux. Here, we advocate for centering the experiences and amplifying the voices of disabled children and young people in and about education spaces, while acknowledging the wider social forces that structure those spaces, as only disabled young people can explain how they feel in the educational spaces where they find themselves.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 02:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231176287?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘I realised it when we played with the doll!’: nursing students’ learning from participation in an action research project that included manikins</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 07:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2242425?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Epistemic Injustice and Legitimacy in U.S. Doctoral Education: A Systematic Review of Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Epistemic injustice is a condition where knowers and knowledge claims are unduly dismissed. Philosophers suggest that epistemic injustice manifests in three forms: testimonial, hermeneutical, and contributory. Although distinct, all forms of epistemic injustice stem from relations of power, privilege, and positionality — where some have the opportunity and authority to legitimize the knowledge contributions of others. The purpose of this study was to explore the presence of epistemic injustice in U.S. doctoral education through a systematic review of literature. We methodically searched hundreds of peer-reviewed journals for studies focused on teaching, advising, peer interaction, doctoral socialization, and other experiences concerning doctoral education across the humanities, social science, and science disciplines. We retained, reviewed, and analyzed 107 manuscripts. Our analysis revealed epistemic injustice in doctoral education as well as rules that foster the conditions for epistemic injustice. Implications for doctoral education and future research are offered.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 06:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231187628?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Trekking Across Some Rough Terrain: Rural Teacher Education for Multilingual Students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 02:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238502?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Recruiting and Retaining Teachers in Rural Schools: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 01:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238491?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making Connections Explicit</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 572-585
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p572.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Translanguaging Pedagogy in Elementary Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 586-591
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p586.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advancing Agency Through Conjecturing</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 592-597
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p592.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing Meaning for Mathematical Expressions</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 598-603
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p598.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making Sense of Algebraic Expressions in Context</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 604-612
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p604.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Harnessing the Power of a Single-Number Number Talk</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 613-616
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p613.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Numbers: A Platform for Conjecture and Exploration</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 617-620
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p617.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Checking Math IDs to Launch the School Year</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 566-569
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p566.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Problems to Ponder</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 621-625
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p621.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GPS: Teaching Shapes Inclusively</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 626-630
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p626.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Revisiting How to Foster and Improve S3D</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 631-632
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p631.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Mathematics: The Universal Language?”</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 633-643
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p633.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Mathematics of Sewing</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 8&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 644-644
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/8/article-p644.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ecology of Rural Cross-Sector School-Community Partnerships: A Literature Review</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2023 02:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238521?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introduction: NREA’s Rural Education Research Agenda 2016–2021</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2023 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238487?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meaning and Structure of Mathematical Connections in the Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The making of mathematical connections in the classroom plays a dual role. While many studies highlight the importance of connections for the learning of mathematics, others inform of students’ difficulties associated with the making of connections. This study aims to characterise the mathematical connections that arise in habitual classroom practice, using an inductive approach, in the context of introducing integers with pupils aged 12–13. Results show that connections emerge as networks of links resulting from interactions between the teacher and the students. We present a definition of connection, a detailed characterisation of their internal structure as networks of links and a global characterisation which takes into account the role of the connection in the context in which it takes place. The complementarity of the two characterizations allows us to coordinate, from a classroom perspective, existing specific classification proposals for connections with a broader notion of connection used by relevant curricular guidelines. Factors that may determine the complexity of connections and may be related with students’ difficulties when dealing with connections in the classroom are also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00281-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring computational thinking as a boundary object between mathematics and computer programming for STEM teaching and learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Programming is an interdisciplinary practice with applications in both mathematics and computer science. Mathematics concerns rigor, abstraction, and generalization. Computer science predominantly concerns efficiency, concreteness, and physicality. This makes programming a medium for problem solving that mediates between mathematics and computer science in intriguing ways. Behind programming practices is computational thinking (CT), a mode of thinking involved in formulating and solving problems so that the solutions could be represented and carried out by computing means. In this paper, CT is seen as a boundary object connecting mathematics and computer science in a school problem-solving context. In particular, we examine and analyse middle school students’ work upon engaging in mathematical problem solving-in a programming environment, taking CT as a boundary object embedded in the block-based programming environment, Scratch. The analysis is guided by observing boundary crossing features of CT in the students’ artefacts produced in Scratch while solving mathematical problems related to symmetry and arithmetic sequence. The findings of this study open up new dimensions to explore CT as a boundary object in integrated STEM pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01509-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reflections from an insider researcher ‘doing’ feminist participatory action research to co-produce a research agenda with British Pakistani women; a seldom heard group</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Participation of community stakeholders in health research priority setting is an emerging trend. Despite this, the involvement of marginalised groups in research prioritisation is limited and where they are involved, sample sizes are small, where individuals are merely consulted with, rather than coproducing the research agenda. Without addressing power dynamics inherent in research prioritisation with marginalised groups, their engagement in the research process can be tokenistic and the resulting research agenda unreflective of their needs. This article, therefore, aims to generate knowledge on how feminist participatory action research was used to co-produce an obesity research agenda with British Pakistani women, a seldom heard population, living in deprived areas. The methodology enabled Pakistani women to be involved in all stages of the project, culminating in the co-production of an obesity research agenda that accurately reflects their unmet needs. Women’s engagement in the project led to their increased confidence, the formation of relationships that lasted beyond the research project, improvements to their lifestyles, and engagement in further research. Feminist participatory action research may be used by researchers as a guiding methodology due to its ability to improve women’s lives and develop research agendas for women’s health.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-28-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231191854?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
