<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Overlooked Explanation for Increasing Suicidality: LGBQ Stressors Felt by More Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Recent data show rising suicidality among high school girls. We posit this increase may be related to an overlooked factor: more girls identifying as LGBQ. Using four cohorts of national Youth Risk Behavior Survey data (N = 22,562 females, N = 22,130 males), we found that LGBQ identification among females rose from 15% in 2015 to 34% in 2021. LGBQ females consistently reported higher suicidality, although rates remained stable within both LGBQ and heterosexual groups. The rise in females’ suicidality may stem from social pressures faced by LGBQ youth. Male suicidality and LGBQ identification showed smaller changes. More support for LGBQ students is essential to address this trend.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2025 08:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241305329?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 11:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2025.2453306?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educators’ interventions in gendered harassment: the importance of school culture</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 10:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2442935?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hands-on Consensus Building: Leveraging Deep Learning Models to Unveil Hand Gestures in Consensus-Building Discourses</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2448797?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promoting mathematical competence development through programming activities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The reasons for teaching programming in school are indeed manifold. Programming can for example be utilized as a vehicle for understanding and learning particular mathematical subject matter, or as a tool for solving mathematical problems. In this paper, however, we propose to utilize programming as a vehicle for developing mathematical competencies such as problem-solving, exploration, modeling, reasoning, representation, generalization, and abstraction. We perform a design study utilizing a systematic, iterative development process for designing teaching sessions, focusing on one mathematical competence at a time. We apply the proposed methodology on a set of teaching sessions that are developed, implemented, and tested in a range of classroom settings. Based on this development process, we conclude that programming can be used to develop mathematical competencies. Furthermore, we identify a set of teacher practices that can be used to facilitate mathematical competence development in programming activities.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10380-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Works for Whom: Exploring the Students, Settings, and Outcomes in What Works Clearinghouse Study Data</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-14-2025 04:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2427762?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Empirical Benchmarks for Effect Size Interpretation and Study Planning with Social and Behavioral Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-14-2025 04:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2427767?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Addressing teacher shortages in an international context: implications for the quality and status of teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 12:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2025.2447968?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rera/95/1&quot;&gt;Volume 95, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 154-170, February 2025. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 10:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241308357?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supervising, Coaching, and Preparing Dual Language Bilingual Education Teachers: A Collaborative Autoethnography</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Feedback and preservice teachers’ (PSTs’) clinical practice/field experiences are vital for their learning. Understanding influences on field supervisors’ feedback is critical, especially for preparing dual language bilingual education (DLBE) teachers because it requires specialized knowledge—yet systematic guidelines and programs for DLBE teacher preparation are lacking. We conducted a collaborative autoethnography to determine how our identities and experiences with language and DLBE related to our feedback and supervision of DLBE PSTs. We analyzed and discussed the narratives we wrote about our experiences and the feedback we provided while supervising 13 Spanish–English bilingual PSTs in elementary DLBE classrooms. Our identities and experiences, which were influenced by families, education, language histories, geography, and sociopolitical contexts, influenced our feedback. Considering identities and experiences illuminates what is (sometimes unconsciously) prioritized and ignored in feedback. Engaging in deep reflection is important for continued support of supervisors and PSTs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 10:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241312351?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Democracy on the Sidelines: The Erosion and Potential of Youth Sports as Democratic Education</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;In this philosophical paper, we argue that youth sports, both in and out of schools, are a largely unrealized space for democratic/civic education. Where youth sports leagues used to be low cost, local, and inclusive, much has changed over the last several decades. We are now in the neoliberal era of exclusive, privatized, and professionalized youth sports. Drawing on Dewey’s robust conception of democracy and Talisse’s concerns about partisan polarization, we argue that youth sports should be spaces to develop democratic habits, dispositions, and values. We explore the benefits of youth sports as well as current challenges, including excessive costs and pressure, disrupted families, and hyperindividualism. We end by offering suggestions for reforming youth sports to recenter their educational and democratic potential and value, including supporting loosely structured play, modeling democratic behavior, teaching democratic habits directly, and learning from more progressive national sports models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 09:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241311810?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inscribing proportional relationships using partitioning, co-occurrence, and same extent</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 08:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2025.2450408?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using video case studies to provide prospective secondary teachers in Kenya opportunities to notice and reflect on pedagogical practices</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2025 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2446289?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can We Learn From Qualitative Impact Evaluations About the Effectiveness of Lobby and Advocacy? A Meta-Evaluation of Dutch aid Programmes and Assessment Tool</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Official development agencies are increasingly supporting civil society lobby and advocacy (L&amp;amp;A) to address poverty and human rights. However, there are challenges in evaluating L&amp;amp;A. As programme objectives are often to change policies or practices in a single institution like a Government Ministry, L&amp;amp;A programmes are often not amenable to large-n impact evaluation methods. They often work in strategic partnerships to foster change; hence, contribution may be a more relevant evaluation question than attribution. Small-n qualitative approaches are available to measure the effectiveness of L&amp;amp;A which use the theory of change as their analytical framework. We conducted a meta-evaluation of 36 evaluations of multi-component international programmes to support civil society L&amp;amp;A across Asia, Africa and Latin America, comprising the majority of programmatic support from one international donor. We assessed the confidence in causal claims in the evaluations using a new tool that we developed. Assessments of the contribution of the programmes to the changes in outcomes were not provided in many of the evaluations, nor were predictable sources of bias addressed. Given that L&amp;amp;A programmes are likely to adopt an influencing approach where many different inside-track and outside-track engagement objectives, opportunities and strategies are attempted, many of which might be expected to fail, there appeared to be a clear bias in the evaluations towards reporting outcomes that were achieved, ignoring those that were not. We provide guidance on how to improve the design, conduct and reporting of small-n qualitative evaluations of aid effectiveness.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2025 04:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X251314731?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inferences, mastery, and objectivity: examining student understanding of mathematical concepts with inferentialism</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Inferentialism has emerged as a valuable theoretical resource in mathematics education. As a theory of meaning about the use and content of concepts, it offers a fresh perspective on traditional epistemological and linguistic questions in the field. Despite its emergence, important inferentialist ideas still need to be operationalized. In this paper, I operationalize multiple inferentialist concepts to analyze prospective secondary mathematics teachers’ learning about graphs and quantitative and covariational reasoning in a mathematics content course. I use Robert Brandom’s ideas about upstream, downstream, and incompatible inferences to illustrate the inferentialist mastering metaphor for learning and Brandom’s ideas about objectivity. My analysis shows (a) inferentialism’s capacity to address epistemological issues like objectivity and conceptual understanding, (b) the importance of attending to different types of inferences to assess learning from an inferentialist perspective, and (c) how the development of mastery is associated with virtues. I conclude by identifying the study’s potential limitations and trajectories for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10377-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Refining” Our Understanding of Early Career Teacher Skill Development: Evidence From Classroom Observations</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Novice teachers improve substantially in their first years on the job, but we know remarkably little about the nature of this skill development. Using data from Tennessee, we leverage a feature of the classroom observation protocol that asks school administrators to identify an item on which the teacher should focus their improvement efforts. This “area of refinement” overcomes a key measurement challenge endemic to inferring from classroom observation scores the development of specific teaching skills. We show that administrators disproportionately identify two skills when observing novice teachers: classroom management and presenting content. Struggling with classroom management, in particular, is associated with early career attrition. Using a returns to experience framework, we observe improvement in these skills among teachers who remain.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 12:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241303146?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Service-user research and Peter Kropotkin: a personal note of thanks to Professor Carol Munn-Giddings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 08:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2444099?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Speaking Up, Pushing Back, Closing the Door: Agency of Open and Covert Teacher Resistance in Dual-Language Bilingual Education</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;The increasing prominence of dual-language bilingual education (DLBE) in the United States necessitates deeper understanding of institutional roles and professional identities of DLBE teachers, particularly when incongruent. We qualitatively analyzed teacher resistance in discordant situations as discussed in conferences between DLBE teachers and a bilingual instructional coach in two districts over 2 years. In these conversations, we found a distinction between nonconfrontational and open, direct resistance. We applied an agentive triad model of teacher identity, agency, and power to understand how DLBE teachers navigated discordant situations in their schools. Teachers acted from different identity positions, including agentive compliance, anagentive compliance (without agency), and nonconfrontational resistance. Findings and theorization demonstrate that DLBE programs present special considerations for teacher identity, role, and resistance. Moreover, context-specific characteristics, including program age, model, and administration, may impact teachers’ approach to resistance. Findings and theorization are relevant to successful DLBE program implementation and equity focused instructional coaching.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 08:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241311818?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/50/1&quot;&gt;Volume 50, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 180-182, February 2025. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 08:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241308335?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/50/1&quot;&gt;Volume 50, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 3-4, February 2025. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 08:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241301538?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>In-the-moment discussions during launch rehearsals: an analysis of participation, substance, and structure</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Learning to launch problem-based lessons is challenging for prospective teachers (PTs). Teaching rehearsals offer an opportunity for PTs to practice launches in a controlled environment in which the action can be paused to discuss situations that arise. Typically, the teacher educator (TE) initiates the vast majority of these pauses, but in this study, the TE encouraged any PT to also initiate a pause in the action whenever they identified a potential learning opportunity for the class. We collected detailed data on each in-the-moment discussion in order to determine who initiates and participates in these discussions, how discussions initiated by the PTs and the TE differ in structure and substance, and whether PTs want to remember discussions with particular structures or substances. We found that over half of the discussions were initiated by PTs themselves. We also found that PTs across the class actively engaged in the in-the-moment discussions. Looking closer at the structure and substance of the discussions showed that the TE and PTs structured the discussions in similar ways, but there were some differences in the substance of those discussions. We also found that PTs were more likely to want to remember discussions they had initiated as well as those that were framed as highlighting a productive move.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09677-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional learning interventions for inquiry-based pedagogies in primary classrooms: A scoping review (2012–2022)</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In the contemporary educational landscape characterised by performativity pressures, schools face increasing scrutiny regarding their students’ mathematical outcomes. Inquiry-based approaches in mathematics education offer promising potential to enhance reasoning and problem-solving capabilities across diverse student populations. However, the transition from teacher-centred methodologies to student-centred, inquiry-based approaches presents significant challenges for educators. This scoping review examines reported professional learning approaches aimed at building teacher capacity in implementing inquiry-based mathematics instruction, with the potential to improve student engagement and interest in the subject. Here, capacity refers to a teacher’s ongoing professional ability to implement and effect change. The review provides insights into various hindrances to implementing inquiry-based learning, including the substantial time investment required, teachers’ confidence levels, and the challenge of shifting deeply ingrained pedagogical beliefs. Conversely, it identifies a range of supports for facilitating this pedagogical shift, with the ultimate goal of improving students’ mathematical outcomes. These supports include school-wide commitments to providing opportunities for teachers to actively collaborate with specialist educators and mentors within their institutions. Findings from this review underscore that the transition to inquiry-based approaches is a gradual process requiring sustained effort and commitment. The foundation for this shift lies in cultivating a school culture that acknowledges and addresses the complex needs of both teachers and leaders in implementing inquiry-based learning. This review contributes to the growing body of literature on professional development in mathematics education, offering valuable insights for educators, administrators, and policymakers seeking to enhance mathematical instruction and student outcomes through inquiry-based approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00516-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Hybrid EM Algorithm for Linear Two-Way Interactions With Missing Data</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We study an Expectation-Maximization (EM) algorithm for estimating product-term regression models with missing data. The study of such problems in the frequentist tradition has thus far been restricted to an EM algorithm method using full numerical integration. However, under most missing data patterns, we show that this problem can be solved analytically, and numerical approximations are only needed under specific conditions. Thus we propose a hybrid EM algorithm, which uses analytic solutions when available and approximate solutions only when needed. The theoretical framework of our algorithm is described herein, along with three empirical experiments using both simulated and real data. We demonstrate that our algorithm provides greater estimation accuracy, exhibits robustness to distributional violations, and confers higher power to detect interaction effects. We conclude with a discussion of extensions and topics of further research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-09-2025 11:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241304015?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Feasibility of the Knowledge, Language, and Inquiry (K.L.I.) intervention for multilingual English learners</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-09-2025 10:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2449035?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
