<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Corrigendum to Do the Effects Persist? An Examination of Long-term Effects After Students Leave Turnaround Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-14-2024 10:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241302042?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Influence of Earning Industry Certifications on High School Graduation: Evidence from Florida</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Dropping out of high school creates barriers to economic self-sufficiency. Career and technical education (CTE) may help students engage with school by showing the connection between school and work. Prior research has shown that high school CTE participation promotes positive academic outcomes including high school graduation. This paper uses a quasi-experimental design to examine the association between certifications and on-time high school graduation. Our findings indicate that certifications exert a meaningful influence on the likelihood of high school graduation, and that the effect is stronger for students who are at risk for dropping out or are economically disadvantaged.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-14-2024 10:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241292625?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Academic Cheating, Achievement Orientations, and Culture Values: A Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This preregistered meta-analysis investigated whether cultural values moderate the relations between students’ achievement orientations and their tendency to cheat. We identified 80 studies on the associations between performance/learning orientations and academic cheating in 27 countries with 40,867 participants. Performance orientation positively correlates with academic cheating (r = .09, 95% CI = 0.04 to 0.13), and learning orientation negatively correlates with academic cheating (r = −.16, 95% CI = −0.20 to –0.13). Univariate meta-analysis, hierarchical meta-regression, and meta-analytic structural equation modeling (MASEM) revealed that cultural values at the country level significantly moderate the relations between achievement orientations and cheating. These findings suggested that cultural values play a significant role in influencing the relations between achievement orientations and academic cheating, and, thus, cheating prevention programs must consider culture to achieve optimal effects. Based on these findings, we propose a new model that integrates cultural values into the existing model of academic cheating decision-making.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-13-2024 10:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241288240?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Persistence and Emergence of Literacy Skills: Long-Term Impacts of an Effective Early Grade Reading Intervention in South Africa</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-13-2024 07:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2417288?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Admissions, Organization, Culture, and Policy: Understanding the Postsecondary Structures that Shape Women’s Entry into Computing Bachelor’s Programs</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Despite the growing popularity of computing bachelor’s programs, women remain vastly underrepresented in these fields. Using Social Cognitive Career Theory and intersectionality as guiding theories, this qualitative study explores how postsecondary institutions shape women’s experiences choosing and entering computing bachelor’s programs. Twenty-eight of 40 participants entered their institutions with plans to study computing, while 12 developed a new (or renewed) interest in computing as postsecondary students. Findings outline four postsecondary structures that shaped women’s entry into computing majors, including university-level admissions and participant perceptions of financial and cultural accessibility; academic college-level organization and admissions processes; institutional computing cultures, namely introductory course experiences and social environments; and major declaration policies. Findings also show how these structures differentially shaped participant experiences based on intersecting social identities. Overall, findings illustrate the precarious relationship between computing interest development, major intent, and major enrollment for undergraduate women in computing.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-13-2024 07:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241290758?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Long-Term Effects of the Dana Center Mathematics Pathways Model: Evidence from a Randomized Trial</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-13-2024 05:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2394537?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning to speak mathematically at the Japanese supplementary school in Sweden: critical cases of praxeological anomaly</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Natural language is known to play a crucial and specific role for children’s learning in school mathematics. Not only does it carry special vocabulary, but subtle differences between natural languages may lead to surprising challenges, for instance, for learners who are not taught mathematics in their mother tongue. In this paper, the anthropological theory of didactic (ATD) is used as a main framework, and we analyse some praxeological anomalies from the teaching of fractions at Japanese schools abroad, while learners attend, at the same time, a regular school in some other language (in this case, the local language, Swedish). Our findings indicate that these praxeological anomalies arise not only from linguistic disparities related to specialised vocabulary and syntax for elementary mathematics but also from institutional and curricular differences. This study gives new insights on these language challenges related to mathematics as taught at expatriate schools, particularly in the case of Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10365-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A “Wise” Intervention to Increase Hand Hygiene Compliance of Nurses in Acute Care Units in US Hospitals: A Multiple Baseline Interrupted Time-Series Evaluation</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Objective: This study tested a ‘wise’ intervention (quick prompt of a specific psychological mec) in acute care hospital units to improve nurses’ hand hygiene compliance (HHC). Design: A multiple baseline design in two medical-surgical teaching hospitals in the United States. Measurements: Hand hygiene data was collected using an electronic compliance monitoring system with sensors placed in doorways and on corresponding soap and alcohol-based hand rub dispensers. The outcome measure was the proportion of opportunities in which HH was undertaken by staff per week in each unit. Intervention: A quick-and-easy psychological prime to reinvigorate professional identity. Methods: Interrupted time series analysis using a quasi-Poisson regression model with statistical process control charts for each unit. Results: A statistically significant increase in HHC rates that was sustained for months post-intervention. However, the patterns by unit were not statistically significant once temporal trends were considered. Other factors, such as the unit type and the use of incentives could have impacted the results. Conclusions: These analyses suggest that the aggregate impact should not be taken as evidence of intervention effectiveness. This study therefore cannot be considered to have provided a strong foundation for use of a ‘wise’ intervention, despite its relatively small financial, logistical and psychological cost.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2024 09:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241299854?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Designing professional experience placements: learning to innovate</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2024 08:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2422083?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estimating the Impact of Integrated Student Support on Elementary School Achievement: A Natural Experiment</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;National interest is growing in Integrated Student Support (ISS) interventions, which offer schools systematic ways to reduce barriers to learning. The present study exploits the random component embedded within the school assignment system of a large urban school district to estimate the effect of schools providing ISS on student academic achievement at third, fourth, and fifth grade. The sample included students (N = 2,342) randomly assigned to schools—with or without ISS—via enrollment lottery. Students assigned to schools implementing ISS demonstrated higher achievement (from approximately .02% to more than 50% of a standard deviation) than those assigned to control schools. While we found some evidence for the efficacy of ISS by third grade, treatment effects were consistently largest and proved most robust across modeling strategies at fifth grade. The practical significance of these findings is discussed with attention to ongoing national efforts to improve the learning opportunities of economically disadvantaged students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2024 07:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241292072?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Science Outcome Design Parameters for Cluster-Randomized Trials Involving Teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2024 07:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2417283?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Accessing and Assessing Components of Elementary and Middle School Students’ Mathematical Disposition Through Metaphors</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2024 04:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2419291?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mental constructions for the learning of the concept of vector space</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study contributes to the literature on linear algebra instruction by designing and researching a teaching sequence based on APOS Theory to introduce engineering students to vector spaces. The sequence offers students multiple opportunities to understand the concept. Another contribution is the evidence that introducing prerequisite concepts—such as equality, sets, and binary operations—before tackling vector space was crucial for grasping the role of proof in determining whether a set is a vector space. The findings confirm that, as other studies have shown, vector space is challenging for students. However, the results demonstrate that students were able to face this challenge. All students showed evidence of developing an understanding of the concept, with nine achieving a clear grasp of vector space and the role of proof by the end of the experience. Additionally, the progress observed—from having difficulties with symbols to successfully proving statements involving unconventional operations—underscores the effectiveness of the teaching approach.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01640-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Secondary school students’ strategies when interpreting histograms and case-value plots: an eye-tracking study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Many students persistently misinterpret histograms. This calls for closer inspection of students’ strategies when interpreting histograms and case-value plots (which look similar but are different). Using students’ gaze data, we ask: &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;How and how well do upper secondary pre-university school students estimate and compare arithmetic means of histograms and case-value plots?&lt;/em&gt; We designed four item types: two requiring mean estimation and two requiring means comparison. Analysis of gaze data of 50 students (15–19 years old) solving these items was triangulated with data from cued recall. We found five strategies. Two hypothesized most common strategies for &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;estimating&lt;/em&gt; means were confirmed: a strategy associated with horizontal gazes and a strategy associated with vertical gazes. A third, new, count-and-compute strategy was found. Two more strategies emerged for &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;comparing&lt;/em&gt; means that take specific features of the distribution into account. In about half of the histogram tasks, students used correct strategies. Surprisingly, when comparing two case-value plots, some students used distribution features that are only relevant for histograms, such as symmetry. As several incorrect strategies related to how and where the data and the distribution of these data are depicted in histograms, future interventions should aim at supporting students in understanding these concepts in histograms. A methodological advantage of eye-tracking data collection is that it reveals more details about students’ problem-solving processes than thinking-aloud protocols. We speculate that spatial gaze data can be re-used to substantiate ideas about the sensorimotor origin of learning mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10351-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Teachers With Absent Students Feel Less Job Satisfaction?</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Research and policy have focused predominantly on the individual consequences for students who miss school. Yet absenteeism does not occur in a vacuum, and less work has focused on how student absenteeism correlates to classroom dynamics. Practically no attention has been paid toward teachers. We propose in this study that student absences make it challenging for teachers to enjoy the very function of their jobs and thus experience more dissatisfaction at work as a result. We find that teachers have lower job satisfaction when more of their students are absent. However, we find statistically significant differences only for broad aspects of teacher satisfaction—job enjoyment, usefulness, and belief in the profession—rather than differences among other related measures of teaching.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-11-2024 09:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241292331?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educational Pluralism and Social Cohesion: A Themed Issue of the Peabody Journal of Education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/hpje20/99/5&quot;&gt;Volume 99, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, November-December 2024&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-11-2024 05:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2407243?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning to leverage teachers’ ideas: facilitators’ growth in moderation practices with simultaneously strong goal focus and participant focus</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When novice facilitators start to lead teachers’ professional development (PD), they have been found to struggle to combine a strong participant focus (i.e., valuing and working with participating teachers’ needs and ideas) and goal focus (working toward the PD goals), whereas expert facilitators seem to be more able to integrate both focus. Empirical studies have identified these challenges across contexts and several situational demands, for example, when facilitators set goals, plan a PD activity, notice teachers’ ideas, and moderate video-based discussions. In this paper, we contribute to this line of research by investigating another situational demand in a longitudinal perspective: We studied how two novice facilitators moderated the discussion after the same PD activity several times. The qualitative comparative analysis of transcribed videos from PD sessions revealed that each facilitator used several practices with varying degrees of goal and participant focus. Over time, they learned to apply more practices that were, simultaneously, strongly goal and participant focused: By leveraging teachers’ ideas toward the PD content goals, they achieved integration of both focus, which have sometimes previously been experienced as conflicting. We discuss implications for facilitator preparation programs in terms of unpacking facilitation practices and explicitly working with the content elements for finer-grained goals.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09660-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of a classwide reading intervention on reading fluency and comprehension of content area text with students in middle school</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2024 10:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2423185?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledgement of reviewers</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09665-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics achievement at rural and urban secondary schools: a trends analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The education gap between rural and urban areas hinders social and economic development. Urban students often have better academic performance, leading to more job opportunities and higher social status. This perpetuates social stratification as high-level skills are in demand. Recognizing and addressing these disparities is crucial to tackling social inequalities. Bridging these gaps will promote social and economic progress and empower communities in an ever-changing world. This study aimed to examine the relationship between mathematics achievement and various factors at the student and school levels among eighth-grade students in rural and urban areas of Malaysia. Using data from the Trends in International Mathematics and Science Study (TIMSS) collected from 1999 to 2015, separate multilevel analyses were conducted for students in rural and urban schools. The findings indicate that student-level factors play a significant role in mathematics achievement in both urban and rural schools, but school-level factors have a greater association with the achievement of urban schools. Additionally, compositional factors, such as students&#39; socioeconomic background, have a greater relationship with mathematics achievement in urban schools compared to rural schools. The study highlights the need to address the achievement gap in mathematics between urban and rural students in Malaysia, with factors such as attitudes towards mathematics, educational aspiration, and parental education becoming more significant in recent years. Recommendations include investing in early childhood education, attracting high-quality teachers for rural schools, providing resources and technology access, and promoting self-concept in students through collaborative efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00511-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mitigating Omitted Variable Bias in Exploratory Differential Item Functioning Assessment: A Propensity Score Adjustment Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Omitted variable bias (OVB) in differential item functioning (DIF) assessment can lead to biased estimates of DIF effects, increasing type I error rates and reducing statistical power. Methodologies for addressing OVB, particularly under exploratory conditions where DIF is assessed without prior information, remain underdeveloped. This study addresses these challenges by applying the propensity score (PS) method to enhance the parsimony of the DIF model. Furthermore, this study incorporated the DIF-free-then-DIF (DFTD) strategy into the PS method, establishing the PS.DFTD method for exploratory DIF assessment. The simulation results reveal that the PS.DFTD method appears promising for mitigating OVB in DIF assessment, demonstrating its potential for practical applications.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2024 10:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241280308?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Board Elections Before, During, and After the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Media reports suggest that parent frustration with COVID school policies and the growing politicization of education have increased community engagement with local public schools. However, there is no evidence to date on whether these factors have translated into greater engagement at the ballot box. This paper uses a novel data set to explore how school board elections changed following the start of the COVID-19 pandemic. I find that school board elections following the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic were more likely to be contested and that voter turnout in contested elections increased. These changes were large in magnitude and varied with several district characteristics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2024 05:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241291029?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racial Change in Suburbia: America’s Diversifying Elementary Districts and Their Effect on School Segregation</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The ethnic and racial makeup of the United States has changed during the last several decades. Scholars have qualitatively shown how these changes affect school districts but have not identified their scale. We examine residential demographic change using a novel dataset derived from a geographic technique that leverages satellite imagery with 2000 and 2020 census data. We then analyze the effects of demographic change on student isolation and dissimilarity in elementary school districts. Our findings indicate that most elementary districts have changed, but the changes are uneven. The number of districts with White student intense isolation declined, particularly in suburban locales. Meanwhile, districts with student of color intense isolation increased, particularly in urban locales. These changes indicate that increasing diversity for White students has coincided with greater isolation for students of color. These findings should prompt scholars to reconsider their conceptualization of suburban school districts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2024 05:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241290754?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledgements to reviewers 2024</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01645-0</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
