<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I Loved Seeing How Their Brains Worked!”—Examining the Role of Epistemic Empathy in Responsive Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Studies in science and mathematics education have shown that teachers’ responsiveness to students’ ideas, feelings, and experiences is critical for promoting epistemic agency, disciplinary engagement, and equity. Such responsiveness is particularly important for students whose cultures, backgrounds, and funds of knowledge have been traditionally marginalized in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) classrooms. Yet, what allows teachers to enact responsive teaching is less clear. We argue that epistemic empathy—the capacity for tuning into and appreciating learners’ intellectual and emotional experiences in constructing, communicating, and critiquing knowledge—is an essential driver of teacher responsiveness. In this work, we examine how epistemic empathy can serve to support teachers’ attention and responsiveness to students’ sensemaking experiences in the classroom and discuss emergent tensions that arise in this work. We end with implications for research and for teacher education to cultivate epistemic empathy as a resource for responsive teaching and a target for teacher learning.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 07:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231187313?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career and Technical Education at Community Colleges: A Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;I review the literature evaluating sub-baccalaureate career and technical education (CTE) at community colleges. The goal of this study is to review the evidence describing how earning these types of credentials affects students’ outcomes, as well as which program characteristics contribute to student success. The research suggests that, on average, there are significant labor-market returns to obtaining short, technical credentials, although the returns vary across locations and fields of study. Researchers examining career pathway programs, sectoral partnerships, and apprenticeships have found mixed effects of participating in these programs, although so far, the literature is largely limited to short-term outcomes. More research is needed that ties program characteristics to student outcomes to develop our understanding of how to increase the probability of success for students enrolling in postsecondary CTE. We also need more studies examining the long-term outcomes for students graduating from these programs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 06:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231186618?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Postsecondary Aspirations of Rural Indigenous Adolescents and How Schools Support These Dreams, Goals, and Plans: A Literature Review and Synthesis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 01:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238509?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rural Students in Higher Education: From College Preparation and Enrollment to Experiences and Persistence</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 01:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238508?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: On designing better structures for feedback in practice‑based professional development: Using “failure” to innovate</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09592-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring change in secondary mathematics teachers&#39; noticing of argumentation through experiencing peer-assessment strategies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study examines changes in secondary mathematics teachers&#39; noticing of argumentation through experiencing a peer-assessment cycle. Sixty-one teachers participated in such a cycle comprised of (a) analyzing a written argumentation classroom situation (ACS) using a report format, (b) collaboratively assessing peers&#39; ACS-reports using an ACS rubric format and providing feedback to peers, (c) receiving feedback from peers and individually refining the initial ACS-reports, and (d) reflecting on their experience. Analysis of teachers&#39; initial and refined ACS-reports revealed changes in teachers’ noticing of various dimensions associated with argumentation. Analysis of teachers&#39; written reflections and semi-structured interviews provided insights into the characteristics of the experience that supported or inhibited the change in their noticing of argumentation, from their perspective. The study provides evidence of the potential of the peer-assessment-cycle process for teachers&#39; learning to notice key aspects of argumentation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09586-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ perceptions of less successfully organized professional development practices in mathematics: A study of nine secondary schools in Shanghai, China</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Professional development (PD) for mathematics teachers in China, especially in Shanghai, has received growing international attention. However, most of available research concerning Chinese PD has focused on successful practices, and far too little attention has been paid to less successfully organized PD practices, particularly for mathematics teachers in Shanghai. This study aims to examine key aspects and underlying reasons for less successfully organized PD practices in Shanghai from teachers’ perspectives. The data were collected from 132 mathematics teachers in 9 randomly selected secondary schools in Shanghai through a questionnaire survey and follow-up interviews. The results show that Shanghai mathematics teachers perceived “time, duration and frequency”, “assessment and management” and “objective” as the three most unsatisfactory aspects in less successfully organized PD they attended, and they considered that organized PD practices were less successful mainly due to lack of assessment for the PD organizers and of necessary coordination between PD organizers at different levels. In addition, there were statistically significant differences in teachers’ perceptions of various specific problems in different aspects about less successfully organized PD between teachers with different demographic features, such as length of teaching experience and gender. Implications of the findings of the study to Chinese educational settings and beyond are discussed at the end of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09591-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging Number Lines and Unit Fractions to Build Student Understanding: Insights from a Mixed Methods Study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Fractions remain a challenging area of school mathematics at every stage of education, with impacts that extend far beyond the school years. For this study, researchers engaged in classroom-based design research over a 6-year period to investigate effective strategies for teaching fractions with Canadian students. Participants included 86 teachers (representing 12 collaborative research teams spread across 8 school boards) and over 2000 students from Grades 3–10. Quantitative analyses revealed significant pre-post gains in students’ fraction knowledge. Qualitative findings revealed some best practices in fractions instruction, including the importance of focusing on unit fractions and number lines to facilitate student sense-making. These findings lead to a detailed discussion of the benefits of (1) focusing on unit fractions as a central construct that allows students to meaningfully work with fractions and make connections across ideas of increasing complexity; (2) leveraging powerful representations as objects-to-think-with that combine concrete and abstract thinking about fractions; and (3) using a design research methodology in the context of collaborative work with teachers.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00278-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>U.S. Ninth Graders’ Math Course Placement at the Intersection of Learning Disability Status, Race, and Socioeconomic Status</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This study integrates an intersectional framework with data on 15,000 U.S. ninth graders from the High School Longitudinal Study of 2009 to investigate differences in ninth-grade math course placement at the intersection of adolescents’ learning disability status, race, and socioeconomic status (SES). Descriptive results support an increased liability perspective, with the negative relationship between a learning disability and math course placement larger for adolescents more privileged in terms of their race and/or SES. Adjusted results suggest that the lower math course placements of youth with learning disabilities are due to cumulative disadvantage rather than disability-related inequities in the transition to high school for youth of diverse racial and socioeconomic backgrounds. In addition to demonstrating the importance of intersectional perspectives, this study provides a roadmap for future studies by introducing the new perspective of increased liability to be used in conjunction with the widely employed perspective of multiple marginalization.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-25-2023 11:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231186612?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Extending the Simple View of Reading in Second and Foreign Language Learning: A Meta-Analytic Structural Equation Modeling Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study used a meta-analytic structural equation modeling approach to build extended versions of the simple view of reading (SVR) model in second and foreign language (SFL) learning contexts (i.e., SVR-SFL). Based on the correlation coefficients derived from primary studies, we replicated and integrated two previous extended meta-analytic SVR models, that is, Quinn and Wagner’s (2018) model with an English-speaking population with a cognitive factor and Peng et al.’s (2021) model with Chinese-speaking readers with metalinguistic skills. A total of 180 independent samples (N = 36,235) obtained from 152 empirical studies in SFL contexts were included in our meta-analytic structural equation model. The results revealed that the collected data successfully replicated H. Lee et al.’s (2022) SVR model in SL contexts (SV2R) in terms of overall model fit and moderation effects; in addition, the results confirmed that the data fit well with the extended SVR-SFL models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-25-2023 06:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231186605?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Causal Stories and Problem Definitions: How Policymakers and Superintendents Frame School Turnaround</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This study uses framing theory and the concept of causal stories to examine beliefs about causes and solutions to improving chronically low-performing schools in response to Michigan’s school turnaround policy. Across cases, policymakers and district leaders assigned most responsibility to poor leadership, poverty, and chronic educator turnover as primary causes of problems leading to turnaround identification. These causal stories were most often framed as side effects of policy or practice rather than as intentional actions. However, a notable subset assigned blame more directly to intentional policy action (or inaction) that would help districts counteract the effects of concentrated poverty, such as weighted funding. In terms of solutions, most leaders believed that improved funding was necessary to strengthen and stabilize the workforce and meet the nonacademic needs of children—for instance, attending to the deleterious effects of poverty through wraparound services or efforts to address trauma.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-25-2023 06:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231186425?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of contextual knowledge in noticing students’ strategies in-the-moment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-25-2023 06:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2239418?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I can’t just keep talking about the men”: Black girl resistance in a history classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-25-2023 02:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2239715?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking Collective Reflection in Teacher Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Collective reflection, which has become a de rigueur activity in teacher training and professional development, is predicated upon Schön’s theory of reflective practice. This concept, according to which people learn to be reflective-in-action through reflection on practice, relates primarily to individual and one-on-one mentorship processes. The shift from individual to collective processes has gone largely unstudied and unproblematized. This study of collective teacher reflection in a professional development workshop calls prevailing assumptions into question by bringing an alternative lens, textual trajectories, to bear on this ubiquitous activity to better account for oft-ignored issues of context and identity. Using linguistic ethnographic methods, it traces textual trajectories of key ideas indexed in a collective reflection event. Key findings include the nonlinearity of the reflective process and the centrality of identity-work in collective teacher reflection. This study thus reveals functions of this ritual that belie its ostensible purposes and suggest a rethinking of this practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-24-2023 08:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231188702?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Plantation “All Charter” Model and the Long Durée of Resistance for Black Public High Schools in New Orleans</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Education research has often overlooked how the long durée of resistance for Black education has shaped current educational policy. We complicate notions of Black public school closures in two case studies from extensive ethnographic research in post-Katrina New Orleans through our reading of the plantation. Findings suggest these institutions have served as linchpins for the transferal of the blues. Data analysis also indicates that traditional public school closures have functioned as a plantation management device. We encourage future inquiries into portfolio governance models, school “choice,” and school closures to consider the plantation complex and to recognize that post-Katrina education reforms were not isolated policy enactments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-24-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231182751?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bayesian Change-Point Analysis Approach to Detecting Aberrant Test-Taking Behavior Using Response Times</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/48/4&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 490-520, August 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Change-point analysis (CPA) is a method for detecting abrupt changes in parameter(s) underlying a sequence of random variables. It has been applied to detect examinees’ aberrant test-taking behavior by identifying abrupt test performance change. Previous studies utilized maximum likelihood estimations of ability parameters, focusing on detecting one change point for each examinee. This article proposes a Bayesian CPA procedure using response times (RTs) to detect abrupt changes in examinee speed, which may be related to aberrant responding behaviors. The lognormal RT model is used to derive a procedure for detecting aberrant RT patterns. The method takes the numbers and locations of the change points as parameters in the model to detect multiple change points or multiple aberrant behaviors. Given the change points, the corresponding speed of each segment in the test can be estimated, which enables more accurate inferences about aberrant behaviors. Simulation study results indicate that the proposed procedure can effectively detect simulated aberrant behaviors and estimate change points accurately. The method is applied to data from a high-stakes computerized adaptive test, where its applicability is demonstrated.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-24-2023 01:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231151961?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Improved Inferential Procedure to Evaluate Item Discriminations in a Conditional Maximum Likelihood Framework</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A modified and improved inductive inferential approach to evaluate item discriminations in a conditional maximum likelihood and Rasch modeling framework is suggested. The new approach involves the derivation of four hypothesis tests. It implies a linear restriction of the assumed set of probability distributions in the classical approach that represents scenarios of different item discriminations in a straightforward and efficient manner. Its improvement is discussed, compared to classical procedures (tests and information criteria), and illustrated in Monte Carlo experiments as well as real data examples from educational research. The results show an improvement of power of the modified tests of up to 0.3.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-20-2023 05:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231183335?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Latent Trait Item Response Models for Continuous Responses</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A general framework of latent trait item response models for continuous responses is given. In contrast to classical test theory (CTT) models, which traditionally distinguish between true scores and error scores, the responses are clearly linked to latent traits. It is shown that CTT models can be derived as special cases, but the model class is much wider. It provides, in particular, appropriate modeling of responses that are restricted in some way, for example, if responses are positive or are restricted to an interval. Restrictions of this sort are easily incorporated in the modeling framework. Restriction to an interval is typically ignored in common models yielding inappropriate models, for example, when modeling Likert-type data. The model also extends common response time models, which can be treated as special cases. The properties of the model class are derived and the role of the total score is investigated, which leads to a modified total score. Several applications illustrate the use of the model including an example, in which covariates that may modify the response are taken into account.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-20-2023 05:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231184147?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Over-Tourism to Under-Tourism via COVID-19: Lessons for Sustainable Tourism Management</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;With various strains of the novel coronavirus emerging during the last few years, there is a need to reinvent and manage the tourism industry by engaging various stakeholders. Industry and policymakers need to observe the shift and curate tourism-related products and offerings accordingly. In light of the increasing demand for innovations and future directions in the post-COVID-19 period, this article conducts a bibliometric analysis for sustainable tourism studies spanning the years 1990–2021. This paper presents an integrative review of tourism, environment and sustainable tourism to reveal geographical, contextual, and methodological directions for future research. The comprehensive analysis includes contributions on topics and methods, country collaborations, and thematic analysis. The findings are consistent with the Sustainable Development Goals of sustainable production and consumption (SDG-12), with a particular emphasis on sustainable tourism to promote local culture and create jobs (SDG-12.b) and on sustainable growth (SDG-13). The study’s findings can be used to inform future policies and directions; for example, the findings indicate that the hospitality industry is facing challenges that necessitate new regulations to address its socioeconomic and environmental impacts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-20-2023 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231189805?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strengthening mathematical orientation: how university mathematics courses can gain relevance for pre-service teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of the article is to discuss how university mathematics courses can become more relevant for pre-service teachers (PSTs). We therefore introduce a concept we call mathematical orientation and develop an analytical framework based on Felix Klein’s pervasive approach to elementary mathematics from a higher standpoint and the work of the practical philosopher Stegmaier on orientation. This framework is used to analyze the mathematical orientation of PSTs on two mathematics courses in Norway and Switzerland. In a qualitative empirical approach, we analyzed 85 reflections written by PSTs on the topic of decimal expansions and reconstructed aspects of their individual mathematical orientation. Our results show that mathematical orientation varies across PSTs to a certain extent. In particular, different points of reference, perspectives, standpoints, and types of links between the mathematical content and teaching situations could be identified. We therefore propose that mathematical orientation can be considered a key variable in addressing the mathematical needs of PSTs in university courses.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2023 16:28</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01492-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Puzzle identification in action research in initial teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2023 09:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2238003?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Evidence Clearinghouses Can Avoid the Winner’s Curse</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2023 07:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2194298?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Nudging Mentors Weaken Student Support? Experimental Evidence from a Virtual Communication Intervention</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2023 07:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2186291?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Chain as Strong as Its Strongest Link? Understanding the Causes and Consequences of Biases Arising from Selective Analysis and Reporting of Research Results</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-18-2023 05:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2219673?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
