<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>“The PTA intimidates”: racially segregated parent organizations in a dual immersion school</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2023 06:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2192915?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Corrigendum to “School Inclusion of Refugee Students: Recent Trends From International Data”</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2023 03:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231166441?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Talking the technology talk</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 42-46, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The school lives of students and educators have long been affected by technological changes, but the advent of digital technologies, from smartphones to social media, have amplified the effects on their daily lives. Unfortunately, school curricula rarely focus on critically examining our relationships with technologies. Daniel G. Krutka, Jacob Pleasants, and T. Philip Nichols offer a framework called the technology education iceberg to help educators plan and reflect on how they teach about technology. They argue that the science, social studies, and English subject areas offer opportunities to encourage a technoskeptical stance in students and educators that is needed for flourishing lives and democratic societies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168262?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Five key questions educators ask about SEL</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 47-53, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Schools have become increasingly interested in social-emotional learning (SEL) over the past decade, and that interest has grown due to concern about student well-being resulting from the COVID-19 pandemic. However, there is confusion around SEL. Christi Bergin, Christina Cipriano, Tia Barnes, Shannon B. Wanless, researchers who have studied and designed SEL for decades, respond to questions frequently asked by educators as they consider an SEL approach for their school. They discuss what SEL is, its benefits, how it aligns with other programs, how to select an SEL program, and where to learn more about SEL programs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168263?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preventing online radicalization and extremism in boys: A conversation with Pasha Dashtgard</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 30-35, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Online extremism is on the rise, with boys and young men being targeted by misogynistic social media influencers like Andrew Tate. When boys repeat comments they’ve heard online in the classroom, educators can play a role in preventing students from being further influenced by online extremism. Pasha Dashtgard, the director of research at American University’s Polarization &amp;amp; Extremism Research &amp;amp; Innovation Lab (PERIL), talks to Phi Delta Kappan about the importance of prevention, the harms of toxic masculinity, and the crucial role of teachers and other educators.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168260?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking school time</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 36-41, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Efforts to improve education outcomes often involve lengthening the school day or the school year in hopes that spending more time in school will boost student learning. Yet, as Frederick Hess explains, U.S. students spend as much or more total time in school as their peers in other industrialized nations. What matters more than the amount of time is how that time is used. Although research into time usage at school is limited, existing studies have shown that much time spent in school time does not involve actual learning time, either because of interruptions or other non-learning activities or because students are not engaged. Hess suggests that, before adding time to the school day or year, it’s important to understand what schools are doing with their time, rethink their routines, and seek to ensure that they are using time wisely and well.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168261?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Public education is the great perpetuator</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 54-57, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Despite being regarded as the great equalizer, public education’s close ties with the market economy have made it the great perpetuator. High school teacher Jonathan Lancaster writes that public education has become a structure in which students become career ready, as opposed to world ready. Therefore, educators should shift the narrative away from the how of education, and more toward the why of education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168264?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On Leadership: What should students learn?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Despite significant societal changes, the high school experience hasn’t changed much in recent decades. Joshua P. Starr reflects on his own high school experiences and that of his son and considers how schools might change their focus away from requiring students to learn specific facts and toward having them develop skills as they engage in rich content that interests them and their teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168265?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: Policy questions for ChatGPT and artificial intelligence</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-61, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Columnist Jonathan E. Collins interviews his colleague, Professor Suresh Venkatasubramanian, a professor of data science and computer science at Brown University. He is one of the leading experts on the development of guardrails for engaging with automated programs safely. The two discuss how artificial intelligence and ChatGPT could affect education and how school leaders may react to the new tools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168266?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under The Law: Boys, men, and Title IX</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 62-63, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Title IX, the federal law that protects against sex discrimination in schools, is frequently considered a law to protect women from bias, harassment, and assault. However, in recent years, it has also been used to protect the rights of LGBTQ+ students and of men. Robert Kim describes how male victims of harassment have been able to seek justice under Title IX. At the same time, men accused of harassment have turned to the law when they believe that anti-male bias drove the decisions to punish them.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168268?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: Math teacher wants to help risk-averse male students</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 64-65, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Phyllis Fagell advises teachers and a principal who are dealing with their students’ and their own anxiety. A middle school math teacher is finding that more boys than girls in her class are risk-averse when it comes to math. A high school teacher has noticed that a lot of her students are getting sick and missing class when there’s a test. And a principal who’s made some hard calls and gotten blowback wonders if he’s in the right job.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168269?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection - Heritage News</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 70-71, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The Educators Rising conference will give future teachers an opportunity to demonstrate their skills and learn from peers and professionals. Katelen Bennett is the 2022-23 Educators Rising National Student Vice President of Communications. Tiana Jackson is the recipient of the Dr. J. Arnold Webb Endowed Scholarship for 2022. Amy Weems is spotlighted for her support of Educators Rising.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168274?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: Modeling a positive future for all genders</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Young people of all genders need role models from their community to help them see a path ahead. But many boys lack these kinds of positive role models in school. Teresa Preston, Kappan’s editor-in-chief, previews the April 2023 Kappan on “Educating Boys.” The articles in the issue describe the importance of role models for boys of color, for boys who might excel in the humanities, and for boys who are vulnerable to the influence of online misogynists and provocateurs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168254?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: How can schools support boys?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 68-68, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Educators Rising students share how schools could provide more support to boys.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168272?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 69-69, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Frederick M Hess recommends the book So Much Reform, So Little Change: The Persistence of Failure in Urban Schools by Charles M. Payne. Darius O. Johnson recommends Teaching on Days After: Educating for Equity in the Wake of Injustice by Alyssa Dunn.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168273?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Artistic License: Celebrating the talents of students and educators</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 72-72, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Student Katherine Tombaugh’s watercolor painting depicts sailboats on a bay. Teacher Babs Wheelden’s photograph shows a sunrise reflected in the water
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168275?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The need for Black male mentors</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 25-29, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The academic achievement of Black boys in the U.S. has been declining, and Black male mentorship can positively change these outcomes. Schools have tried many interventions to help Black boys receive the academic, social, and emotional support they need to close the performance gap. Some case studies have proven that Black male mentorship works. Bobby J. Rodgers Jr. and Devery J. Rodgers examine Black male student academic performance and propose Black male mentoring as a solution that offers promise in closing the performance gap.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168259?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Backtalk: Why not be flexible in assessments?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 66-67, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Tests and exams are a source of stress for many students. High school teacher Jacob Wells has found that he can alleviate some of that stress by allowing students to weigh in on when their assessments are scheduled. He describes why this has been helpful and shares some of the parameters that have made it feasible.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168271?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming schools and improving outcomes for boys of color</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 6-11, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Since the early 1980s, young women have outpaced men in educational outcomes. The gender gap is even more pronounced among Black and Latinx students. Moreover, these academic gaps have widened since the pandemic. Based on a five-year study of a district-wide initiative designed to improve academic outcomes for Black and Latino males, Adriana Villavicencio lays out a three-pronged approach to supporting the socioemotional well-being and academic success of young men of color through 1) culturally relevant classrooms, 2) improved school relationships, and 3) robust academic and college preparation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168256?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Boys and the humanities: Making the twain meet</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 12-17, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Misalignment between the mandates and structures of formal schooling and the developmental needs of boys, particularly in the humanities, is receiving increased levels of public and scholarly attention. The problems may be especially acute for low-income and minoritized children. But little guidance for identifying and implementing best and promising practices is available for educators. Tim Spitsberg and Jonathan A. Plucker outline recent work on this problem and identify some promising state- and local-level strategies for beginning the hard work of improving humanities learning for boys. They advocate pairing common-sense policy and curricular changes (improved data-sharing, curricular reviews for gender bias) with research-supported interventions (personalization, pathways programs into humanities-based learning and professions). When implemented with care, these strategies could improve the education of all students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168257?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Resisting racism in school</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/7&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 18-24, April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Darius O. Johnson, Briana Markoff, and Dorinda J. Carter Andrews examined data from focus groups conducted with more than 60 Black boys in midwestern high schools to learn how teachers and schools can refuse antiblackness and reimagine futures for Black boys in school. Black boys and young men want safe school environments and will create safe communal spaces when needed. They seek teachers who are culturally relevant; they want to be able to trust their teachers; and they want to be their full, authentic selves at school. Findings show how educators can work within antiblack institutions toward reducing in-school suffering while working to create better futures for Black boys in school.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231168258?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meta-Reflexivity and Teacher Professionalism: Facilitating Multiparadigmatic Teacher Education to Achieve a Future-Proof Profession</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The present work discusses the relevance of meta-reflexivity, both for the professionalization of the teaching profession and for teacher education. Meta-reflexivity is based on the multiparadigmatic system of teacher education, which finds itself grounded in diverse scientific disciplines. The approach takes uncertainty as an essential element characterizing the act of teaching. Inherent rationales of specific theories and empirical findings are made explicit, thus creating a referential framework for situation-specific interpretations and professional action. Based on a theoretical reconstruction, we propose meta-reflexivity as an essential element of pedagogic practice and, consequently, teacher professionalism. Such professionalism is characterized by teachers being able to undertake exemplary-typifying interpretations of situations, based on a deep understanding of multiple approaches. While assessing specific situations in school, a teacher can refer to these interpretations. Possible principles of a meta-reflexive teacher education are proposed that can potentially enrich the practice of teacher education for a future-proof profession.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 06:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231162295?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/45/2&quot;&gt;Volume 45, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Summer 2023, Page 87-89&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 01:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2191578?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Deepening a conceptual framework in travelling between languages and cultures: the case of the documentational approach to didactics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Translation is a critical issue in international mathematics education studies but has seldom been carefully investigated. How can a theoretical approach be translated and subsequently used in different languages, and to what extent could the translation processes deepen the approach itself? This paper addresses such issues in the case of the Documentational Approach to Didactics (DAD). We explore possibilities of translating selected critical notions expressed in English terms into French, Arabic and Chinese, and developing insights from these possibilities. We further deal with the translation issues ‘in situ’, i.e. in an English mathematics teacher’s lesson where we can identify the embodiments of the DAD concepts. The most challenging part in the translation is the embedding of the English terms in the English cultural sphere, and ‘re-bedding’ them into another cultural sphere. It is claimed that examining the nuances between the different possibilities of translation for the same concept, in connection with their use ‘in situ’, and drawing inspiration from the educational, cultural and theoretical traditions in other cultural spheres, can help to deepen the theoretical constructs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01471-w</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
