<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Robot-Assisted Language Learning: A Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This meta-analysis included 27 empirical studies to explore the effectiveness of robot-assisted language learning (RALL) as well as the moderating effects of a number of variables. The comparison of 64 effect sizes from 2,637 participants indicated significant variability between the independent samples. The overall results showed that the combined linguistic and affective gain of RALL was significant. The results of moderator analysis showed that most moderators, including place of the study, type of robot, publication type, instructional level of the learners, design of the study, time points of assessment, learning setting, second language (L2) proficiency level, type of assessment, language domain, and the non-RALL condition had no significant effects on learning outcomes. However, the moderating effect of the participants’ age was significant as RALL was found to be more effective for elementary school students (7–12 years old). The findings provide insights into the design of effective robots for second language acquisition (SLA) that support learners with certain characteristics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-02-2024 05:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241247227?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Energizing a Sustainability Inquiry</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 326-335
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p326.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Lunar Phases With the Moon Pie ­Simulation</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 336-345
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p336.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modeling the Impact of the Chernobyl Disaster</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 346-352
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p346.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Make Your Number Talks More Ambitious</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 353-360
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p353.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Centering Empathy in a Mathematics Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 361-370
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p361.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Wind Racer Revisited</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 371-377
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p371.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics and ­Science: A ­Collaboration</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 322-323
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p322.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Problems to Ponder</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 378-382
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p378.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GPS: Using Games to ­Explore Composing and Decomposing</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 384-387
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p384.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learn to Like Your ­Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 388-390
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p388.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Kenta, Kilts, and ­Kimonos: Exploring ­Cultures and Mathematics through Fabrics”</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 392-399
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p392.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond Gauss Sum in “Proof by Tomatoes”</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 400-400
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p400.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Centering Students’ Voices and Identities</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: e1-e1
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-pe1.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Validity Evidence for an Observational Fidelity Measure to Inform Scale-Up of Evidence-Based Interventions</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;As evidence-based interventions are scaled, fidelity of implementation, and thus effectiveness, often wanes. Validated fidelity measures can improve researchers’ ability to attribute outcomes to the intervention and help practitioners feel more confident in implementing the intervention as intended. We aim to provide a model for the validation of fidelity observation protocols to guide future research studying evidence-based interventions scaled-up under real-world conditions. We describe a process to build evidence of validity for items within the Session Review Form, an observational tool measuring fidelity to interactive drug prevention programs such as the Botvin LifeSkills Training program. Following Kane’s (2006) assumptions framework requiring that validity evidence be built across four areas (scoring, generalizability, extrapolation, and decision), confirmatory factor analysis supported the hypothesized two-factor structure measuring quality of delivery (seven items assessing how well the material is implemented) and participant responsiveness (three items evaluating how well the intervention is received), and measurement invariance tests suggested the structure held across grade level and schools serving different student populations. These findings provide some evidence supporting the extrapolation assumption, though additional research is warranted since a more complete overall depiction of the validity argument is needed to evaluate fidelity measures.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-30-2024 12:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241248864?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Equity Intersections: Teachers’ Experiences with Student Wellness Support During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers often address student wellness concerns such as health and mental health. Yet, this work goes largely unacknowledged and unsupported by professional preparation. COVID-19 intensified these concerns amid disrupted systems of student support and increased student distress. Our national survey (N = 1398) pursued the powerful opportunity present during the pandemic to understand the extent and distribution of demands on teachers to address student wellness and the support they receive for such work. We found that the demand for teachers’ wellness work was inequitably distributed across teachers, varying largely by their schools’ sociodemographic characteristics. Additionally, access to support for this work did not align with demand levels. We discuss these findings’ implications for teacher preparation, support, and workload equity.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-30-2024 10:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241245385?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: Common spaces matter: curricular experiences through mathematics with young prisoners and prospective teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-30-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01582-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ professional development for inclusion of experimental mathematics and interactive resources in the classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Information technology enhances the nature of mathematics as an empirical discipline, leading to an approach called “experimental mathematics” (EM). It fosters the use of technology-based interactive resources (IRs) in mathematics education, giving mathematics an experimental dimension and reflecting a tension between the empirical-inductive nature of IRs and formal mathematics (FM). Our qualitative research focused on professional development (PD) for IR-based teaching of EM intertwined with FM based on a threefold theoretical framework that combines the mathematical knowledge required by EM, the pedagogical functionality of IRs, and instrumental orchestration. The research analyzed 14 high school teachers’ documents generated in the course of a PD program, revealing the evolution of their orientation. We argue that teachers’ evolving orientation toward IR-based EM inclusion in school mathematics is the result of meticulous dynamic PD design implementing three key aspects framed by the threefold theoretical framework: teachers playing various roles during the PD, teacher-researcher collaboration, and theoretical support. The beginning of the evolution of the teachers’ orientation toward IR-based EM inclusion in school mathematics was made possible by a design grounded in the above theoretical framework and observed through its lens.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-30-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01581-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Problem solving in mathematics education: tracing its foundations and current research-practice trends</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In tracing recent research trends and directions in mathematical problem-solving, it is argued that advances in mathematics practices occur and take place around two intertwined activities, mathematics problem formulation and ways to approach and solve those problems. In this context, a problematizing principle emerges as central activity to organize mathematics curriculum proposals and ways to structure problem-solving learning environments. Subjects’ use of concrete, abstract, symbolic, or digital tools not only influences the ways to pose and pursue mathematical problems; but also shapes the type of representation, exploration, and reasoning they engage to work and solve problems. Problem-solving foundations that privilege learners’ development of habits of mathematical practices that involve an inquiry method to formulate conjectures, to look for different ways to represent and approach problems, and to support and communicate results shed light on directions of current research trends and the relevance of rethinking curriculum proposals and extending problem-solving environments in terms of teachers/students’ consistent use of digital tools and online developments.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-30-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01578-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Differential Prediction for Disadvantaged Students and Schools: The Role of High School Characteristics</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Validity studies of college admissions tests have found that, on average, students who are Black or Hispanic earn lower freshman grade-point averages (FGPAs) than predicted by these test scores. This differential prediction is used as a measure of bias. These studies, however, conflate student and school characteristics. The differential prediction affecting minoritized groups may arise in part because they attended high schools in which college enrollees, regardless of race, perform worse than predicted. Using data on students who graduated from New York City public high schools in 2011 and enrolled in the City University of New York, we examined this using college admissions and high school test scores. There was no differential prediction based on race/ethnicity among students within high schools when school characteristics were accounted for. Instead, overprediction of FGPA was associated with the school proportion of enrolled Black and Hispanic students. Overprediction was larger in models with high school test scores.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 12:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241245088?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Towards a Critical Framework of Social Media Literacy: A Systematic Literature Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The role of social media in the global society and economy has increased substantially over the years across different populations, age groups, and contexts. Using social media can be both beneficial and risky. People’s ability to navigate it safely and effectively largely depends on their social media literacy skills, which has significant implications for individuals and society. Drawing on the critical literacy and affordances-in-practice frameworks, we explore the concept of critical social media literacy (CSML) through a systematic literature review to determine whether and how its components—users’ goals, use context, inquiry, reflection, and action—have been addressed in the literature. Twenty out of the 50 publications identified reflected all the components of the CSML framework at different levels. We focused on empirical studies to identify instructional approaches and recommendations to support the development of CSML skills. Implications for research and practice, including curriculum connections, are also discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 12:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241247224?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Computing Education Interventions to Increase Gender Equity from 2000 to 2020: A Systematic Literature Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although gender parity has been achieved in some STEM fields, gender disparities persist in computing, one of the fastest-growing and highest-earning career fields. In this systematic literature review, we expand upon academic momentum theory to categorize computing interventions intended to make computing environments more inclusive to girls and women and consider how those characteristics vary by the success of the intervention. Particular attention is given to the efficacy of broadening participation and success for women in computer science, information technology, and related fields. After scrutinizing 168 relevant studies, 48 met the inclusion criteria and were included. We introduce a framework for gender equity in computing, expanding on existing research on academic and STEM momentum to encompass new domains representing social and structural momentum. Our analysis reveals the complex roles of intervention domains, strategies, goals, levels, and duration in shaping their efficacy. Implications for theory, research, and practice are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 11:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241241536?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: Leadership takes practice</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt; Kappan editor-in-chief Teresa Preston presents an overview of the May issue on student leadership.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251872?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: Policy, not politics</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 62-63, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The 2024 presidential election features a rematch from four years ago: President Biden and former President Trump. While all presidential elections matter, columnist Jonathan E. Collins argues that this election is especially pivotal to K-12 education policy. Collins poses major education policy questions that we should be asking heading into the upcoming election.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251891?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
