<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meta-Analyses and Narrative Review of Home-Based Interventions to Improve Literacy and Mathematics Outcomes for Children Between the Ages of 3 and 5 Years Old</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The purpose of these meta-analyses was to examine the effectiveness of home-based interventions aimed at improving literacy and mathematics outcomes for preschool-age children (mean age = 4.29 years; range = 3.07–5.32 years) and to develop an understanding of what home-based interventions work in different contexts. A total of 32 studies met the inclusion criteria for these meta-analyses; 30 studies included sufficient data for inclusion in the meta-analyses, and two studies did not contain sufficient quantitative data and instead were summarized in a narrative review. The average weighted effect size for interventions with literacy (d = 0.10; CI = [−0.17, 0.38]; n = 27) and mathematical outcomes (d = 0.18; CI = [−1.62, 1.99]; n = 8) were minimal. Hence, these meta-analyses showed that home-based interventions had minimal effect on literacy and mathematical outcomes for preschoolers. There were more home-based interventions with literacy (N = 28) than mathematical outcomes (N = 10). The heterogeneity showed no variability, indicating that all intervention impacted on children’s outcomes to similar effect. Overall, many interventions were relatively light touch (i.e., time spent engaging in parent training), and the engagement requirement of the parent in some studies was minimal (e.g., reading a short text message). More in-depth research into the components of interventions (e.g., focus, training approaches) and evaluation of interventions before they are implemented is essential for ensuring that early interventions will be effective and lead to the development of the intended skills.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2023 04:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231212491?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An investigation into the approach of mathematics undergraduates to a non-routine task</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2023 03:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2277459?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: developing algebraic activity through conjecturing about relationships</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01515-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of digital technologies in mathematics education: purposes and perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Over the last decades, digital technologies (DTs) have become ubiquitous in mathematics education. Still, their integration into classroom teaching and learning varies enormously. In this narrative overview, we focus on the different purposes for which DTs are used in mathematics education in order to study how the effectiveness of DTs depends on researchers’ underlying goals and perspectives. We set up an experience- and literature-based framework including five different purposes. Applying this framework gave rise to the following results: (1) there is evidence for the benefit of using DTs for mathematics learning; (2) research on DTs leads to new theoretical developments and (3) to new design paradigms; (4) issues of equity with respect to access to and use of DTs are important but under-researched; and (5) DTs challenge curricula and teaching and assessment practices. While early research on the use of DTs focused on questions such as “does it work?” or “does it work better?”, the maturing of the field has shifted to more nuanced questions. As a future research agenda, we recommend further study of how the use of DTs in mathematics education impacts the time required for learning as well as the temporality of teaching and learning, how it changes the nature of doing mathematics and the relation to basic skills and higher-order skills in particular, how curricula, teaching practices, and assessment might change due to the availability of sophisticated mathematical tools, how DTs and other resources might be combined in teaching and learning, and how they may help to address equity issues in education. These questions will prompt the development of new theoretical constructs and approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01535-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effective School District Policies and Practices: Synthesizing Theoretical Frameworks and Empirical Findings across Disciplines</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-20-2023 08:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2269923?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Performance Evaluation of Urban Emergency Governance: Conceptual Connotations and Empirical Research Based on the Crisis Life Cycle Theory</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although scholars have discussed in depth about the evaluation content and the construction of evaluation index system of emergency management and crisis management, a unified and standardized interpretation of system construction concepts and empirical research on the performance evaluation of urban emergency management is still lacking. In view of this, this paper is based on the theory of the  crisis life cycle, with the four phases of urban emergency management and the content of the task as a clue, constructed a performance evaluation index system containing 12 primary indicators and 44 secondary indicators, and centered on the emergency management work situation of S city. The study reveals that emergency management underperforms in S city, with a score of 5.948, qualifying as the “defined level”. The “prevention and preparedness stage” receives poor evaluation, indicating a significant bias for crisis response instead of prevention. The report suggests the improvement of emergency material stockpile planning, the formation of grassroots emergency response teams, the emergency management publicity, and special emergency drill plans, etc., with a view to providing reference for city managers to comprehensively review and evaluate the emergency management system, and to promote the construction of a more systematic, complete and scientific urban emergency management system.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-20-2023 01:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231215208?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2023 05:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2281118?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/epaa/45/4&quot;&gt;Volume 45, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 696-701, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231213600?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Recent developments in using digital technology in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper we review selected significant developments in the use of digital technology in the teaching and learning of mathematics over the last five years. We focus on a number of important topics in this field, including the evolvement of STEAM and critical making as well as the process of redefining learning spaces in the transformation of the mathematics classroom. We also address the increasing use of computer algebra systems and dynamic geometry packages; and the issue of student collaboration online, especially using learning environments and social media. We briefly touch on artificial intelligence systems, including hyper-personalisation of learning, multimodality and videos. We include a brief discussion on the impact of COVID-19 on mathematics education, and lastly on the more theoretical perspective of the epistemology of digital technology and the construct of humans-with-media. We conclude the discussion with some possible concerns and mentioning some possible new topics for research in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01530-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Corrigendum to Power Approximations for Overall Average Effects in Meta-Analysis With Dependent Effect Sizes</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2023 12:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231207878?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>ARJ special issue: The inner journey and mindset shifts of transformation</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2023 10:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231215405?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2023 09:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2281117?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2023 09:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2281119?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reflecting on metaphors and the possibilities of ‘language change’ in teaching and teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2023 02:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2282372?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“It’s like there is a veil placed over racial issues”: AfroBrazilians’ educational experiences negotiating transnational racialization and the pedagogy of mestizaje of the Americas</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2023 02:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2279304?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Need for Educational Research Engagement With Courts, Public Policy, and Practice in a Post-Dobbs Era</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization (2022), the U.S. Supreme Court overturned decades of precedent regarding the federal right to an abortion for people who can carry pregnancies. This case has substantial significance for the education field, directly affecting school- and college-age marginalized students who can carry pregnancies. In this essay, I argue that Dobbs and subsequent policies have created a significant need for educational research to inform courts, public policy, and practice to improve social and educational structural support for marginalized students who can carry pregnancies in a post-Dobbs era. This need is because Dobbs and subsequent policies have significantly diminished reproductive justice, and reproductive justice is intricately tied to marginalized students’ ability to fully engage in their education. Timely educational research is critical to address the systemic inequities that Dobbs and related policies have exacerbated and reified.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2023 10:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231209969?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Continuous Improvement, Institutional Review Boards, and Resistance to Practitioner Scholarship</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this essay, we explore the tension between research using continuous improvement (CI) paradigms, such as improvement science, and conventional research, and the role and regulation of Institutional Review Board (IRB) oversight. We argue that the current regulatory structure privileges traditional research and hinders collaborative inquiry that centers the voice and agency of those traditionally marginalized. We also question whether IRBs should limit CI efforts required of educational leaders as part of their jobs. We offer recommendations for how IRBs and scholar-practitioners can together support CI efforts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2023 10:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231208413?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A multidimensional approach to the study of school climate and student engagement</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2023 10:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2278771?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring student teachers’ aesthetic learning processes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2023 05:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2278802?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/48/6&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 942-944, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2023 04:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231214154?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BSRLM day conference proceedings</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/rrme20/25/3&quot;&gt;Volume 25, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, December 2023, Page 414-418&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2023 04:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2260356?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On understanding mathematical problem-posing processes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Problem posing engages students in generating new problems based on given situations (including mathematical expressions or diagrams) or changing (i.e., reformulating) existing problems. Problem posing has been at the forefront of discussion over the past few decades. One of the important topics studied is the process of problem posing as experienced by students and teachers. This paper focuses on problem-posing processes and models thereof. We first provide an overview of previous research and then present the results of a scoping review regarding recent research on problem-posing processes. This review covers 75 papers published between 2017 and 2022 in top mathematics education research journals. We found that some of the prior research directly attempted to examine problem-posing processes, whereas others examined task variables related to problem-posing processes. We conclude this paper by proposing a model for problem-posing processes that encompasses four phases: orientation, connection, generation, and reflection. We also provide descriptions of the four phases of the model. The paper ends with suggestions for future research related to problem-posing processes in general and the problem-posing model proposed in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01536-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Real and illusionary difficulties in conceptual learning in mathematics: comparison between constructivist and inferentialist perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Due to the learning paradox, students cannot have real difficulty in understanding a mathematical concept that they have not yet understood. There is a gap between real difficulties, directly experienced by students, and illusionary ones, only observed by researchers. This paper aims to offer a critical reflection on our understanding of the term &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;difficulty&lt;/em&gt; in mathematics education research. We start this paper by arguing that a constructivist perspective, which has often been adopted in researches on mathematical task design, can deal with difficulties in solving a mathematical problem, but it cannot theoretically deal with those in understanding a mathematical concept. Therefore, we need the alternative philosophy of Robert Brandom’s inferentialism to capture students’ real difficulties in conceptual learning. From an inferentialist perspective, we introduce the idea of illusionary and real difficulties. The former is defined as what students cannot do, but they are not conscious of what they should do, while the latter is defined as what students cannot do despite their consciousness of what they should do. Through an eighth grade classroom episode, we argue that it is important in mathematics education research to focus not only on illusionary difficulties but also on the transition from illusionary to real difficulties. Researchers are encouraged to design a learning environment in which students become conscious of what they cannot do and to observe their mathematics learning in such an environment.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-15-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00478-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Tribute to Anna Sierpińska</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-15-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00231-1</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
