<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Humanizing mathematics education: quantitative and arithmetic argumentation of indigenous cultural practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Dehumanized and globalized mathematics education in the last centuries has led to established learning processes disconnected from indigenous knowledge. The effect of cognitive imperialism, given the systematic negation of the language and the culture, has as a disastrous consequence of the gradual and systematic loss of knowledge and indigenous reasoning. Thus, recognizing, appreciating and updating it turns into a task and challenge for the teaching and learning of math in the intercultural classroom. Therefore, the purpose of this research is to focus on analyzing the mathematical reasoning of the indigenous student while encoding and decoding an historic numeric registry artifact called &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;püron&lt;/em&gt; (knot in the Mapuche language). The study was conducted in three schools on Mapuche territory of Araucanía Region in Chile, using the Participatory Action Research method. The results show that encoding/decoding quantities helps indigenous students to recognize structures and to establish a numeration system close to the historically reported cultural practices of the Mapuche people. Moreover, it extends the mathematical quantitative structure and reasoning to an arithmetic one seen in the present day cultural practices such as the measurement of fields for planting. Thus, the experience contributes to the students’ linguistic awareness of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mapudungun&lt;/em&gt; (Mapuche language) in a numeration system framework.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-24-2023 04:10</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01490-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When mathematics has spirit: Aki Chike Win</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper is an examination of the way mathematics, and STEM, arises through stories of teaching and learning on, with, and alongside &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Land&lt;/em&gt;. It emerges from research, undertaken in different Nations (Cree, Dene, Métis, Mi’kmaw, Naskapi, Canada), that considers what locally meaningful K-12 STEM teaching and learning might look like in Indigenous contexts. The paper reflects our research process. Each story is followed by a conversation that surfaces elements of how mathematics, language, learning, and different ways of knowing, being, and doing circulate together and emerge in relation to &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Land&lt;/em&gt; and all relations living within it. We frame the work in ethical relationality to open a space where Indigenous and Western knowledges might co-exist, attending to ongoing tensions in the work between ways of knowing, being, and doing of different people and peoples/nations, between perspectives and experiences of indigenous and non-indigenous participants, between languages, while still creating spaces where we might move closer together through iterative processes of collective learning. This exploration provides insight into how and when we might remember that mathematics has spirit, how quantity and pattern live in various contexts, when numbers might be inadequate for a context, and how all these ideas can meaningfully inform mathematics teaching and learning via relationships between language, mathematics and learners. We seek a mathematics that resists abstraction as extraction and instead lives and enspirits teaching and learning through relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-24-2023 04:10</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01482-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interscholastic Policy Debate Promotes Critical Thinking and College-Going: Evidence From Boston Public Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Few interventions reduce inequality in reading achievement, let alone higher-order thinking skills, among adolescents. We study policy debate—an extracurricular activity focused on improving middle and high schoolers’ critical thinking, argumentation, and policy analysis skills—in Boston schools serving large concentrations of economically disadvantaged students of color. Student fixed effects estimates show debate had positive impacts on English Language Arts (ELA) test scores of 0.13 SD, equivalent to 68% of a full year of average ninth-grade learning. Gains were concentrated on analytical more than rote subskills. We find no harm to math, attendance, or disciplinary records, and evidence of positive effects on high school graduation and postsecondary enrollment. Impacts were largest among students who were lowest achieving prior to joining debate.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2023 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231200234?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cost-Effectiveness of Algebraic Technological Applications</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2023 07:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2269918?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Teacher’s Role in Discourse and Social Regulation of Learning: Insights from Collaborative Sessions in High-School Physics Classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2023 04:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2266847?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Organizational Features of University-Based STEM Outreach Units in Canada</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Within Canada, the need for individuals with science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) skills has been well documented. One tactic towards increasing the number of individuals with STEM skills is to focus on the kindergarten to grade 12 (K-12) STEM education stakeholders, who can directly and/or indirectly influence a student’s STEM education trajectory. One of those stakeholders is K-12 STEM outreach units (SOUs). The purpose of this research was to contribute to the STEM education literature in Canada by identifying the landscape of university-based K-12 SOUs and exploring their organizational features (mission, target audience, stakeholders, initiatives, capacity, resources, and partnerships). This study used an explanatory two-phase approach involving quantitative and qualitative data collection and analysis. Phase 1 was an environmental scan of university-based SOUs websites. Phase 2 consisted of an online survey designed to further explore SOUs’ organizational features. The findings from this study suggest commonality in SOUs’ mission and intentionality towards engaging youth, including those underrepresented and underserviced in STEM fields such as Black youth, Indigenous youth, racialized youth, youth from low socio-economic communities, and girls. However, the findings indicate a large variability of other organizational features such as their size, operating budget, and the number of partnerships. Overall, the findings affirm that university-based SOUs have a role to play in the K-12 STEM learning ecosystem, helping students develop STEM knowledge and skills.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-22-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00289-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘Led by Intelligence&#39;: A Scoping Review on the Experimental Evaluation of Intelligence-Led Policing</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Intelligence-led policing (ILP) was introduced in the 1990s as a proactive approach to policing, but to date, there is a lack of studies that have synthesized and summarized the central characteristics and insights of (quasi-)experimental studies related to ILP. This study aims to address this gap by synthesizing and characterizing the central characteristics of 38 quasi-experimental and experimental studies related to ILP. In this study, a scoping review is conducted on different quasi-experimental and experimental studies that relate to the framework of ILP. It was found that most studies within the domain of ILP focus on testing the crime reduction effects of using spatio-temporal crime intelligence to deploy police resources more efficiently and effectively. However, some studies have combined different types of crime intelligence or used solely offender-related intelligence. Several statistical-methodological challenges were also identified that should be considered when designing experimental research within the domain of ILP. Additionally, most studies focused solely on measuring crime reduction, with few focusing on secondary effects of interventions. The review concludes that future evaluation studies should consider evaluating the use of different types of crime intelligence and establish specific, objective, and realistic criteria for measuring specific performance measures such as crime disruption. Future experimental research within the domain of ILP should consider applying the 3-i model, evaluating each leg of ILP thoroughly. The limitations of the study are also discussed. This review provides valuable insights for future research and development of ILP-related approaches.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2023 09:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231204588?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher noticing in mathematics education: a review of recent developments</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The teacher noticing construct is widely recognized in teacher competence and education research, particularly in the field of mathematics education. This paper surveys recent research on mathematics teacher noticing published between July 2019 and 2022, following an earlier literature review on teacher noticing across different disciplines. The study presented here analyzed 118 English-language articles published in peer-reviewed journals, focusing on conceptualizations, research methods, and relationships with other constructs, including teacher knowledge and beliefs. The findings suggest that the cognitive-psychological perspective on noticing, which emphasizes a set of cognitive processes, remains the predominant conceptualization. Recent research on noticing is characterized by a high proportion of studies based on small samples and qualitative research methods. While several studies have demonstrated the interrelatedness of noticing and professional knowledge, the relationship between noticing and beliefs and between noticing and instructional quality has rarely been addressed. Based on these findings, we highlight noteworthy contributions and critical shortcomings, and suggest directions for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01527-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The field of mathematics education research and its boundaries</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10270-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: One hundred years of mathematics education seen through the lens of ICMI. Fulvia Furinghetti &amp;amp; Livia Giacardi (Eds.) (2022). The International Commission on Mathematical Instruction, 1908–2008: People, Events, and Challenges in Mathematic</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10267-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impact of Technology-Aided Activity-Based Learning Approaches on Learning Outcomes: Experimental Evidence from Community Schools in Rural Zambia</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-20-2023 07:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2268072?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do mathematical thinking processes influence visual estimation skills in students?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-20-2023 06:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2269529?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptualising Bedouin teachers’ social-emotional learning in the context of teaching children with neurodevelopmental disorders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-20-2023 06:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2261385?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining students’ mathematical modeling competences in video-based modeling tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-20-2023 05:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2269533?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collaborating with industry to highlight the relevance of mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-19-2023 12:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2263843?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Classroom Concentration of English Learners and Their Reading Growth</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this brief, we use a nationally representative sample of ever-English learners (ELs; N = 783) to examine relations between EL concentration within classrooms and reading growth between kindergarten and Grade 5. Piecewise growth models were used to estimate relations for four developmental periods (K–1, Grades 1–2, Grades 2–3, and Grades 3–5). Results indicate nonsignificant, trivially sized relations for classroom EL concentration across periods, with and without controls for school concentration and student characteristics. Results were robust across multiple specifications. Findings call into doubt the academic benefits of the common practice of grouping ELs together in particular classrooms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-19-2023 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231203646?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exposure to Adversity and Trauma Among Students Who Experience School Discipline: A Scoping Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;While the disproportional application of school discipline has garnered notable attention, the relationship between trauma or adversity and school discipline is under examined. The purpose of the current scoping review was to map the state of the literature, empirical and theoretical, at the intersection of school discipline, and trauma or adversity. The findings identified a gap in our knowledge as only 14 of the 49 included articles detailed empirical studies focused on the relationship between adversity and school discipline, with very few from outside of the United States. However, this burgeoning body of knowledge points to a significant relationship between trauma/adversity and experiencing school discipline that warrants further study and contextualizes expanded adversities, including poverty and racism as adversity. We believe this is necessary to acknowledging the hidden and unaddressed trauma among students being disproportionally disciplined, leading to a greater understanding of student lives, and evidence-based, trauma-informed, and culturally attuned discipline.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2023 05:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231203674?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of EthnoSTEM-based mathematics modular instruction on Sama students’ mathematical thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2023 01:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2269536?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ties That Bind: An Examination of School-Family Relationships and Middle School Discipline in New York City</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Inequities in exclusionary discipline result from a complex process involving students, families, and school personnel. However, little research has explored the topic from parent perspectives. This study used parent survey data from New York City to investigate the link between school-family relationships and students experiencing exclusionary discipline. Results indicate that stronger parental trust toward teachers is connected to a reduced probability that a student receives an office discipline referral, while greater trust in principals is associated with a lower chance of suspension. Several aspects of school-family relationships, such as parent-principal trust, parental involvement, and school outreach and communication, heterogeneously predict a lower likelihood of experiencing exclusionary discipline by student race and special education status. These findings demonstrate the interdependent role of families and school staff in child development and highlight the need to cultivate positive school-family relationships as a potential strategy for addressing exclusionary discipline disparities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 11:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231203696?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“She didn’t mean it that way”: theorizing gendered Islamophobia in academia</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2268318?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Road Safety Efficiency on Interurban Roads in Spain</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The slowdown in economic development caused by traffic accidents in Spain, together with the disparity in the risk of death or injury due to traffic accidents in its provinces, makes it necessary to evaluate their road safety performance. Therefore, the objectives of the present research are, on the one hand, to find out the level of road safety efficiency of Spanish provinces in the period 2014–2018. On the other hand, it is also aimed to determine to what extent the annual efficiency change is originated by pure changes in efficiency or by technological changes. To achieve both objectives, the nonparametric technique of Data Envelopment Analysis and the Malmquist Index have been used based on the consideration of the Safety Performance Indicators (SPI) as the inputs of the process. The research findings show changes in the level of road safety efficiency in each of the years of the study period. Thus, it is possible to identify a geographical delimitation of the causes that generate changes in efficiency in recent years. A contraction in efficiency and technological progress is identified in part of the Spanish provinces in the north, northeast, and south of Spain.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 05:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231207443?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining Standards Across Five K-12 Academic Disciplines in the United States: Similarities, Distinctions, and Implications for Teacher Preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/45/4&quot;&gt;Volume 45, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Winter 2023, Page 355-372&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 02:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2247372?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/45/4&quot;&gt;Volume 45, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Winter 2023, Page 279-281&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 02:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2260290?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BSRLM day conference proceedings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 02:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2260356?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
