<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measuring the Mathematical Maturity of Students in an Academic Development Programme</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study focuses on students who are registered for the University of Pretoria’s academic development programme, the Four-year Programme (FYP). The programme was introduced as a gateway for students who are under-prepared but have the potential to succeed. This programme helps them to then continue their studies in mainstream science programmes. Our research focuses on measuring the change in the academic maturity of these students. In the theoretical framework that we developed, academic maturity is subdivided into two components, namely, non-subject based maturity, and subject based maturity (mathematical maturity). A mathematics test was also administered twice (at the beginning of the year and after the first semester) and was used to measure the subject based maturity of students. The results of the pre- and post-tests were compared to measure the improvement in students’ mathematical skills. The results showed that in all of the topics and constructs, there was an improvement in students’ mathematical abilities. The study also shows that students still struggle with the fundamentals of some mathematics topics, even after a semester of tuition in the FYP.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00222-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Children engaging with partitive quotient tasks: elucidating qualitative heterogeneity within the Image Having layer of the Pirie–Kieren model</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The paper presents findings from a study that examined, through the lens of the Image Having layer of the Pirie–Kieren model, the qualitative characteristics of the images that different children formed when engaging with eight, novel partitive quotient tasks. The Image Having layer is the first point of abstraction within the Pirie–Kieren model. Therefore, this research is significant in aiming to advance theoretical insight into how the notion of child-created images relates to the development of children’s mathematical understanding, in the context of novel for them tasks. This study adopted a qualitative, microgenetic research design and involved nine Year 5 (aged 9–10 years) children. Data based on children’s verbal responses and jottings were collected through multiple trials over eight individual sessions with each child. Analysis of 72 interview transcripts showed that children formed and used a range of different images that varied across tasks but also within the same task. This study provides a nuanced description of qualitative distinctions in the nature of child-created images. It thus reveals varied dimensions of a dynamic process of knowledge development and sense-making. This highlights, for educators, the need to be aware of and adaptive to the varied and dynamic dimensions of knowledge that children draw from, when dealing with novel tasks, and which change as children’s understanding of new mathematical content develops.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00461-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Extending an Identified Four-Parameter IRT Model: The Confirmatory Set-4PNO Model</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Given the frequent presence of slipping and guessing in item responses, models for the inclusion of their effects are highly important. Unfortunately, the most common model for their inclusion, the four-parameter item response theory model, potentially has severe deficiencies related to its possible unidentifiability. With this issue in mind, the dyad-four-parameter normal ogive (4PNO) model was developed. This model allows for slipping and guessing effects by including binary augmented variables—each indicated by two items whose probabilities are determined by slipping and guessing parameters—which are subsequently related to a continuous latent trait through a two-parameter model. Furthermore, the dyad-4PNO assumes uncertainty as to which items are paired on each augmented variable. In this way, the model is inherently exploratory. In the current article, the new model, called the set-4PNO model, is an extension of the dyad-4PNO in two ways. First, the new model allows for more than two items per augmented variable. Second, these item sets are assumed to be fixed, that is, the model is confirmatory. This article discusses this extension and introduces a Gibbs sampling algorithm to estimate the model. A Monte Carlo simulation study shows the efficacy of the algorithm at estimating the model parameters. A real data example shows that this extension may be viable in practice, with the data fitting a more general set-4PNO model (i.e., more than two items per augmented variable) better than the dyad-4PNO, 2PNO, 3PNO, and 4PNO models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2023 12:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231181587?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using cooperative learning strategy to increase undergraduate students’ engagement and performance</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2023 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2231512?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading with care: four mentor metaphors in collaboration between teachers and researchers in action research (Translated from the Swedish and revised by the authors)</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2023 06:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2229870?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Post-Pandemic Onset Public School Enrollment and Mobility: Evidence From Virginia</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Public school enrollment dramatically decreased during the pandemic, but the patterns of decline and student movement across schools are not yet well understood. Using statewide student-level data from Virginia, we find pre-K–12 enrollment dropped by 4% between fall 2019 and the first post-pandemic fall of 2020. The changes were the largest in pre-kindergarten and kindergarten and explained mostly by decreases in new enrollees, though exits also increased. K–12 enrollment declines were the largest among White and economically-advantaged students (but largest for Black and economically-disadvantaged pre-kindergartners). We also observe a decline in school transfers (both within and between districts), concentrated among Black and economically-disadvantaged students and students with disabilities. Findings have implications for equity, school funding, and student well-being.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231178299?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What motivates and demotivates Estonian mathematics teachers to continue teaching? The roles of self-efficacy, work satisfaction, and work experience</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Estonian students achieved high scores in the latest Programme for International Student Assessment surveys. At the same time, there needs to be more knowledge about the teachers guiding these students, as this could provide insights into effective teaching methods that can be replicated in other educational contexts. According to the Teaching and Learning International Survey, Estonian teachers&#39; average age is among the highest in the world, and the shortage of young, qualified mathematics teachers is well-documented. The present study aimed to map the motivating and demotivating factors for mathematics teachers to continue working in this profession. The effective sample comprised 164 Estonian mathematics teachers who responded to items regarding self-efficacy and job satisfaction and open-ended questions about motivating and demotivating factors regarding their work. The results showed that &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;students&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;salary and vacation&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;job environment &lt;/em&gt;are both motivating and demotivating for mathematics teachers. On the one hand, helping the students to succeed (and witnessing the progress), satisfying salaries and a good job climate motivate the teachers. And at the same time, students&#39; low motivation, poor salary, and straining work conditions (e.g., very high workload) serve as demotivating factors. We showed that mathematics teachers&#39; work experience is an essential factor to be considered when thinking about motivating and demotivating factors for teachers, as well as their self-efficacy and job satisfaction. The reasons, possible impact, and potential interventions on an educational policy level are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09587-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reading and Writing Relations Are Not Uniform: They Differ by the Linguistic Grain Size, Developmental Phase, and Measurement</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We conducted a meta-analysis to investigate reading-writing relations. Beyond the overall relation, we systematically investigated moderation of the relation as a function of linguistic grain size (word reading and spelling versus reading comprehension and written composition), measurement of reading comprehension (e.g., multiple choice, open-ended, cloze), and written composition (e.g., writing quality, writing productivity, writing fluency, writing syntax), and developmental phase of reading and writing (grade levels as a proxy). A total of 395 studies (k = 2,265, N = 120,669) met inclusion criteria. Overall, reading and writing were strongly related (r = .72). However, the relation differed depending on the subskills of reading and writing such that word reading and spelling were strongly related (r =.82) whereas reading comprehension and written composition were moderately related (r =.44). In addition, the word reading-spelling relation was stronger for primary-grade students (r =.82) than for university students/adults (r =.69). The relation of reading comprehension with written composition differed depending on measurement of reading comprehension and written composition—reading comprehension measured by multiple choice and open-ended tasks had a stronger relation with writing quality than reading comprehension measured by oral retell tasks; and reading comprehension had moderate relations with writing quality, writing vocabulary, writing syntax, and writing conventions but had weak relations with writing productivity and writing fluency. Relations tended to be stronger when reliability was higher, and the relation between word reading and spelling was stronger for alphabetic languages (r = .83) than for Chinese (r = .71). These results add important nuances about the nature of relations between reading and writing.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2023 08:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231178830?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Moving Toward Integration or Segregation? Racial Change in Suburban Public Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Suburbs across the US are experiencing demographic shifts with consequences for suburban schools. While scholars have expressed concern about rising segregation among suburban public schools, we extend this work by examining changes in racial/ethnic school segregation across a typology of suburban municipalities in the Chicago-Naperville-Elgin metropolitan area between 2007 and 2018. Our findings are mixed- contingent on the measure of segregation employed. We find that Black-white and Hispanic-white segregation in mature suburbs is rising, but is at least in part driven by shifting demographics. The results suggest intra-suburban variation in segregation, highlighting the connection between race and neighborhood change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2023 05:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231178021?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emerging trends in statistics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The rapidly increasing capacity of technology to collect, organize, and manage data has spurred changes in the practice of statistics: new methods of collecting data, large data sets, new forms of data, different ways to visualize and represent data, and recognition of the importance of being able to understand and to communicate data-based arguments and findings from the perspective of data consumers and data producers. Using a narrative review based on Delphi methods, wee asked leading members of the statistics education community to describe trends they have observed in the field and to identify interesting and relevant papers related to those trends. We received 24 responses and over 200 suggestions for papers. Our analysis included papers published in journals, book chapters, conference proceedings, handbooks, and curricular documents. We focused on future directions for statistics education research, and thus included articles based on opinion or principles if the arguments made a strong case supported by evidence as to why the idea was needed. From our analysis of 50 papers in this review, we suggest four emerging themes in statistics education research, challenging what should be taught and suggesting new ways of thinking about the teaching and learning of statistics: Data Science, Visibilizing Statistical Concepts, Social Statistics, and New Contexts for Learning. The review focuses on articles from 2017-mid 2022 and highlights the relevance and importance of each theme. Our choice of a particularly important paper for each theme is annotated in the references.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01501-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A culturally relevant action research model for Bhutanese secondary science teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-30-2023 12:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2230593?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Becoming Equitable Educators: Practical Measures to Support Teachers’ Dispositional Growth</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Animating equity in teaching and learning depends on teacher dispositions—orientations to self, others, and society that underlie how we think and act. Teacher dispositions are virtues or qualities of moral character that modify the ways we interact with students and educator colleagues. Although interest in “measuring to improve” teaching and teacher education has grown recently, most measures lack validity evidence for practical usefulness. Integrating Messick’s “unified validity framework” with Janssen et al.’s notion of “practicality” (as face validity), we find through an iterative, mixed-methods analysis of interviews with equitable educators and survey responses from teacher candidates that incorporating recognizability, relevance, and feasibility concerns of equity disposition concepts (i.e., Social Awareness, Meekness, Advocacy for Students) within survey items enhances item-to-factor structure of a self-report measure. We discuss implications (a) to develop and appraise formative measures and (b) to support teacher learning and development to become equitable educators.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-30-2023 11:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231183090?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Antecedents of Chilean in-service science teachers’ emotions: the important role of teacher motivation towards teaching career and self-efficacy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-30-2023 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2229003?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race, Whiteness, and Student Life in On-Campus Housing: A Case Study of Three Universities</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Residence halls are consequential spaces for many college students and purport to offer comfort, community, and home while facilitating meaningful learning opportunities, including interaction across difference. This qualitative case study uses theories of white space to examine campus housing at three historically white universities. Findings juxtapose staff’s and administrators’ relatively harmonious and idyllic beliefs about community with Students of Color’s experiences in campus residence halls. Across campuses, Students of Color’s sense of comfort and belonging in residence halls was ruptured by racist expression, speech, and an overwhelming presence of white people. Findings illuminate how residence halls often functioned as white spaces, where white students were disproportionately entitled to comfort, safety, and belonging. Implications for research and practice are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-30-2023 06:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231175643?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cognitive tuning in the STEM classroom: communication processes supporting children’s changing conceptions about data</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The teaching and learning of statistical thinking begins at a young age in Australia, with a focus on data representation and interpretation from Foundation Year (age 5), and the collection, sorting and categorising of items from the natural environment starting even earlier. The intangible concept of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;data,&lt;/em&gt; as part of statistical literacy, can be complex for children to grasp, especially when applying the notion of data to the everyday world or when data are explored in isolation to an investigation process. Authentic data modelling experiences present meaningful opportunities to apply statistical thinking although expert STEM knowledge is not always accessible to primary classroom teachers, nor is it always obvious how to implement such authentic problems within a classroom context. In this exploratory case study, we present data from a Year 4 classroom (age 9) statistical investigation addressing, ‘How big is a leaf?’ linking data to the real-life STEM context they represented. The authors were interested in how the teacher’s communication processes supported her students’ emerging understandings about data. Wit’s (&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r31&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/span&gt;) cognitive tuning framework offered a way to capture how the communication processes in a group build to a commonly shared frame of reference. Findings revealed a pattern of communication between the teacher and students, supporting students’ changing conceptions of data and related statistical thinking processes, throughout the investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00465-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Disruptiveness of COVID-19: Differences in Course Engagement, Self-Appraisal, and Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We investigated how the transition to remote instruction during the COVID-19 pandemic affected students’ engagement, self-appraisals, and learning in advanced placement (AP) Statistics courses. Participants included 681 (Mage=16.7 years, SDage=.90; %female=55.4) students enrolled in the course during 2017–2018 (N=266), 2018–2019 (N=200), and the pandemic-affected 2019–2020 (N=215) school years. Students enrolled during the pandemic-affected year reported a greater improvement in affective engagement but a decrease in cognitive engagement in the spring semester relative to a previous year. Females enrolled in the pandemic-affected year experienced a greater negative change in affective and behavioral engagement. Students enrolled during the pandemic-affected year reported a greater decrease in their anticipated AP exam scores and received lower scores on a practice exam aligned with the AP exam compared to a prior year. Although students were resilient in some respects, their self-appraisal and learning appear to have been negatively affected by pandemic circumstances.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2023 12:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231177967?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Noticing for Equity in Written Work: Exploring One Teacher’s Student Work Analysis Practices</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2023 08:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2223767?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Authentic assessment as a support for student teachers’ reflection</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2023 05:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2229004?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Designing an instrument to measure the development of techno-mathematical literacies in an innovative mathematics course for future engineers in STEM education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Techno-mathematical Literacies (TmL), which are defined as a combination of mathematical, workplace and ICT knowledge, and communicative skills, are acknowledged as important learning goals in STEM education. Still, much remains unknown about ways to address them in teaching and to assess their development. To investigate this, we designed and implemented an innovative course in applied mathematics with a focus on Techno-mathematical Literacies for 1st-year engineering students, and we set out to measure the learning effect of the course. Because measuring TmL is an uncharted terrain, we designed tests that could serve as pre- or posttests. To prevent a test learning effect, we aimed to design two different but equally difficult tests A and B. These were assigned randomly to 68 chemistry students, as a pretest, with the other one serving as posttest after the course. A significant development in TmL was found in the B-pre group, but not in the A-pre group. Therefore, as a follow-up analysis we investigated whether the two tests were equally difficult and searched for possible explanations. We found that test B was indeed perceived as more difficult than test A, but also that students who were assigned B (pre) were previously higher achieving than A (pre), and a sound mastery level of basic skills that ground the higher-order TmL seemed necessary. Furthermore, as TmL are very heterogenous by nature, some of them are easier learned and measured than others. Based on the results, we propose ways of testing TmL, which should be validated in future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01507-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: From planning to publishing: navigating the researcher’s journey. James Hiebert, Jinfa Cai, Stephen Hwang, Anne K Morris, Charles Hohensee (2023) Doing Research: A New Researcher’s Guide</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10248-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When teachers construct tests for assessing students’ competencies: a taxonomy</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Little is known about how teachers construct tests. For that reason, this study addresses the use of teacher-constructed tests for assessing educational goals, expressed in terms of student mathematical competencies. The focus is on meanings that upper secondary school mathematics teachers assign to their own test construction practices for assessing educational goals, expressed in terms of mathematical competencies in the curriculum. The methodological approach of grounded theory, underlined by symbolic interactionism, is applied to semi-structured interviews with teachers. The core category, the emerging taxonomy, is derived by revealing distinctions in degree of paying attention to competencies: no attention, superficial attention, and qualitative attention, as well as two different phases of the assessment: constructional and marking. Finally, a couple of possible implications for developing and improving test construction are offered. This includes collaborative work, inside and outside of schools, with both prospective and in-service teachers, for improvement of competence implementation in regular teaching and learning in alignment with mathematical content.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10233-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On designing better structures for feedback in practice-based professional development: Using “failure” to innovate</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This research article contributes to the growing literature highlighting the potential for innovation in mathematics education through design cycles that involve creative risk-taking and failure-based learning. Specifically, we explore how “failed” cycles of Story&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Circles&lt;/em&gt;—a practice-based professional development approach that centers on teacher collaboration—have been productive in fostering innovations within the program. Our focus is on the challenges that arose in our efforts to enable feedback mechanisms within the Story&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Circles&lt;/em&gt; system that support teachers’ interrogation of their own instructional practice, as they collaboratively develop lessons and expand their collective knowledge base for teaching mathematics. Through examples of three challenges, we illustrate how various lesson artifacts, including those constructed by teachers in anticipation of implementation and those extracted from actual implementations, failed to serve as the sole source of feedback for supporting teachers’ growth.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09588-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing early career teachers’ professional digital competence: a systematic literature review</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2023 12:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2229006?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How can practitioner action research support the design, implementation, and evaluation of on-campus mental health and addiction services?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2023 12:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2229402?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
