<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Segregating Gotham’s Youngest: Racial/Ethnic Sorting and the Choice Architecture of New York City’s Pre-K for All</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;New York City’s Pre-K for All (PKA) is the nation’s largest universal early childhood initiative, serving over 64,000 four-year-olds annually. Stemming from the program’s choice architecture as well as the city’s stark residential segregation, PKA programs are extremely segregated by child race/ethnicity. Our current study explores the complex forces that influence this segregation, including the interplay between family choices, seat availability, site-level enrollment priorities, and the PKA algorithm that weighs these and other considerations. We find that a majority of PKA segregation lies within local communities, and that areas with increased options and greater racial/ethnic diversity exhibit the most extreme segregation. We also conduct a simulation that leverages family PKA choices to maximize site-level racial/ethnic diversity and reduce between-site segregation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 08:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231190071?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where internationalisation and digitalisation intersect: designing a virtual exchange to enhance student teachers’ professional awareness as European teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 07:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2243644?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading Rural Districts: Research Synthesis of Rural Educational Leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 12:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238519?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participatory pedagogies enhance engineering education for sustainability</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 10:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2240858?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Practicum in ELT: a systematic review of 2010–2020 research on ELT practicum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2242577?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward a Conceptual Understanding of Inclusion as Intersubjective Experiences</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Inclusion has become a global buzzword relating to education policy and practice. Mostly, it is tied to discussions about access and opportunities in education spaces as well as school policies and the curriculum decisions and pedagogical actions of teachers. As part of this critique, we propose defining inclusion as intersubjective experiences associated with feelings of belonging, acceptance, and value that are dynamic, ephemeral, spatial, and in flux. Here, we advocate for centering the experiences and amplifying the voices of disabled children and young people in and about education spaces, while acknowledging the wider social forces that structure those spaces, as only disabled young people can explain how they feel in the educational spaces where they find themselves.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 02:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231176287?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Clustering eye-movement data uncovers students’ strategies for coordinating equations and diagrams of vector fields</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In mathematics education, students are repeatedly confronted with the tasks of interpreting and relating different representations. In particular, switching between equations and diagrams plays a major role in learning mathematical procedures and solving mathematical problems. In this article, we investigate a rather unexplored topic with precisely such requirements—that is, vector fields. In our study, we first presented a series of multiple-choice tasks to 147 introductory university students at the beginning of their studies and recorded students’ eye movements while they matched vector field diagrams and equations. Thereafter, students had to solve a similar coordination task on paper and justify their reasoning. Two cluster analyses were performed including (i) transition and fixation data on diagrams and options (Model 1), and (ii) additionally the number of horizontal and vertical saccades on the diagram (Model 2). In both models, two clusters emerge—with Model 1 distinguishing behaviors related to representational mapping and Model 2 additionally differentiating students according to representation-specific demands. Model 2 leads to a better distinction between the groups in terms of different performance indicators (test score, response confidence, and spatial ability) which also transfers to another task format. We conclude that vertical and horizontal saccades reflect executive actions of perception when approaching vector field coordination tasks. Thus, we recommend targeted interventions for mathematics lessons; these lessons must focus on a visual handling of the vector field diagram. Further, we infer that students’ difficulties can be attributed to covariational reasoning, thereby indicating the need for further investigations. From a methodological perspective, we reflect on the triangulation of eye-tracking and verbal data in (multiple-choice) assessment scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10243-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘I realised it when we played with the doll!’: nursing students’ learning from participation in an action research project that included manikins</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 07:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2242425?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Epistemic Injustice and Legitimacy in U.S. Doctoral Education: A Systematic Review of Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Epistemic injustice is a condition where knowers and knowledge claims are unduly dismissed. Philosophers suggest that epistemic injustice manifests in three forms: testimonial, hermeneutical, and contributory. Although distinct, all forms of epistemic injustice stem from relations of power, privilege, and positionality — where some have the opportunity and authority to legitimize the knowledge contributions of others. The purpose of this study was to explore the presence of epistemic injustice in U.S. doctoral education through a systematic review of literature. We methodically searched hundreds of peer-reviewed journals for studies focused on teaching, advising, peer interaction, doctoral socialization, and other experiences concerning doctoral education across the humanities, social science, and science disciplines. We retained, reviewed, and analyzed 107 manuscripts. Our analysis revealed epistemic injustice in doctoral education as well as rules that foster the conditions for epistemic injustice. Implications for doctoral education and future research are offered.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 06:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231187628?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Trekking Across Some Rough Terrain: Rural Teacher Education for Multilingual Students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 02:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238502?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Recruiting and Retaining Teachers in Rural Schools: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 01:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238491?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ecology of Rural Cross-Sector School-Community Partnerships: A Literature Review</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2023 02:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238521?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introduction: NREA’s Rural Education Research Agenda 2016–2021</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2023 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238487?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meaning and Structure of Mathematical Connections in the Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The making of mathematical connections in the classroom plays a dual role. While many studies highlight the importance of connections for the learning of mathematics, others inform of students’ difficulties associated with the making of connections. This study aims to characterise the mathematical connections that arise in habitual classroom practice, using an inductive approach, in the context of introducing integers with pupils aged 12–13. Results show that connections emerge as networks of links resulting from interactions between the teacher and the students. We present a definition of connection, a detailed characterisation of their internal structure as networks of links and a global characterisation which takes into account the role of the connection in the context in which it takes place. The complementarity of the two characterizations allows us to coordinate, from a classroom perspective, existing specific classification proposals for connections with a broader notion of connection used by relevant curricular guidelines. Factors that may determine the complexity of connections and may be related with students’ difficulties when dealing with connections in the classroom are also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00281-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring computational thinking as a boundary object between mathematics and computer programming for STEM teaching and learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Programming is an interdisciplinary practice with applications in both mathematics and computer science. Mathematics concerns rigor, abstraction, and generalization. Computer science predominantly concerns efficiency, concreteness, and physicality. This makes programming a medium for problem solving that mediates between mathematics and computer science in intriguing ways. Behind programming practices is computational thinking (CT), a mode of thinking involved in formulating and solving problems so that the solutions could be represented and carried out by computing means. In this paper, CT is seen as a boundary object connecting mathematics and computer science in a school problem-solving context. In particular, we examine and analyse middle school students’ work upon engaging in mathematical problem solving-in a programming environment, taking CT as a boundary object embedded in the block-based programming environment, Scratch. The analysis is guided by observing boundary crossing features of CT in the students’ artefacts produced in Scratch while solving mathematical problems related to symmetry and arithmetic sequence. The findings of this study open up new dimensions to explore CT as a boundary object in integrated STEM pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01509-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reflections from an insider researcher ‘doing’ feminist participatory action research to co-produce a research agenda with British Pakistani women; a seldom heard group</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Participation of community stakeholders in health research priority setting is an emerging trend. Despite this, the involvement of marginalised groups in research prioritisation is limited and where they are involved, sample sizes are small, where individuals are merely consulted with, rather than coproducing the research agenda. Without addressing power dynamics inherent in research prioritisation with marginalised groups, their engagement in the research process can be tokenistic and the resulting research agenda unreflective of their needs. This article, therefore, aims to generate knowledge on how feminist participatory action research was used to co-produce an obesity research agenda with British Pakistani women, a seldom heard population, living in deprived areas. The methodology enabled Pakistani women to be involved in all stages of the project, culminating in the co-production of an obesity research agenda that accurately reflects their unmet needs. Women’s engagement in the project led to their increased confidence, the formation of relationships that lasted beyond the research project, improvements to their lifestyles, and engagement in further research. Feminist participatory action research may be used by researchers as a guiding methodology due to its ability to improve women’s lives and develop research agendas for women’s health.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-28-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231191854?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Assessment of Eighth Graders’ Mathematics Higher Order Thinking Skills in the Chinese Context</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Based on Bloom’s Taxonomy of Educational Objectives and the assessment framework of PISA, this study aimed to develop a three-dimensional assessment framework to measure junior high school students’ higher order thinking skills in mathematics in China. A total of 28,153 eighth graders from 11 districts and counties in Z city were involved in the test. The results showed that (1) in the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical ability&lt;/em&gt; dimension, students scored the lowest in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Problem-solving&lt;/em&gt;; (2) in the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Cognitive level&lt;/em&gt; dimension, students scored the lowest in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Evaluate&lt;/em&gt;; (3) there was little difference between students’ scores on problems in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Realistic&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Intramathematical situations&lt;/em&gt;; (4) there were significant differences in the higher order thinking skills of students at different academic levels; and (5) there were no gender differences in students’ higher order mathematical thinking skills (HOMTS). Implications for assessment in HOMTS and suggestions for future study are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-28-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00279-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond language: conceptualizing epistemic violence against Black immigrant students in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper provides on-the-ground accounts of epistemic violence against Black immigrant children in mathematics classrooms. From a critical feminist perspective, we introduce Dotson’s notion of silencing as an enactment of epistemic violence. According to Dotson, one way to enact epistemic violence is to damage a particular group’s ability to speak and be heard. A successful act of communication depends on the audience’s willingness and ability to “hear” the speaker. Therefore, denying this reciprocity in communication is a form of epistemic violence. Using this conceptualization, we conducted a secondary data analysis from a larger study aimed at enhancing teachers’ knowledge and abilities to implement problem-solving teaching. We identify and characterize three practices of silencing Black immigrant students in Chilean mathematics classrooms that damage their agency as knowers and doers of mathematics. Beyond language issues, we show that silencing is a form of anti-Black onto-epistemic violence that prevents Black immigrant students from being recognized as legitimate subjects of knowledge in mathematics classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01512-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The influence of students’ prior numeracy achievement on later numeracy achievement as a function of gender and year levels</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students’ prior achievements in school have significant correlations with their later achievements. Specifically, students’ prior numeracy achievement is the most important predictor of later numeracy success. However, the assessment of this predictor across gender and its trend across students’ year levels is often overlooked or not adequately investigated. This study examined the relationships between prior numeracy achievement and its influence on students’ later numeracy achievement across gender. A focus on students’ year level also supported this examination. The data source was the Australian National Assessment Program—Literacy and Numeracy (NAPLAN) numeracy results of Years 5, 7 and 9 students (ages 9 to 14) from the 2017 to 2021 test years. The NAPLAN numeracy scores were analysed using regression analysis. The author examined prior numeracy achievement to determine the predictive value for students’ numeracy performance in NAPLAN across students’ year levels and gender. Findings from this study indicate that prior NAPLAN numeracy results for students were found to be very large in its predictive value (between &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; = .591 and .747) across the year levels. Notably, the predictive value showed an increasing pattern as students progressed through their academic years. Additionally, the study observed a discernible influence of gender on the predictive value of prior numeracy results. Potential initiatives to assist the educational outcomes of students across gender are discussed. Awareness of the influence of numeracy performance across gender might help teachers and educators create better and more efficient mathematics programs and targeted interventions. Such a decision requires identifying the relevant factors and measuring their degree of influence across students’ year levels and gender.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00469-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I Loved Seeing How Their Brains Worked!”—Examining the Role of Epistemic Empathy in Responsive Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Studies in science and mathematics education have shown that teachers’ responsiveness to students’ ideas, feelings, and experiences is critical for promoting epistemic agency, disciplinary engagement, and equity. Such responsiveness is particularly important for students whose cultures, backgrounds, and funds of knowledge have been traditionally marginalized in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) classrooms. Yet, what allows teachers to enact responsive teaching is less clear. We argue that epistemic empathy—the capacity for tuning into and appreciating learners’ intellectual and emotional experiences in constructing, communicating, and critiquing knowledge—is an essential driver of teacher responsiveness. In this work, we examine how epistemic empathy can serve to support teachers’ attention and responsiveness to students’ sensemaking experiences in the classroom and discuss emergent tensions that arise in this work. We end with implications for research and for teacher education to cultivate epistemic empathy as a resource for responsive teaching and a target for teacher learning.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 07:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231187313?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career and Technical Education at Community Colleges: A Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;I review the literature evaluating sub-baccalaureate career and technical education (CTE) at community colleges. The goal of this study is to review the evidence describing how earning these types of credentials affects students’ outcomes, as well as which program characteristics contribute to student success. The research suggests that, on average, there are significant labor-market returns to obtaining short, technical credentials, although the returns vary across locations and fields of study. Researchers examining career pathway programs, sectoral partnerships, and apprenticeships have found mixed effects of participating in these programs, although so far, the literature is largely limited to short-term outcomes. More research is needed that ties program characteristics to student outcomes to develop our understanding of how to increase the probability of success for students enrolling in postsecondary CTE. We also need more studies examining the long-term outcomes for students graduating from these programs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 06:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231186618?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Postsecondary Aspirations of Rural Indigenous Adolescents and How Schools Support These Dreams, Goals, and Plans: A Literature Review and Synthesis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 01:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238509?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rural Students in Higher Education: From College Preparation and Enrollment to Experiences and Persistence</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 01:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238508?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: On designing better structures for feedback in practice‑based professional development: Using “failure” to innovate</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09592-5</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
