<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Kindergarten and First-Grade Students’ Understandings of Arithmetic Properties Across Different Kinds of Problems</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this article, we present research on eight kindergarten and eight first-grade students’ understandings of the arithmetic properties of commutativity, additive identity, and additive inverse during a classroom teaching experiment, selected from a larger study that included 88 students. In this study, we explore the students’ types of understandings in terms of Skemp’s (1987) framework (instrumental and relational), the basic relationships in the conceptual field of additive structures (combination, transformation, and comparison), and their performance on different problems involving numerical operations, equations, and word problems. Our findings show that students performed better on additive identity and additive inverse properties. Problems involving substituting and simplifying expressions that combined two properties had a lower performance rate. The differences in understandings and performance observed between kindergarten and first-grade students have implications for instructional design geared to introduce arithmetic properties in the early grades. This study highlights the difference between correctly solving a problem and providing evidence of a relational understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00331-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice Teachers’ Experiences With, Beliefs About, Self-Efficacy In, and Instructional Practices for Mathematical Writing</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-16-2024 12:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2398958?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fugitive Care: The Politics of Care Enacted by Afro-Caribbean Women Teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The future of teaching will increasingly rely on overseas-trained teachers (OTTs) to address teacher shortages. While research on OTTs in the United States is expanding, studies focusing on Afro-Caribbean teachers are emerging. Despite the growing call for more teachers of color, Afro-Caribbean OTTs’ contributions are often overlooked due to their immigrant status. We propose the concepts of “radical transparency” and “fugitive care” to articulate how these teachers’ classroom practices offer alternative possibilities for schooling, making the learning process both explicit and equitable for all students. Drawing on a Transnational Black Feminist Framework (TBF), we highlight the unique politics of care practiced by these teachers, revealing gaps in our cultural understanding and underscoring their vital, yet understudied, contributions to education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-16-2024 12:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241275219?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Immigrant students’ experiences of (Re)producing school mathematics in home-School transitions – epistemological positioning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-16-2024 02:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2401484?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming fifth graders’ misconceptions in solving probability comparison problems with purposefully designed instructional interventions</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-15-2024 01:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2403044?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Redefining Item Response Models for Small Samples</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Popular item response theory (IRT) models are considered complex, mainly due to the inclusion of a random factor variable (latent variable). The random factor variable represents the incidental parameter problem since the number of parameters increases when including data of new persons. Therefore, IRT models require a specific estimation method and large samples for accurate parameter estimation. The two-parameter IRT model is redefined by analytically integrating out the random person factor in the latent response formulation of the model to make it suitable for small sample applications. This IRT Bayesian covariance structure model (IRT-BCSM) describes the clustering of (latent) responses by persons through a structured covariance matrix in which a common covariance parameter represents the dependence implied by a unidimensional random factor variable. The IRT-BCSM is a latent-variable-free model and consists of (fixed) item parameters and a common covariance parameter, where person parameters can be post-hoc sampled. An efficient Gibbs sampler is proposed for parameter estimation. In simulation studies, the performance of the IRT-BCSM is compared to two-parameter IRT models for small samples, and results show an optimal performance of the IRT-BCSM even in sample sizes as small as 50 to 100 persons and 5 to 10 items. Generalizations of the IRT-BCSM show that a redefinition of more complex IRT models also lead to much more efficient parameterizations, which can broaden the scope of IRT applications.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241269886?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating Intersectional Fairness in Algorithmic Decision Making Using Intersectional Differential Algorithmic Functioning</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Ensuring fairness is crucial in developing modern algorithms and tests. To address potential biases and discrimination in algorithmic decision making, researchers have drawn insights from the test fairness literature, notably the work on differential algorithmic functioning (DAF) by Suk and Han. Nevertheless, the exploration of intersectionality in fairness investigations, within both test fairness and algorithmic fairness fields, is still relatively new. In this paper, we propose an extension of the DAF framework to include the concept of intersectionality. Similar to DAF, the proposed notion for intersectionality, which we term “interactive DAF,” leverages ideas from test fairness and algorithmic fairness. We also provide methods based on the generalized Mantel–Haenszel test, generalized logistic regression, and regularized group regression to detect DAF, interactive DAF, or other subtypes of DAF. Specifically, we employ regularized group regression with three different penalties and examine their performance via a simulation study. Finally, we demonstrate our intersectional DAF framework in real-world applications on grade retention and conditional cash transfer programs in education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2024 11:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241269820?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Education is not the problem, but part of the solution</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2024 10:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2402613?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effect of a whole-group intervention on children’s participation in interactive book reading</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2024 05:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2399135?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First encounter with constructing graphs in the functional thinking approach to school algebra in 3rd and 4th grades</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Given the relevance of graphs of functions, we consider their inclusion in primary education from the functional approach to early algebra. The purpose of this article is to shed some light on the students’ production and reading of graphs when they solved generalization problems from a functional thinking approach. We aim to explore how 3rd and 4th graders construct graphs associated to functions and what elements they use; and how they read function associated graphs and whether they connect pairs of values to see beyond the data. After four working sessions about functions, we designed and implemented individual interviews to 12 students. Through a qualitative analysis, we highlight that the students can read data in a graph on two different cognitive levels and also construct it from different elements of the graph initially provided. Regarding data reading, we evidence two levels: (a) literal reading of a given element in the graph, and (b) reading beyond the data. The construction of the graph is described with base on the axes, values and labels on the axes, scale of the axes, and construction techniques. We present examples of students’ work that evidence that graph construction varied depending on whether it was created from a blank sheet or it was necessary to provide help regarding the axes or the scale of the graph. We describe several techniques used by the students in the representation of data that yield non-canonical representations of a graph and that help glimpse how students are interpreting this representation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01627-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publishing mathematics education research in English: amplifying voices from the field</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper we investigate the issue of representation within the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Journal of Mathematics Teacher Education&lt;/em&gt; (JMTE) and the broader academic publishing landscape, particularly focusing on the underrepresentation of authors from various world regions. A questionnaire, distributed globally, aimed to amplify the voices of the underrepresented, exploring the constraints and affordances of publishing in English-medium mathematics education research journals. The question that guided our investigation was: What do voices from the mathematics education community raise in their responses to questions about publishing in English-medium research journals like JMTE? We used qualitative methods to review the responses and identify common themes. The findings revealed significant barriers and challenges related to language, research location, and institutional support, highlighting the complexities of navigating the global academic community and the academic publishing culture. We propose actionable suggestions to foster a more equitable, diverse, and inclusive publishing environment.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09659-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teacher educators’ navigational expertise when designing multimodal representations of practice: a semiotic analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Critical elements of the expertise of mathematics teacher educators (MTE) can be identified in the artifacts they design for working with prospective teachers (PT), specifically for engaging PT in the double role of practitioners and students of practice. While MTE are increasingly utilizing &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; multimodal representations of practice (such as storyboards), theoretical frameworks and methods for analyzing these pedagogical artifacts and the meanings they support are still in early development. We utilize a semiotic framework, expanding systemic functional linguistics to encompass non-linguistic elements, to identify aspects of what we call &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;navigational expertise—&lt;/em&gt;which supports PTs in engaging both as practitioners and students of the practice&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; We view this expertise as tacit knowledge-in-use, enacted through artifact production. The paper demonstrates MTE’s navigational expertise by showing how MTE design storyboards of practice to engage PT as fellow teachers experiencing the lesson taught by a peer &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; as university students who consider the artifact (including the represented lesson) as an object of study. The framework allows us to identify how MTE’s navigational expertise lies in seamlessly interweaving these two purposes and navigating between them, knowing when, how, and for what purposes to invoke each. Through analysis of storyboards from four MTE in diverse US settings, we uncover some of the nuanced tacit components of navigational expertise, highlighting linguistic and non-linguistic design choices and their potential meanings for transactions with PT.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09658-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Designing specific tools to enhance the numeracy of adults with intellectual disabilities</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00504-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Principal Leadership of Pre-K Programs in Elementary Schools: Evidence from North Carolina</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Pre-Kindergarten (Pre-K) programs are becoming increasingly common in elementary schools across the United States—in fact, a recent analysis of federal data revealed that 57% of public schools have a Pre-K grade. Despite the prevalence of Pre-K programs in schools, principals—known to be among the most important factors in school success—often lack the knowledge and professional supports to effectively lead Pre-K programs. In this study, guided by sensemaking theory, we work to advance knowledge on Pre-K principal leadership through a sequential mixed-methods analysis of elementary school principals in the state of North Carolina. Our study includes a statewide survey of all lead and assistant principals in the state (N = 520) as well as follow-up interviews with 27 of the surveyed principals. Our findings reveal that while they report strong conceptual support for the Pre-K programs in their schools, principals demonstrate limited engagement with them. We also find that principal background and preparation in early education and the proportion of students from a Pre-K program that ultimately enroll in the school for kindergarten are important factors that help explain variation in principal orientations to Pre-K leadership.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2024 10:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241271365?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>In between jockeying and resisting proximities to whiteness: the challenges and promises of cross-racial solidarity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2024 08:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2402327?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The immovable veil of black disability: an introduction to Black disability threat theory and its application to the school to prison nexus</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2024 08:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2398474?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engagement Matters: Reimagining Family, School, and Community Relations in Teacher Education to Improve Student Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/75/4&quot;&gt;Volume 75, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 365-368, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-11-2024 11:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241266315?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘I view teaching differently’: identity development of university teachers doing professional doctorates</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-11-2024 11:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2400480?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Becoming exceptional: the role of capital in the development and mediation of mathematics identity and degree trajectories</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;There is a burgeoning interest in the concept of identity within mathematics education research, with recent work suggesting that the interplay of identity and capital (cultural, social, and economic resources) offers a productive lens for understanding school students’ trajectories into, or away from, mathematics. This paper adds to understandings of how interactions of identity and capital play out over time, focusing on how these mediated the mathematics degree trajectories of three young men, Tom, Neb, and Gerrard, who were selected from a wider longitudinal study, as the only young people who went on to take mathematics degrees. Analysis of longitudinal data from 24 semi-structured interviews, conducted with the three young men from age 10 to 21 and two of their parents/carers, found that all three identified as being “good/exceptional at mathematics”. These identifications developed at an early age, were sustained and augmented by capital, and were closely related to pursuing the subject at university and enjoyment of mathematics. However, developing and sustaining an identity as “good at maths” relied on interactions with mathematics capital through families, school, and wider networks. Moreover, classed differences in the distribution of capital were implicated in their different degree outcomes. We argue that attending to the longitudinal interplay between capital and identity offers a rich understanding of how young people come to see themselves and be seen by others as “naturally able” at mathematics and in turn supports choosing to study a mathematics degree. Implications for mathematics education policy and practice are considered.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10360-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Speaking Stata: Quantile–quantile plots, generalized</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 514-534, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Quantile-quantile plots in the precise sense of scatterplots showing corresponding quantiles of two variables have long been supported by official command qqplot. That command is generalized here in several ways in a new command, qqplotg. In this article, I explain the major features of qqplotg and give several examples of its use. Themes include the use of quantile-quantile plots to explore the possibilities for working on a transformed scale and the value of plotting difference between quantiles versus mean quantile or plotting position. Various historical and methodological remarks are sprinkled throughout.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276114?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 156: Concentration and diversity measures using egen</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 535-545, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276115?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Updates</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 551-551, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276117?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tests and confidence bands for multiple one-sided comparisons</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 446-477, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;One-sided inference should be used in some applications, but Stata has limited support for one-sided tests and confidence intervals for a single compari­son and almost no support for one-sided tests and confidence bands for multiple comparisons. In this article, we provide an introduction to one-sided tests and confidence intervals for a single hypothesis and to one-sided tests and confidence intervals for multiple comparisons. We also discuss extensions of the sotable com­mand introduced in Drukker (2023, Stata Journal 23: 518-544) to cover one-sided tests and confidence bands for a single comparison and for multiple comparisons. We also provide examples of how to use sotable to perform multiple tests against values other than zero and how to perform multiple tests after commands like margins and nlcom that support the post option.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276111?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 157: Adding extra lines to graphs</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 546-550, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276116?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
