<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Lottery-Based Evaluations of Early Education Programs: Opportunities and Challenges for Building the Next Generation of Evidence</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Lottery-based identification strategies offer potential for generating the next generation of evidence on U.S. early education programs. The authors’ collaborative network of five research teams applying this design in early education settings and methods experts has identified six challenges that need to be carefully considered in this next context: (a) available baseline covariates that may not be very rich; (b) limited data on the counterfactual; (c) limited and inconsistent outcome data; (d) weakened internal validity due to attrition; (e) constrained external validity due to who competes for oversubscribed programs; and (f) difficulties answering site-level questions with child-level randomization. The authors offer potential solutions to these six challenges and concrete recommendations for the design of future lottery-based early education studies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-01-2024 06:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241231933?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Text-to-Speech Technology and Math Performance: A Comparative Study of Students With Disabilities, English Language Learners, and Their General Education Peers</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study investigates the relationship between text-to-speech (TTS) usage and item-by-item performance in the 2017 eighth-grade National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP) math assessment, focusing on students with disabilities (SWDs), English language learners (ELLs), and their general education (GE) peers. Results indicate that all students use TTS more for longer and more difficult math items as well as for multiple-choice or short-response formats. Among SWDs and GE students, lower math proficiency and higher perceived time pressure are linked to higher TTS usage. Moreover, among GE students, factors such as male gender, minority status, lower math persistence, and higher math interest and effort during testing contribute to higher TTS usage. TTS usage is positively associated with item performance for SWDs and ELLs who received extended time accommodations but not for those who did not receive such accommodations or for general education students. The study suggests that the time constraints of speeded digital assessments may limit the potential benefits of TTS for SWDs and ELLs in math problem-solving.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-29-2024 09:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241232995?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Consequential Intersections: Examining Equity Expressions and Experiences Within Special Education Ecosystems</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;We employ the metaphor of an educational ecosystem to explain how racial inequity in special education manifests in a midsized urban school district via equity expressions and experiences. We focus on two ecosystems operating at the mesol-evel within school districts:1) special education and 2) equity ecosystems. We show how these educational ecosystems converge and diverge when a state education agency (SEA) cites a local education agency (LEA) via federal disability legislation for racial disparities in special education outcomes—commonly referred to as racial disproportionality. Using document analysis and semistructured interview data, we empirically examine how equity and special education ecosystems converge and diverge and discuss the implications for addressing racialized inequities. We highlight that there was limited equity absorption across the two ecosystems and how racism and ableism are implicated in the convergences and divergences between the two systems. We conclude with recommendations for policy and practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-29-2024 09:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241230056?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Discourse in Research-Practice Partnership Meetings: A Comparison of Conditions Across Contexts</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research-practice partnerships (RPPs) are gaining international attention as they promise to close the gap between research and practice in education. As RPPs bring together participants with diverse expertise, how people dialogue to collectively learn and address problems of practice is critically important. Analyzing video data from RPP meetings in Switzerland and the United States, this micro-analytic study examines the extent of generative discourse in RPP meetings and the conditions under which it occurs. Since RPPs vary significantly along a number of dimensions, it is useful to compare them to see how these features influence discourse and learning. Across the Swiss and US contexts, almost half of the meeting time was generative—altering meanings and/or creating new knowledge and perspectives. Discourse patterns varied, however, reflecting the different sizes, purposes, and activity structures of the RPPs. Examining meeting discourse across conditions may help promote knowledge generation and continuous improvement in RPPs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-29-2024 08:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241230051?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Implementing action research to improve L2 classroom communication patterns: a grounded theory analysis approach</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-29-2024 02:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2324184?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meaning and subjectivity in the PISA mathematics frameworks: a sociological approach</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Social institutions function not only by reproducing specific practices but also by reproducing discourses endowing such practices with meaning. The latter in turn is related to the development of the identities or subjectivities of those who live and thrive within such institutions. Meaning and subjectivity are therefore significant sociological categories involved in the functioning of complex social phenomena such as that of mathematical instruction. The present paper provides a discursive analysis centered on these categories of the influential OECD’s PISA mathematics frameworks. As we shall see, meaning as articulated by the OECD primarily stresses the utilitarian value of mathematics to individuals and to society at large. Furthermore, molding students’ subjectivities towards endorsing such articulation of meaning is emphasized as an educational objective, either explicitly or implicitly, as connected to the OECD’s definition of mathematical literacy. Therefore, the OECD’s discourses do not only serve to reproduce the type of mathematical instruction implied in the organization’s services concerning education, but also concomitantly provide a potentially most effective educational technology through which the demand of these very services may be reproduced.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-29-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10296-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Kids Have Taught Me. I Listen to Them”: Principals Legitimizing Student Voice in Their Leadership</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Few studies have shared insights on how principals invite student voice to enact equitable leadership practice. The purpose of this study was to explore the ways in which principals demonstrated their commitment to equity via advocating for student voice using in-depth interview data from six school principals in the United States. We present three findings that contribute to the field of leadership and student voice: (a) motivation for student voice, (b) desires and concerns for student future, and (c) student voice for authentic learning. This study advances how school leaders develop student democratic agency and critical consciousness through pursuing and welcoming student voice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-28-2024 10:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241232596?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the Superintendent Pipeline: A Call for a National Longitudinal Dataset</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A recent study published in Educational Researcher by White (2023) examined superintendent gender gaps. This work required 4 years of internet searches to identify and match superintendent names with each of the roughly 13,000 school districts in the United States. Although this study provided important insights into the superintendent gender gaps, the study is unable to examine gaps for females of color or the long-term career pathways of superintendents. The lack of a national longitudinal superintendent dataset has meant researchers and policymakers have limited insights into superintendent racial and gender gaps, turnover rates, experience, and career pathways to the superintendency. Drawing on data from the Texas State Longitudinal Data System, we offer several findings to provide a glimpse of what could be accomplished with a longitudinal dataset. Policymakers, school boards, search firms, and communities will fail to understand the full range of challenges and opportunities to diversifying and strengthening the superintendent workforce until such a dataset exists and is accessible to researchers and other interested parties.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-28-2024 09:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241232621?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Working Conditions and Dissatisfaction Before and During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;With a goal of contextualizing teacher job dissatisfaction during the first full school year of the COVID-19 pandemic, we contrast teachers’ experiences with the decade and a half leading up to the pandemic. We draw on nationally representative data from the Schools and Staffing Survey and National Teacher and Principal Survey from the 2003–04 to 2020–21 school years. Through descriptive and regression analysis, we show that (1) increases in teacher dissatisfaction beginning in the 2015–16 school year persisted into the 2020–21 school year, (2) levels of dissatisfaction during the pandemic were not equal across subpopulations of teachers, and (3) positive working conditions consistently predicted lower job dissatisfaction, including in the 2020–21 school year.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-28-2024 09:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241232657?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematicians’ conceptualisations of isomorphism and homomorphism: a story of contexts, contrasts, and utility</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-28-2024 03:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2320870?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Mismatch Between World Bank Actions and the Decentralization of Educational Systems in LMICs</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The World Bank’s (WB) growing emphasis on decentralizing educational systems has sparked widespread discussion in the literature. This study examines whether WB reforms are indeed associated with decentralizing educational systems in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs), as commonly assumed. Using unique, untapped country-level panel data on 30 LMICs from 1990 to 2019, I do not find a significant association between the WB’s actions and changes observed in educational systems. Employing the institutional logics perspective, I argue that the WB’s diffusion of “homogeneous” educational reforms may clash with “heterogeneous” socioeconomic, political, and cultural contexts, thus hindering the direct translation of reforms into tangible outcomes on the ground.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-27-2024 09:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241229027?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Invisible Policy Brokers: The Political Roles of Interpreters in Educational Policy Negotiations With Language Minoritized Mothers</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Educational interpreters are not neutral mediators of messages. In education, they are policy brokers whose translations can reflect their own social identities and often align with larger social power dynamics, including deficit perspectives of racialized multilingual people. In U.S. schools, language minoritized parents have the right to make decisions about their children’s education; yet current theory does not account for their power to shape educational policies—or the political roles of interpreters who represent their negotiations. I propose a theory of interpreters as invisible policy brokers and identity mediators. I employ an approach that centers the questions and agency of newly arrived, predominantly Spanish-speaking mothers in a Midwest school district with growing demographics of language minoritized students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-27-2024 08:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241228837?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Generic or subject-specific? A survey comparing Dutch secondary school visual art teachers’ early-career experiences to teacher experiences in non-arts subjects</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-27-2024 06:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2311702?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Democratic pedagogies in initial teacher education: co-constructing a supportive learning framework</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-27-2024 05:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2317202?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ noticing of proportional reasoning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The importance of understanding what and how mathematics teachers notice is well documented, but more research is needed on content-specific noticing. In particular, knowing how teachers notice proportional reasoning, a vital topic spanning all grades of mathematics, could inform measures that support students’ proportional reasoning. We examined how teachers noticed when responding to two prompts (one student-focused and one teacher–student-interaction-focused) after watching a video of a middle grades proportional reasoning lesson. We analyzed the proportional reasoning reported from 13 elementary and 20 secondary prospective teachers and used cooccurrences along with noticing practices to describe how teachers noticed proportional reasoning and what aspects of proportional reasoning they noticed. Results indicate: (a) the two prompts resulted in differences in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; participants noticed proportional reasoning, (b) participants were primarily descriptive and not interpretative when describing the proportional reasoning they noticed, and (c) the elementary and secondary prospective teachers both noticed similar aspects of proportional reasoning but showed differences in how the proportional reasoning cooccurred with the noticing practices. These findings reiterate the importance of the prompts used with teachers, the potential of using video to advance teachers’ noticing of proportional reasoning, and the methodological potential of using cooccurrences to examine teachers’ content-specific noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09625-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Development of teachers’ attitudes and self-efficacy expectations for inclusive mathematics instruction: effects of online and blended learning programs</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper presents the results of a quantitative study investigating the development of teachers&#39; attitudes and self-efficacy expectations for inclusive mathematics instruction in the context of an in-service training that was designed in a blended learning format and compared to an unsupported online offer. In the blended learning format, 101 teachers participated in an in-service training, designed as a combination of six workshops with concrete activities based on materials for inclusive mathematics teaching and intermittent practical phases with collaborative learning environments for children aged 6–12 years. The teachers&#39; attitudes toward inclusive mathematics instruction and self-efficacy expectations are collected by using published scales (KIESEL) and scales under development. The effects of the blended learning program are analyzed by the t test for dependent samples or the nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test and compared to the effects of an online offer without further guidance and support. On the one hand, the results indicate the importance of the blended learning program in comparison with the unsupported online offer. On the other hand, they show insights into the relevance of the participants&#39; interaction with the materials during the concrete activities as well as of their try outs in and their reflection on teaching practice during the intermittent practical phases.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09624-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Discursive Variability of Mathematics Coaches</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Research on how coaches talk with teachers during coaching cycles is underdeveloped. We analyzed 1,649 discourse moves from 24 mathematics content-focused coaching cycles to determine the extent to which coaches’ discursive tendencies vary. We explored variation between coaches, between planning and debriefing conversations, and between cycles for the same coach–teacher pair. Findings indicate there existed significant variability in the coaches’ discourse moves during coaching cycles. We also found discursive differences from planning to debriefing meetings, noting that coaches were more directive and less reflective in planning conversations compared with debriefing conversations. Across multiple coaching cycles, we found variation across coaches, with one coach increasing the prevalence of directive moves across four planning conversations and another increasing the prevalence of reflective moves across four debriefing conversations. Although we focus on mathematics coaches, the findings and methodology may be applicable to other disciplines.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 11:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241231537?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Discipline, Police Contact, and GPA: A Mediation Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Exclusionary school discipline is one of the primary ways that schools address student behavior. Existing scholarship has focused on examining the implications of exclusionary school discipline for two sets of outcomes: academic achievement and future juvenile and criminal legal involvement. However, these two areas of scholarship are largely treated as separate. In this paper, we bridge these two research areas by drawing on scholarship examining the negative educational consequences of police contact for youth. Specifically, we formally test the proposition that the association between school suspension in childhood and adolescent academic achievement is mediated by police contact experienced in early adolescence. Using data from the Future of Families and Child Wellbeing Study, we find support for this hypothesis: Early adolescent police contact explains approximately 30% of the association between school suspension in childhood and adolescent GPA. By relying on exclusionary school discipline, our results suggest that schools are setting the stage for youth to become involved in the criminal legal system, which, in turn, hinders future academic achievement.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 10:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241231988?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of Information Provision on the Gender Gap in Technology: Experimental Evidence From Course Enrollment and Major Decisions</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article reports on the impacts of a nudge intervention designed to narrow the gender gap in technology education. I randomly assigned approximately 4,000 college freshmen to one of three advising interventions during new student orientation. Students in the treatment group received a brochure containing information about technology courses and were exposed to stereotypical imagery, neutral imagery, or counter-stereotypical imagery. Information provision had a positive impact on both technology course take-up and technology major selection. A stronger response by men led to an overall increase in the gender gap, but this gap is smallest among students exposed to counter-stereotypical imagery.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 05:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241228278?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dual Language Immersion Programs and Student Achievement in Early Elementary Grades</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper presents evidence of the effects of dual language immersion (DLI) programs on the academic outcomes of students in elementary grades. Leveraging enrollment lotteries from four cohorts of DLI applicants across 10 oversubscribed programs, analyses estimate the intent-to-treat effect of access to bilingual education on reading and math test scores. On average, native English-speaking students in Grades 1 through 4 who win access to a DLI program score higher in reading and math by 0.12 and 0.14 SDs, respectively. The achievement gains in test scores are realized as early as first grade.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 05:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241228829?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>After School: An Examination of the Career Paths and Earnings of Former Teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We use a novel linkage of school district administrative data to Internal Revenue Service records to study educators’ post-exit career outcomes. The majority of leavers remain in education and mean earnings are slightly below pre-exit earnings even 8 years later. However, these average changes conceal wide variation in outcomes. Roughly 20% of leavers are unemployed, and the bottom quartile of employed leavers earn less than $20,000 annually. At the same time, earnings among the top quartile of employed leavers are higher than those of nearly all stayers, sometimes exceeding $100,000. Post-exit employment and earnings declines are associated with the presence of children or a high-earning spouse for voluntary female leavers, suggesting a role for family-conscious policies for teacher retention.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241227906?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race Matters: A Family–Educator Antiracist Curriculum Collaboration</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 02:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2308483?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fostering pre-service teachers’ attention to mathematical objects: The realization tree mediator as a teaching representation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Using teaching representations is one of the common means for preparing pre-service mathematics teachers (PSTs) to learn how to teach mathematics meaningfully. However, turning PSTs’ attention to the mathematical objects that students engage with during the lesson is a challenging pursuit. This paper suggests using the Realization Tree Mediator (RTM) as a visual teaching representation for PST learning to implement cognitively demanding tasks in their classrooms. The RTM depicts the mathematical object at the core of a task and its different realizations while illustrating imaginary classroom discussions in which different realizations and the links between them are produced. By analyzing PSTs’ conversations around RTM images, we show how contrasting pairs of RTMs can be used for eliciting conversations about various aspects of cognitively demanding instruction. We discuss the affordances of the RTM as a teaching representation and how it can assist in making the mathematical content and meanings visible, public, and communicable among teachers and teacher educators.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09622-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial, The transformative power of action research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-25-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2321728?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
