<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher shortages: a social justice perspective on an Australian teacher education policy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2024 10:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2404831?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher use of multimodal signs to support kindergarten students’ developing understanding of mathematical equivalence</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Across multiple age groups and academic disciplines, research has shown that incorporating multimodal signs into instruction can enhance student learning. For instance, gesture might be synchronized with speech or written signs. The present study reports on the semiotic resources used by a teacher-researcher to support kindergarten students’ developing understanding of the equal sign. An analysis of seven classroom lessons designed to advance students’ understanding of the equal sign and equations in various forms revealed four categories of language and two categories of gesture used by the teacher-researcher that were specifically related to mathematical equivalence. Our findings contribute to understanding the role of multimodal signs in supporting instruction on mathematical equivalence.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00508-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Accelerated Postsecondary Pathways: The Longer-Term Impact of the Early College High School Model on Postsecondary Degree Attainment</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Utilizing a lottery-based natural experiment, this study assessed the longer-term impact of early colleges on postsecondary degree attainment. It found that early colleges significantly increased the overall degree completion and associate degree completion rates within 10 years of expected high school graduation. While the impact on bachelor’s degree or advanced degree attainment was no longer significant 10 years after high school, results from earlier years suggest that early college students attained these degrees at a higher rate and faster pace than control students. This study also found that the early college impact on bachelor’s degree attainment was significantly stronger for underrepresented minorities and that the impact on associate degree attainment was significantly stronger for students with higher prior achievement.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2024 12:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241276855?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Black Teacher Pipeline: Insights From a State Longitudinal Data System</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;We use longitudinal data across public postsecondary institutions in Tennessee to examine the stages at which potential Black educators disproportionately exit the teacher pipeline. Black and White bachelor’s graduates declare and complete teaching-related majors at similar rates, suggesting comparable levels of initial interest in teaching careers; moreover, newly certified Black college graduates are more likely than their White peers to gain employment in the state. However, in between those points, Black undergraduate program completers are substantially less likely to become licensed. Additionally, Black graduate students are less likely to complete master’s degrees in teaching-related majors and receive teaching licenses, though newly certified Black master’s graduates are again more likely to gain employment than their White peers. These results suggest that the largest loss of potential Black teachers occurs at the end of teacher preparation, which can be explained partially but not fully by inequities in certification exam passage rates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2024 01:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241280917?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publisher Correction: Contributions to the characterization of the Schema using APOS theory: Graphing with derivative</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01637-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student approaches to generating mathematical examples: comparing e-assessment and paper-based tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Example-generation tasks have been suggested as an effective way to both promote students’ learning of mathematics and assess students’ understanding of concepts. E-assessment offers the potential to use example-generation tasks with large groups of students, but there has been little research on this approach so far. Across two studies, we investigate students’ responses to a particular sequence of example-generation tasks, posed either on paper or through e-assessment. We identify a striking difference in students’ example-generation strategies and success, for e-assessment and paper-based versions of the same tasks. This suggests the use of example-generation tasks in e-assessment may not be straightforward, and we conclude by discussing the implications for teaching and research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10361-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining Enactments of Project-based Learning in Secondary English Language Arts</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Project-based learning (PBL) grounds instruction in authentic learning experiences where students engage in real-world explorations that culminate in a final product or performance. We report on a mixed methods study with 43 ninth-grade English language arts (ELA) teachers (22 PBL and 21 comparison) and 1,671 students exploring the feasibility of enacting PBL in ELA classrooms and examining how teachers and students perceived this approach to learning. PBL teachers enacted PBL design principles significantly more than comparison teachers. The majority of PBL teachers perceived positive instructional shifts including more student-centered and authentic learning, more student choice, and greater student engagement. Many teachers also expressed a sense of renewal and passion. Students in PBL classrooms reported more meaningful learning experiences, opportunities for collaboration, and other aspects of social and emotional learning. We discuss tensions, including the challenge of covering required content and skills within a PBL-focused classroom.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2024 04:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241269829?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Living in the Big Pond: Adding the Neighborhood as a Frame of Reference for Academic Self-Concept Formation</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research on the big-fish-little-pond effect demonstrates that class-average achievement negatively affects students’ academic self-concept via social comparison processes. The neighborhood-effects literature reports positive effects of advantageous socioeconomic neighborhood conditions on students’ academic development via collective socialization mechanisms. To investigate how socioeconomic neighborhood conditions affect academic self-concept, we separately and simultaneously analyzed classroom- and neighborhood-level composition effects on students’ academic self-concept, using two samples drawn from two grade levels ([math] = 3,906, [math] = 3,277). Analyses of the neighborhood level only indicate that socioeconomic neighborhood conditions negatively predict general, math, and German self-concept in Grade 5. In Grade 9, this holds only for math self-concept. In simultaneous analyses including classrooms and neighborhoods, socioeconomically advantageous neighborhood conditions negatively predicted general and math self-concept in Grade 5.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2024 04:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241269816?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A survey of Spanish research in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This survey paper presents recent relevant research in mathematics education produced in Spain, which allows the identification of different broad lines of research developed by Spanish groups of scholars. First, we present and describe studies whose research objectives are related to student learning of specific curricular contents and process-oriented competencies, namely arithmetic, algebra, geometry, functions and calculus, probability and statistics, and argumentation or proof in geometric contexts. Next, we present characteristics and foci of investigations dealing with different aspects of mathematics teacher education, encompassing a large part of Spanish research in mathematics education. The descriptions of other transversal lines of research complement the previous two big blocks: research on students with special educational needs and the effects of using technology in different curricular contents and educational levels. Finally, we report on the research activities and advances of Spanish research in mathematics education from two main theoretical frameworks created or developed by Spanish researchers. This plurality of research strands also corresponds to a wide range of international collaborations, especially with Latin American colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01638-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leaks in the College Access Pipeline: Examining Summer Melt in a Large Urban School District</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Some high school seniors who plan to attend college in the fall following graduation do not enroll. This phenomenon, known as summer melt, contributes to lower educational attainment, particularly among low-income students. We extend the literature on summer melt in two ways. First, we show that melt estimates can be sensitive to measurement decisions and local context, and in particular that estimates based on student-level National Student Clearinghouse data can overstate the extent of summer melt. Second, we show that aspects of students’ behavior and perceptions, such as their attendance rates, Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA) completion, and confidence about their intended college, predict summer melt. These results suggest ways that school staff and summer melt interventions could potentially target additional support to college-intending students to facilitate their successful transition to college.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 12:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241278314?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Application of Behavioral Economics to Teacher Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher professional development (PD) is among the most prominent levers used to improve teaching quality. The findings of research studies examining PD interventions are heterogeneous, with meta-analyses indicating mean positive impacts but also the existence of many ineffective programs. Educational Researcher has served as a critical platform for conversations on strengthening the research base on teacher PD. In this article, we argue that insights from behavioral economics have the potential to improve professional development research by pointing toward solutions that can strengthen the implementation of well-designed PD. We provide illustrative examples of how concepts from behavioral economics can inform our understanding of barriers to effective PD implementation and discuss behavioral-economics-based tools to mitigate these barriers. We conclude by discussing future applications and research directions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 12:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241282296?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>College Behind Bars: A Historiography of Higher Education in Prison</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article presents a synthesized historiography of higher education in American prisons, exploring interactions of federal, state, and institution-level policies within six specific states: California, Illinois, Massachusetts, Mississippi, New York, and Texas. We define considerations for researchers, policymakers, and advocates regarding efforts to sustain educational access for incarcerated students. Findings suggest access is inextricably linked to policies relying on the social construction of crime and incarceration. As such, sole reliance on federal support may be detrimental for programs. A focus on diversifying funding sources will likely better ensure the long-term durability of support for higher education in prison programming.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 12:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241283017?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Accumulation of Opportunities Predicts the Educational Attainment and Adulthood Earnings of Children Born Into Low- Versus Higher-Income Households</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Scholars theorize that “opportunity gaps” drive achievement disparities between children born into poverty versus affluence. In a 26-year longitudinal study (N = 814), we examine (a) economic disparity in children’s accumulation of opportunities—from birth through high school—at home, childcare, school, afterschool, and in the neighborhood; (b) the extent to which opportunity is linked with educational attainment and earnings in early adulthood; and (c) whether opportunity is most strongly associated with these adult outcomes for children from low-income households. We document large opportunity gaps between children from low- versus higher-income households. These opportunity gaps are strongly linked with educational attainment and earnings, particularly for low-income children, helping explain why household income in early childhood predicts these outcomes in adulthood.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 11:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241283456?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact and Implementation of Academic Interventions During COVID-19: Evidence from the Road to Recovery Project</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Pandemic-era disruptions to schooling resulted in academic setbacks for many students. To help students catch up, school districts nationwide are implementing a range of academic recovery interventions. In this paper, we use multiple data sources to evaluate the impact and implementation of academic recovery interventions in four school districts during the 2021-2022 school year. Our estimates suggest the interventions failed to reach the expected number of students and had little detectable impact on students’ test scores. Interviews with district officials highlight a host of challenges districts faced during the 2021-2022 school year. Considering the overall scale of pandemic learning loss, our results raise urgent questions about the adequacy of academic recovery efforts relative to students’ needs. The results also have implications for how districts might respond to disrupted learning in the future (e.g. in the wake of natural disasters).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 10:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241281286?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcements</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 552-552, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 10:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276118?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The discursive positioning of teacher education in the Flemish teacher shortages policy debate: praise, blame, tensions, and contradictions</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 04:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2407961?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The shortage of teachers in Estonia: Causes and suggestions for additional measures from the perspective of different stakeholders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 04:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2408641?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A decade of PISA: student perceived instructional quality and mathematics achievement across European countries</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study examines the relationship between instructional quality and mathematics achievement, taking into account socioeconomic status. Data from ten European countries participating in PISA 2012 and 2022 were analysed using the framework of the Dynamic Modelling of Educational Effectiveness. In PISA 2012, instructional quality was defined by student-oriented instruction, classroom management, teacher support, disciplinary climate, and cognitive activation. The finding indicated that teacher support, disciplinary climate, and cognitive activation positively predict student achievement, but dimensions of student-oriented instruction and classroom management were negatively related in several countries. Instructional quality was captured by four dimensions in PISA 2022, namely, teacher support, disciplinary climate, cognitive activation in mathematics of encouraging mathematical thinking and of fostering reasoning. Teacher support and disciplinary climate had a positive effect on achievement, but two aspects of cognitive activation had opposite effects on achievement. SES also had significant indirect effects on achievement through various instructional quality dimensions. Across two PISA cycles, teacher support, disciplinary climate, and cognitive activation consistently benefited low-SES students, while classroom management and student-oriented instruction tended to harm their performance. These results underscore the role of instructional quality in promoting equity for disadvantaged students. Trend data from these two cycles of PISA, give an indication of specific instructional strategies that do consistently contribute to student achievement. Implications and findings are discussed in relation to the policy and practice context in different education systems.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01630-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice Mathematics Teachers’ Proportional Reasoning: The Case of Angle Measure Conversions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study explored preservice mathematics teachers’ (PMTs’) use of proportional reasoning given a situation that involves relating degrees to radian angle measure. Five PMTs participated in a semi-structured task-based interview to solve conversion questions from degrees to radians. Thematic analysis of the transcripts showed PMTs using and connecting various proportional reasoning concepts to describe angle measure in radians when given the measure in degrees. The PMTs also justified using memorized facts and calculations for efficiency and practicality. Findings suggest that conversion questions elicit meanings that are attuned to proportional reasoning concepts. I conclude that PMTs’ meanings for the relationship between degrees and radians are complex and not limited to memorization. Mathematics teacher educators can support PMTs by building on proportional reasoning in situations involving conversion between degrees and radians to encourage them to move beyond memorized facts and calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00257-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career change teachers: solving the teacher shortage?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-24-2024 07:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2407546?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of the 5E Instructional Model: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;We conducted a comprehensive, systematic review and meta-analysis on the effects of the BSCS 5E Instructional Model—and its related variants—on science, math, and motivation outcomes. The 5E Instructional Model is a framework for delivering STEM instruction that is based on constructivist learning theory; it has been used throughout the U.S. and other countries, particularly in Turkey. Despite its wide usage, no comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis on the effects of 5E and related models has yet been conducted. Our search and screening procedures yielded 61 randomized controlled trial studies, estimating 156 effect sizes; 70% of studies met WWC standards with or without reservations. We found that the 5E instructional model resulted in improved science outcomes (g = 0.82, 95% CI [0.67, 0.97]), but a large amount of heterogeneity requires some caution (t = 0.56). We explored numerous explanations for the effect heterogeneity and provided practical recommendations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-24-2024 05:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241269866?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: Interpolation and extrapolation in Year 5 STEM activities: exploring data about viscosity without advanced statistics</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-24-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00505-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do You Want to Be a Teacher? A Natural Language Processing Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Heightened concerns about the health of the teaching profession highlight the importance of studying the early teacher pipeline. This exploratory, descriptive article examines preservice teachers’ expressed motivation for pursuing a teaching career. Using data from a large teacher education program in Texas, we use a natural language processing algorithm to categorize into topical groups roughly 2,800 essay responses to the prompt, “Explain why you decided to become a teacher.” We identify 10 topics that largely reflect altruistic and intrinsic (although not extrinsic) reasons for teaching. The frequency of topics varied substantially by preservice teacher gender, race/ethnicity, and certification area. Intrinsic enjoyment of teaching and experiences with adversity predicted higher clinical teaching performance and lower attrition as a full-time teacher.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-23-2024 12:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241276814?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The changing role of ICT-coordinators in schools: a longitudinal study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-23-2024 06:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2406893?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
