<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>In between jockeying and resisting proximities to whiteness: the challenges and promises of cross-racial solidarity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2024 08:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2402327?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The immovable veil of black disability: an introduction to Black disability threat theory and its application to the school to prison nexus</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2024 08:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2398474?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engagement Matters: Reimagining Family, School, and Community Relations in Teacher Education to Improve Student Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/75/4&quot;&gt;Volume 75, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 365-368, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-11-2024 11:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241266315?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘I view teaching differently’: identity development of university teachers doing professional doctorates</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-11-2024 11:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2400480?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Becoming exceptional: the role of capital in the development and mediation of mathematics identity and degree trajectories</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;There is a burgeoning interest in the concept of identity within mathematics education research, with recent work suggesting that the interplay of identity and capital (cultural, social, and economic resources) offers a productive lens for understanding school students’ trajectories into, or away from, mathematics. This paper adds to understandings of how interactions of identity and capital play out over time, focusing on how these mediated the mathematics degree trajectories of three young men, Tom, Neb, and Gerrard, who were selected from a wider longitudinal study, as the only young people who went on to take mathematics degrees. Analysis of longitudinal data from 24 semi-structured interviews, conducted with the three young men from age 10 to 21 and two of their parents/carers, found that all three identified as being “good/exceptional at mathematics”. These identifications developed at an early age, were sustained and augmented by capital, and were closely related to pursuing the subject at university and enjoyment of mathematics. However, developing and sustaining an identity as “good at maths” relied on interactions with mathematics capital through families, school, and wider networks. Moreover, classed differences in the distribution of capital were implicated in their different degree outcomes. We argue that attending to the longitudinal interplay between capital and identity offers a rich understanding of how young people come to see themselves and be seen by others as “naturally able” at mathematics and in turn supports choosing to study a mathematics degree. Implications for mathematics education policy and practice are considered.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10360-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Speaking Stata: Quantile–quantile plots, generalized</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 514-534, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Quantile-quantile plots in the precise sense of scatterplots showing corresponding quantiles of two variables have long been supported by official command qqplot. That command is generalized here in several ways in a new command, qqplotg. In this article, I explain the major features of qqplotg and give several examples of its use. Themes include the use of quantile-quantile plots to explore the possibilities for working on a transformed scale and the value of plotting difference between quantiles versus mean quantile or plotting position. Various historical and methodological remarks are sprinkled throughout.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276114?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 156: Concentration and diversity measures using egen</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 535-545, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276115?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Updates</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 551-551, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276117?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tests and confidence bands for multiple one-sided comparisons</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 446-477, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;One-sided inference should be used in some applications, but Stata has limited support for one-sided tests and confidence intervals for a single compari­son and almost no support for one-sided tests and confidence bands for multiple comparisons. In this article, we provide an introduction to one-sided tests and confidence intervals for a single hypothesis and to one-sided tests and confidence intervals for multiple comparisons. We also discuss extensions of the sotable com­mand introduced in Drukker (2023, Stata Journal 23: 518-544) to cover one-sided tests and confidence bands for a single comparison and for multiple comparisons. We also provide examples of how to use sotable to perform multiple tests against values other than zero and how to perform multiple tests after commands like margins and nlcom that support the post option.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276111?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 157: Adding extra lines to graphs</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 546-550, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276116?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fitting garbage class mixed logit models in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 427-445, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;AbstractIn this article, I describe the garbagejnixl command, which fits the garbage class and standard panel mixed logit models in Stata.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276110?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>cnevent: Event study with Chinese equity market data</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 478-502, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;AbstractIn this article, we present a new command, cnevent, that runs event studies about Chinese-listed companies. With cnevent, researchers are required to provide only a list of events with the Chinese stock code and the corresponding date for each event, and the command can automatically extract indexes and each individual stock’s return data to run the whole process of the event study. Furthermore, cnevent enables users to choose the benchmark from among different market indexes and different event window sets with options. The command then generates daily abnormal returns for all trading days within the event window and aggregates the cumulative abnormal returns (CARs) for the whole event window. Finally, cnevent can plot a graph to show the trend of the CARt within the event window and test whether the event has a significant effect on valuation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276112?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>miesize: Effect-size calculation in imputed data</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 503-513, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I describe the miesize command for the calculation of effect sizes in imputed data. There may be situations where an effect size needs to be estimated for an intervention, an exposure, or a group membership variable but data on the independent or dependent variable are missing. Such missing data are commonly dealt with by multiply imputing plausible values. However, in this circumstance, the estimated effect size and associated standard errors will need to be pooled and estimated from the imputed dataset. The miesize command automates this process and calculates effect sizes for a binary variable from multiply imputed data in wide format. The estimates and standard errors (used to calculate the confidence intervals) are recombined using Rubin’s (1987, Multiple Imputation for Nonresponse in Surveys [Wiley]) rules. These rules are applied such that the average point estimate for the effect size is calculated from the imputed datasets. The pooled standard error, and hence confidence intervals, is calculated to account for both the variance between the imputed datasets and the variance within them. Pooled effect sizes and confidence intervals for Cohen’s (1988, Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences, 2nd ed. [Lawrence Erlbaum]) d, Hedges’s (1981, Journal of Educational Statistics 6: 107-128) g, and Glass’s (Smith and Glass, 1977, American Psychologist 32: 752-760) delta are provided by miesize.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276113?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting away from the cutoff in regression discontinuity designs</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 371-401, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;AbstractRegression discontinuity (RD) designs are highly popular in economic research because of their strong internal validity and straightforward intuition. While RD estimates are local in nature, several recent articles propose methods that generalize RD estimates to units outside a small neighborhood of the cutoff. In this article, I introduce the getaway package, which implements the method proposed by Angrist and Rokkanen (2015, Journal of the American Statistical Association 110: 1331-1344) to extrapolate treatment-effect estimates “away from the cutoff”, relying on a classical unconfoundedness condition. Additionally, the package features a data-driven algorithm designed to identify a set of covariates that fulfills the unconfoundedness assumption. It also incorporates a toolkit intended for testing and visualization purposes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276108?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fitting spatial stochastic frontier models in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/3&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 402-426, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;AbstractIn this article, we introduce a new command, xtsfsp, for fitting spatial stochastic frontier models in Stata. Over the last decades, stochastic frontier models have seen important theoretical progress via the incorporation of various types of spatial components. Models that can account for spatial dependence and spillovers have been developed for efficiency and productivity analysis, drawing extensive attention from industry and academia. Because of the unavailability of the statistical packages, the empirical applications of the new stochastic frontier models appear to be lagging. The xtsfsp command provides a procedure for fitting spatial stochastic frontier models in the style of Orea and Álvarez (2019, Journal of Econometrics 213: 556-577) and Galli (2023, Spatial Economic Analysis 18: 239-258), enabling users to handle different sources of spatial dependence. In this article, we introduce spatial stochastic frontier models, describing the syntax and options of the new command and providing several examples to illustrate its usage.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241276109?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does Teacher Professional Development Improve Student Learning? Evidence from Leading Educators’ Fellowship Model</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 08:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2361467?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The routes to intellectual authority in a prior colonial empire: continued racialised, geopolitical inequalities in the academic staff composition and employment conditions of UK universities</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 01:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2398491?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Productive Problem-Solving Behaviors of Students with Learning Disabilities</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2396720?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching science through art studio methods: Impact on third-grade academic achievements</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 01:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2397407?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measurement invariance between subjects: what can we learn about subject-related differences in teaching quality?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Recent publications emphasize the need to take greater account of differences in teaching quality between subjects. The empirical analysis of this topic requires a comparison of teaching quality in different subjects to distinguish generic aspects of teaching quality from subject-specific ones. In this paper, we compare teaching quality in mathematics and German lessons using observational data from primary schools in Switzerland (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Math&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; = 319; &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;German&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; = 237). Data were collected using an observation instrument reflecting the teaching dimensions of the MAIN-TEACH model, which was developed based on a synthesis of established observation frameworks. The dimensions of classroom management, motivational-emotional support, selection and implementation of content, cognitive activation, support for consolidation, assessment and feedback, and adaptation were tested for subject-related measurement invariance. With a two-fold measurement invariance approach, differences between the subjects were investigated at both a global and an indicator level. When applying alpha accumulation correction, no significant subject-related differences in factor loadings or intercepts were found. The factorial structure of our data was basically identical for the two subjects. The comparison of latent factor means revealed no mean differences between the subjects. We discuss the implications for both the MAIN-TEACH model and research into subject-related differences of teaching in general.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01622-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparative analysis between three theoretical approaches through empirical experiences at university level</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research into mathematics education at university level includes a wide range of theoretical approaches. This poses considerable challenges to researchers in terms of understanding and harmonizing the compatibility and commensurability of those approaches. The research community has already problematised and studied these challenges using networking theories. The networking theories framework is taken as a starting point in this study to contrast different approaches and to broaden the comparison of different frameworks. In particular, three case studies framed in the Action, Process, Object, Schema Theory, in the Problem-Solving approach, and in the Anthropological Theory of the Didactic are analysed. The differences and possible similarities between the three with regard to the research questions addressed, their objects of study, their empirical bases, as well as their research ends are considered. The analysis offers an insight into the potential for collaboration and the networking of theories in the field of university mathematics education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01632-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The emergence of the analytic-structural way of thinking in linear algebra as a blended space</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study aims at elaborating a well-established theoretical framework that distinguishes three modes of thinking in linear algebra: the analytic-arithmetic, the synthetic-geometric, and the analytic-structural mode. It describes and analyzes the bundle of signs produced by an engineering student during an interview, where she was asked to recall linear algebra topics she had learned the previous year. Following the theory of conceptual blending, the presented case study is used as a model for the description of the emergence of the analytic-structural mode. It shows how the evolution of the used signs and their relationships suggests that the analytic-structural mode emerges as a blend between the other two ways of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10354-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Principals’ Priorities, Teacher Evaluation, and Instructional Leadership</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Instructional leadership has become the dominant paradigm in principal preparation and professional learning. In parallel, teacher evaluation has risen in prominence. Using interviews from 84 principals in 23 districts and three states, we asked how teacher evaluation influenced principals’ reported priorities and conceptions of instructional leadership. We found that although teacher evaluation loomed large in principals’ priorities, their implementation of it generally seemed far from robust. Although 81% of our sample noted teacher evaluation as a priority, only 24% reported integrating it into their efforts to improve teaching and learning. As one of the first studies to investigate how teacher evaluation factors into principals’ priorities and conceptions of instructional leadership and the resulting implications, our study extends prior research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-09-2024 11:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241273903?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating the Economic Impacts of a Cage-Free Animal Welfare Policy in Southeast Asian and Indian Egg Production: A Systematic Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Animal welfare is increasingly understood to be a key component of sustainable agricultural production. Southeast Asia and India are witnessing an emerging market for cage-free egg production. To evaluate the economic sustainability of cage-free policies in the region, it is critical to understand how this transition will affect farmers’ costs and revenues. In this article, we provide an overview of the available information that can inform evaluations of cage-free egg production in Southeast Asia and India. Cage-free egg producers around the world tend to experience higher costs, but these costs are offset by higher revenues. As demand for cage-free eggs is stimulated in Southeast Asia and India by retailer or government policies, we expect that producers will be capable of meeting this demand. In Asia specifically, the dominant cost component is poultry feed. We conclude that the economic viability of egg production in the region is likely to be driven by feed prices and associated government policies, rather than production system per se.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-09-2024 07:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241280681?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
