<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating the Effectiveness of Maternal, Neonatal, and Child Healthcare in Moroccan Hospitals and SDG 3: Using Two-Stage Data Envelopment Analysis and Tobit Regression</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Maternal, neonatal, and child health play crucial roles in achieving the objectives of Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) 2030, particularly in promoting health and wellbeing. However, maternal, neonatal, and child services in Moroccan public hospitals face challenges, particularly concerning mortality rates and inefficient resource allocation, which hinder optimal outcomes. This study aimed to evaluate the operational effectiveness of 76 neonatal and child health services networks (MNCSN) within Moroccan public hospitals. Using Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA), we assessed technical efficiency (TE) employing both Variable Returns to Scale for inputs (VRS-I) and outputs (VRS-O) orientation. Additionally, the Tobit method (TM) was utilized to explore factors influencing inefficiency, with hospital, doctor, and paramedical staff considered as inputs, and admissions, cesarean interventions, functional capacity, and hospitalization days as outputs. Our findings revealed that VRS-I exhibited a higher average TE score of 0.76 compared to VRS-O (0.23). Notably, the Casablanca-Anfa MNCSN received the highest referrals (30) under VRS-I, followed by the Khemisset MNCSN (24). In contrast, under VRS-O, Ben Msick, Rabat, and Mediouna MNCSN each had three peers, with 71, 22, and 17 references, respectively. Moreover, the average Malmquist Index under VRS-I indicated a 7.7% increase in productivity over the 9-year study period, while under VRS-O, the average Malmquist Index decreased by 8.7%. Furthermore, doctors and functional bed capacity received the highest Tobit model score of 0.01, followed by hospitalization days and cesarean sections. This study underscores the imperative for policymakers to strategically prioritize input factors to enhance efficiency and ensure optimal maternal, neonatal, and child healthcare outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-20-2024 08:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241264863?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Intervention for early literacy success: Phonological awareness and rapid automatized naming</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2024 12:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2374393?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Finding the sweet spot for insider action research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2024 03:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2381247?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Newly qualified teachers as a resource in school in a micropolitical perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2024 03:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2381577?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unleashing the potential: spatializing middle school mathematics for enhanced learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study assessed the effectiveness of a spatialized mathematics intervention on the mathematical performance and spatial visualization skills of students from an underprivileged Indonesian community. Grade 8 students (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 407) were assigned to one of twelve experimental classes, receiving the spatial mathematics intervention, or one of seven control classes, continuing with the standard mathematics curriculum. Prior to and following the intervention, a pre-test and post-test design was administered. The data were analyzed using Analysis of Covariance to ascertain the effect of the intervention. Results revealed that the students in the experimental group exhibited significant improvements in spatial visualization skills and mathematics performance (including both spatial and non-spatial competencies), compared to the control group. Importantly, the findings provide evidence that the transfer effects of the spatialized curriculum occur differentially for students of varying ability levels. The findings highlight the importance of spatial intervention in enhancing mathematics performance and spatial visualization skills. The study suggests potential avenues for a paradigm shift in mathematics education that recognizes and embraces the profound influence of spatial thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-19-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10343-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Benefits of reflection-based monitoring in action research projects</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article reports on reflection-based monitoring tools developed and used in an action research project to improve gender equality in science and research institutions. Several of these tools were developed to facilitate individual and joint reflection from the perspective of the co-researchers involved. The aim of the article is to make the case for the integration of a systematic reflection-based monitoring approach, to describe its approach and theoretical underpinnings that link critical reflection theory with reflexive action learning theory, and to present the details of six monitoring tools so that they can be adopted in other project settings. It also highlights how these monitoring tools stimulated both individual and group reflection and how they facilitated the sharing of knowledge and experience between change agents involved in co-production. The article also shows that the process monitoring approach based on systematic reflection can contribute to successful project implementation and offers several important advantages.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-18-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241260963?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Re-thinking mathematical connections with theories of difference</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-18-2024 05:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2368476?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial for a special issue on mathematical connections in the teaching and learning of mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-18-2024 05:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2372378?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Oceania in the Desert: A QuantCrit Analysis of the (Under)Counting of Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander Students at an AANAPISI-HSI</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-18-2024 02:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2349671?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students&#39; Self-work During Lectures in Calculus Courses – Cognitive and Affective Effects of a Small Intervention</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study describes the effects of a small pedagogical intervention in first semester calculus at an engineering college; it is a collaboration between two lecturers: a pure mathematician and a mathematics education researcher, who wished to learn about the effects of self-work (i.e., students solving problems on their own during class) on students&#39; exam achievements, self-efficacy, and students&#39; written communication. Students were given mastery experiences of self-work and feedback in three out of five classes. In all five classes, students were given in-class quizzes with peer instruction. Data was collected in multiple forms: quiz results, questionnaires, exam questions, and reflections; both quantitative and qualitative analysis methods were used. The findings show self-work increases students’ engagement and self-efficacy and slightly improved students’ achievement in class and on the final exam grade. Moreover, it positively influences students&#39; learning experience. There were nonconclusive findings for improvement in the quality of students&#39; written communication in the final exam. Self-work can be easily incorporated, even in coordinated courses with a common syllabus and a large lecture, without requiring instructors to make big changes to their lecture style. Effects of self-work should be further studied.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-18-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00249-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Connecting the threads: the role of multiplicative thinking in algebraic, geometrical, and statistical reasoning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-17-2024 09:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2372365?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Twenty-five years of change laboratories in schools: a critical and formative review</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-17-2024 06:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2379343?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building a Better Wall: Assessing Children’s Design Technology Learning in Nature-Based Early Childhood Education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The teaching and learning of design technology that occurs in nature-based early childhood education and care (ECEC) contexts such as nature kindergartens remains under-theorised. There is a growing body of scholarship that describes how teaching and learning occurs in these contexts as well as highlighting the benefits for young children learning in the natural environment. Recently, in the perspective of the Australian ECEC sector, how students experience design technology in nature-based contexts (bush kinders, an adaption of the European forest school approach to ECEC) was reported on. Despite design technology being accounted for in bush kinders as part of play-based learning of STEM, assessment of how this learning is supporting student’s comprehension of design technology remains an area for further attention. Often, educators rely solely on observations and anecdotal note taking for assessment which points to a need to support teachers with more rigorous assessment models. This paper adapts an assessment model for science learning and reconsiders it in terms of design technology teaching and learning. The paper’s aim is to support educators to develop children’s deeper understandings of design technology and make learning meaningful in nature-based education settings. Using vignettes, the children’s learning of design technology available in natural surroundings is analysed. This paper proposes that bush kinders are a valuable context for teaching and learning as they allow educators to develop skills to assess children’s design technology knowledge. The analysis of the data and its consideration against one play-based learning assessment model is also valuable in generating a broader narrative that deepens insights into the teaching and learning experience of design technology education in early childhood nature-based contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00320-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Connections within the Multiplicative Field: A Case Study of Adán’s Mathematical Thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-16-2024 06:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2372976?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Units Construction and Coordination: Past, Present, and Future</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uiml20/16/3&quot;&gt;Volume 16, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, July 2024&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-15-2024 03:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2357046?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/46/3&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Fall 2024, Page 187-188&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-15-2024 03:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2373031?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Classroom profiles of instructional quality: contribution of level and variability of students’ perception</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Different approaches for measuring instructional quality have been debated. Previous studies based on student ratings have primarily used class-average ratings. Beyond this, the high within-classroom variability of students’ ratings might indicate that instruction caters to some, but not all students. Therefore, we investigated student-reported instructional quality in mathematics classrooms by considering the average student ratings and rating heterogeneity within classrooms. Using a case-centered clustering approach, we aimed to detect meaningful configurations of the level and heterogeneity of student-reported instructional quality in terms of the Three Basic Dimensions (TBD): classroom management, cognitive activation, and student support. We analyzed data from &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 973 grade eight students across &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 106 classes. Using Latent Profile Analysis (LPA), we identified four classroom profiles comprising 20% to 28% of the sample. The results indicate that the profile with the lowest average ratings showed consistently high heterogeneity for all indicator variables. However, the profile with the highest average ratings exhibited consistently low heterogeneity. We gained interesting insights into between-class differences in instructional quality by considering rating heterogeneity. Furthermore, we explored how classrooms from the identified profiles differed regarding socio-economic status (SES) and mathematics-related characteristics (interest, intrinsic motivation, self-concept, and achievement).&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01583-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Experts’ intuitive mathematical discourses about integration in complex analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Although complex analysis is part of the study programs of many mathematics undergraduates, little research has been done on how individuals interpret basic concepts from complex analysis. To address this gap, this paper investigates how experts individually think about complex path integrals. For this purpose, the commognitive framework is used to conceptualize experts’ interpretations of mathematical concepts discursively, namely in terms of so-called intuitive mathematical discourses. A total of nine interpretations of complex path integrals, so-called discursive images, as well as eight sets of rules governing their construction, so-called discursive frames, are derived from expert interviews. These interpretations range from a rejection of intrinsic meaning to connections with real and vector analysis, mean values, and individual formulations of theorems. The paper also raises questions for the inclusion of the results into teaching and addresses further research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01610-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racialized teacher tracking: the systematic exclusion of black teachers from advanced-level coursework</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-12-2024 06:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2370763?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Connectivity in resources for teaching graph theory in engineering education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This contribution explores the teaching of graph theory in the context of engineering education. We examine how teachers use collectively designed resources in terms of their backgrounds. After a literature review, we justify the choice to develop an analytical framework for studying the materials in terms of connections to be established in the resources. We suggest developments around the theoretical concept of connectivity, which allows us to analyze the potential connectivity, characterized by the connections enabled by the resources for teaching; and the effective connectivity that develops in teachers’ practices and during the implementation of resources. We study the effective connectivity in terms of each teacher’s personal relationship with graph theory. Graph theory evolves at the interface of mathematics and computer science research. We consider the case of two teachers, a computer scientist and a mathematician in a French Engineering School in France. The data collected consists of resources for teaching graph theory in engineering courses and interviews with teachers. As for results, we characterize how forms of connectivity developed in the use of resources for teaching graph theory are largely determined by the teachers’ backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01613-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Testing the potency of ethnoscience instruction on biology students’ critical thinking ability</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/vjer20/117/4&quot;&gt;Volume 117, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, 2024, Page 218-227&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2024 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2373464?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hurdles and Straightaways: Building a Cross-School Community of Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2024 01:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2373126?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unraveling high-quality mathematics teaching in algebra: insights from overlaying domain-specific and content-specific observation instruments</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When analyzing instructional quality in mathematics, observational measures can consider domain-specific instructional approaches (e.g., effective teaching of mathematics) and content-focused practices (e.g., effective teaching of a specific mathematical topic). In this study, we analyze lesson videos from secondary algebra classrooms using two different instruments—one focused on ambitious mathematics teaching practices and one focused on instructional features that support students’ learning opportunities in algebra specifically. We consider the information provided by overlaying these instruments to raise implications for instructional improvement efforts, particularly related to how information from the instruments might inform formative feedback to teachers. We consider how alignment between instrument and instructional emphasis can influence the strengths and areas of instructional improvement identified in a given lesson. We further model a collaborative process for looking across observation instruments to deepen understanding of the information provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01606-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inside the Black Box: Detecting and Mitigating Algorithmic Bias Across Racialized Groups in College Student-Success Prediction</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Colleges and universities are increasingly turning to algorithms that predict college-student success to inform various decisions, including those related to admissions, budgeting, and student-success interventions. Because predictive algorithms rely on historical data, they capture societal injustices, including racism. In this study, we examine how the accuracy of college student success predictions differs between racialized groups, signaling algorithmic bias. We also evaluate the utility of leading bias-mitigating techniques in addressing this bias. Using nationally representative data from the Education Longitudinal Study of 2002 and various machine learning modeling approaches, we demonstrate how models incorporating commonly used features to predict college-student success are less accurate when predicting success for racially minoritized students. Common approaches to mitigating algorithmic bias are generally ineffective at eliminating disparities in prediction outcomes and accuracy between racialized groups.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241258741?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
