<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Profiling Teachers’ Motivation for Professional Development: A Nationwide Study</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Situated in the context of advanced placement (AP) reform in the United States, we investigated profiles of teachers’ motivation for participating in professional development (PD) courses in a two-cohort sample of nt1 = 2,369 and nt2 = 2,170 chemistry teachers via multilevel latent class analysis. In addition, the study investigated to what extent profile membership was related to factors at the teacher, school, and PD levels. Participation in PD courses was associated with one of three profiles, labeled “reform-motivated,” “convenience-motivated,” and “interaction-motivated.” Participation in PD courses was more likely to be reform-motivated if a teacher had a major in chemistry, more experience teaching AP, more positive attitudes toward PD, or higher enactment of AP redesign in the classroom, or if the PD course was formal and face-to-face. The results show that teachers have different motivations for participating in PD courses and provide insight into how to engage teachers in professional learning.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-08-2024 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241247777?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Whether and How Teacher Residencies Offer a Different Kind of Preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The past two decades have seen the rise of the residency model, another nontraditional pathway to certification that offers an intensive, practice-based, context-specific preparation designed to address shortages in hard-to-staff districts. Although advocates call the model innovative, research examining residencies at scale warrants skepticism around whether they truly offer a distinctive preparation. Surveying all programs across Tennessee about their adoption of features that characterize the model, we find that residencies offer a unique pathway to teaching in some expected ways though not all. Specifically, residencies reported longer clinical placements, more financial support for residents, and higher rates of mentor training, though they mostly did not report unique practices of candidate recruitment, district partnership, mentor selection, or curricular design. Moreover, we see that the distinctiveness of the model is in decline, with evidence of its dilution among newer residencies and the spread of its features among traditional programs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-07-2024 10:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241231937?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preliminary Development of the Racial Equity-Oriented Social-Emotional Learning Practices Measure</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;This article delineates the development of a measure to assess teachers’ reported engagement in practices that center on issues of racial equity as part of their SEL instruction. An iterative mixed-method approach included theoretical grounding, literature reviews, content expert evaluation, focus groups, cognitive interviews, and multiple survey administrations. Exploratory and confirmatory factor analyses were conducted using data from three independent samples of fifth- to eighth-grade teachers (N range = 240–260; White = 67–89%; Black = 3–7%; Latinx = 5–23%). Test-retest reliability was assessed in a fourth national sample from the RAND American Education Panels (N = 482; Black/African American = 19.9%, Latino/Hispanic = 16.2%, Asian/Asian American = 2.7%, American Indian/Native American = 1.9%, White = 66.0%, Middle Eastern/North African = 0.6%, and Other = 2.7%). Results suggest (1) evidence of strong internal consistency for the 41-item Racial Equity-oriented Social Emotional Learning (REQSEL) measure; (2) REQSEL scores correlated with multiple relevant measures of teachers’ beliefs and behaviors regarding race, ethnicity, culture, and social justice; and (3) REQSEL scores correlated with teachers’ own ethnic-racial identity beliefs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-06-2024 11:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241246717?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modeling Partial Knowledge in Multiple-Choice Cognitive Diagnostic Assessment</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Diagnostic tests are typically administered in a multiple-choice (MC) format due to their advantages of objectivity and time efficiency. The MC-deterministic input, noisy “and” gate (DINA) family of models, a representative class of cognitive diagnostic models for MC items, efficiently and parsimoniously estimates the mastery profiles of examinees. However, the existing models often overestimate the latent traits of examinees when they respond with partial knowledge, which is often observed in educational assessment. Therefore, the novel models of the MC-DINA family that can appropriately handle such responses were developed in this study. Unlike the existing models, the proposed models placed no restrictions on the Q-vector, which represents attribute specifications. Simulation and empirical studies verified that the proposed approach could resolve the overestimation problem.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-06-2024 09:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241245707?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Within-Year Teacher Turnover in Head Start and Children’s School Readiness</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers in early childhood education (ECE) settings are central to providing children with high-quality experiences that promote both early development and long-term well-being; unfortunately, rates of teacher turnover are high in ECE settings. There are strong theoretical reasons to assume turnover is negatively linked with children’s academic and socioemotional development, but few empirical studies test this hypothesis. Using an econometric fixed effects approach in two waves of data from the nationally representative Head Start Family and Child Experiences Survey, this study provides the first national estimate of the relationship between within-year lead teacher turnover and children’s development in Head Start. I find an annual within-year turnover rate of ~9%, about twice that of K–12, and that turnover is negatively associated with children’s language outcomes alongside suggestive evidence for behavioral outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-06-2024 09:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241245094?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Long and Winding Road: Mapping the College and Employment Pathways to Teacher Education Program Completion in Washington State</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Nationally, more than 75% of individuals who are credentialed to teach are prepared in traditional college- or university-based teacher education programs (TEPs). But the college and employment pathways that prospective teachers take to TEP enrollment and completion have not been comprehensively examined. A better understanding of how credentialed individuals find their way into TEPs helps us understand the sources of new teacher supply early in the prospective teacher pipeline. With that in mind, we analyze pathways into and through TEPs using historical postsecondary and unemployment insurance data from Washington State. We find that the pathways are quite varied, with around 40% of bachelor’s-level TEP completers spending at least some time in community colleges and fewer than 40% enrolling and finishing at the same university directly after high school. Pathways to master’s TEP completion are even more varied, with almost half of the completers having prior employment experience. For researchers, this varied landscape raises important questions about the relationship between pathways, candidate persistence, and eventual job performance. For policymakers, the results suggest that efforts to recruit the next generation of teachers need to look beyond the pool of students already enrolled at a 4-year university to include students at 2-year colleges or in the labor force who might be interested in entering a TEP.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-06-2024 08:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241247848?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ever English Learner 4-Year Graduation: Toward an Intersectional Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This brief analyzes 4-year graduation rates among students ever classified as English learners (ever-ELs) and those never classified as English learners (never-ELs) at the intersections of gender, race/ethnicity, and neighborhood income. We follow two cohorts of New York City students who entered ninth grade in 2013–2014 and 2014–2015 (N = 127,931). We find substantial variations in 4-year graduation among these subgroups, with differential predicted probabilities depending on the student’s ever-EL status, race/ethnicity, and neighborhood income. These findings reveal important intersectional disparities in this diverse group of ELs—nuances that are lost when analyzing across a single social dimension and that push us to adopt an intersectional lens in quantitative research on ELs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-06-2024 02:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241246747?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the reliability and validity of multiple mini-interviews in admission to teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-05-2024 03:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2351068?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racialized Patterns in the Distribution of Congressional Pork: Implications for Postsecondary Equity and Organizational Transformation</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Troubled by the inequities in competitive grantmaking, we use critical quantitative methods to analyze the FY2023 federal academic earmarks as a potential mechanism for racialized change work. Specifically, we ask: To what extent does Congress distribute academic earmarks in ways that reinforce or weaken the racialized stratification of resources across organizations in the field? Accordingly, we identify distribution patterns of academic earmarks, considering the allocation of dollars and types of earmarks (i.e., general capacity-building versus specialized grants) across colleges and universities, between White-serving institutions and minority-serving institutions (MSIs), and among MSIs. Based on our analysis, Congress favored a racially reproductive funding portfolio, driven by smaller and more restrictive allocations, not fewer earmarks. However, the distribution of earmarks among MSIs defied normed expectations, as Congress did not privilege whiter, more prestigious MSIs, signaling the potential of pork-barrel politics for racially reparative work.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-04-2024 12:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241245973?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acceptable dark skinned women and egotistical light skinned women: black women speak on colorism and colorist microaggressions within the black community on campus</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-04-2024 10:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2349870?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strategies and interventions employed by teachers in supporting students with mathematics learning difficulties in Kenya</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-03-2024 12:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2339811?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing preschool teacher graduate students’ professional identity with action research: connecting theory and practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-02-2024 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2349536?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reconceptualising school placement assessment in initial teacher education: a figurational perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-02-2024 11:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2345904?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An investigation of teacher candidates’ ideologies towards emergent bilingual students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-02-2024 10:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2349611?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Robot-Assisted Language Learning: A Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This meta-analysis included 27 empirical studies to explore the effectiveness of robot-assisted language learning (RALL) as well as the moderating effects of a number of variables. The comparison of 64 effect sizes from 2,637 participants indicated significant variability between the independent samples. The overall results showed that the combined linguistic and affective gain of RALL was significant. The results of moderator analysis showed that most moderators, including place of the study, type of robot, publication type, instructional level of the learners, design of the study, time points of assessment, learning setting, second language (L2) proficiency level, type of assessment, language domain, and the non-RALL condition had no significant effects on learning outcomes. However, the moderating effect of the participants’ age was significant as RALL was found to be more effective for elementary school students (7–12 years old). The findings provide insights into the design of effective robots for second language acquisition (SLA) that support learners with certain characteristics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-02-2024 05:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241247227?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating equal groups from n items: mathematical creativity in kindergarten</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study examines the solutions of 34 kindergarten children as they create equal groups from &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; bottle caps, where &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; was equal to 8, 9, 22, and 23. For each &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;, children were asked to find as many different solutions as possible. The number of solutions they found, i.e., children’s fluency, as well as the strategies used to create equal groups, was analyzed. Findings indicated that for large numbers, fluency was greater for an even number of objects than for an odd number of objects. In general, most children reached only one solution. For all four tasks, most children created only two equal groups of caps, even though they could have created three groups or more. A significant association was found between tasks and a preferred strategy. While children employed between one and two strategies when working on a single task, when considering all four tasks, they generally employed between two and three strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10322-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Tribute to Guy Brousseau</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00235-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working Interinstitutionally to Apprentice Doctoral Students in Mathematics Education Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Journal for Research in Mathematics Education&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 55&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 3&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 119-126
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/jrme/55/3/article-p119.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identity, Power, and Dignity: A Positional Analysis of Gisela in Her High School Mathematics Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Journal for Research in Mathematics Education&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 55&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 3&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 127-147
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/jrme/55/3/article-p127.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Attending to Coherence Among Research Questions, Methods, and Claims in Coding Studies</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Journal for Research in Mathematics Education&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 55&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 3&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 148-155
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/jrme/55/3/article-p148.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Energizing a Sustainability Inquiry</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 326-335
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p326.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Lunar Phases With the Moon Pie ­Simulation</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 336-345
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p336.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modeling the Impact of the Chernobyl Disaster</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 346-352
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p346.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Make Your Number Talks More Ambitious</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 5&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 353-360
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/5/article-p353.xml</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
