<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Mental Health and District Employee Support in Rural Communities: A Sequential Exploratory Mixed Methods Study</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although existing research explores the need for mental health for students in P-12 schools, scholarship regarding mental health needs and support for teachers is lacking, particularly in rural contexts. This study used sequential exploratory mixed methods to explore mental health needs and support in school districts in a predominantly rural state. Analysis included qualitative survey data from P-12 teachers in school districts about how teaching impacts mental health, and a quantitative analysis of employee assistance programs in participant school districts. Findings demonstrated teachers struggling with mental health, and a lack of employee support available. Implications and exploration of district policy are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-18-2024 09:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241305528?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-17-2024 12:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241310025?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Link Between Students’ Sense of School Belonging and Shared Leadership in U.S. High Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;This study investigated whether and to what extent shared leadership in school was associated with a positive and equitable sense of school belonging among students from diverse backgrounds in the United States. We denoted shared leadership as collective practices that take place in schools in which principals enact inclusive practices in the decision-making process and teachers collaborate with their colleagues to support all students’ learning. We used linear mixed-effects modeling to analyze a nationally representative sample from the base-year data of the High School Longitudinal Study of 2009 (HSLS:09) provided by the National Center for Education Statistics (NCES). Our exploratory analyses revealed that shared leadership practices in school were positively associated with all students’ school belonging. We also found that shared leadership practices in school contributed to American Indian/Alaska Native students’ positive sense of school belonging through a cross-level interaction effect.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-17-2024 06:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241304699?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Critical Participatory (Action Research) adaptation in the Teaching English as a Second Language Practicum: developing individual and collective reflective practices towards equitable practices</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-16-2024 09:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2439980?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tikking the Tok and Leading the Way: Teacherpreneurs Leading on TikTok</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-16-2024 09:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2442313?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CareACT in communities. Theatre interventions for justice-oriented and participatory learning processes in Caring Communities</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-16-2024 05:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2439975?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Chilling Effects of Tennessee’s Prohibited Concepts Law: What Is the Potential Role of School Board Members and Superintendents?</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Prohibited concept laws have a chilling effect on teaching, resulting in the erasure of social justice topics; however, the extent to which district-level actors support such laws or the role they play in perpetuating the effect is unclear. I offer a framework for understanding how district-level policy messaging contributes to the chilling effect in the context of increased partisanship and nationalized politics at the local level. I use survey data to describe school board members’ and superintendents’ perceptions of Tennessee’s PK–12 Prohibited Concepts Law. Overall, there is support for the law, but there are significant differences between the perspectives of school board members and superintendents, with the latter more likely to express neutrality. There are no differences by location, but there are significant differences based on political affiliation and perspectives about state control of curriculum, supporting the larger trend of increased nationalized partisanship of local politics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-16-2024 03:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241304750?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A scientometric study of pre-service teacher preparation for educational equity and social justice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-15-2024 11:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2432891?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strengths-Based Approaches to Investigating Early Math Development in Family and Community Context: A Conceptual Framework</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research and practice that builds on family strengths is uniquely positioned to support children’s math learning in ecologically valid and culturally meaningful ways. Yet, there is little specificity as to what it means to take a strengths-based approach in early math research. We propose a conceptual framework for studying early math from a strengths perspective, as an extension of sociocultural theory and family funds of knowledge. We propose four construct domains critical to the study of strengths (family knowledge/skills, family routines, family interests, community knowledge) and two methodological considerations (participatory design, adaptability of resources). To demonstrate the framework as a tool for organizing cumulative knowledge, we classify exemplar strengths-based studies of early math (n = 11) according to the construct domains and methodology considerations. Our aims are to improve the specificity with which strengths-based perspectives in early math are operationalized and to provide a framework for evaluating literature and guiding future studies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-14-2024 11:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241302059?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>In School, Engaged, on Track? The Effect of the Pandemic on Student Attendance, Course Grades, and Grade Retention in North Carolina</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We examine effects of the pandemic on student attendance, course grades, and grade retention in North Carolina in 2020–2021 and 2021–2022 using descriptive and regression analyses. We find each outcome worsened on average in 2020–2021, with larger changes at the high end of the absence distribution, the low end of the grade distribution, and among historically marginalized student groups. In 2021–2022, grade and retention outcomes recovered, but attendance worsened. Furthermore, gaps between students narrowed, driven by greater recovery in grades for students who were initially most negatively impacted but worsening absenteeism among students who initially maintained high attendance. These findings highlight the substantial variation in impacts of the pandemic across students and differing patterns of impact and recovery across outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-14-2024 11:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241299397?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Integrating Content and Language Instruction for Multilingual Learners: A Systematic Review Across Program Types</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Given the growing multilingual student population worldwide, many countries/regions have implemented content-based instruction (CBI) programs that include content-area classrooms where language learning takes place during content learning. Scholars have suggested that more attention needs to be given to how teachers teach language in content-area classrooms and that research findings across program contexts should speak to/build on each other. This systematic review draws on sociolinguistic theories to synthesize 199 studies from 2012–2022 about teacher understandings and practices regarding content-language integration across CBI programs worldwide, including content and language integrated learning (CLIL), English medium of instruction (EMI), immersion or dual language bilingual education (DLBE), and English as a second/additional language (ESL/EAL). Studies described uneven understandings of the content-language relationship and indicated a variety of content-language integration practices (e.g., teaching disciplinary literacy, encouraging discussion, translanguaging, writing language objectives, using visuals, and collaborating between content and language teachers). However, researchers reported challenges including lack of training, time, and curricular guidance. Based on these findings, we offer directions for research and educator preparation/professional learning to help teachers implement content-language integrated practices that support multilingual learners in developing deep content and language learning in content-area classrooms across contexts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-14-2024 09:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241298667?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Attending to Race in Teacher Well-Being Interventions: A Systematic Review and Recommendations</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Many teachers are dissatisfied with their jobs, struggle with feeling effective at work, experience high levels of stress and burnout, and report higher levels of depressive symptoms than the average adult. Moreover, growing evidence shows that teachers’ professional experiences are racialized, resulting in well-being disparities between White teachers and Teachers of Color (TOC). In this article, we use a novel AI-assisted tool to review existing research on interventions (N = 89) geared to improve teacher well-being, with a specific focus on whether and to what extent researchers acknowledge or discuss the racialized nature of teachers’ professional experiences. Grounded in a theory of schools as racialized organizations, we (a) review the most common intervention strategies for improving teacher well-being and (b) document the extent to which teacher well-being interventions address race or racism in their designs and analyses. Consistent with past work, we find that the vast majority of interventions to improve teacher well-being aim to equip teachers with psychological tools (mindfulness, coping strategies, compassion training) to navigate their professional experiences. However, only half of the studies reviewed here report the racial demographics of their samples, and only four consider how their interventions might differentially impact TOC versus White teachers. We discuss the reasons for and implications of this omission from the teacher well-being literature and provide recommendations for researchers to contend with the racialized nature of teacher well-being in research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-14-2024 09:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241289568?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Complex text and fluency: Evaluating the read like us protocol with third and fourth grade students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-14-2024 09:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2436875?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-14-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2442163?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improving Ninth Graders’ Academic Outcomes Through Personalization for Academic and Social-Emotional Learning (PASL)</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Personalization for academic and social-emotional learning (PASL) is a systemic approach to high school reform that works to strengthen and bridge preexisting academic and social-emotional systems within schools and classrooms. Analyzing student administrative records from 12 schools in a large Florida urban district, we found that, on average, PASL was associated with fewer unexcused absences of ninth graders. Its effects were stronger for students with prior disciplinary incidents in increasing credits earned and reducing unexcused absences. PASL effects did not vary by student race/ethnicity or family income status. The findings provide evidence for the school reform model with an improvement-science approach and suggest directions for supporting students with middle to high school transition.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2024 11:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241296102?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inequality Beyond Standardized Tests: Trends in Extracurricular Activity Reporting in College Applications Across Race and Class</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;For years, discussions on inequality in college admissions have addressed standardized tests, but less is known about inequality in nonstandardized components of applications. We analyzed extracurricular activity descriptions in 6,054,104 applications submitted through the Common Application using natural language processing methods. Overall, White, Asian American, wealthier, and private-school students reported more activities, top-level leadership roles, and distinctive accomplishments (e.g., honors and awards). However, there was little to no difference in the percentage of activities with top-level leadership roles for different racial/ethnic groups. Disparities decrease when controlling for key variables, but salient differences related to race and class remain. Findings do not necessarily support a return to required standardized tests or ending consideration of activities in admissions. Implications are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2024 11:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241292309?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cripistemologies of Teacher Education: Centering Disabled Ways of Knowing in Learning to Teach</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Extant research demonstrates the deeply embedded intersections of racism and ableism in school systems. In response, researchers have proposed DisCrit Classroom Ecology as a framework for teaching and learning that rejects the deficit positioning of multiply-marginalized students and reimagines schooling to amplify their assets. However, little is known about the enactment of these pedagogies by disabled and multiply-marginalized teacher candidates (TCs). This study used DisCrit Classroom Ecology and cripistemology as a conceptual frame to examine how four disabled TCs engaged in culture circles to implement anti-ableist and antiracist pedagogy. Our findings show that disabled and multiply-marginalized TCs offered significant insight into the process of learning to teach but also highlighted the ways in which ableism gets normalized as a standard for teaching proficiency, thus creating unique challenges for disabled TCs to navigate. Implications for teacher education and future research are explored.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2024 09:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241301996?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Framework for Designing Consequential Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Building from established literature and his research, Milner introduces a framework for designing consequential research. The framework is constructed to help researchers design, identify, and assess research as potentially consequential. In particular, the framework is developed for researchers to intentionally include essential elements that might lead to consequentiality: research worth conducting because it identifies problem spaces with an explicit aim to solve, address, and improve them. Six interrelated principles shape the framework in designing consequential research: (a) understand and connect history, (b) respond to and advance knowledge base, (c) amplify researcher positionality, (d) reject essentializing and polarization, (e) prioritize voices of those most marginalized, and (f) consider multiple dissemination outlets.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2024 11:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241298244?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/edra/53/9&quot;&gt;Volume 53, Issue 9&lt;/a&gt;, Page 531-535, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2024 06:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241303810?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Adolescents Acquire Cultural Capital Through Social Capital Access and Exposure? Experimental Evidence of the Impact of Ties to College-Educated Adults</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Scholars question whether cultural capital reproduces existing inequalities or leads to upward mobility. While families provide opportunities to increase cultural capital, schools value and reward cultural capital. Thus, adolescents need to obtain cultural capital through their families to be able to navigate the education system. However, most research does not provide causal evidence of cultural capital acquisition and lacks clarity about how disadvantaged adolescents might increase cultural capital. We hypothesize that adolescents may increase cultural capital through social capital access and exposure—their ties to and meeting frequency with other important adults knowledgeable about the education system. Using data from a randomized control trial on mentoring relationships, we find that high levels of social capital positively affect cultural capital, but only for otherwise disadvantaged adolescents with parents who have some college experience. Our findings suggest cultural capital may be a more limited engine of mobility if disadvantaged adolescents from less educated households cannot acquire or increase their cultural capital.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2024 05:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241305120?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Multilingual Learners and Elementary Science Achievement: Exploring Trends and Heterogeneity Across Subgroups</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Multilingual learners (MLs) represent an increasing proportion of public school students. Although much attention has been given to their academic performance in English language arts and math, less research has addressed their academic performance in science, particularly in elementary school. This study leveraged nationally representative data from the Early Childhood Longitudinal Study of 2010–2011 to document the science test score trajectories of MLs from kindergarten through fifth grade. Using descriptive statistics and regression analyses, our findings document wide variation in elementary science test performance among subgroups of MLs while also documenting the rapid gains this group makes in science performance across the elementary years compared with non-MLs. Our study is among the first to use nationally representative data to examine science learning trajectories of MLs and provides a foundation for policy, practice, and future research aimed at understanding how the linguistic assets of MLs promote science learning.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2024 05:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241303498?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Construction of subitized units is related to the construction of arithmetic units</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10375-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Starting Well: A Meta-Analysis of the Relationship Between Socioeconomic Status and Academic Skills in Early Childhood</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study presents a meta-analysis of the relationship between socioeconomic status (SES) and academic skills in early childhood using both cross-sectional and longitudinal effect sizes. The cross-sectional (111 studies with 435 effect sizes representing 86,808 participants) and longitudinal (59 studies with 321 effect sizes representing 46,870 participants) analyses show midlevel effect sizes (r cross = 0.25, r long = 0.31). The moderation analyses reveal that (a) higher GDP per capita strengthens the SES–academic skill relation in a cross-sectional analysis; (b) early education expansion might reduce the effect of SES on academic skill over time; (c) income inequality does not moderate the relation between SES and academic skill; and (d) the pooled longitudinal relation (i.e., within one year) between SES and academic skill is larger than the pooled cross-sectional relation. Taken together, these findings can guide future work on the relationship between SES and academic skill in early childhood.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2024 09:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241293448?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sounding like the Chil’ren’s Qyah: The Case of Black Language and One Black Male Mathematics Teacher’s Pedagogy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2024 06:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2435201?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
