<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>“What’s that supposed to mean?”: Examining Chicanx/Latinx transfer student intersectional microaggressions at a public four-year research-intensive university</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2024 12:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2394071?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Associations Between Administrative Burden and Children’s ECE Stability During the Covid-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The Covid-19 pandemic caused widespread closures of early care and education (ECE) facilities that negatively impacted children’s socioemotional, behavioral, and academic development. Policies permitting child care centers to remain open by obtaining waivers from closure directives involved varying levels of administrative burden. This study examined administrative burden within waiver policies and its association with ECE stability, as measured by children’s enrollment in waiver-obtaining child care centers. I found Black children were significantly less likely than White children to be enrolled in a waiver-obtaining center, and also far less likely to have a center that obtained a waiver very early on in the pandemic. Analyses showed rates of enrollment in waiver-obtaining centers were far lower among children whose centers experienced more administrative burden, and suggested racial disparities in ECE stability were driven by Black children’s concentrated residence in communities where the waiver application process was more burdensome.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2024 09:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241271356?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educational Philanthropy’s “Racial Reckoning” in the Wake of 2020: Understanding Grantmakers’ Responses to Racialized Crises</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The intersection of the COVID-19 pandemic and anti-Black violence prompted talk of racial reckoning among educational grantmakers in 2020 to 2021. This study examines the nature and extent of this reckoning, offering insights into policy actors’ responses to racialized crises. Through an analysis of grantmakers’ professed policy repertoires—consisting of administrative practices, sites of intervention, and sources of expertise—we delineate the mechanisms shaping grantmaker responses to sociopolitical crises. While some grantmakers temporarily shifted administrative practices in response to COVID-19, deeper changes remained elusive. The study highlights how institutionalized white-centered norms and practices persist within educational policymaking, constraining material progress toward racial equity. Moreover, it underscores the pivotal role of proximity to racial injustice in motivating substantive changes to policy repertoires. We conclude with an appeal to grantmakers and other policy actors to shift from performative reckoning to tangible reparative actions that can weaken racialized structures.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2024 12:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241263843?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improving the Estimation of Site-Specific Effects and Their Distribution in Multisite Trials</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In multisite trials, researchers are often interested in several inferential goals: estimating treatment effects for each site, ranking these effects, and studying their distribution. This study seeks to identify optimal methods for estimating these targets. Through a comprehensive simulation study, we assess two strategies and their combined effects: semiparametric modeling of the prior distribution and alternative posterior summary methods tailored to minimize specific loss functions. Our findings highlight that the success of different estimation strategies depends largely on the amount of within-site and between-site information available from the data. We discuss how our results can guide balancing the trade-offs associated with shrinkage in limited data environments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2024 09:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241254286?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“History-in-person: who is afraid to become an English Teacher?“</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2024 02:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2395334?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning through teaching: novice mathematics teacher educators coping with unfamiliarity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;There is a growing research interest in examining how mathematics teacher educators grow professionally in their practice. In this study, we focus on the experiences of novice mathematics teacher educators who had been secondary mathematics teachers before becoming instructors of an elementary methods course. During individual, semi-structured interviews, the participants (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 6) described their general experience in teaching the course and shared specific incidents that informed their practice. Our analysis reveals that this specific group of mathematics educators experienced multiple layers of unfamiliarity with the methods course, including unfamiliarity related to the elementary school context and to the course students, in response to which they adopted various coping strategies. We illustrate what novice mathematics teacher educators learned from their experiences of unfamiliarity, and how their expanded personal knowledge was reflected in their subsequent teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09654-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Research-based design of coaching for ambitious mathematics instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Despite the evidence of its effectiveness on student learning, ambitious mathematics instruction has proven to be challenging for teachers to enact. Increasingly, instructional coaching programs have become a way of providing intensive one-on-one support to teachers to improve the quality of mathematics instruction. Researchers have identified various design features of effective mathematics coaching programs (e.g., lesson planning, co-teaching, deep and specific discussions of instruction). However, there is a lack of theoretical explanation for how and why these design features support teacher learning, which is critical for successfully implementing and adapting what &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;. Motivated by the need to illuminate what current research has left in the shadows, we first identify the processes of teacher learning based on past research and then illustrate how specific design features of a new coaching model can work together to activate these processes and consequently produce teacher learning. We use the conjecture mapping approach to achieve our goal, informed by a research-based high-level conjecture: Effective coaching programs engage teachers in learning processes similar to the learning processes that students experience in ambitious classrooms. This work will guide the development of an empirically grounded theory for teacher learning through coaching. The reification of teacher learning processes is particularly important for the adaptation of coaching practices in different contexts and content areas. We also argue that focusing on these processes will bring a new perspective to coach navigation of tensions, for example, between responsiveness and directiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09637-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rezoning Educational Opportunities: The Relationship Between School Attendance Zone Boundary Changes and Access to Schools of Varying Quality</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;U.S. public schools provide substantially different educational opportunities to students—even within school districts, where attendance zone boundaries (AZBs) shape most children’s access to schools. The (re)drawing of AZBs is therefore a highly consequential policy decision. In this paper, I study how AZB changes in the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area affect children of different races between 2000 and 2020, including how they alter children’s travel times to school and access to school-level educational opportunities. Findings are starkly unequal, with rezoning disproportionately negatively affecting Black and Hispanic children. Results highlight the need for educational leaders to explicitly consider how AZB changes will redistribute opportunity within their districts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-29-2024 10:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241271370?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Number Talks as Access to Teaching Practices: Pre-Service teachers’ Attention to Mathematical Teaching Practices While Reflecting on Number Talks Enacted in a Field Placement</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-29-2024 10:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2393060?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Shifting Towards Didactic Thinking Development as a Tool for Mathematics Teachers’ Agency</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Contributing to a scientific field is not always a scenic route. One cannot always act in the world according to the posted signs others have thought constituted relevant information. In doing so, one would prevent itself from taking uncharted roads with possibly much to discover. This autoethnographic journey of a didactician of mathematics tells the story of what might happen if we take a side road. Moving from a deficit-oriented perspective of professional development, summarized as teaching didactic knowledge to teachers, to contributing to the development of the teachers’ didactic thinking as a tool for agency is not easy. To do so, one needs to become conscious he needs to listen to the other, really listen, which can be risky. I needed to listen to what Ms. Callaghan had to say and she needed to listen to what Javier, her student, had to say, even if it did not fit our respective intended narratives. This is the story of how a didactician and a teacher worked together to raise each other’s consciousness and bring forth a new orientation for the development of a didactic of mathematics that anchors itself in and for actual people teaching–learning mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-29-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00325-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Considering Race in Teacher Well-Being</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Despite evidence that teachers’ professional experiences are racialized, few studies have quantitatively examined possible racial disparities in teachers’ job satisfaction. Using data from a nationally representative survey of teachers in the United States, we find that Black teachers report significantly lower job satisfaction than their White colleagues. Moreover, we find that teacher perceptions of school safety are the primary predictor of this gap in job satisfaction. We argue that centralizing race and racialized experiences in consideration of teacher job satisfaction will open new sites of inquiry in educational research and can guide educational policy to promote equity in K–12 schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2024 11:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241271410?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analyzing teacher audio: The contribution of classroom mathematics instruction to early numeracy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2393607?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2024 04:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2396752?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The PRIUM qualitative framework for assessment of proof comprehension: a result of collaboration among mathematicians and mathematics educators</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;While proof has been studied from different perspectives in the mathematics education literature for decades, students continue to struggle to build proof comprehension. Complicating this, the manner in which proof comprehension is assessed largely remains to be the definition-theorem-proof format in which students are asked to reproduce proofs or similar proofs that are presented in class. This approach can encourage students to memorize proofs rather than develop tools for syllogistic reasoning. This paper reports on a seven-year collaboration among research mathematicians and mathematics educators. Following a model for proof comprehension, they implemented a cycle of planning assessments, implementing them and evaluating student responses in several courses each semester for three years at two universities. The model-based assessments were designed with probing questions about proofs or subproofs to point student attention to the relationships among definitions, statements and their relationships, as well as the logic used to help students to both develop proof knowledge and demonstrate their mathematical thinking. Discrepancies between the intention of assessments and student responses led to refinements as the team reviewed the results to inform its practice. Collaboration, experience and empirical data informed the development of the new &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Promoting Reasoning in Undergraduate Mathematics &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;(PRIUM) Qualitative Framework for Proof Comprehension&lt;/em&gt;. The paper discusses three main results: the Framework and how to use it, the Framework’s utility at the individual, course and program levels of departmental evaluation, and a collaborative research process that may be utilized between research mathematics educators and mathematicians.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01628-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teachers’ multiple perspectives on adaptive tasks: task evaluation and selection as core practices for teaching quality</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The selection of tasks based on the evaluation of task features can be considered a core practice of teaching and a relevant component of teaching quality. This is typically part of teachers’ preparation for their classroom teaching, which prompts the following question: What are the characteristics of the tasks that teachers use when selecting tasks for differentiated teaching? To answer this question, we analyzed systematic differences in the focus of 78 in-service high school and lower secondary school teachers during the evaluation of task features. The teachers had to select eight tasks about the practice of fractions with respect to their differentiation potential—operationalizing their adaptive teaching competence from a mathematics educational perspective. To analyze the differences, we performed a cluster analysis of the task features that the teachers drew upon. Three groups of teachers could be identified with variations in their focus on directly or indirectly relevant, domain-specific or domain-general task features. Taking into account such variations may explain differences in teaching quality and student outcomes and may be relevant when designing teacher professional development programs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01626-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What do university mathematics students value in advanced mathematics courses?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we present a qualitative study on what values students perceive in their abstract algebra course. We interviewed six undergraduates early in their abstract algebra course and then again after their course was completed about what motivated them to learn abstract algebra and what value they saw in the subject. The key finding from the analysis was that participants found intrinsic value (i.e., their enjoyment of the subject) to be essential to learning abstract algebra. While participants desired utility value in the form of mathematical applications, they ultimately did not find this necessary to learn abstract algebra. Finally, some participants had different motivations for learning abstract algebra than for learning other branches of advanced mathematics, such as real analysis, suggesting that motivation research in mathematics education should not treat mathematics as a unitary construct. We offer analysis about how the nature of advanced theoretical proof-oriented mathematics may have contributed to these findings.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01616-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Defining and measuring quality in students’ mathematical writing: a systematic literature review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical communication, encompassing writing in, about, and for mathematics, is a critical competency. Defining excellent mathematical writing standards, however, remains challenging. To address this, we conducted a systematic review of 48 scholarly works on quality in mathematical writing. Our findings reveal mathematical writing for different purposes under scrutiny, including general mathematical writing, proof writing, reflective writing, expository writing, and descriptive writing during problem solving. To assess quality, researchers explore a variety of facets, such as syntax and semantics. Progression pathways vary, with both quantitative and qualitative evaluations—analysing text structure, writing style, and the use of different semiotic elements. It seems that in mathematics education, a consensus on quality measurement remains elusive. Proof writing is a notable exception. Among reviewed articles examining proof writing, a common set of standards emerges and provides valuable guidance. We propose that mathematical writing, perhaps especially in the context of reporting solutions in problem solving, can draw from proof writing standards. ‘Good’ mathematical writing would then require students to focus on (1) defining assumptions and assigning variables; (2) producing a coherent narrative, including relevant calculations (semantic issues); (3) using correct language, representations, and mathematical symbols (syntax issues); and (4) attending to what is appropriate in the context.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00501-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Triadic mentoring through the lens of positioning theory and frame analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-27-2024 06:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2395335?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining Power Through Practice in Continuous Improvement in Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this conceptual article, we argue for the need to examine power relations in continuous improvement (CI) in education. Specifically, we contend that examining power in CI requires an examination of practices that constitute the work of CI. Drawing on practice theory, we conceptualize practice and power and use these constructs to examine a CI effort on improving mathematical proficiency in an elementary school. From this case, we draw out three power moves to illustrate how examining power through practice in CI can generate insight into the varied power dynamics in a CI effort. We end by arguing for more examinations into the practice of CI work to understand power relations and the enactment of CI efforts in education broadly.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-27-2024 04:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241271359?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Metacognitive control during problem solving at early ages in programming tasks using a floor robot</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This research, following a sequential mixed-methods design, delves into metacognitive control in problem solving among 5- to 6-year-olds, using two floor-robot environments. In an initial qualitative phase, 82 pupils participated in tasks in which they directed a floor robot to one of two targets, with the closer target requiring more cognitive effort due to the turns involved. The results of this phase revealed that younger students often rationalised their decisions based on reasons unrelated to the difficulty of the task, highlighting limitations in children’s language and abstract thinking skills and leading to the need for a second quantitative study. In this subsequent stage, involving 117 students, a computerised floor-robot simulator was used. The simulator executed the students’ planned movements and provided feedback on their validity. Each participant had three attempts per problem, with the option to change their target each time. The simulator stored the information pertaining to the chosen resolution path, design of the plan, and re-evaluation of decision making based on the results and feedback received. This study aims to describe the criteria upon which students base their metacognitive control processes in decision making within problem-solving programming tasks. Additionally, through a comparative analysis focusing on age and gender, this research aims to assess the relationship between metacognitive processes and success in problem-solving programming tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01621-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Epistemic emotions and pre-service mathematics teachers’ knowledge for teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Affective and cognitive processes may be jointly researched to better understand mathematics learning, paying special interest to emotions related to knowledge acquisition. However, it remains necessary to explore these processes in studies linked to the education of pre-service mathematics teachers. This study aims to characterize epistemic emotions in different practices linked to the practice of mathematics teaching: problem-solving, anticipating what would happen with the students and reflecting on classroom implementation. It considers the theory of Mathematical Working Spaces to describe the mathematical and cognitive dimensions generated by epistemic emotions, paying special attention to the cognition-affect interaction and the workspace created. The results indicate that the epistemic emotions of the pre-service mathematics teachers associated with the distinct practices were different. Differences are observed in the interaction between emotions and cognitive epistemic actions, depending on whether the pre-service mathematics teachers analyze them within the framework of their own solving or anticipate them in their students. This reveals how personal work relates to what is considered to be suitable for students. Specifically, certain antecedents and consequences have been specified for the emotions of surprise and boredom in relation to the characteristics of the optimization problems and the cognitive activity of the subject when solving them. These results highlight the need to enhance the education of pre-service mathematics teachers through training that helps regulate their epistemic emotions and model effective strategies for regulating their own emotions and those of their students.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01624-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Facilitating collaborative inquiry into practice around artifacts of mathematics teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Although there has been increasing attention to the importance of teacher agency in professional development, there has been little attention to what it takes to facilitate collaborative work that both centers teachers’ assets and expertise and leads to productive learning. This paper presents a framework for focused and responsive facilitation of productive discourse around instructional practice in teacher learning communities. Drawing on a situative perspective, we trace the development of six novice teacher leaders as they were mentored to lead online collaborative lesson design groups focused on analyzing artifacts of K-8 mathematics instruction in a large urban district in the US. Our framework articulates how leaders facilitated the discussions in ways that both built on teacher knowledge, experiences, and contributions while also focusing on professional learning goals. Our analysis also shows how rich learning opportunities were co-constructed and sustained by the mentors, teacher leaders, and participants in each group over time. Through narrative descriptions of one group, we show how the teacher participants began to take on some of the facilitation practices themselves as they apprenticed into the practices of the community. This approach to professional learning positions teachers’ experience and knowledge as important assets while supporting them to try out and reflect on new classroom practices.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09649-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Department-Wide Transition to a New Mode of Computer-Aided Assessment Using STACK</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We focus on the integration of STACK—a Computer-Aided Assessment (CAA) technology—in the mathematics department of a high-ranking University in the United Kingdom. We study a department-wide project where instructors were expected to implement STACK into continuous assessment tasks for (nearly) all core modules across the first two years of undergraduate study. We present this work as a departmental case study, drawing on semi-structured interviews with six novice STACK assessment designers (and module leaders), supplemented by students’ responses to an open-response feedback questionnaire, and the reflections of a co-project lead (also first author). Our thematic analysis identified four themes related to the design of STACK-based assessments by novice to STACK tutors: the process of ‘STACKification’, technical challenges, users’ perspectives on the role of CAA, and finally, variations in assessment designers’ approaches to the role of feedback. In presenting our results, we are guided by Sangwin’s (&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r18&quot;&gt;2013&lt;/span&gt;) design principles for mathematics assessment. We consider various technical aspects of implementing STACK-based assessments as a first-time user, and the knowledge required to do so effectively and coherently. We conclude with a series of reflections on the role of CAA in undergraduate mathematics, and the ways in which such technology can be productively integrated with established practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00251-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Second-order covariation: enlarging the theoretical framework of covariational reasoning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-26-2024 10:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2393889?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
