<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher attitudes towards streaming in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, teacher attitudes towards streaming in New South Wales (NSW), Australia were explored. This mixed  methods research surveyed 30 secondary mathematics teachers. Findings indicated that NSW teachers had experience teaching both mixed-attainment and streamed mathematics classes, however streaming was the prevalent practice. Teachers believed streaming was the ideal method of grouping students in mathematics, allowing for better management of workloads and resulting in less behavioural issues. Teachers also believed that streaming positively impacted the academic outcomes of perceived high-ability students. However, there were mixed findings in teachers’ beliefs about the overall impacts of streaming on perceived low-ability students. While, teachers felt that streaming was able to better meet the academic needs of perceived low-ability students, the negative impacts of streaming on the wellbeing of these students was also noted. Overall, we argue that findings indicate that further exploration is needed into ways in which streaming can be made more equitable as it appears to currently be an intractable practice in Australia and other international settings.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09641-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Implementation models for teacher peer feedback: A systematic review</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-11-2024 12:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2363854?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-10-2024 12:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2366099?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sources, Conceptualizations, and Mechanisms of Racism/Oppression for Academic and Mental Health Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Interpersonal and systemic racism and discrimination persist in our educational system—from primary and secondary institutions through college, despite the forward strides of desegregation, the Civil Rights Movement, and the Black Lives Matter movement. This special topic collection identifies and applies empirically and theoretically grounded conceptualizations of racism to improve our understanding of the experience of racism, interventions to mitigate it, and protective factors. The papers in this collection reflect two themes: 1) racial and religious identities in classrooms, schools, and universities, focusing on how educators mitigate and perpetuate systemic racism, including how White teachers understand the impact of race, how inclusive and antiracism curricula are received and rejected by future educators and clinicians, and the impact of exclusionary social networks in the hiring of teachers of color and 2) school belonging and climate, including documenting that students of color feel less safe, are disproportionately exposed to harsh discipline, question their belonging, and question commitments to diversity. The negative sequelae are concurrent and last into adulthood. In addition, there are several advances in theory and measurement, including assessing gendered and racial biases in teachers’ attributions about students’ abilities, frameworks for mitigating colonial and racialized trauma, and domains of antiracist activism to bring racial justice and equity to schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-10-2024 11:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241258464?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Holistic teacher education: emphasising relationships, pedagogies and environments</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-10-2024 03:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2366580?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publisher Correction: Future teachers’ reflections on mathematical errors made in their teaching practice</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01599-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Socio-political features shaping the mathematics teaching and professional identities of muslim minority teachers in Western Thrace</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The importance of mathematics education in preparing students to become successful citizens raises continuous challenges for schools and educational systems, especially in minoritized settings. Research has identified practices and structures in the social and educational context that do not equally support all students’ learning and all teachers’ teaching and learning to teach. The study presented here employs a cultural-historical activity theory perspective to identify micro and macro practices and structures that challenge Muslim teachers’ mathematics teaching and their professional development in Western Thrace, Greece. The data exploited in the study, which is part of a larger project on Muslim students’ learning, were generated through interviews with in-service minority teachers. The results highlight micro and macro socio-political formations that interact to activate minoritization processes. These shape the practice of teaching mathematics as well as individual and collective identities connected to learning and teaching mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01601-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>High-quality use of representations in the mathematics classroom – a matter of the cultural perspective?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The teacher’s use of representations is a crucial aspect of instructional quality in mathematics education, given their pivotal role in facilitating mathematics learning. However, in our international research community, perspectives on what constitutes high-quality use of representations may vary. This cross-cultural study aims to explore whether the perspectives from Western literature, emphasizing the importance of explicit connections between symbolic and graphic representations, can be extended legitimately to the East Asian context. Using a situated approach, the study elicited norms of high-quality representation use from researchers in Germany and Taiwan. A total of 31 mathematics education professors from both countries evaluated the use of representations in three secondary mathematics classroom situations presented as text vignettes. The vignettes, designed by the German research team, each depicted a situation where from their perspective, a norm of high-quality representation use, specifically the explicit connection between symbolic and graphic representations, was violated. Qualitative analysis of the researchers&#39; responses revealed that in each situation, at least half of the German researchers expected explicit connections between representations. Conversely, the majority of Taiwanese researchers only expected such connections in one situation, particularly when the graphic representation served as an independent learning objective rather than solely aiding conceptual understanding. These findings indicate easily unnoticed culture-specific differences regarding how a common aspect of instructional quality is expected to unfold in teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01597-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of socioscientific issues-based teaching on attitudes: Students’ resources as moderator</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-08-2024 12:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2362159?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Action research with sociodrama in a healthcare institution</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article presents an action research study initiated in 2021, which employed the sociodrama method within a medical institution with healthcare assistants to improve their situation. The study discusses firstly the implications of the deepening and broadening nature of action research knowledge generation within that specific context. Secondly, it delves into the sociodrama method, emphasizing its compatibility with both the fundamental elements and the core principles of action research. Lastly, the study presents various project outcomes, categorized based on their focus: direct effects on individuals and groups, actions and action plans implemented at the group and institutional levels, and identified issues concerning the institutional and cultural context.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-08-2024 03:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241258875?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ripple Effect of Managerial Behavior: Exploring Post-experimental Impact of Leading by Example on Small Firms’ Cooperation and Performance</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Cooperation between employees in a company is an important input to firm performance. This study examines how a manager’s cooperative behavior and the visibility of this behavior affect the cooperation amongst employees, and subsequently firm performance. To do so, we conducted a field experiment with managers and their employees from 320 Vietnamese small and micro firms to determine the impact of a manager’s leading by example (LBE) on employees’ behavior, corporate culture, and firm performance. Both managers and employees participated in a Public Good experiment which aimed to elicit an individual cooperative behavior. Noteworthy is that the decision made by a manager in the experiment was given as an example to employees before they made decision in that same experiment. We considered that the example of cooperation by managers in the Public Good experiment communicated a powerful signal to the employees regarding the importance of fostering cooperation in the workplace. Such a signal by the manager, who is at the top in the organizational hierarchy, would impact their employees’ behavior in the workplace and firm’s outcomes beyond the experiment. Interestingly, we found that concealing a manager’s identity from their employees enhances the impacts of LBE.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-08-2024 02:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241260466?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A scoping literature review of the impact and evaluation of mathematics and statistics support in higher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper presents the results of a systematic scoping literature review of higher education mathematics and statistics support (MSS) evaluation focusing on its impact on students. MSS is defined as any additional organised mathematical and/or statistical aid offered to higher education students outside of their regular programme of teaching by parties within the students’ institution specifically assigned to give mathematical and/or statistical support. The objective of this review is to establish how MSS researchers investigate the effect of MSS on students and what that impact is. Based on a predefined protocol, five databases, the proceedings of eight conferences, two previous MSS literature reviews’ reference lists, and six mathematics education or MSS networks’ websites and reports were searched for publications in English since 2000. A two-round screening process resulted in 148 publications being included in the review which featured research from 12 countries. Ten formats of MSS, seven data sources (e.g., surveys), and 14 types of data (e.g., institution attainment, usage data) were identified with a range of analysis methods. Potential biases in MSS research were also considered. The synthesised results and discussion of this review include the mostly positive impact of MSS, issues in MSS evaluation research thus far, and rich opportunities for collaboration. The role MSS has and can play in mathematics education research is highlighted, looking towards the future of MSS evaluation research. Future directions suggested include more targeted systematic reviews, rigorous study design development, and greater cross-disciplinary and international collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10332-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Education Research-Practice Partnerships: Impacts and Dynamics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-07-2024 12:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357033?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ beliefs on integrating children’s literature in mathematics teaching and learning in Indonesia</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The integration of children’s literature, specifically mathematical story picture books, in mathematics education has demonstrated significant benefits. Nevertheless, its actual implementation largely hinges on teachers’ beliefs. This exploratory mixed-methods study examines the beliefs of 78 teachers regarding the integration of children’s literature into mathematics teaching and learning, with a focus on identifying its barriers and enablers. Data were collected through an open-ended survey and semi-structured interviews and analyzed using thematic analysis framed by the concept of belief indication. The study identifies 15 barriers (across five themes) and 16 enablers (across six themes) that, teachers believe, affect their decisions to integrate children’s literature into mathematics teaching and learning. This paper contextualizes the findings within the Theory of Planned Behavior (TPB), a framework from social psychology, to provide actionable recommendations and compare findings from studies conducted in Asian and Western countries. Ultimately, this research offers a broader understanding of teachers’ behaviors and their receptiveness to educational reforms, such as the integration of children’s literature, across diverse cultural and international settings.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-07-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10334-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Mathematics Teacher Education Partnership: The Power of a Networked Improvement Community to Transform Secondary Mathematics Teacher Preparation: A Review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;A review of Martin, W. G., Lawler, B. R., Lischka, A. E., &amp;amp; Smith, W. M. (&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r1&quot;&gt;2020&lt;/span&gt;). &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The Mathematics Teacher Education Partnership: The Power of a Networked Improvement Community to Transform Secondary Mathematics Teacher Preparation&lt;/em&gt;. Charlotte, North Carolina: Information Age Publishing, xix + 412 pp., $62.04 (paperback), ISBN 978–1-64,113–931-1, $89.24 (hardcover), ISBN 978–1-64,113–932-8.&lt;/p&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This book offers a thorough overview of a 7-year initiative by the Mathematics Teacher Education Partnership (MTE-Partnership), a national consortium uniting over 90 universities and 100 school systems. Focused on preparing secondary mathematics teachers, the MTE-Partnership operates as a Networked Improvement Community (NIC), merging improvement science with networking for accelerated progress. Addressing key challenges in teacher preparation, such as content knowledge development, impactful clinical experiences, recruitment, and equity considerations, the book explores existing knowledge and initiatives by Research Action Clusters (RACs). These collaborative clusters iteratively refine processes and products to enhance secondary mathematics teacher preparation. The book outlines successful RAC approaches and specific products, offering insights for educators and policymakers. Reflecting on the NIC model, it provides valuable considerations for research design, with explicit references to the Standards for Preparing Teachers of Mathematics (Association of Mathematics Teacher Educators, 2017), enhancing practical applicability. This resource is essential for advancing the field of secondary mathematics teacher preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-07-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00316-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Documenting the Distribution of Instructional Coaching Programs</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We present data from the Schools and Staffing Survey and the National Teacher and Principal Survey to document the prevalence of instructional coaching programs (ICPs) and consider how ICPs are distributed by school level, urbanicity, new teachers in a school, student enrollment, school poverty levels, student achievement levels, and state. We show that ICPs are most common in elementary schools, schools located in cities, schools with larger proportions of new teachers, larger schools, schools enrolling larger fractions of economically disadvantaged students, and schools with lower student achievement levels. Additionally, more affluent and higher achieving schools experienced the sharpest increase in ICPs over time.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-06-2024 06:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241256935?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Integrating subject-generic and subject-specific teaching frameworks: searching for stages of teaching in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Currently there is an attempt to combine subject-generic and subject-specific teaching frameworks to comprehensively capture teaching quality. This study explores the possibility of integrating two widely used and validated frameworks, the subject-generic Dynamic Model of Educational Effectiveness (DMEE) and the subject-specific Mathematical Quality of Instruction (MQI). Toward this end, we drew on data from 38 upper-grade primary school teachers, each observed in six mathematics lessons, which were coded using both frameworks. Data were analyzed using the Extended Logistic model of Rasch to explore whether a common scale of teaching quality with good psychometric properties could be developed. Saltus was then utilized to investigate the possibility of forming levels of effective teaching in mathematics. A common scale encompassing both subject-generic and subject-specific teaching aspects, which had good psychometric properties, was developed. The subject-generic and subject-specific teaching aspects of these frameworks were clustered in five distinct levels. With the exception of the top level that included only subject-generic aspects, all other levels included teaching aspects from both frameworks, thus providing support to the assumption that it is possible to develop levels of effective teaching that combine related subject-generic and subject-specific aspects. In discussing the study findings, we consider their implications for developing an integrated framework of teaching quality and for developing professional development programs that combine subject-generic and subject-specific teaching aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-06-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01591-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Being a Workforce to Agents of Change: An Interpretive Meta-ethnography of Different Approaches to Participatory Research With Young People</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A growing amount of educational research employs participatory methods in which young people actively gather and analyze data in collaboration with the investigators. Considering the diverse use of the label “participatory,” we examined participatory studies with young people to understand how researchers justify using this approach and conceptualize its purposes and goals, as well as these studies’ contributions to scholarship and youth’s civic learning. We conducted an interpretive meta-ethnography of 95 studies, identifying four distinct types of participatory studies with youth: technical, capacity building, justice-oriented, and transformative. We conclude that research that labels itself “participatory” but does not benefit the participants and their communities puts the approach’s credibility at risk. To challenge structural inequalities and power relations between participants and researchers, academic studies should better align with the transformative approach that has the potential to support youth in becoming agents of change by engaging them in self-directed civic learning and activism.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-05-2024 11:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241255625?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining the elements of culturally relevant pedagogy captured and missed in a measure of high-quality mathematics instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics instruction is not race or culture neutral. For students who have been historically marginalized in mathematics classrooms, high-quality mathematics instruction, instruction that helps students build conceptual understanding, on its own might not be enough to disrupt inequities. These students might also need instruction that is culturally relevant, with teachers who demonstrate cultural competence, build critical consciousness, and support student learning. Our goal in this study was to understand which components of culturally relevant pedagogy (CRP) are captured and which are missed in a typical U.S. framework of high-quality mathematics instruction. To find the overlaps and gaps, we analyzed the mathematics lessons of three elementary teachers through both the lens of CRP and the Mathematics-Scan, a mathematics observation tool. We found the strongest overlap between the two frameworks in the patterns of strengths and weaknesses in the teachers’ lessons. When the teachers were delivering high-quality instruction, they were also often supporting students’ learning or showing cultural competence. When the teachers were delivering lower quality instruction, they were also often missing opportunities to enact CRP. At the same time, key elements of CRP including linguistic support for students, high expectations, critical consciousness, and nuances within cultural competence, were missed by the high-quality instruction framework. High-quality instruction was the foundation for CRP in the teachers’ classrooms, but CRP was more than just high-quality instruction. We conclude with recommendations for increasing the alignment between the frameworks and implications for international educators also grappling with equity in their own frameworks of mathematics instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01595-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptualizing functional relationships in an augmented reality environment: connecting real and virtual worlds</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper describes how students conceptualize real-life phenomena in which two or more quantities are covarying in an augmented reality environment. With this technology, real-world phenomena and virtual representations may be connected simultaneously. We aim to investigate how students connect elements of the two worlds when conceptualizing functional relationships. We relied on Zindel’s conceptual facet model for functional relationships to achieve this goal, specifically focusing on the covariational approach. Three 11th-grade students participated in two real-life experiments (Galileo and Hooke’s law experiments) at the heart of this study. The qualitative analysis of selected episodes revealed how students relate the two worlds and how covariational reasoning is reflected in such connections. The findings show that students frequently related elements of the real and virtual worlds while engaging in several forms of covariational reasoning. The theoretical contribution resulting from this study is expanding Zindel’s model to address the conceptualization of families of functions indexed by a parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01594-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Boardrooms to Classrooms: How Interorganizational Networks Influence Education Policy Adoption</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper examines how relationships among government and “outside” organizations influenced policy implementation of new dropout prediction data systems. Using comparative historical and network analyses of three cities, I suggest the concept of interorganizational coupling—highlighting how the dependence and (in)formal collaborations among local school improvement organizations affected implementation speed, variation, and constraint. In Chicago, the loosely coupled system influenced slow and varied implementation, sustained by interpersonal relations and challenged by unclear division of labor. In Philadelphia, the tightly coupled system shaped swift and uniform changes, constrained by questions of sustainability. In New York, the tightening system led to fast yet variable transformations, limited by competition among organizations. Broadly, the article contributes to studies of education policies, interorganizational networks, and school improvement.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-04-2024 12:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241254791?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Choice, Socioeconomic Status, and Stratified Enrollment in Urban Districts: Evidence From Detroit</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Researchers and policymakers have often debated whether urban schools of choice enroll students who are relatively advantaged compared to their traditional public school peers. Existing research has not adequately answered this question due to a reliance on inadequate quantitative measures of socioeconomic status and an emphasis on differences between racial or class groups rather than within them. This mixed-methods study contributes new evidence based on novel survey data and interviews with parents and educational leaders in Detroit. Detroit charter schools enroll significantly fewer students living in deep poverty than neighborhood schools, and selective schools enroll a distinctly advantaged population. These stratified enrollment patterns result from differences in geographic constraints, the influence of social networks, school type reputations, and school practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-04-2024 11:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241254783?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptualizing political knowledges needed to teach inclusive mathematics: theorizing through counterstories</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;How do teachers develop and use political knowledge to create equitable and inclusive conditions for and with disabled students, particularly disabled students of color? In this essay, we build on concepts of political teacher knowledge in mathematics education, critical inclusive mathematics education and disability studies to explore teacher knowledges that support disabled students’ mathematical learning. We focus on four aspects of political knowledge for teaching mathematics: (1) knowledge as relational and unfolding over time, (2) understanding and negotiating the political contexts in which we teach mathematics, (3) deconstructing deficit discourses about marginalized students, and (4) learning to creatively resist the systems for and with our students. To develop our theoretical analysis, we use a counterstory of a middle school Latino student named Luis and his Latina mathematics teacher, Ms. Marquez. Our aim is to open up discussions in mathematics teacher educational research about the politics at play in teaching inclusive mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01598-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student visual attention during group instruction phases in collaborative geometry problem solving</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teacher gestures support mathematics learning and promote student collaboration. Aligned with speech, gestures can help students to notice the important visual information of geometry tasks. However, students’ visual attention to the teacher’s gestural cues during collaborative problem solving remains a largely unexplored field in mathematics education research. This mixed-method case study investigated relations between students’ visual attention, teacher gestures, and students’ collaborative problem-solving process on a geometry task. The data were collected with video cameras and mobile gaze trackers on four students simultaneously in two Finnish 9th-grade mathematics lessons with the same teacher. The findings show that the students attended to their own papers most of the time during the teacher&#39;s gestures, but differences in student attention between the gesture types emerged. The qualitative analysis showed that the teacher’s tracing, pointing, and representational gestures helped in directing student attention to targets relevant to the situational learning process. We conclude that teacher gestures can both convey mathematical contents and direct student attention, which intermediates mathematical thinking in problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10337-1</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
