<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Errybody Sayin ‘No New Friends’?: The Proverbs of Rap and Why Young People Recite Them</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 06:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2240460?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Phronesis in teacher education: a critical reexamination</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 12:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2253495?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning programming for mathematical investigations: an instrumental and community of practice approach</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 11:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2239195?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Wealth-Based Inequalities in Higher Education Attendance: A Global Snapshot</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study provides a comprehensive global snapshot of wealth-based inequalities in higher education attendance. We draw on data from 117 countries to describe cross-national patterns in higher education attendance rates, disaggregated by wealth quintile and country income group. We then calculate four different indicators to quantify the size of wealth-based inequality in higher education attendance and completion for each country. Our findings point to large wealth-based inequalities in higher education attendance cross-nationally, which are: substantially larger than inequalities in secondary completion, larger in low- and middle-income countries than high-income countries, and negatively associated with national wealth. The results serve as a foundation for future studies on how country-level factors and policies exacerbate or reduce wealth-based inequalities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 10:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231194307?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating Psychometric Differences Between Fast Versus Slow Responses on Rating Scale Items</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Some previous studies suggest that response times (RTs) on rating scale items can be informative about the content trait, but a more recent study suggests they may also be reflective of response styles. The latter result raises questions about the possible consideration of RTs for content trait estimation, as response styles are generally viewed as nuisance dimensions in the measurement of noncognitive constructs. In this article, we extend previous work exploring the simultaneous relevance of content and response style traits on RTs in self-report rating scale measurement by examining psychometric differences related to fast versus slow item responses. Following a parallel methodology applied with cognitive measures, we provide empirical illustrations of how RTs appear to be simultaneously reflective of both content and response style traits. Our results demonstrate that respondents may exhibit different response behaviors for fast versus slow responses and that both the content trait and response styles are relevant to such heterogeneity. These findings suggest that using RTs as a basis for improving the estimation of noncognitive constructs likely requires simultaneously attending to the effects of response styles.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231195260?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching rational number concepts and skills to students receiving tier two interventions</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-31-2023 04:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2248046?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identifying school-based teacher educators’ professional learning needs: an international survey</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 05:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2251658?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>My brother’s keeper: two Black men navigating the tenure-track experience</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 05:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2248892?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Proof and proving in school and university mathematics education research: a systematic review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This systematic review aims to provide a complementary to existing synopses of the state-of-the-art of mathematics education research on &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;proof&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;proving&lt;/em&gt; in both school and university mathematics. As an organizing framework, we used Cohen et al.’s triadic conceptualization of instruction, which draws attention not only to the main actors of the didactical process (i.e., the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teacher&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students&lt;/em&gt;) and the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Content&lt;/em&gt; around which the actors’ work is organized (herein, content related to proof and proving), but also to the relationships among the actors and the content. Out of the 103 papers we reviewed, almost half fell in the Student-Content category, which is consistent with the existence of a substantial number of frameworks, methods, and research findings related to students’ engagement with proof and proving. About a quarter of the papers fell in the Student–Teacher-Content category, which reflects an emphasis on viewing instructional practice in proof and proving in a holistic, systemic way. Only few papers fell in the categories that did not include Content in them, namely, the categories of Student, Teacher, and Student–Teacher; this suggests mathematics education research on proof and proving has a strong disciplinary identity, which potentially differentiates it from other mathematics education research strands. About a fifth of the papers were oriented towards ‘breaking ground’ through making an explicit theoretical and/or methodological contribution (Student–Teacher-Content and Content were the main categories where such contributions appeared), whilst the majority of the papers were focused on ‘building ground’ through elaborating or employing existing methodological and/or theoretical approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01518-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing how college mathematics instructors and high-school teachers recognize professional obligations of mathematics teaching when making instructional decisions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper investigates how mathematics instructors&#39; recognition of the professional obligations of mathematics teaching varies based on their institutional environment, specifically whether they teach high school or college mathematics. Using an instrument that measures instructors’ recognition of four hypothesized professional obligations, we surveyed 471 US high school mathematics teachers and 239 university mathematics instructors to measure the extent to which they recognized professional obligations when evaluating the appropriateness of certain instructional actions. After testing measurement invariance of four item sets, each of which measures one of the four hypothesized professional obligations—disciplinary, institutional, interpersonal, and individual obligations-, we compared the instructors’ recognition of each of the four obligations between the two groups. We found that university instructors recognized the institutional obligation more than high school teachers, while recognizing the individual and interpersonal obligations significantly less. This investigation provides insight into the variation in the nature of mathematics teaching practice across different levels of schooling.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09595-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Magnifying the Scope of Nature of Science (NOS) Toward the Whole: An Investigation of NOS Representation in Early Childhood Science Education Standards</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Effective teaching and learning of Nature of Science (NOS) has been a curriculum goal for decades and its inclusion into the science education from K-12 is becoming commonplace worldwide, regardless of the differences in the adapted science curricula. However, less attention, if any, has been paid to the holistic representation of NOS at kindergarten schooling level. This study utilizes the Family Resemblance Approach (FRA) on NOS to investigate how NOS is represented in the United Arab Emirates (UAE) science curriculum documents for the kindergarten school years, and the extent of its alignment with the international benchmarks and educational research evidence. Findings from the FRA-based curriculum analysis have demonstrated that the standards include “the nature of science” as one of the key domains of science education in the kindergarten stage. However, the cognitive-epistemic dimensions of NOS appeared to be more dominant than the social-institutional system dimensions. Specifically, the majority of the standards and learning outcomes emphasize learning of scientific methods, scientific practices, and scientific knowledge, alongside very few NOS aspects related to scientific ethos, social values, professional practices, and social organization. Pedagogical and practical implications of these results for science education are presented, along with recommendations to help structure NOS account into the UAE science standards that is more progressive, holistic, and interactive, all which can be of interest to a broader audience for purposes of curriculum policy reform both locally and internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00282-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Winds of Changes: How Research Alliances Respond to and Manage Shifting Field-Level Logics</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Research alliances, like other research-practice partnerships (RPPs), aim to bridge the historic divide between educational research and practice and improve education in particular local contexts. Yet, although these demands reflect multiple and contested field-level logics, little prior research has examined the ways these logics impact the work of RPPs. This longitudinal, qualitative study explores the field-level logics that dominated the local contexts of two research alliances; how these logics shifted over time; and how research alliances responded to these shifts. Results show that field-level logics of research, practice, and community contended in both local contexts, and that alliance design, resources, and local contexts shaped research alliances’ efforts to respond to and manage shifting demands.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-29-2023 07:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231193401?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging AI to enhance learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 40-45, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) technologies, such as ChatGPT, have ushered in a new digital era that presents formidable challenges related to cheating and plagiarism in the classroom. Although many school systems have reacted by banning AI language models and related applications, these technologies present opportunities to leverage formative assessment practices to enable students to demonstrate more complex and valued learning outcomes. Using the ICE (Ideas, Connections, Extensions) model, Louis Volante, Christopher DeLuca, and Don A. Klinger offer educators a research-informed pathway, based on best practices and policy, to promote critical, creative, and higher order thinking in secondary schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197475?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher expertise isn’t enough</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 46-50, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In recent research with classroom teachers on their personal pedagogical trajectories, Jeremy Glazer found teachers expressing concerns that their teaching practice was getting worse and they were not able to do the best teaching they knew how to do. The accounts of these teachers suggest that, when thinking about strategies for improving teachers’ practice, education leaders need to expand their focus beyond the knowledge, skills, and experience of teachers themselves and begin to look at the contexts in which teachers do their jobs. Specifically, teacher development initiatives need to include advocacy for sustainable workloads and teacher autonomy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197476?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why teachers leave: It isn’t what you think</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 51-55, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;With all the talk of turnover and shortages, it would be easy to think that many teachers have simply given up on education. Yet, despite the myriad challenges teachers have faced recently, this is not the case: Teachers care about their work as much as ever. Andrew Pendola, David Marshall, Tim Pressley, and Deja Trammell present a new narrative suggesting that there is no shortage of teacher dedication, even if some are leaving. They provide strategic, school-level changes that can not only help keep our best teachers, but also enrich their core purpose and dedication.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197477?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emerging stronger</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 24-28, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Pentucket Regional School District serves three small suburban communities north of Boston. Historically, its student performance had been quite high, but had been declining steadily for about a decade. The district had started reversing those losses, but the pandemic set it back. Now, however, the district has emerged even stronger; in most cases, student achievement already exceeds pre-pandemic levels. The reasons: new, high-quality curricula in multiple areas; a strong system of implementation supports; and a data-driven approach to help teachers address the specific needs of individual students. Assistant Superintendent Brent Conway explains how they did it.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197471?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A design course for every student</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 29-33, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Integrating STEAM with human-centered design is one way to transform the teaching of high school mathematics. Susanna Kemp described how this was done at Evanston Township High School in Illinois through a project-based learning class called STEAM Design Thinking &amp;amp; Innovation. The course equips students with real-world skills like critical thinking, creativity, communication, curiosity, collaboration, and empathy. Kemp describes the creation of the course as well as the design thinking process, shares how the course addresses critiques of design thinking, and encourages educators to develop curricula that focus on process over outcome and that de-emphasize competition.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197473?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Continued support for teachers; growing support for four-day school week: Findings from the 55th annual PDK poll</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 34-39, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The 55th Annual PDK Poll finds that a wide majority (66%) of adults say teachers should have a substantial say in what’s taught in public schools, more than say so about school boards, local residents, or lawmakers. Support for teachers also is apparent in another result from the 2023 PDK Poll: 67% of respondents support increasing local teacher salaries by raising property taxes. That result reflects the public’s broad sense that public school teachers are undervalued, underpaid, and overworked. At the same time, more than half of Americans support shifting to a four-day school week in their community, nearly twice as many as said so two decades ago. And structurally, beyond a four-day week, the poll finds that about six in 10 adults support other changes in how schools operate — longer school days and/or a longer school year — as ways to try to improve student learning outcomes. On another topic, results show widespread support for schools conducting mental health assessments of students. The survey was produced by Langer Research Associates for PDK International, with data collected June 16-25, 2023, in English and Spanish, among a representative, random national sample of 1,002 adults.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197474?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: PDK International appoints new CEO</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 69-71, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;News from PDK International: The Board of Directors of PDK International and the Board of Governors of the PDK Foundation announce the appointment of James F. Lane as CEO of PDK International. The 2023 Educators Rising conference featured the first-ever student delegate meeting and selection of new national officers. Student leader Milan Aranda, scholarship winner Kaitlyn Hannah, and emerging leader Kathryn Wiley are spotlighted.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197490?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Poll Points: Digging deeper into 2023 PDK Poll results</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 72-72, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The 2023 PDK Poll showed a sharp increase in the percentage of Americans who support the idea of a four-day school week since the question was last asked in 2003. A slim majority in 2023 (53%) said they would support a four-day school week, with longer school days, as a means of saving money. This infographic gives a snapshot of who supports this idea.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197491?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>One good thing, one day at a time: A conversation with Rebecka Peterson</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 8-12, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The 2023 National Teacher of the Year Rebecka Peterson is a high school math teacher in Tulsa, Oklahoma. Union High School serves more than 3,000 students, 72% of whom qualify for free and reduced-price lunch, and 62 languages are represented. Peterson, an immigrant to the U.S. whose parents were medical missionaries, builds trust in her classroom through stories—her stories and those of her students. During her first year of teaching, she discovered the “One Good Thing” blog founded by math teachers. It encouraged teachers to post their own stories of good things that happened during the day. The practice of scanning her day for one good thing that had occurred changed her mindset, allowing her to see more good things and finally persuading her to be the “one good thing” for her students each day.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197468?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Local success in the standards era</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 18-23, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The Common Core State Standards and Next Generation Science Standards were adopted in the early 2010s in most U.S. states with high hopes of improving educational achievement and equity. Almost a decade later, there is little evidence of the hoped-for improvements at the state and national level. However, state and national averages obscure gains that occurred in particular schools and districts. Elaine Allensworth, Laura M. Desimone, and Latrice Marianno share findings from studies of successes in multiple states and in Chicago. Their research shows that improvement was most likely when teachers engage in professional learning that is both flexible and specific, incorporates collaboration, focuses on practice, and offers guidance in using resources.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197470?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: The power of the bright side</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The September 2023 issue of Kappan focuses on “What’s going well in schools?” But it’s being published in a time when the news about schools seems to be nothing but bad. Teresa Preston, Kappan’s editor-in-chief, explains that there are lots of good things going on in individual districts, schools, and classrooms. Seeing the good takes time and mental discipline, but forming the habit of looking for good things makes it easier to recognize them when they appear.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197465?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How change-making teachers create bottom-up reforms</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/1&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 13-17, September 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Within our schools are change-making teachers who innovate and find ways to make their schools better for students. Rose Sebastian shares the stories of two change-making teachers who taught at high schools where integration within the school stopped at the classroom doors. With perseverance, a strong sales pitch, and a willingness to compromise, both teachers were able to create new, more integrated courses at their schools. By looking closely at their paths to change, we can gain new insights into how bottom-up reforms are created and into how we can support more teachers in becoming change-makers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-28-2023 11:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231197469?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
