<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: How can university mathematics overcome Klein&#39;s second discontinuity? Specific course design</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01611-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Towards an advanced mathematical language task for the early primary school years: preliminary results on reliability and validity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical language (or the content-specific words in mathematics) has repeatedly shown to be related to mathematical abilities in preschool and in the early grades of primary education. Research in this field has predominantly focused on young children’s quantitative and spatial language. At the same time, recent research has discovered that children in the early years of primary education already possess advanced mathematical skills such as reasoning about patterns, proportions and probabilities. In this study we developed an advanced mathematical language task to measure children’s understanding of mathematical language proper of the domains of patterning, proportionality, and probability, specifically aimed at first, second, and third graders (ages 5 -8). To develop a valid test instrument, our task was substantiated by a review of relevant literature and previously conducted studies. Further, the task was optimized based on the feedback received from expert professionals and a pilot study with 36 children. After administering the advanced mathematical language task to 236 first, second, and third graders, the results suggest that the task provides reliable scores in these grades. The internal consistency is excellent (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;α&lt;/em&gt; = .993). In addition, the test–retest reliability was checked in 49 children (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; = .704; &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; .001), and shows that the test also produces stable results over time.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10342-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Political conocimiento in teaching mathematics: mathematics teacher candidates enacting their ethical identities</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09646-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Units Coordination in Preservice Elementary Teachers&#39; Mathematical Knowledge for Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2024 11:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2370178?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher education for mathematical modelling: exploring the experiences of secondary school teachers in two courses</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper focuses on in-service teacher education as a crucial agent in driving educational paradigm shifts for the teaching and learning of mathematical modelling. Our paper presents empirical research based on two case studies, examining training courses for in-service secondary school mathematics teachers. The first course integrates different modelling approaches, while the second one is based on the anthropological theory of the didactic and uses the proposal of the study and research paths for teacher education. Both experiences conclude with teachers working on the design of modelling tasks to be implemented in secondary schools. Both courses are analysed through the lenses of how teachers progress on the collective identification of conditions and constraints for modelling, when teachers deal with the design of modelling tasks and analyse their implementations. First, the results show the kind of modelling tasks teachers design and the level of disciplinary specificity at which they plan modelling to be implemented. Second, we analyse how teachers address the “ecological analysis”, that is, the identification of conditions and constraints that facilitate or hinder the integration of modelling in secondary school classrooms after their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01609-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beginning mathematics teachers’ values and beliefs about pedagogy during a time of policy flux</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study interrogates how beginning secondary mathematics teachers align their beliefs with their practice when they justify their pedagogical choices in the context of recent English mathematics education policy which is strongly influenced by approaches to mathematics teaching in Shanghai and Singapore currently referred to as ‘mastery’ approaches. It seeks to understand beginning teachers’ perceptions and understandings of these approaches and the extent to which they recognise aspects of ‘mastery’ in practice. In setting the context, pre-service teachers’ beliefs were surveyed and found to be congruent with constructivist approaches to learning. We then draw on qualitative data from semi-structured interviews secondary mathematics teachers in their first year post-qualification. The interviews were designed to interrogate and capture understanding of the features of mastery within their own classrooms. By using vignettes to capture participants’ beliefs, our aim was to present a ‘more nuanced understanding of the phenomena’ (Skilling and Stylianides in Int J Res Method Educ 43(5):541–556, 2019, 10.1080/1743727x.2019.1704243). The analytical framework developed draws on Guskey’s (In: Wright J (ed) International encyclopedia of the social &amp;amp; behavioural sciences, 2015, vol 14, 2nd edn, Elsevier, pp 752–759) interpretation of Bloom’s theory of mastery learning together with features of mastery learning in mathematics articulated by Drury (How to teach mathematics for mastery, 2018, Oxford University Press) and Boylan et al. (Edu Sci 8(4):202, 2018, 10.3390/educsci8040202). This posed a research design challenge given the variation in interpretation of mastery learning as it is understood in practice. The data exposes differences in the interpretation of mastery approaches in the settings where they learn to teach, as well as the tensions that arise between beginning teachers’ beliefs, practice, professional knowledge and agency in their developing classroom roles.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09647-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School gardens as sites for community, empowerment, and justice: a participatory action research study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 12:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2374746?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting students’ participation in collective argumentation: Use of displays in a secondary mathematics classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 04:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2371515?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Development of prospective elementary teachers’ knowledge to teach early algebra through case discussions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigated the development of prospective elementary teachers (PETs)’ subject matter and pedagogical content knowledge for teaching early algebra through participation in case discussions. PETs attended five weeks of intervention as part of a method course, which included case discussions. During the intervention, the participants were presented with big ideas of equivalence and equations, generalized arithmetic, and functional thinking as the content of early algebra through text-based classroom cases. Data were collected through one-hour individual interviews before and after the early algebra lessons. The analysis of the pre-interviews indicated that prospective elementary teachers may not be ready to foster algebraic thinking in elementary grades in terms of the required knowledge for teaching. We found that PETs needed more development of required subject matter knowledge to guide algebraic thinking in elementary grades, such as the relational meaning of the equal sign, generalizing, representing, or justifying arithmetic or functional relationships, and reasoning with them. Likewise, PETs were found to lack in pedagogical content knowledge related to students’ conceptions and misconceptions and effective teaching strategies to promote early algebraic thinking. However, we found that specifically designed method courses could help develop PETs’ knowledge of teaching early algebra. Following early algebra lessons centered around case discussions, PETs showed progress in multiple aspects of knowledge across all big ideas, though their improvement in generalized arithmetic was somewhat less pronounced. This progress was observed in their subject matter and pedagogical content knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09642-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A proposal for the study of mathematics teachers’ beliefs through the analysis of their practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In recent years, research on mathematics teachers’ beliefs has increasingly shifted its focus toward understanding their connection with instructional practices. This article introduces a model designed to explore mathematics teachers’ beliefs through a comprehensive analysis of their practices. The contributions of models that study the relationship between beliefs and practices of teachers, such as those from Schoenfeld (Journal of Mathematical Behavior, 18(3), 243–261, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r27&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/span&gt;) and Cobb and Yackel (Educational Psychologist, 31(3), 175–190, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r5&quot;&gt;1996&lt;/span&gt;), were reviewed and considered. Additionally, it includes methodological considerations from Leatham and Speer for studying beliefs. These approaches are integrated by utilizing the notions of practice, types of didactic-mathematical practices and norms, derived from the onto-semiotic approach, as the central organizing axis. Furthermore, we demonstrate the application of these stages of analysis for exploring teachers’ beliefs by analyzing the beliefs of a prospective mathematics teacher. The findings enable us to identify the beliefs held by this prospective teacher regarding the use of introductory activities characterized by a high motivational level but a low mathematical level. Additionally, these results provide insights into potential avenues for developing training programs aimed at instigating a shift in these beliefs, thereby fostering an enhancement in teaching practices. These outcomes show the feasibility of the analytical model proposed in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00496-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building mathematical micro-identities through supporting productive struggle</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 11:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2372711?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Focusing on foundational Calculus ideas to understand the derivative concept via problem-solving tasks that involve the use of a Dynamic Geometry System</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of this paper is to review recently calculus curriculum reforms and research studies that document what types of understanding students develop in their precalculus courses. We argue that it is important to characterize what difficulties students experience to solve tasks that include the use of foundational calculus concepts and to look for possible ways for students to develop a way of reasoning to work on problems that involve variational phenomena. Thus, we identified tasks in which calculus students exhibit limited understanding of essential concepts to approach and solve those tasks. The purpose is to illustrate and discuss how the systematic use of a Dynamic Geometry System (DGS) could provide a set of affordances for students to develop ways of thinking to grasp calculus foundational ideas and to study the derivative concept. Here, we relied on Thurston’s seminal work that emphasizes the relevance for learners to identify, connect, and coordinate different dimensions and meanings (intuitive, symbolic, algorithmic, geometric, physical, and formal) to construct, understand, and apply the concept of derivative.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01607-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Catherine P. Vistro-Yu &amp;amp; Tin Lam Toh (eds.) (2019) School mathematics curricula – Asian perspectives and glimpses of reform</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10338-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Aligning school mathematics with a manufactured crisis: re-rendering neoliberal and neoconservative discourses as commonsensical in a rural place</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;School reform efforts are situated within social and political contexts and, as such, are susceptible to the commonsense discourses circulating through, and shaping, society. Two discourses prevalent in US education reform are those perpetuating the ideologies of neoliberalism and neoconservatism. These ideologies are inherently contradictory—with the former promoting a small state and the latter a strong state—but converge to promote their agendas, shaping school reform efforts. &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; this occurs is not always clear, especially in rural contexts, where there has been limited attention to ideological discourses’ relation to schooling. In this analysis, we describe how dominant, yet contradictory, discourses of neoliberalism and neoconservatism are resolved in a rural context. We find that the leaders of one rural, public school district identified fifth-grade number sense as a problem of practice needing improvement—framing the cause of their problem as misalignment and the solution as consistency within and across grade levels. In doing so, district leaders’ conversations were limited to those of standardization (e.g., state-mandated mathematics standards, approaches to timed-fact tests, and curriculum between grade levels). Alignment as a frame excluded conversations related to deeper considerations, such as students’ experiences in mathematics or issues of equity. We find that dominant discourses constrain the ways district leaders frame their mathematics-related problem and work through the frame (in this case, one of alignment) to resolve inherent contradictions and advance their agendas. We suggest that these discourses serve to distract from potentially more pressing issues in education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10340-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First- and second-grade prospective teachers reconstructing definitions of polygon diagonals</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The current study examined how prospective first- and second-grade mathematics teachers define the polygon diagonals concept, how they reconstruct their definition during and following an intervention, and how their concept images develop over time. Twenty-three prospective teachers participated in the study, during which they were asked to analyze mathematical events involving a conflict that could be resolved using a precise mathematical definition of a polygon diagonal. Data were collected from prequestionnaires, postquestionnaires, and observations of class discussions. The study findings indicate that before the intervention, all participants provided incorrect definitions and struggled to identify nonprototypical examples of polygon diagonals in the prequestionnaire. However, the process of analyzing mathematical events helped the participants reconstruct their definitions of polygon diagonals and identify the critical attributes of this concept, which improved their ability to extend the concept’s image to include nonprototypical examples. The participants’ improved understanding was evident in the significant improvements in the postquestionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00495-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The development of elementary teachers’ personal meanings of problem-solving through engaging in open-ended tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, we explored elementary school teachers’ experiences working on open-ended mathematics tasks during a 10-day professional development (PD) workshop. Teachers engaged with the tasks daily in a session call Morning Math (MM). Thirty-two elementary teachers from three school districts in the USA participated in a 2-year professional development (PD) program. Analysis of videos of teacher engagement in the tasks and interviews shows that the use of open-ended mathematics tasks embedded within problem-solving focused PD could shape elementary school teachers’ personal meanings about learning mathematics through problem-solving. The findings indicate that the teachers’ take-aways from the PD were not limited to the mathematical content of the MM problems (i.e., mathematical residue), instead teachers’ experiences with open-ended mathematics tasks engendered personal meanings reflecting pedagogical residue with cognitive, affective, and social components. This result shows the crucial  role of PD in shaping teachers’ mathematics-related personal meanings  which research suggests that it will subsequently influence their beliefs and instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00493-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Contextualizing Explanations to Support Sense Making</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 7&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 480-487
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/7/article-p480.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Break Out of Your Routine with Escape Rooms</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 7&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 488-494
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/7/article-p488.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Benchmarks to Support Fraction Addition</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 7&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 495-501
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/7/article-p495.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Productive Talk Across a Launch-Explore-Discuss Lesson</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 7&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 502-506
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/7/article-p502.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cultivating Critical Statistical Literacy in the Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 7&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 507-511
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/7/article-p507.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Snapping Spaghetti and Opening Doors</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 7&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 512-519
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/7/article-p512.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Belonging and Classroom Tests</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 7&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 474-476
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/7/article-p474.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Problems to Ponder</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 7&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 520-523
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/7/article-p520.xml</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
