<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Breaking Bad/Good? Patterns and Correlates of Public School Teachers’ Multiple Jobholding</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Stagnating teacher salaries and the widening gap between public school teachers and similar workers have led to growing concerns that teachers will seek additional employment—possibly leading to teacher burnout and/or attrition in the process. Using data ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-17-2025 11:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312251316256?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Students on Track? Comparing the Predictive Validity of Administrative and Survey Measures of Cognitive and Noncognitive Skills for Long-Term Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Education leaders need valid metrics to predict students’ long-term success. We use a unique data set with cognitive skills, self-regulation, behavior, course performance, and test scores for eighth-grade students from a Northeast school district. We link ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-17-2025 11:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X251321422?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Three-Part Random Effect Models for Longitudinal Skewed Survey Data With “Not Applicable” Responses</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In survey data, some questions are asked only of a subset of applicable participants. This frequently occurs together with floor effects of the provided responses. For example, in the longitudinal Population Assessment of Tobacco and Health (PATH) survey, ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-17-2025 05:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986251318028?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A National Look at Shifts in Disability Self-Identification for Students Enrolled in Higher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Utilizing data from the Beginning Postsecondary Students Longitudinal Study 2012/2017 dataset, this study examined disability self-identification during the first 3 years of postsecondary education in a nationally representative sample of students in the ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-17-2025 04:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584251322511?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BSRLM Day Conference Proceedings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-17-2025 04:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2025.2467158?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Openness in mathematical modelling: do experiences of competence and autonomy mediate the effects of an intervention on modelling problems on task values and cost?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-17-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>/article/10.1007/s11858-025-01670-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning together: Organizing schools for teacher and student learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2025 02:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2025.2476365?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Lesson Design Actions: Examining Elementary Preservice Teachers’ Pedagogical Design Capability for Inquiry</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2025 01:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2025.2476968?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Metacognitive activities in high school students’ mathematical modelling: findings from an epistemic network analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>/article/10.1007/s11858-025-01664-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Addressing the Disadvantage Gap Through Generative Learning: A Case for the Science Writing Heuristic Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study investigated the long-term impact of the science writing heuristic (SWH) approach on students’ science achievement, focusing on differences between low and high socioeconomic status (SES) groups. Through a longitudinal design, students were ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-14-2025 12:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X251324141?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Evaluation of Aggregated and Disaggregated Approaches to Multilevel Factor Scoring</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Approaches to multilevel measurement modeling are often distinguished as aggregated or disaggregated. While past research has established the benefits and limitations of these modeling frameworks, none have critically evaluated the reliability of factor ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-14-2025 11:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986251321380?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dubious Evidence, Valuable Information</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;I explore how “low-quality evidence” from program performance might still be useful in decision-making. Conceptually, a local government named “Here” is motivated to consider a program from “Elsewhere” that seems to show year-over-year exemplary ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-14-2025 11:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X251324594?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Problem posing or mathematical modeling? The process of expert instructional design</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-14-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>/article/10.1007/s11858-025-01668-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing the Impact of Informational Interventions on Perceptions of School Quality</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Perceptions of school quality affect many aspects of education policy and politics. Using two randomized survey experiments, we studied the factors that individuals use to evaluate school quality. Our surveys included two novel components: text analysis ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2025 12:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312251315740?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Weighting for Equity: The Impact and Challenges of Weighted Student Funding Implementation</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This mixed-methods study examines the impact and implementation of Nevada’s weighted student funding (WSF) model that targets funding to students with the greatest need. We use event study models to analyze student achievement data from 2017–2018 to 2021–...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2025 12:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241313470?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice Elementary Teachers’ Integrated STEM Teaching Self-Efficacy: Contributing Sources Within STEM Education Courses</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Elementary teachers often feel underprepared to teach integrated STEM (iSTEM) and describe their preservice teacher preparation as ineffective. The purpose of this study is to investigate the extent to which semester-long STEM methods courses influenced ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2025 03:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584251321472?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Role of the Policy Environment in Shaping the Work of Professional Learning Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Building on previous work studying research–practice partnerships, we use the framework of policy attributes to explore success and resilience in organizations tasked with quickly adapting to serving teachers and students in school environments vastly ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2025 03:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584251316465?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teachers’ ethical decision-making approaches in instructional practices</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>/article/10.1007/s10649-025-10396-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Researching the expertise of mathematics teacher educators in initial teacher education settings</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>/article/10.1007/s10857-025-09688-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How do Introduction-to-Proof Textbooks Explain Conditionals and Implications?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>/article/10.1007/s40753-024-00263-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming Racial Climate Health on Campus: The Need for Structural Competency in a Legal Context of “Race-Neutrality”</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Campus climate assessment has been an important strategy for improving students’ racialized experiences and racial equity in higher education. But when these assessments lack critical interventions in structural racism, they are easily co-opted to keep ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2025 11:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241304405?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Latent School-Level Classes of Teacher Working Conditions in Virginia: Description, Teacher Preferences, and Contextual Factors</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Many dimensions of teacher working conditions influence both teacher and student outcomes; yet, analyses of schools’ overall working conditions are challenged by high correlations among the dimensions. Our study overcame this challenge by applying latent ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2025 10:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584251321454?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading During Crisis: State and Local Education Leaders’ Equity Focused Approaches During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic exacerbated equity issues in education, spanning race, disability, language, and socioeconomic status. However, few studies examine the ways that district or state educational leaders consider equity in their decision-making during a ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2025 10:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584251318993?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Case for Preregistering Quasi-Experimental Program and Policy Evaluations</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The recognition that researcher discretion coupled with unconscious biases and motivated reasoning sometimes leads to false findings (“p-hacking”) led to the broad embrace of study preregistration and other open-science practices in experimental research. ...
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2025 03:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X251326738?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
