<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>“On a Risky Slope of Democracy”: Racialized Logics Embedded in Community–School Board Interactions</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;As school board meetings are integral sites of local education policymaking, scholars must consider how structural racism manifests in these spaces across various district contexts. We examine how racialized institutional logics undergird the interactions between majority-Black district leadership and a local Black community during school board meetings. Through an ethnographic case study of school board meetings over the 2019–2020 school year, we find that racialized pressures led predominantly Black school board members and district administrators to uphold policies and practices that limited two-way authentic interactions with their Black constituents. In conclusion, we argue that racial representation in educational politics may be important, but is not sufficient unless accompanied by changes to policies and practices that privilege Whiteness and reproduce racism.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-19-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231175166?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Approaches to investigating young children’s mathematical activity</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-17-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00464-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics Self-Efficacy, Utility Value and Well-Being Among School Students in India: Mediating Role of Student Engagement</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-16-2023 06:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2224652?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking mathematics preservice teachers’ conceptions of equity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This report describes initial findings from a larger study conducted in the USA focusing on mathematics teacher preparation and beginning teacher practice as they relate to equity. We particularly address in this report a gap in the literature with respect to pre-service teachers’ conceptions of equity and equitable practice as they relate to issues of identity and power at the end of their teacher education programs. Interviews of 33 students near the completion of their teacher education programs were analyzed using Gutiérrez’s four dimensions of equity—access, achievement, identity, and power. Our findings suggest that these pre-service teachers had ways of thinking about these domains that were both varied and nuanced, with many students describing critical aspects of equitable instruction including attention to bias, representation, student participation, and classroom power structures. Our findings are consistent with prior research in that future teachers described many ideas related to equitable teacher practice that focused on access to mathematics, and, in many cases, deficit perspectives persisted. At the same time, our study suggests that beginning teachers may complete their education programs with critical knowledge around equity that could provide fertile ground for further professional learning.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-16-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00463-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Wiley handbook on violence in education: Forms, factors, and preventions</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-15-2023 11:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2221557?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Health Policies as Education Policies? A Review of Causal Evidence and Mechanisms</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Despite lagging behind other high-income countries, the United States has made slow but steady improvements in health, especially for children from low-income households, through a series of health policies and programs since the 1990s. Have these health benefits spilled over to educational attainment and achievement? In this article, we systematically review the causal impact of various health policies and programs on children’s educational outcomes in the United States. We find that several health policies and programs aimed at improving the physical health of children and parents have modest spillover effects on key educational outcomes for school-age children. On the other hand, there is a paucity of research on policies aimed at improving children and adolescents’ mental health (and limited evidence on their efficacy on educational outcomes where research exists). We contextualize the effects of these health policies by providing benchmarks from other education policies and conclude with some key open questions and suggestions that can guide research and policymaking at the health-education nexus.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-15-2023 11:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231177616?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Teachers Feel Valued in Society? Occupational Value of the Teaching Profession in OECD Countries</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher accountability reforms implemented around the globe have heightened a sense that teachers are losing the support of policymakers and the general public. To examine the global pattern in teachers’ perception of occupational value and identify possible outcomes and predictors, we analyzed the 2018 Teaching and Learning International Survey (TALIS) data. We found an overwhelming majority of teachers feel undervalued in almost all OECD countries. In addition, teachers who feel undervalued reported less collective teacher effort for school improvement and job dissatisfaction consistently in four countries of comparison with different policy contexts—the United States, Australia, Finland, and Korea. However, the relationships between three working conditions impacted by accountability reforms—compensation, classroom autonomy, and involvement in school decision-making—and perceived occupational value varied across these four countries. Specifically, these working conditions seem to matter more in the United States, where the teacher policy context produces greater disparities across schools in teacher qualifications, distribution of qualified teachers, and degree of professional control.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-15-2023 10:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231179184?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing an Equity-Centered Practice: Teacher Study Groups in the Preservice Context</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Equity-centered preparation builds novice teachers’ capacity to make meaningful instruction accessible to all students, particularly those historically excluded from high-quality learning experiences. Drawing on social learning theory, we examined Teacher Study Groups as a model for supporting preservice special educators’ development of equity-centered practices. We examined 60 preservice teachers’ instruction prior to and following study group participation, embedded in a fieldwork support course, alongside related artifacts shared during weekly sessions. Using a convergent mixed-methods approach, we analyzed quantitative and qualitative data separately and then integrated findings using joint display analysis; in doing so, we generated meta-inferences regarding how teachers’ attitudes mediated growth in practice. We uncovered salient participatory experiences that influenced—and hindered—professional growth. Our findings have implications for programs interested in structuring professional learning in a manner that builds foundations for an equity-centered practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-15-2023 10:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231180536?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>bELonging: Do Students Classified as English Learners Feel Included?</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we analyze student survey data related to sense of belonging and relationships with teachers and adults within and across the fastest growing subgroup of K–12 public school students: students classified as English learners (ELs). Students classified as ELs in our study, overall, felt a similar sense of belonging, or slightly higher sense of belonging than their never and formerly EL-classified peers; however, within the sense of belonging constructs, students classified as ELs varied in their perceptions of school climate. Additionally, current EL-classified students who took the survey in English were more positive than those who took the survey in another language; however, once student demographics and school contexts were held constant, survey language was weakly related to our outcome measures. We conclude by discussing how our findings can guide K–12 education policies, practices, and research to foster inclusive educational environments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-15-2023 10:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231179171?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A General Mixture Model for Cognitive Diagnosis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although the generalized deterministic inputs, noisy “and” gate model (G-DINA; de la Torre, 2011) is a general cognitive diagnosis model (CDM), it does not account for the heterogeneity that is rooted from the existing latent groups in the population of examinees. To address this, this study proposes the mixture G-DINA model, a CDM that incorporates the G-DINA model within the finite mixture modeling framework. An expectation–maximization algorithm is developed to estimate the mixture G-DINA model. To determine the viability of the proposed model, an extensive simulation study is conducted to examine the parameter recovery performance, model fit, and correct classification rates. Responses to a reading comprehension assessment were analyzed to further demonstrate the capability of the proposed model.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-15-2023 06:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231176012?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Equity in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reviews research on equity in mathematics education (excluding gender equity) for the period 2017–2022. From the publications identified, five themes were distilled: conceptualizations and framing of equity in mathematics education; research methodologies and researcher positionalities; equity-focused practices, pedagogies and teacher education; equitable mathematics curriculum content, access and pathways; and equity in mathematics education at system levels, nationally and internationally. The review concludes by engaging some of the critique and suggests future directions for research. The research demonstrates that there is growing voice and visibility of equity-focused studies in mathematics education and that conceptualizations of equity have broadened and deepened through an increasing diversity of studies in this area. At the same time, the review also shows the dominance of the Global North in shaping equity discourses and the paucity of research on equity in mathematics education from the Global South.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-15-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01504-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics instructor actions and knowledge integration: utilizing resources in mathematics courses for teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Future mathematics teachers must integrate their knowledge of mathematics, pedagogy, and learners to effectively teach mathematics. Historically, these different forms of knowledge were taught separately in teacher preparation and left to the preservice teacher to integrate on their own. This raises the question; what resources can be leveraged to promote knowledge integration in mathematics courses for teachers? In this study, we identified six instructional actions that were associated with potential knowledge integration when implemented within the environment of a mathematics course for preservice teachers. We posit these instructional actions can be implemented in concise and minimally invasive ways in a variety of mathematics content courses. Further unpacking of these instructional actions and considerations for implementation are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-15-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01502-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collective Bargaining Agreement Restrictiveness in Unionized Charter Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although charter schools are frequently afforded flexibility from many state laws that govern traditional public schools, a growing number of charter school teachers have now unionized and introduced collective bargaining to the charter sector. Using data from a detailed content analysis of teacher CBAs from California, we compare the restrictiveness of CBAs in 75 unionized charter bargaining units to the restrictiveness of CBAs in 31 nearest neighbor traditional public school district bargaining units. We find that independent charter CBAs are much more flexible than the CBAs of traditional public school districts, but charter school CBAs of bargaining units combined with traditional public school districts are comparably restrictive.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-14-2023 12:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231178024?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating Arts Education Effects on School Engagement and Climate</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;There is a renewed focus on what constitutes a well-rounded education, as well as a growing interest in broader indicators of educational success, including social and emotional development and school engagement. However, identifying educational practices that improve such outcomes has proven elusive. We explore the role of arts education on a broad range of educational outcomes using administrative and survey data from Boston’s public schools. We find that students receiving the arts in school attend more, are more engaged, and their parents and teachers are more likely to participate and be engaged at school, with larger effects for students with individualized education plans, students with lower standardized test scores, and students with a history of chronic absenteeism. These findings call attention to the pivotal role of the arts in providing students with socially and emotionally supportive learning environments that enhance relationships between students and schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-14-2023 12:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231174880?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Troublemakers? The Role of Frequent Teacher Referrers in Expanding Racial Disciplinary Disproportionalities</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers’ sensemaking of student behavior determines whether students get in trouble and are formally disciplined. Status categories, such as race, can influence perceptions of student culpability, but the degree to which teachers’ initial identification of student misbehavior exacerbates racial disproportionality in discipline receipt is unknown. This study provides the first systematic documentation of teachers’ use of office discipline referrals (ODRs) in a large, diverse urban school district in California that specifies the identity of both the referred and referring individuals in all ODRs. We identify teachers exhibiting extensive referring behavior, or the top 5% referrers, based on the number of ODRs they make in a given year and evaluate their contributions to disciplinary disparities. We find that “top referrers” effectively double the racial gaps in ODRs for both Black-White and Hispanic-White comparisons. These gaps are mainly driven by higher numbers of ODRs issued for Black and Hispanic students due to interpersonal offences and defiance and also partially convert to racial gaps in suspensions. Both the level and racial compositions of the school sites where top referrers serve and their personal traits seem to explain some of their frequent referring behavior. Targeting supports and interventions to top referrers might afford an important opportunity to reduce racial disciplinary gaps.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-14-2023 11:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231179649?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Shutting the Door Won’t Do: Teaching With the Specter of Community Backlash and the Implications for Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Recently, numerous news stories have detailed the ways teachers across the country have been disciplined for addressing issues of oppression and justice in their schools. This paper engages poststructural discourse analysis to consider data from a year-long study of recent graduates of a justice-oriented teacher education program during their first year teaching, examining the ways that stories of community backlash functioned to discipline early career teachers to behave in particular ways. I theorize that these stories serve to discourage teachers from pursuing justice-oriented work in the classroom and that such discourses must be addressed in teacher education programs to prepare preservice teachers for the political realities of entering classrooms in the United States in the current cultural moment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-14-2023 10:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231180831?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Strong Case for Rethinking Causal Inference</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-14-2023 07:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2203683?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bayesian Exploratory Factor Analysis via Gibbs Sampling</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Bayesian methods to infer model dimensionality in factor analysis generally assume a lower triangular structure for the factor loadings matrix. Consequently, the ordering of the outcomes influences the results. Therefore, we propose a method to infer model dimensionality without imposing any prior restriction on the loadings matrix. Our approach considers a relatively large number of factors and includes auxiliary multiplicative parameters, which may render null the unnecessary columns in the loadings matrix. The underlying dimensionality is then inferred based on the number of nonnull columns in the factor loadings matrix, and the model parameters are estimated with a postprocessing scheme. The advantages of the method in selecting the correct dimensionality are illustrated via simulations and using real data sets.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-14-2023 05:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231176023?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Deep Learning Imputation for Asymmetric and Incomplete Likert-Type Items</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Asymmetric Likert-type items in research studies can present several challenges in data analysis, particularly concerning missing data. These items are often characterized by a skewed scaling, where either there is no neutral response option or an unequal number of possible positive and negative responses. The use of conventional techniques, such as discriminant analysis or logistic regression imputation, for handling missing data in asymmetric items may result in significant bias. It is also recommended to exercise caution when employing alternative strategies, such as listwise deletion or mean imputation, because these methods rely on assumptions that are often unrealistic in surveys and rating scales. This article explores the potential of implementing a deep learning-based imputation method. Additionally, we provide access to deep learning-based imputation to a broader group of researchers without requiring advanced machine learning training. We apply the methodology to the Wilmington Street Participatory Action Research Health Project.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-14-2023 05:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231176014?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bayesian Estimation of Attribute Hierarchy for Cognitive Diagnosis Models</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Attribute hierarchy, the underlying prerequisite relationship among attributes, plays an important role in applying cognitive diagnosis models (CDM) for designing efficient cognitive diagnostic assessments. However, there are limited statistical tools to directly estimate attribute hierarchy from response data. In this study, we proposed a Bayesian formulation for attribute hierarchy within CDM framework and developed an efficient Metropolis within Gibbs algorithm to estimate the underlying hierarchy along with the specified CDM parameters. Our proposed estimation method is flexible and can be adapted to a general class of CDMs. We demonstrated our proposed method via a simulation study, and the results from which show that the proposed method can fully recover or estimate at least a subgraph of the underlying structure across various conditions under a specified CDM model. The real data application indicates the potential of learning attribute structure from data using our algorithm and validating the existing attribute hierarchy specified by content experts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-14-2023 05:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231174918?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building Community and Creating Change: Collaboratively Engaging Diverse Educational Constituents in Schoolwide Equity-Based Work</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-13-2023 12:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2222092?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>University Supervisors’ Perceptions of Their Personal Experiences and Professional Effectiveness in a Study Abroad Student Teaching Program in Germany</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-13-2023 11:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2222089?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Knowledge-in-action for crafting mathematics problems in realistic contexts</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study articulates the epistemological support of reflective practices for the professional practice of crafting mathematics problems in realistic contexts. The data were collected from 15 middle school pre-service mathematics teachers in two semesters as they were generating problems and engaging in three reflective practices, which served to elicit their knowledge-in-action. The prospective teachers’ reflections indicated that the knowledge-in-action for crafting realistic mathematics problems encompassed various but particular forms of the content; that is, pedagogical, curricular, and interdisciplinary forms of the content. Thus, particularly for the professional practice of crafting realistic mathematics problems, the prospective teachers identified epistemological supports that blended not only content and pedagogy but also other knowledge dimensions, which have crucial implications for mathematics teacher education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-13-2023 10:23</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09541-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A framework for selecting strategies for whole-class discussions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study focused on the practice of selecting student strategies for whole-class discussions with teachers working toward a vision of instruction that is responsive to students’ mathematical thinking. Selecting strategies is one of the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;5 practices&lt;/em&gt; identified in Smith and Stein&#39;s (5 practices for orchestrating productive mathematics discussions, National Council of Teachers of Mathematics, 2018) seminal work on orchestrating productive mathematics discussions, but I argue that this practice has been under-appreciated and under-researched, and implementation remains challenging for many teachers. To address these issues, I explored the selecting of student strategies with two sets of upper elementary school teachers engaged in professional development focused on the teaching and learning of fractions. One set consisted of 3 teachers who had demonstrated expertise in teaching that is responsive to students’ mathematical thinking, and I explored the selecting of strategies in these teachers’ classrooms. The other set consisted of 30 teachers with varying levels of expertise in this type of teaching, and I examined their selecting of strategies during professional development activities. Findings led to the creation of a two-level framework that showcases teachers’ criteria for selecting strategies for whole-class mathematics discussions. The framework, which extends and adds a coherent structure to selection criteria currently identified in the literature, highlights considerations related to the mathematics of the strategy, the author of the strategy, and the class engagement with the strategy. The framework, which is presented through a case, was designed to not only provide guidance for the purposeful selection of strategies but also to be accessible and useful to teachers at any phase of their development in being responsive to students’ mathematical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-13-2023 10:23</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09536-5</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
