<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Shift in School Reform: Examining Site-Level Spending and Student Academic Growth</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Accountability efforts under the Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) has brought greater attention to school-level processes and practices and their impact on student outcomes. This has pushed states to report more school-level inputs, including per-pupil expenditures. Grounded in an open systems theory (OST) framework, we identify the association between school-level per-pupil spending and academic growth on statewide assessments for seventh graders in Michigan. Overall, our findings suggest an overall positive association between school-level per-pupil expenditure and student growth.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 10:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241243066?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Education Experiments in Latin America: Empirical Evidence to Guide Evaluation Design</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Randomized experiments involving education interventions are typically implemented as cluster randomized trials, with schools serving as clusters. To design such a study, it is critical to understand the degree to which learning outcomes vary between versus within clusters (schools), specifically the intraclass correlation coefficient. It is also helpful to anticipate the benefits, in terms of statistical power, of collecting household data, testing students at baseline, or relying on administrative data on previous cohorts from the same school. We use data from multiple cluster-randomized trials in four Latin American countries to provide information on the intraclass correlations in early grade literacy outcomes. We also describe the proportion of variance explained by different types of covariates. These parameters will help future researchers conduct statistical power analysis, estimate the required sample size, and determine the necessity of collecting different types of baseline data such as child assessments, administrative data at the school level, or household surveys.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 08:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241241354?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>State Goals, Institutional Social Constructions, and Utah’s Postsecondary Education Governance Reform Efforts</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;State-level postsecondary education governance has experienced a lull in successful reform efforts since the turn of the century. However, in 2020, the Utah System of Higher Education and Utah System of Technical Colleges were formally merged following a multi-year effort by state legislators and higher education officials. Framed by the theory of social construction and policy design, this study considers underlying institutional considerations and statewide goals that led to Utah’s governance merger and how these changes impacted the public higher education sectors in the state, offering insights for research examining higher education governance and reform efforts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 06:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241243082?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nuancing the narrative: understanding Asian American opposition to NYC’s selective high school admissions reform</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 05:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2334459?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We’re not fully us without our languages”: multilingual latina educators and raciolinguistic ideological clarity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 05:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2334457?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student groups evaluating their group work and learning of critical online reading</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-29-2024 03:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2333565?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Relevance of Historically Black Colleges and Universities: From a Critical Race Theorist Standpoint</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-28-2024 01:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2331936?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning more about derivative: leveraging online resources for varied realizations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract  &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Recent literature underlines the increasing use of online platforms in learning undergraduate mathematics, where students refer to these as supplementary resources to develop their mathematical understanding. Through an intrinsic case study, we focus on a highly viewed YouTube learning resource for learning derivative. The selected case is from &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;3Blue1Brown&lt;/em&gt;, a YouTube channel whose founder has received an award from the American Mathematical Society. The video has garnered more than 3.3 million views in the past couple of years. Reflecting on the relevant literature, a realization tree for derivative is developed and then used as an analytical tool to analyze this resource to explore what realizations have been used in it to facilitate students’ understanding of derivative. The findings indicate that the analyzed YouTube resource discusses various realizations of derivative, including all its five main realizations, and effectively utilizes new digital technology for discussing these realizations. Such an exceptional resource for learning mathematics leads us to suggest that mathematics lecturers raise their awareness about such online free resources and incorporate them into their teaching packages when appropriate to facilitate student learning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01564-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Mathematics is a battle, but I’ve learned to survive”: becoming a disabled student in university mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In university mathematics education, students do not simply learn mathematics but are shaped and shape themselves into someone new—mathematicians. In this study, we focus on the becoming of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dis&lt;/em&gt;abled mathematical subjects. We explore the importance of abilities in the processes of being and becoming in university mathematics. Our interest lies in how teaching and assessment practices provide students with ways to understand themselves as both able and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dis&lt;/em&gt;abled, as &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dis&lt;/em&gt;abilities are only understood with respect to the norm. We analyse narratives of nine university students diagnosed with learning disabilities or mental health issues to investigate how their subjectivity is constituted in discourse. Our analysis shows how the students are shaped and shape themselves as &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dis&lt;/em&gt;abled mathematicians in relation to &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;speed&lt;/em&gt; in mathematical activities, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;disaffection&lt;/em&gt; in mathematics, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;individualism&lt;/em&gt; in performing mathematics, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;measurability&lt;/em&gt; of performance. These findings cast light on the ableist underpinnings of the teaching and assessment practices in university mathematics education. We contend that mathematical ableism forms a watershed for belonging in mathematics learning practices, constituting rather narrow, “normal” ways of being “mathematically able”. We also discuss how our participants challenge and widen the idea of an “able” mathematics student. We pave the way for more inclusive futures of mathematics education by suggesting that rather than understanding the “dis” in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dis&lt;/em&gt;ability negatively, the university mathematics education communities may use &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dis&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dis&lt;/em&gt;rupting order. Perhaps, we ask, if university mathematics fails to enable accessible learning experiences for students who care about mathematics, these practices should indeed be disrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10311-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making an Impact</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00312-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the relationship between legislative theatre and critical participatory action research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-27-2024 12:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2332435?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reasoning with Two Types of Multiplicative Units Structures in Solving Middle-Grade Mathematics Problems</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-27-2024 05:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2329664?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reclaiming inclusion in an age of indignation</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 44-47, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;As educators have pushed for inclusion of all marginalized students of different identities, we’ve seen a backlash of political and parental indignation. Andy Hargreaves and Dennis Shirley suggest that while it’s sometimes clear who is right and who is wrong in these disputes, some issues aren’t so clear, and people’s multiple identities can come in conflict. They suggest that better representation, drawing upon our capacity for sympathy, not giving up on the power of learning, seeking out what serves the common good, and conducting disagreements with consideration for each other’s rights, are some of the best ways to define and defend the inclusive school and get through the storms of outrage and indignation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244905?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Free books to close the reading achievement gap</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 48-51, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Richard Allington reviews the nature of the reading achievement gap between students from low-income and high-income families, concluding that the limited access to children’s books experienced by children from low-income families lies at the base of the problem. The fact that children from low-income families lose reading achievement every summer largely explains summer reading loss. Allington and his colleagues completed two large-scale studies assessing the impact of giving free books of their choice to students from low-income families for them to read over the summer. After three years of summer books, the children gained almost a year in reading achievement compared to the students who did not receive books. The summer books project cost far less than a summer school program and produced greater achievement gains than having low-income children attend summer school programs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244906?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mini-observations 2.0</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 52-57, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Traditional teacher evaluations – full-lesson observations, write-ups, and debriefs — are time-consuming and largely ineffective. As a principal, Kim Marshall found that mini-observations — short, frequent, unannounced classroom visits, each followed by a face-to-face coaching conversation and brief narrative summary — actually improved teaching and learning. With the benefit of hindsight, he shares ways mini-observations could be even more effective and shares some common observation practices he believes leaders should rethink.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244907?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning with Leaders: Excellence for all students, districtwide: Luvelle Brown</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Luvelle Brown, superintendent of the Ithaca City School District in New York, talks with James F. Lane about his work on leadership, equity, and transforming instruction. As an educator, he’s committed to promoting excellence for students who have been denied opportunities. As a district leader, he’s sought to bring greater diversity to leadership. He encourages educators to find joy in their mission and commit to doing the work.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244908?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Taking a LEAP toward community-engaged leadership</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 26-31, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Historical and contemporary factors have disenfranchised and destabilized certain school communities (specifically communities of color). Education leaders can be more inclusive and address the persistent impacts of these broader trends by embracing a community-focused approach to leadership. Darrius A. Stanley, Dan Brogan, and Emily Colton borrow from contemporary research which suggests that educational leaders can help bridge the gaps between schools and historically disenfranchised communities through community-engaged leadership. They offer a research-based, conceptual argument and practical approach to building and sustaining community inclusive schools through listening, engaging, advocating, and partnering.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244902?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Safe, seen, and ready to learn</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 20-25, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;For far too many students, schools are not places of belonging. This is due, in part, to the cultural mismatch between schools and students that, despite even the best of intentions, too often leads to student harm and negative student outcomes. Gloria McDaniel-Hall and Nina F. Weisling provide insights for understanding why belonging is vital to student learning, how teachers can recognize when they fall short of building spaces where all students feel they belong, and suggestions for starting to learn, unlearn, and relearn so that all students feel safe, seen, and ready to learn.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244901?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guarding against book challenges with professionalism and confidence</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 38-43, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Teaching literacy skills through high-quality trade books that provide diverse cultural perspectives is increasingly difficult due to challenges to teachers’ book selections. To meet their professional responsibilities, teachers must select literature they judge effective for developing students’ awareness and understanding of others’ perspectives. Adriana L. Medina, Rachelle Kuehl, and Edwina Pendarvis discuss how teachers can prepare for challenges by relying on learning standards, consulting book awards lists, and building trust with families. They offer methods for navigating controversy while fostering social responsibility and global competencies and protecting students’ access to literature that teaches perspective-taking and promotes understanding of people with differing backgrounds, experiences, and societal contributions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244904?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Disrupting disparities in school discipline</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 32-37, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Schools across the country are grappling with vocal resistance to educational equity efforts, while disparities, including racial disproportionality in school discipline, persist. In this research-practice-partnership project, Adai A. Tefera, Genevieve Siegel-Hawley, Ashlee Sjogren, and David Naff learned of the ways educators and leaders across three distinct schools adopted and engaged in widespread discipline interventions and practices that often failed to consider race, culture, and context — issues central to racial disproportionality in discipline. To counter these race-evasive interventions and practices, they offer recommendations for leaders, educators, and students to engage in race-conscious discipline to advance more just school policies and practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244903?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading inclusion</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 14-19, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The 42 school districts participating in the state of Washington’s Inclusionary Practices Project achieved a significant 12.8% increase in inclusion in the least restrictive environment (LRE 1, or in general education for 80-100% of the school day) over four years, surpassing the state average increase of 6.8%. Katie Novak and Helene Paroff highlight the importance of leadership, collaboration, progress assessment, and continuous professional learning to the success of the project. The project challenges the perception that inclusion is limited to special education and underscores the role of executive sponsorship. Above all, the work provides valuable insights for replicating and creating inclusive environments in other education systems.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244900?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: Education policy reform for the hip-hop era</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-61, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Fifty years after the birth of hip-hop, Jonathan E. Collins considers how hip-hop can transform U.S. education. Many schools have barred hip-hop and disciplined students who use it. But these restrictions have been built on flimsy premises that ignore the beauty and complexity of the art form. Embracing and incorporating hip-hop can improve student engagement, particularly among Black students, and help schools forge stronger connections with the community.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244909?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: Principal lets students get away with too much</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 66-66, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In Career Confidential, Phyllis Fagell answers work-related questions from educators. This month’s column includes a teacher who is frustrated that the principal isn’t much help when she sends students to him for their behavior.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244912?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: How schools promote belonging</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/7&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 7&lt;/a&gt;, Page 68-69, April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Educators Rising students share what their schools do to promote a sense of belonging among students and offer ideas for what they could do better.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-26-2024 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241244913?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
