<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of Large-Scale Early Math Interventions on Student Outcomes: Evidence From Kentucky’s Math Achievement Fund</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Addressing the educational needs of students in math early on is critical given that early gaps in math skills widen further over the course of schooling. This study examines the effectiveness and costs of Kentucky’s Math Achievement Fund—a unique state-level program that combines targeted interventions, peer-coaching, and close collaboration among teachers to improve math achievement in grades K–3. The program is found to improve not only math achievement, but also reading test scores and non-test outcomes including student attendance and disciplinary incidents. The benefits exist across students from various socioeconomic backgrounds, and they are slightly higher for racial minorities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-31-2024 11:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241303142?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Ordering Theory to Learn Attribute Hierarchies From Examinees’ Attribute Profiles</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In cognitive diagnosis, attribute hierarchies are considered important structural features of cognitive diagnostic models, as they provide auxiliary information about the nature of attributes. In this article, the idea of ordering theory is applied to cognitive diagnosis, and a new approach to identify attribute hierarchy based on the attribute correlation intensity matrix is proposed. This approach attempts to identify attribute hierarchy in data with a small sample size while ensuring a high accuracy rate. The results of simulation studies and empirical data analysis show that the proposed approach can be used to identify attribute hierarchy in diagnostic tests, especially in small samples, making it worth popularizing.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-31-2024 06:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241280389?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Navigating Precarious Citizenship in Schools: Newcomer Youth of Color at the Intersection of Race and Ability</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Refugee and asylum-seeking youth of color from African and Middle Eastern countries contend with racist-ableist structures in host-nation schools, primarily through newcomer supports offered to them. Considering their unique migratory experiences, this comprehensive systematic literature review explored how youth of color from Africa and the Middle East are supported in host-nation schools already entrenched in systemic racism and ableism. This review advanced precarious citizenship as a framework to explain student experiences. The findings showed how segregation and exclusion, ableist determinations of civic fitness, and assimilationist imperatives introduced precarity and foreclosed educational opportunities. Implications for research and practice are discussed, emphasizing the importance of disrupting racism and ableism in supporting newcomer youth of color.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-30-2024 11:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241293443?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Playing in the Dark? Blackness, Humanity, and Studies of Black Life in Education 2012–2022</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The series of high-profile Black deaths in the United States between 2012–2022 (e.g., Trayvon Martin, Michael Brown, Breonna Taylor) mark an important turning point in studies of Black life in education. The increasing use of anti-Blackness theorizing coupled with the introduction of Black critical theory (BlackCrit) to the field of education has inspired new research investigations aiming to understand anti-Black racial harm more precisely. Growing interest in such study leads us to wonder how education researchers envision Black life in their work, and more specifically, the subject of Blackness and its relationship to notions of humanity. As scholars whose research demonstrates a disciplined intellectual commitment to Black humanity, we observe that a uniform scholarly conception of humanity + Blackness remains elusive. In this systematic review of 226 peer-reviewed articles, we seek to better understand (a) how education researchers conceptualize Black humanity in articles published during a period of intense social change and political upheaval in the United States (i.e., 2012–2022); (b) what specific claims they make about Black life as a result; and (c) what long-term implications emerge as a result of this knowledge production. Ultimately, this paper offers insight for sharpening the theoretical and interpretive heft of education research that probes the substance of Black people’s lived education realities, the knowledge from which is desperately needed to imagine, design, and steward education futures that all America’s children need to thrive.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-30-2024 10:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241302344?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond the Classroom: The Broader Effects of Public Preschool Expansion on Children’s Early Educational Experiences and Early Literacy Skills</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Preschool has direct effects on attendees, but less is known about how public preschool expansions targeted to low-income children affect early educational experiences and school readiness in a broader community. We use Virginia administrative data (~630,000 students) and a discrete increase in targeted public pre-K (Virginia Preschool Initiative Plus [VPI+]) to estimate the effects of means-tested pre-K expansion on preschool participation patterns and school readiness. VPI+ expansion decreased the probability that children spend no time in licensed settings (6–7 percentage points), increasing the probability for public pre-K and private centers (5–8 and 2–3 percentage points, respectively). Kindergarten literacy skills improve (5%–6% of SD). Effects are larger among the target population but shared broadly (perhaps through private centers). These previously unmeasured benefits inform future policy and research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-30-2024 03:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241303166?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Differential Responses to Teacher Evaluation Incentives: Expectancy, Race, Experience, and Task</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher evaluation systems and their associated incentives have produced fairly mixed results. Our analyses are motivated by theory and descriptive evidence that accountability systems are highly racialized, and that individuals are less likely to respond to incentives when they have low expectations of success (and vice versa). Using a regression discontinuity design, we find that Black novices in the District of Columbia Public Schools faced the most negative consequences (dismissal threats) and the least benefits (salary incentives), without responding to either. White novices, in contrast, exhibited high expectations of success and large behavior changes, particularly in response to dismissal threats (0.6 SD). We also find some evidence of heterogeneity in effects by task difficulty, often used as a proxy for expectancy, though these differences are less stark.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-30-2024 03:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241298666?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identifying the types of collective engagement structures that manifest in middle-grade mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-30-2024 03:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2447591?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tensions experienced by second-career student teachers at the start of their training programme</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-27-2024 12:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2445105?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preparing middle and high school teachers for teaching mathematical modeling: building curriculum vision and trust through curricular and professional noticing</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Preservice teachers need more opportunities to learn about mathematical modeling, and the field needs more research-based knowledge about effective course design, strategies, and practices to foster preservice teachers’ professional competency for teaching mathematical modeling. This case study examined how curricular and professional noticing frameworks helped preservice teachers develop curriculum vision and curriculum trust. Eight preservice mathematics teachers enrolled in a secondary (6–12) teacher preparation program participated in a 15-week professional development seminar series in which they (a) analyzed model eliciting activities and made sense of their curricular and pedagogical opportunities, (b) planned and enacted modeling tasks, and (c) reflected on their enactment through the lens of curricular and professional noticing. The results of this study suggest that using curricular and professional noticing can help preservice teachers recognize and make sense of the design principles of modeling tasks, the long-term learning goals afforded by the tasks, and potential implementation obstacles. However, developing curriculum vision seems to be easier than developing curriculum trust. Our analyses provide pedagogical implications for mathematics teacher education and professional development in order to better prepare mathematics teachers for the instruction of mathematical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09673-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tools to support learning to plan discussions that promote students’ mathematical reasoning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We investigate pre-service teachers’ learning to plan discussions promoting students’ mathematical reasoning. Specifically, we analyse opportunities to learn to plan provided by three planning tools: a conceptual framework of the mathematical work of reasoning and proving, a set of talk moves, and a mathematical task with students’ work. In learning cycles, the pre-service teachers investigated, planned, enacted, and reflected on practice, using role-plays as an approximation to practice. The planning was organised in small groups, and these groups’ collaborative work was videotaped, transcribed, and analysed using thematic analysis. Our findings reveal three patterns of tool use: tools as a support for planning, planning as a context to make sense of the tools, and the use of talk moves to plan when the students’ work was insufficient as a support. From these patterns, we identify several opportunities to learn afforded by the tools. However, we also identify and discuss limitations in the design of the tools, particularly related to mathematical reasoning. Based on our findings, we discuss implications for teacher education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-26-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09668-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Initiating a conversation about expertise in designing elementary mathematics methods courses for equity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Many elementary education programs have only one mathematics methods course designed for preservice teachers (PTs). Such courses typically cover a range of content and present a challenge for mathematics teacher educators (MTEs) who strive to prepare their PTs to teach mathematics in equitable and humane ways. Due to the “stand-alone” nature of these semester-long courses, additional expertise is required for MTEs who desire to intentionally and authentically attend to equity and support PTs in developing pedagogy that aims for equity as outlined by (Gutiérrez, in: Herbel-Eisenmann, Choppin, Wagner, Pimm (eds) Equity in discourse for mathematics education, Springer, Berlin, 2012). In this paper, we take a first step at outlining this expertise by proffering a framework for conceptualizing MTE curricular knowledge for designing mathematics methods courses for equity. Using 12 syllabi for stand-alone elementary mathematics methods courses in initial teacher licensure programs from MTEs who have demonstrated expertise in the field of equitable mathematics teaching (MTE-EEs), we examined how aspects of their curricular expertise were evidenced in course descriptions, goals, objectives, assignments, topics, and related readings. Findings indicated that MTE-EEs often included similar design features in their courses and concentrated their attention to equity on access and identity. Implications and future directions for research are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-26-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09670-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating the impact of racial microaggressions on Black, racialized, and Indigenous students: a narrative synthesis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-25-2024 12:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2447118?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From teacher surplus to teacher shortage and its effects on teacher education: the Portuguese case</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-25-2024 06:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2443668?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Validating Classrooms: Teaching Strategies to Advance Equity in Developmental Education</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research on developmental education reform has given surprisingly limited attention to what happens inside the classroom between faculty and students. Our qualitative study used interview data from 20 faculty and 20 students in corequisite math and English courses at one of the nation’s largest and most racially diverse community college systems. Specifically, we used validation theory to examine faculty teaching strategies and support structures that may increase academic success among corequisite students. Our findings demonstrate that the most effective faculty, who often had course pass rates 20% above the institutional average, created validating learning environments that addressed students’ academic and interpersonal needs. We provide recommendations for expanding the use of validating teaching and learning practices in corequisite-developmental education courses to ensure more equitable student outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 12:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241309575?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Finessing the system: navigating and negotiating the model minority identity as South Asian American youth</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 10:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2446210?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Updates</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 788-789, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297954?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcements</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 788-789, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297955?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On synthetic difference-in-differences and related estimation methods in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 557-598, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we describe a computational implementation of the synthetic difference-in-differences (SDID) estimator of Arkhangelsky et al. (2021, American Economic Review 111: 4088-4118) for Stata. SDID can be used in many circumstances where treatment effects on some particular policy or event are desired and repeated observations on treated and untreated units are available over time. We lay out the theory underlying SDID both when there is a single treatment adoption date and when adoption is staggered over time, and we discuss estimation and inference in each of these cases. We introduce the sdid command, which implements these methods in Stata, and provide several examples of use, discussing estimation, inference, and visualization of results. Along with SDID, the sdid command allows for the implementation of standard synthetic control and difference-in-differences methods in an identical framework, permitting estimation, inference, and the generation of graphical output in a computationally efficient way.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297914?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>require: Package dependencies for reproducible research</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 599-613, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The ability to conduct reproducible research in Stata is often limited by the lack of version control for community-contributed packages. In this article, we introduce the require command, a tool designed to ensure package dependencies are compatible across users and computer systems. Given a list of packages, require verifies that each package is installed, checks for a minimum or exact version or package release date, and optionally installs the package if prompted by the researcher.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297915?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estimating treatment effects when program participation is misreported</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 614-629, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Instrumental variables are commonly used to estimate treatment effects in cases of imperfect compliance. However, if participation in the program is misreported, standard techniques can yield severely biased results. We present a new command, ivreg2m, that implements the mismeasured robust local average treatment-effect estimator developed by Calvi, Lewbel, and Tommasi (2022, Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 40: 1701–1717) and Tommasi and Zhang (2024b, Journal of Applied Econometrics, doi.org/10.1002/jae.3079), to estimate the heterogeneous treatment effect of a program in the presence of treatment noncompliance and misreporting. The ivreg2m command can be used as the preferred strategy in cases of exogenous (nondifferential) misclassification.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297916?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Outlier detection for inequality and poverty analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 630-665, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Extreme values are common in survey data and represent a recurring threat to the reliability of both poverty and inequality estimates. The adoption of a consistent criterion for outlier detection is useful in many practical applications, particularly when international and intertemporal comparisons are involved. In this article, we discuss a simple univariate detection procedure to flag outliers. We present outdetect, a command that implements the procedure and provides useful diagnostic tools. The output of outdetect compares statistics obtained before and after the exclusion of outliers, with a focus on inequality and poverty measures. Finally, we carry out an extensive sensitivity exercise where the same outlier detection method is applied consistently to per capita expenditure across more than 30 household budget surveys. The results are clear and provide a sense of the influence of extreme values on poverty and inequality estimates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297918?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 158: The devil is in the delta</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 777-783, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297950?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Erratum: Power and sample-size calculations for trials that compare slopes over time: Introducing the slopepower command</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 784-787, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297951?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Distinguishing differences in construct from differences in response style: gsem for item response theory models with anchoring vignettes</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 666-686, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Item response theory models allow estimation of participant and group-mean trait scores from responses to a set of items, but estimates can be biased when participants vary in their response style. We illustrate models fit in gsem that can account for such response style differences by comparing self-report with their ratings of anchoring vignettes—descriptions of other individuals displaying different levels of the trait. Simulation results from standard item response theory, mean bias, random bias, and free-threshold models are illustrated. We show that unbiased estimates can be recovered when the vignettes rated depend on the participants’ own self-rating or are even rated by a different sample, substantially broadening their scope of application.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297920?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
