<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The significance of children’s olfactory experiences in a Norwegian kindergarten: an olfactory researcher-practitioner collaboration</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 09:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2240391?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engaging Preservice Teachers with Equity-Related Cases to Make Visible the Inequities in Mathematics Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 07:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2242312?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching and learning of probability</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we develop a personal synthesis of the most outstanding research on the teaching and learning of probability in the past years. We conducted a systematic search to examine publications on this topic in mathematics education, statistics education, education, and psychology journals. This exploration was complemented by additional studies published in conference proceedings or books. We classified these papers to highlight the main recent research tendencies in the field, according to the theme studied and considering the research objectives. Epistemological analyses suggest that informal inference based on simulation diminishes the topic abstraction but reduces probability to its frequentist view. Topics receiving particular attention include children’s probabilistic knowledge, the effect of visualizations on solving conditional probability problems, teachers’ education and probability modelling. In the final section, we recommend relevant points in which more investigation is needed to complete our knowledge about teaching and learning. In particular, we miss research on teachers’ mathematical knowledge of many probability concepts and on their didactic knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01511-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The battle for curriculum: arrested semantics and reconciling racism with critical race theory and Ethnic Studies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 12:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2239726?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Placing Equity Front and Center” for Teacher Education in a Time of Crisis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/74/4&quot;&gt;Volume 74, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 293-298, September/October 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 08:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231189792?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Segregating Gotham’s Youngest: Racial/Ethnic Sorting and the Choice Architecture of New York City’s Pre-K for All</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;New York City’s Pre-K for All (PKA) is the nation’s largest universal early childhood initiative, serving over 64,000 four-year-olds annually. Stemming from the program’s choice architecture as well as the city’s stark residential segregation, PKA programs are extremely segregated by child race/ethnicity. Our current study explores the complex forces that influence this segregation, including the interplay between family choices, seat availability, site-level enrollment priorities, and the PKA algorithm that weighs these and other considerations. We find that a majority of PKA segregation lies within local communities, and that areas with increased options and greater racial/ethnic diversity exhibit the most extreme segregation. We also conduct a simulation that leverages family PKA choices to maximize site-level racial/ethnic diversity and reduce between-site segregation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 08:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231190071?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where internationalisation and digitalisation intersect: designing a virtual exchange to enhance student teachers’ professional awareness as European teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 07:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2243644?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating the Stroke Risk of Patients using Machine Learning: A New Perspective from Sichuan and Chongqing</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt; Stroke is the leading cause of death and disability among people in China, and it leads to heavy burdens for patients, their families and society. An accurate prediction of the risk of stroke has important implications for early intervention and treatment. In light of recent advances in machine learning, the application of this technique in stroke prediction has achieved plentiful promising results. To detect the relationship between potential factors and the risk of stroke and examine which machine learning method significantly can enhance the prediction accuracy of stroke. We employed six machine learning methods including logistic regression, naive Bayes, decision tree, random forest, K-nearest neighbor and support vector machine, to model and predict the risk of stroke. Participants were 233 patients from Sichuan and Chongqing. Four indicators (accuracy, precision, recall and F1 metric) were examined to evaluate the predictive performance of the different models. The empirical results indicate that random forest yields the best accuracy, recall and F1 in predicting the risk of stroke, with an accuracy of .7548, precision of .7805, recall of .7619 and F1 of .7711. Additionally, the findings show that age, cerebral infarction, PM 8 (an anti-atrial fibrillation drug), and drinking are independent risk factors for stroke. Further studies should adopt a broader assortment of machine learning methods to analyze the risk of stroke, by which better accuracy can be expected. In particular, RF can successfully enhance the forecasting accuracy for stroke.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 07:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231193468?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading Rural Districts: Research Synthesis of Rural Educational Leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 12:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238519?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participatory pedagogies enhance engineering education for sustainability</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 10:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2240858?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Practicum in ELT: a systematic review of 2010–2020 research on ELT practicum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2242577?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward a Conceptual Understanding of Inclusion as Intersubjective Experiences</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Inclusion has become a global buzzword relating to education policy and practice. Mostly, it is tied to discussions about access and opportunities in education spaces as well as school policies and the curriculum decisions and pedagogical actions of teachers. As part of this critique, we propose defining inclusion as intersubjective experiences associated with feelings of belonging, acceptance, and value that are dynamic, ephemeral, spatial, and in flux. Here, we advocate for centering the experiences and amplifying the voices of disabled children and young people in and about education spaces, while acknowledging the wider social forces that structure those spaces, as only disabled young people can explain how they feel in the educational spaces where they find themselves.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 02:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231176287?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Clustering eye-movement data uncovers students’ strategies for coordinating equations and diagrams of vector fields</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In mathematics education, students are repeatedly confronted with the tasks of interpreting and relating different representations. In particular, switching between equations and diagrams plays a major role in learning mathematical procedures and solving mathematical problems. In this article, we investigate a rather unexplored topic with precisely such requirements—that is, vector fields. In our study, we first presented a series of multiple-choice tasks to 147 introductory university students at the beginning of their studies and recorded students’ eye movements while they matched vector field diagrams and equations. Thereafter, students had to solve a similar coordination task on paper and justify their reasoning. Two cluster analyses were performed including (i) transition and fixation data on diagrams and options (Model 1), and (ii) additionally the number of horizontal and vertical saccades on the diagram (Model 2). In both models, two clusters emerge—with Model 1 distinguishing behaviors related to representational mapping and Model 2 additionally differentiating students according to representation-specific demands. Model 2 leads to a better distinction between the groups in terms of different performance indicators (test score, response confidence, and spatial ability) which also transfers to another task format. We conclude that vertical and horizontal saccades reflect executive actions of perception when approaching vector field coordination tasks. Thus, we recommend targeted interventions for mathematics lessons; these lessons must focus on a visual handling of the vector field diagram. Further, we infer that students’ difficulties can be attributed to covariational reasoning, thereby indicating the need for further investigations. From a methodological perspective, we reflect on the triangulation of eye-tracking and verbal data in (multiple-choice) assessment scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-02-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10243-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘I realised it when we played with the doll!’: nursing students’ learning from participation in an action research project that included manikins</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 07:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2242425?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Epistemic Injustice and Legitimacy in U.S. Doctoral Education: A Systematic Review of Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Epistemic injustice is a condition where knowers and knowledge claims are unduly dismissed. Philosophers suggest that epistemic injustice manifests in three forms: testimonial, hermeneutical, and contributory. Although distinct, all forms of epistemic injustice stem from relations of power, privilege, and positionality — where some have the opportunity and authority to legitimize the knowledge contributions of others. The purpose of this study was to explore the presence of epistemic injustice in U.S. doctoral education through a systematic review of literature. We methodically searched hundreds of peer-reviewed journals for studies focused on teaching, advising, peer interaction, doctoral socialization, and other experiences concerning doctoral education across the humanities, social science, and science disciplines. We retained, reviewed, and analyzed 107 manuscripts. Our analysis revealed epistemic injustice in doctoral education as well as rules that foster the conditions for epistemic injustice. Implications for doctoral education and future research are offered.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 06:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231187628?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Trekking Across Some Rough Terrain: Rural Teacher Education for Multilingual Students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 02:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238502?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Recruiting and Retaining Teachers in Rural Schools: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 01:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238491?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Encountering ideas about teaching and learning mathematics in undergraduate mathematics courses</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We study the ideas about teaching and learning mathematics that undergraduate students generate when they encounter tasks designed to embed approximations of teaching practice in mathematics courses taken by a general population of students. These tasks attend to the dual goals of developing an understanding of mathematics content and an understanding of how teachers provide classroom experiences that foster mathematics learning. The study employs a qualitative, multiple-case study methodology, with four cases bounded by the content areas of abstract algebra, single variable calculus, discrete mathematics, and introductory statistics. The data for the study come from undergraduate students’ written work on mathematical tasks, interviews with a subset of students from each course, and interviews with each instructor throughout the term during which they implemented the tasks. Our findings indicate that students identified the broad applicability of teaching skills (discussed by 32 of the 61 interviewed students), recognized the value of examining hypothetical learners’ mathematical work (discussed by 59 of the 61 interviewed students), and reported empathy for hypothetical learners (discussed by 38 of the 61 interviewed students). These findings persisted across the course content and course levels we studied, leading us to conclude that our findings can transfer to additional mathematics courses in secondary mathematics teacher preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01454-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating a teacher-perspective on pedagogical mathematical practices: possibilities for using mathematical practice to develop pedagogy in mathematical coursework</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;One of the challenges of university mathematics courses in secondary teacher preparation is incorporating pedagogical discussions. The focus in a mathematics course is—and should be—on mathematics. But research also suggests that without addressing pedagogical implications these content courses are not meaningful to secondary teachers’ future classroom practice. The thrust of this paper is exploring ideas for how to leverage mathematical practice in university mathematics courses—and, in particular, what have been described as Pedagogical Mathematical Practices (PMPs). The paper reports on a study of (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 10) pre- and in-service mathematics teachers that explored the viability of the PMP construct, with the intent of specifying particular PMPs. Drawing on interviews with teacher participants who had recent experiences in an inquiry-oriented discrete mathematics course, the study reports on the ways in which they identified a set of mathematical practices as being productive pedagogically. The study contributes a teacher-perspective on the construct of PMPs, including the identification of four PMPs from the study data: explicit visualization; multiple approaches; concrete exemplification; and informal justification. Implications for their potential use in university mathematics courses with regard to teacher education are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01468-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prospective Secondary Teachers’ Emergent Knowledge and Beliefs: Inquiry-Oriented Differential Equations Contributing to Teacher Preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article reports on the evolution of prospective secondary teachers’ knowledge (meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                      
                      &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                      
                    &lt;/span&gt;) and beliefs (about teaching and learning mathematics) in a semester-long inquiry-oriented differential equations class. Students entered the course with limited, primarily procedural, meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                      
                      &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                      
                    &lt;/span&gt;. Throughout the semester, they engaged in collaborative mathematical inquiry using a research-based curriculum. As viewed through the emergent perspective, students’ meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq3&quot;&gt;
                      
                      &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                      
                    &lt;/span&gt; and their beliefs about teaching and learning mathematics co-evolved with community norms and practices through the classroom discourse. Students’ end-of-term portfolios and portfolio presentations were analyzed for evidence of meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq4&quot;&gt;
                      
                      &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                      
                    &lt;/span&gt; and beliefs about students’ roles, instructors’ roles, and the general nature of learning mathematics. In these, students expressed rich, multifaceted meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq5&quot;&gt;
                      
                      &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                      
                    &lt;/span&gt; and beliefs about learning as an active process of meaning-making. While many prospective teachers do not see the relevance of advanced mathematics coursework to their career, these students reflected on their experiences in the course and volunteered ways in which their emerging knowledge and beliefs would influence their future practice. We emphasize that the classroom norms supported students in pursuing connections themselves, and conjecture that similar norms would support the development of reflective practitioners in other contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01469-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Enhancing prospective secondary teachers’ potential competence for enacting core teaching practices—through experiences in university mathematics and statistics courses</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In 1908, Felix Klein suggested that to mend the discontinuity that prospective secondary teachers face, university instruction must account for teachers’ needs. More than a century later, problems of discontinuity remain. Our project addresses the dilemma of discontinuity in university mathematics courses through simulating core teaching practices in mathematically intensive ways. In other words, we interpret teachers’ needs to include integrating content and pedagogy. We argue that doing so has the potential to impact teachers’ competence. To make this argument, we report findings from the Mathematics of Doing, Understanding, Learning, and Educating for Secondary Schools (MODULE(S2)) project. The results are based on data from 324 prospective secondary mathematics teachers (PSMTs) enrolled in courses using curricular materials developed by the project in four content areas (algebra, geometry, modeling, and statistics). We operationalized competence in terms of PSMTs’ content knowledge for teaching and their motivation for enacting core teaching practices. We examined pre- and post-term data addressing these constructs. We found mean increases in PSMTs’ outcomes in content knowledge for teaching and aspects of motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01485-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using conceptual analyses to resolve the tension between advanced and secondary mathematics: the cases of equivalence and inverse</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Advanced mathematics is seen as an integral component of secondary teacher preparation, and thus most secondary teacher preparation programs require their students to complete an array of advanced mathematics courses. In recent years, though, researchers have questioned the utility of proposed connections between advanced and secondary mathematics. It is simply not clear in many cases—to researchers, teacher educators, and teachers themselves—exactly how advanced mathematics content is related to secondary content. In this paper, we propose using a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;conceptual analysis&lt;/em&gt;—a form of theory in which one explicitly describes ways of reasoning about a particular mathematical idea—to address this issue. Specifically, we use conceptual analyses for the foundational notions of equivalence and inverse to illustrate how the ways of reasoning needed to support productive engagement with tasks in advanced mathematics can mirror and reinforce those that are similarly productive in school mathematics. To do so, we propose conceptual analyses for the key concepts of equivalence and inverse and show how researchers can use these conceptual analyses to identify connections to school mathematics in advanced mathematical tasks that might otherwise be obscured and overlooked. We conclude by suggesting ways in which conceptual analyses might be productively used by both teacher educators and future teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01495-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making university mathematics matter for secondary teacher preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Internationally, questions about the perceived utility of university mathematics for teaching school mathematics pose an ongoing challenge for secondary mathematics teacher education. This special issue is dedicated to exploring this topic and related issues in the preparation of secondary mathematics teachers—by which we mean teachers of students with ages, approximately, of 12–18 years. This article introduces this theme and provides a semi-systematic survey of recent related literature, which we use to elaborate and situate important theoretical distinctions around the problems, challenges, and solutions of university mathematics in relation to teacher education. As part of the special issue, we have gathered articles from different countries that elaborate theoretical and empirical approaches, which, collectively, describe different ways to strengthen university mathematics with respect to the aims of secondary teacher education. This survey paper serves to lay out the theoretical groundwork for the collection of articles in the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01484-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preparing prospective secondary teachers to teach mathematical reasoning and proof: the case of the role of examples in proving</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics teacher education programs in the United States are charged with preparing prospective secondary teachers (PSTs) to teach reasoning and proving across grade levels and mathematical topics. Although most programs require a course on proof, PSTs often perceive it as disconnected from their future classroom practice. Our design research project developed a capstone course &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical Reasoning and Proving for Secondary Teachers&lt;/em&gt; and systematically studied its effect on PSTs’ content and pedagogical knowledge specific to proof. This paper focuses on one course module—&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Quantification and the Role of Examples in Proving,&lt;/em&gt; a topic which poses persistent difficulties to students and teachers alike. The analysis suggests that after the course, PSTs’ content and pedagogical knowledge of the role of examples in proving increased. We provide evidence from multiple data sources: pre-and post-questionnaires, PSTs’ responses to the in-class activities, their lesson plans, reflections on lesson enactment, and self-report. We discuss design principles that supported PSTs’ learning and their applicability beyond the study context.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01493-4</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
