<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Balancing special education knowledge and expertise in teacher training programs</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-20-2024 10:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2327861?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estimating a Theoretically Consistent Human Capital Production Function With an Application to Head Start</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article describes a conceptual and empirical approach for estimating a human capital production function of child development that incorporates mother- or child-fixed effects. The use of mother- or child-fixed effects is common in this applied economics literature, but its application is often inconsistent with human capital theory. We outline the problem and demonstrate its empirical importance with an analysis of the effect of Head Start and preschool on child and adult outcomes. The empirical specification we develop has broad implications for a variety of applied microeconomic analyses beyond our specific application. Results of our analysis indicate that attending Head Start or preschool had no economically or statistically significant effect on child or adult outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-20-2024 07:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241239512?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Be(com)ing an Educational Researcher in the Global South (and Beyond): A Focus on the Research-Practice Relationship</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Educational researchers are increasingly expected to focus on their research productivity as per their professional performance. Such a trend may have influenced their professional identities and activities, especially in the Global South, where researchers have not been immersed in the new research culture and where their assumed primary role may be to increase teaching efficacy instead. The pervasive focus on research productivity is detrimental to the equitable research-practice relationship whereby two groups of professionals—practitioners and researchers—collaboratively work to achieve the common goal of student learning. This teacher-researcher epistemological clash may exist within individual researchers when they have abundant teaching experience prior to becoming educational researchers. Through the lens of activity theory, we report on a case study of educational researchers’ lived experiences and struggles of navigating teacher-researcher identities in Chile, entailing their boundary-crossing of teacher-researcher identities, internal and external identity conflicts, and beliefs and actions related to the ideal research-practice relationship. In conclusion, we call for changes at the institutional level to promote an equitable and manageable research-practice relationship as well as at the individual level to reflect the ultimate purpose of educational research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 12:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241231548?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Updates</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 182-184, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233681?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcements</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 185-187, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233680?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ordinary least squares and instrumental-variables estimators for any outcome and heterogeneity</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 72-92, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Given an exogenous treatment d and covariates x, an ordinary least-squares (OLS) estimator is often applied with a noncontinuous outcome y to find the effect of d, despite the fact that the OLS linear model is invalid. Also, when d is endogenous with an instrument z, an instrumental-variables estimator (IVE) is often applied, again despite the invalid linear model. Furthermore, the treatment effect is likely to be heterogeneous, say, µ1(x), not a constant as assumed in most linear models. Given these problems, the question is then what kind of effect the OLS and IVE actually estimate. Under some restrictive conditions such as a “saturated model”, the estimated effect is known to be a weighted average, say, E{ω(x)µ1(x)}, but in general, OLS and the IVE applied to linear models with a noncontinuous outcome or heterogeneous effect fail to yield a weighted average of heterogeneous treatment effects. Recently, however, it has been found that E{ω(x)µ1(x)} can be estimated by OLS and the IVE without those restrictive conditions if the “propensity-score residual” d − E(d| x) or the “instrument-score residual” z−E(z| x) is used. In this article, we review this recent development and provide a command for OLS and the IVE with the propensity- and instrument-score residuals, which are applicable to any outcome and any heterogeneous effect.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233645?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nearly collinear robust procedures for 2SLS estimation</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 93-112, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Stata’s two-stage least-squares (2SLS) computation procedures are sensitive to near collinearity among regressors, allowing situations in which reported results depend upon factors as irrelevant as the order of the data and variables. This article illustrates this claim with the public-use data of Oreopoulos (2006, American Economic Review 96: 152–175), where the instrumented coefficient estimate can be made to vary between 0.012 and 30.0 in one specification by permuting the order of the variables. Different methods for improving the accuracy of 2SLS estimates are reviewed, and a Stata command for collinearity-robust 2SLS estimation is provided.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233668?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>ddml: Double/debiased machine learning in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 3-45, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce a package, ddml, for double/debiased machine learning in Stata. Estimators of causal parameters for five different econometric models are supported, allowing for flexible estimation of causal effects of endogenous variables in settings with unknown functional forms or many exogenous variables. ddml is compatible with many existing supervised machine learning programs in Stata. We recommend using double/debiased machine learning in combination with stacking estimation, which combines multiple machine learners into a final predictor. We provide Monte Carlo evidence to support our recommendation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233641?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identify latent group structures in panel data: The classifylasso command</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 46-71, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce a new command, classifylasso, that implements the classifier-lasso method (Su, Shi, and Phillips, 2016, Econometrica 84: 2215–2264) to simultaneously identify and estimate unobserved parameter heterogeneity in panel-data models using penalized techniques. We document the functionality of this command, including 1) penalized least-squares estimation of group-specific coefficients and classification of unknown group membership under a certain number of groups; 2) two lasso-type estimators with robust standard errors, namely, classifier-lasso and postlasso; and 3) determination of the number of groups based on an information criterion. We further develop some postestimation commands to display and visualize the estimation results.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233642?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Bayesian method for addressing multinomial misclassification with applications for alcohol epidemiological modeling</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 113-137, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we describe a new command, bamm, that implements a Bayesian method for addressing misclassification in multinomial data; see Swartz et al. (2004, Canadian Journal of Statistics 32: 285–302). We also describe a postestimation command, bammdx, that was developed to provide additional estimation diagnostics. We describe the method and the new commands and then present results from both a simulation study demonstrating bamm’s performance under a known misclassification data-generating process and an empirical example from alcohol epidemiology modeling.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233671?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 153: Extracting text data from webpages</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 169-173, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233678?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 154: Computing power and sample size for prospective diagnostic accuracy studies using Stata’s official power commands</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 174-181, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233679?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Browse and cite Stata manuals easily: The wwwhelp command</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 161-168, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we describe a new command, wwwhelp, that facilitates direct access to online versions of Stata’s official help files or PDF documentation. Addressing the challenges associated with storing, citing, and sharing documentation, wwwhelp complements the help command by enabling access to documentation outside the Stata environment. In addition to fully using the abundant resources available on Stata’s website, wwwhelp enhances the convenience of citing Stata commands in articles and blog posts, thereby promoting the utilization and dissemination of Stata commands.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233676?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcement of the Stata Journal Editors’ Prize 2024</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1-2, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233638?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>sendemails: An automated email package with multiple applications</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/1&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 138-160, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we illustrate the sendemails command, which allows users to automatically send emails with Stata through PowerShell. Researchers can use this package to perform several email tasks, such as contacting students or colleagues with standardized messages. Additionally, researchers can perform more complex tasks that entail sending randomized messages with multiple attachments from multiple accounts; these tasks are often necessary to conduct correspondence audit tests. This article introduces the sendemails command and illustrates multiple examples of its application. The online appendix discusses an application of this package to correspondence audits.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 10:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241233672?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Animations scientifiques en classe de primaire: des effets motivationnels pour qui et pour quelle intensité de participation?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Primary teachers use informal science workshops to supplement science teaching. These activities are meant to foster student’s motivation in science, but few studies with control groups and randomization have attempted to determine their effects. Our experimental study aims to (1) measure the impact of one of these programs (Les Débrouillards) on students’ motivational processes, and (2) explore the moderating role of certain characteristics of the students (age, gender, socio-familial adversity, and scientific capital) on these effects. We randomly assigned twenty-eight 5th and 6th grade classes (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 526) with one of four conditions: 0, 1, 2 or 3 in-class science workshops of one hour. Students completed a pre-test and post-test questionnaire to assess their self-efficacy as well as their values towards science. The results of the hierarchical regressions indicate that exposure to the program did not have an effect on the motivation of all students. However, participating in the workshops (vs. no workshops) produced a number of interaction effects. The moderators’ examination revealed that the program was more beneficial for boys, for older students (potentially countering the decline in interest as students age), and for students with little science capital, especially. These results suggest that students’ characteristics are important to consider when evaluating the effects of informal science presentations, and that such programs can be an advantage in environments where activities promoting scientific literacy are not easily accessed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-19-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00310-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Academic Effects of Moving to Middle School on Students With Disabilities Relative to Their General Education Peers</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Middle school transitions are increasingly required, despite documented negative effects on general education students (GENs). We explore if and how the move to middle school differentially affects students with disabilities (SWDs), a large and low-performing group. Using an instrumental variables strategy and New York City (NYC) data on nine student cohorts, we find the middle school transition causes a 0.29 SD decline in SWD math performance, a 0.16 SD decline in English language-arts (ELA) performance, and a one percentage point increase in grade retention. Accounting for potential mediators (e.g., peer cohort stability) does not substantially explain estimated effects on SWD performance. However, the middle school transition has similarly large negative effects on GENs, suggesting the need to ease this transition for all students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-18-2024 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241229990?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of Grade Retention on High School Outcomes: Evidence from New York City Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-18-2024 02:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2287607?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advancing Preservice Science Teachers’ Skills to Assess Student Thinking On-the-Fly Through Practice-Based Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers’ assessment of student thinking is both difficult to attain and essential for responsive teaching in ongoing interaction during science lessons. Principles of practice-based learning provide a basis for the design of learning environments which may equip prospective teachers for this challenging task. In an experimental study (N = 104), we examined the extent that the use of different media types as representations of practice (video and written cases), the number of rehearsals, and the complexity of student thinking contribute to preservice teachers’ acquisition of assessment skills. Our findings indicated that participants benefited equally well from video and written cases. The number of necessary rehearsals depended on the complexity of student thinking to be assessed. This finding implies that specifics of the content to be assessed need to be taken into consideration when designing learning environments for practicing assessment skills.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 12:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241237497?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I had no knowledge of this”: disrupting majoritarian narratives regarding Mexican American K12 students and employing documentary film in the preparation of equity-oriented school leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 12:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306410?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Boundary construction and education: un/belonging among Somali refugee students in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 04:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2327109?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating the impact of the race equality charter on diversity staff outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 04:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2328372?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engaging with literacies of resistance</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 03:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2324236?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond a sense of obliviousness: elite education and national identity among Palestinian students in Israel</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2024 11:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2328283?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
