<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evading Race: A Critical Race Analysis of Vocational/Career and Technical Education Policy</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Using critical race theory (CRT) as both our theory and analytical framework, we interrogated vocational, career, and technical education (VCTE) policy as a racial instrument. We applied key CRT themes to examine both primary sources; including historical and contemporary VCTE Acts (e.g., Perkins I-V) and Congressional reports; and secondary sources, including academic analyses of VCTE, its history, and related legislation. Findings demonstrate that VCTE policy upholds race-neutrality, which we argue is problematic because without being designated a special population, racially oppressed students stand to miss out on important funding opportunities that could dramatically alter and improve their lives.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-17-2024 07:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241231956?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ mathematics self-efficacy: a scoping review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students’ mathematics self-efficacy (MSE) is strongly associated with learning behaviours and performance, and students’ future career choices. In our scoping review, we screened what &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;substantive foci&lt;/em&gt; (conceptualization, directionality and role of MSE, change in MSE, and situational specificity of MSE) have been posed and which &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;methodological approaches&lt;/em&gt; (participants, analytical methods, data sources, and congruence of measures) have been used in recent (2018–2022) studies of MSE. Studies of MSE were clearly in the mathematics domain with 21 of 49 included studies exploring specific mathematics areas. The key focus was on strength of MSE. International databases (i.e., PISA) have enabled broad generalization, while in-depth qualitative studies enable minute situation-specificity. Cross-sectional and longitudinal studies using hierarchically nested designs (i.e., students in classrooms) enable us to draw conclusions at both individual, classroom, and school levels. The current state-of-the-art indicates methodological advancement is rapid and we are likely to see further methodological-substantive synergies in the field of MSE in future studies. We see the potential and need for future mixed-methods studies that continue the focus on MSE as a multidimensional and dynamic concept. Careful consideration of the theoretical background of the construct of MSE continues to be important to bring the field forward.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01548-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is It Any Better? A Comparison of PhD Students’ Experiences and Degree Completion Plans Between the Summers of 2020 and 2021</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;PhD students’ experiences in graduate school and associated outcomes vary by field of study, learning environment conditions, and support structures. In the context of the COVID-19 pandemic specifically, PhD students’ individual educational trajectories were potentially rendered more uncertain, as disruptive conditions for learning and research have continued over the past several years. We compared the reports of 422 PhD students at 12 U.S. institutions in terms of their experiences of support or marginalization and educational plans from the summer of 2020 with follow-up data gathered during the summer of 2021. We then examined factors related to PhD students’ changes in their estimated times to degree. We found lower, but still on average moderate, levels of depression symptoms compared to the previous year and continued experiences of emotional, financial, educational, and career stressors. Findings point to the importance of institutional material and psychological structural supports over time.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-15-2024 06:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241228222?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Heuristics and semantic spaces for the analysis of students’ work in mathematical problem solving</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this research, our objective is to characterize the problem-solving procedures of primary and lower secondary students when they solve problems in real class conditions. To do so, we rely first on the concept of heuristics. As this term is very polysemic, we exploit the definition proposed by Rott (2014) to develop a coding manual and thus analyze students’ procedures. Then, we interpret the results of these analyses in a qualitative way by mobilizing the concept of semantic space (Poitrenaud, 1998). This detailed analysis of students’ procedures is made possible by collecting audiovisual data as close as possible to the students’ work using an action camera mounted on the students’ heads. We thus succeed in highlighting three different investigation profiles that we have named explorer, butterfly, and prospector. Our first results tend to show a correlation with these profiles and the success in problem-solving, yet this would need more investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10297-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Proposing and testing a model relating students’ graph selection and graph reasoning for dynamic situations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Using a mixed methods approach, we explore a relationship between students’ graph reasoning and graph selection via a fully online assessment. Our population includes 673 students enrolled in college algebra, an introductory undergraduate mathematics course, across four U.S. postsecondary institutions. The assessment is accessible on computers, tablets, and mobile phones. There are six items; for each, students are to view a video animation of a dynamic situation (e.g., a toy car moving along a square track), declare their understanding of the situation, select a Cartesian graph to represent a relationship between given attributes in the situation, and enter text to explain their graph choice. To theorize students’ graph reasoning, we draw on Thompson’s theory of quantitative reasoning, which explains students’ conceptions of attributes as being possible to measure. To code students’ written responses, we appeal to Johnson and colleagues’ graph reasoning framework, which distinguishes students’ quantitative reasoning about one or more attributes capable of varying (Covariation, Variation) from students’ reasoning about observable elements in a situation (Motion, Iconic). Quantitizing those qualitative codes, we examine connections between the latent variables of students’ graph reasoning and graph selection. Using structural equation modeling, we report a significant finding: Students’ graph reasoning explains 40% of the variance in their graph selection (standardized regression weight is 0.64, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.001). Furthermore, our results demonstrate that students’ quantitative forms of graph reasoning (i.e., variational and covariational reasoning) influence the accuracy of their graph selection.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10299-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Variations autour d’une situation de comparaison de quantités pour l’apprentissage des unités de numération</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Although research has shown that numeration units are essential for learning whole numbers, students in France still face challenges in understanding units, since learning is often limited to designating the position of digits in the writing of numbers. This article investigates a study conducted among 4th and 5th graders, comprised of a baseline scenario and variations, which examines a quantity comparison problem that aims to strengthen the understanding of numeration units as a system of units organized according to the decimal principle. Using teaching design methodology, we describe the design choices (a priori analysis) and examine in-class implementation as well as discussions with students (a posteriori analysis). The results illustrate a variety of teaching methods, some of the difficulties that students face, and opportunities to further an understanding of numeration units.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00307-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching and Learning for Mutual Respect: A Framework for Disrupting Pervasive Power Asymmetries</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article establishes a framework for teaching and learning for mutual respect. I define mutual respect as intervening on power asymmetries typically found in classrooms by way of according students increased equality, autonomy, and equity. In highlighting how equality, autonomy, and equity interact in ongoing and unpredictable ways in classrooms, this framework permits greater awareness of the many dilemmas with which educators are faced. Furthermore, by attending to the different ways mutual respect can be operationalized (i.e., instruction, organization, social relations), this framework can assist school leaders when determining how school-level decisions may interact with mutual respect in classrooms. This framework is thus a tool for researchers and educators when considering how to transform teaching and learning to promote social justice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-14-2024 12:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241227445?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Attention to Equity in Teacher Education Admissions Processes</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study investigated the underexplored topic of teacher preparation program admissions processes by interviewing faculty and analyzing program documents. We investigated how 31 K-12 mathematics and science teacher preparation programs (MSTPPs) and faculty attend to diversity, equity, inclusion, and social and racial justice (DEIJ). Specific foci included applicant recruitment and selection, components of applications (e.g., forms, essays, and interviews), and how applicants’ DEIJ-related information and orientations factor into admissions. We found that all MSTPPs participating in the study collected information related to DEIJ (e.g., applicants’ ethnoracial backgrounds, citizenship), and all interviewed faculty expressed an interest in increasing the diversity of applicants and admitted students. Faculty expressed preferences for applicants who evidenced positive DEIJ orientations, such as recognizing social and ethnoracial injustices, but at the same time, differences were evident in how MSTPPs and faculty attended to DEIJ. Considerations, implications, and dilemmas for teacher preparation programs and faculty are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-14-2024 01:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241230306?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Spare the Rod, Spoil the Child? A Critical Discourse Analysis of State Corporal Punishment Policies and Practices</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Corporal punishment (CP), or inflicting pain through spanking, hitting, and paddling, is still legally sanctioned and exercised in U.S. schools. We use critical discourse analysis and draw on state policy documents and data from the Office of Civil Rights to investigate which discourses pervade policy texts and how CP is practiced. These sources reveal discourses relating to morality, delinquency, and authority that draw on ideas associated with power, punishment, and control. Across all these discourses, we find color-evasive and deficit language to justify CP practices that are disproportionally applied to minoritized students. We conclude with policy implications for CP and school discipline more broadly.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-13-2024 11:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231213040?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Platform Governance and Education Policy: Power and Politics in Emerging Edtech Ecologies</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article develops a framework for understanding and analyzing the intermediary work of platform technologies, and their owners, as an emerging form of platform governance in educational systems. Our investigation is guided by two questions: (a) How do platform technologies shape policy by brokering relations among commercial, technical, and educational actors? And (b) how might these relations contribute to, or compromise, educational equity as they are folded into existing governance regimes? We address these questions by bringing together two critical orientations—critical policy analysis and critical platform studies—to map the power and politics of platformization in and across education systems.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-13-2024 11:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231202469?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reimagining Preservice Experiences for Aspiring Latino Teachers in the United States</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-13-2024 05:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2311421?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of observation mode on ratings of teaching quality in secondary mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In educational research, teaching quality is extensively studied because of its role of a mediator between teacher characteristics and student learning. However, empirical evidence on differences between video and live scoring of teaching quality is rare. In the present study, thirty lessons from 15 secondary mathematics classrooms in a German metropolitan area were observed. Lessons were scored both live in the classroom and using video recordings. Live and video scoring was conducted by (different) trained observers. Ratings were obtained with a “hybrid” observational instrument that covers generic and subject-specific characteristics of teaching quality in mathematics classrooms. Generalizability analysis and paired &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;t&lt;/em&gt; tests were performed to investigate mode effects. The findings showed that in live scoring, classroom management was rated lower, and cognitive activation was rated higher. Rankings of lessons or classrooms were very similar across modes, and reliabilities did not differ to a meaningful extent either, except for classroom management reaching better results for live ratings. This suggests that based on the present findings, classroom observation performed with our hybrid framework of teaching quality generalizes across observation mode only under certain circumstances. Further research is necessary to better understand the relation between observation mode and teaching quality ratings, as well as the impact of the scoring procedures. We discuss the implications of our findings for educational research and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01557-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>More Than One Way: Fifth-Graders’ Varied Digital Reading Behaviors and Comprehension Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Digital reading is ubiquitous, yet understanding digital reading processes and links to comprehension remains underdeveloped. Guided by new literacies and active reading theories, this study explored the reading behaviors and comprehension of thirteen fifth graders who read static digital texts. We coded for the quantity and quality of digital reading behaviors and employed action path diagrams to connect behaviors to comprehension. We used timescape analyses to visualize how behaviors were orchestrated differently across readers. Findings showed no single behavior was related directly to comprehension, indicating varying pathways to digital reading success. Occasional rereading seemed to support active reading and improved comprehension. Instances of students subverting expected digital tools were observed. Minor distractions like mind-wandering did not link to poor performance. This research deepens our understanding of self-monitoring and active reading in static digital contexts, offering insights for future study of more complex digital reading contexts like reading on the internet.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 12:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241226633?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2022 Wallace Foundation Distinguished Lecture Education Reform, Past and Present: Asking Equity Questions and Looking for Hope</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Drawing on a set of studies conducted over 3 decades, this article provides a reflection on what has been learned by centering equity questions in research on educational reform. These studies reveal the need to explore educators’ belief systems, emotions, and agency in relation to reform. They also underscore the co-constructed nature of reform and the importance of attending to context and scale. Although prior research reveals the complex challenges educators, policymakers, and communities face in promoting educational change with social justice aims, it also provides lessons for a hopeful path forward. Pursuing an equity agenda in this pivotal moment requires deep thinking about how we conduct research on educational reform, prepare the next generation of scholars, and work across disciplinary and national boundaries.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241228255?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Critical Quantitative Literacy: An Educational Foundation for Critical Quantitative Research</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Education research has recently seen the emergence of two distinct frameworks guiding the application of quantitative methods through a more critical and equity-oriented lens. These two frameworks are critical quantitative (CritQuant) studies and quantitative critical race theory (QuantCrit). Although different in their intellectual traditions, they both acknowledge the oppressive history of quantitative methods and the need to improve the criticality of quantitative research in education. For applied quantitative research in education to become more critical, it is imperative that learners of quantitative methodology be made aware of its historical and modern misuses. This directive calls for an important change in the way quantitative methodology is taught in educational classrooms. Critical quantitative literacy (CQL) is introduced in this manuscript as a paradigm for teaching, learning, understanding, and applying quantitative methods in a way that supports the application of CritQuant and QuantCrit frameworks in educational research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 07:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241228223?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Preservice Teachers’ Quantitative and Covariational Reasoning in Understanding Climate Change</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 05:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2314499?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Constructing an Educational “Quality” Crisis: (E)quality Politics and Racialization Beyond Target Beneficiaries</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this critical, political discourse analysis, we trace how two concepts, equity and quality, became discursively linked and contested in the administration of postsecondary education policy over time (1968–1994)—a developmental process we refer to as (e)quality politics. By engaging in a historical analysis, we investigate (a) the racialized political origins and discursive processes by which arguments over educational “quality” are advanced as part of an antiequity policy paradigm and (b) how this paradigm reinscribes racial inequity into administrative and organizational action over time. We illustrate how, once an (e)quality politics paradigm is established, racialized policy designs can persist, even in the absence of explicit references to racialized social constructions of target populations in later periods of policy development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2024 05:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231189478?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher practitioner enquiry: a process for developing teacher learning and practice?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-11-2024 05:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2313085?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Moving beyond reflection and toward disruption in the post-field context of mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Prospective teachers bring countless stories of success and failure from different mathematics classrooms to their post-field teacher education courses. These reflective stories often glorify school mathematics classrooms and dominant traditions within, instead of confronting the marginalization of diverse groups in school environments. Mathematics teacher educators have a significant role to play in teaching prospective teachers to reflect critically on their field experiences and, in doing so, create spaces for &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;disruption&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;disruptive pedagogies&lt;/em&gt;. Drawing on critical and equity-based theories applied within the fields of mathematics education and teacher education research, we propose a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;disruptive pedagogy&lt;/em&gt; analytical framework that enables us to study the roles and practices of mathematics teacher educators as they conduct their work in these post-field contexts of teacher education. In this paper, we introduce our disruptive pedagogy framework and present the results that followed from using it to analyze data from a research study in which mathematics teacher educators from across Canada and Norway were interviewed. We claim that our analytical framework can be used to identify those disruptive and transformative practices initiated by mathematics teacher educators—practices that are necessary to bring about shifts in inequitable and unjust classroom practices of school mathematics and in becoming a teacher. Unfortunately, however, results reported here point to the need for further shifts and growth toward more explicitly disruptive practices initiated by mathematics teacher educators in the post-field context.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01547-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The longing to just be – a belonging body in teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2024 06:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2311709?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preschool teachers’ mathematical questions during shared picture book reading</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;High-quality instruction in preschool is important for children’s mathematical development. To date, the domain-specific elements constituting mathematics instruction quality and the factors associated with this quality are hardly studied, resulting in serious gaps in our insights into the topic. We aimed to address this gap by investigating (a) 43 preschool teachers’ mathematical questioning behavior during shared picture book reading, and (b) its association with picture book and teacher characteristics. We analyzed the number and the level of abstraction of mathematical questions when sharing a mathematical (i.e., written with explicit mathematical aim and content) and a non-mathematical (i.e., written without explicit mathematical aim and content) picture book, and their associations with teachers’ professional competence. For mathematical and non-mathematical picture books, teachers formulated mathematical questions, mainly at lower levels of abstraction. They formulated more, but proportionally less abstract, mathematical questions when sharing a mathematical versus a non-mathematical picture book. We found only limited evidence for associations between teachers’ questioning behavior and their professional competence. Our findings indicate that preschool teachers offer opportunities to engage in mathematical interaction during shared picture book reading, pointing to the potential of this activity to implement high-quality mathematics instruction. They further show that mathematical picture books enable more mathematical interaction than non-mathematical picture books, but not at higher levels of abstraction. Future studies are needed to replicate and complement our findings, with special attention for the contribution of teacher professional competence and the fit to children’s competency level.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01544-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Quantification and the homogeneous representation of urban students in school choice research and politics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2024 02:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306395?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working with an instructional video on mathematical modeling: upper-secondary students’ perceived advantages and challenges</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Many instructional videos in mathematics education target knowledge of procedures and algorithms. To design instructional videos that support students in a non-algorithmic domain, such as mathematical modeling, we developed a framework based on research on heuristic worked examples and instructional videos. Because students’ perceptions play an important role in whether they will engage with a learning resource, our research questions focus on the advantages and challenges students perceive when they work with an instructional video on mathematical modeling and solve a subsequent related modeling problem. Using a video based on the developed framework, we conducted an interview study with 14 pairs of upper-secondary students. The results of the qualitative text analysis showed that the perceived advantages and challenges were related to certain design features and to the processes of self-regulated learning with the video. The students experienced challenges regarding the video’s duration, the transfer to a subsequent related modeling problem, the absence of a teacher, and self-discipline. Hence, further learner support is necessary to guide the transition from working with a video to autonomous modeling, such as combining the video with strategic instruments and teacher support. In addition, interactive video features may be essential, as the students enjoyed how those features involved them in the process of watching the video. Overall, the results indicate that instructional videos are promising for providing heuristic worked examples, offering an innovative approach for teaching and learning mathematical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01546-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Trends, insights, and developments in research on the teaching and learning of algebra</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper addresses the recent body of research in algebra and algebraic thinking from 2018 to 2022. We reviewed 74 journal articles and identified four clusters of content areas: (a) literal symbols and symbolizing, (b) equivalence and the equal sign, (c) equations and systems, and (d) functions and graphing. We present the research on each of these content clusters, and we discuss insights on effective teaching practices and the social processes supporting algebraic reasoning. The research base shows that incorporating algebraic thinking into the elementary grades, emphasizing analytic and structural thinking processes, and emphasizing covariational reasoning supports students’ meaningful learning of core algebraic ideas. We close with a discussion of the major theoretical contributions emerging from the past five years, offering suggestions for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01545-9</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
