<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing student teachers’ critical awareness of information and communications technology in primary teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 08:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2407540?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Factors Affecting Students’ Likelihood to Access Feedback</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Previous studies in higher education have found that a considerable number of students do not access feedback. Here, we use assessment system data on nearly 300,000 assignment submissions to statistically analyze demographic and timing factors leading to lower likelihood of feedback collection. The most significant factors were student performance, gender, course level, assignment number, and timeliness relative to the next assessment date. Deprivation was not found to be significant once other factors were accounted for. The insights gained from this study suggest dedicated time for reviewing feedback in course design and consideration of demographics in engagement interventions are needed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2024 09:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241285416?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>For What and for Whom? Expanding the Role of Research Syntheses for Diverse Stakeholders</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Systematic reviews have witnessed significant growth across many fields, including education. In this article, we outline the background of this growth, highlight the tendency to focus on methodological considerations, and propose a framework to support education researchers in preparing systematic reviews with broad impact. We draw on our experience working with education stakeholders in Singapore and on international scholarship to propose a framework that supports education researchers in clarifying and specifying their aims and audiences and crafting syntheses of appropriate types. Our aim is that this framework, which includes examples illustrating four categories of reviews, acts as a reflective tool which researchers can use to maximize the utility, value, and potential impact of education research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2024 09:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241285414?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Gifted Students’ Views on Integrating History of Mathematics in Mathematics Lessons</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2024 09:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2409031?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Performance Evaluation of Governance Mechanisms of Hazardous Waste Recycling in Rural China: A Qualitative Comparative Analysis Based on Multiple Cases</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;As ecological globalization intensifies, rural waste recycling and management has become a global concern. China’s proactive efforts are significant for revitalizing domestic rural ecosystems, offering valuable insights into global environmental governance. The rampant dumping and informal processing of hazardous waste in rural China pose severe threats to local ecological balance and public safety. Thus, efficiently recycling hazardous rural and agricultural waste is pivotal for China’s rural ecological and environmental governance. This study adopts a participatory governance perspective and establishes a theoretical framework for dual principal-agent relationships. This framework examined 22 cases of rural governance spanning Eastern, Central, and Western China. This study evaluated governance mechanisms in four dimensions: policy, material, human, and social capital, using the fuzzy-set qualitative comparative analysis method. The key findings include: (1) The adverse orientation and behavior of hazardous waste recycling governance in rural areas stem from the combined impacts of multiple complex factors. (2) The synergistic interplay between policy, human, and social capital is crucial for advancing hazardous waste recycling governance in rural settings. (3) Three pathway mechanisms––socially driven, market-oriented, and system participation––facilitate the effective governance of hazardous waste recycling. Innovative practices in hazardous waste recycling and management within rural China yielded positive domestic impacts and profoundly influenced global environmental governance. China’s experiences and approaches motivate other nations and regions, showcasing responsibility and dedication to international environmental governance and bolstering Chinese contributions to creating a cleaner, beautiful world.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2024 07:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241289643?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Indigenous Methodologies in International Research on Indigenous Family and Community Engagement</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Indigenous research methodologies have been theorized by prominent Indigenous scholars over the past few decades and advocated for in research focused on Indigenous communities for their emancipatory power to reestablish Indigenous peoples’ expertise and self-determining and sovereignty rights over education and research. Western intrusion in Indigenous education and community focused research through colonial schools and Western research methodologies has negatively impacted the schooling experiences of Indigenous children, their families and communities, as well as the ways they are studied and depicted in research. Responding to calls for Indigenous methodologies in research focused on Indigenous communities, this literature review introduces an Indigenist Methodological Framework, developed from canonical scholarship on Indigenous methodologies, that we use to explore the applications (and potential misapplications) of Indigenous methodologies in 20 international studies about Indigenous family and community engagement. We aimed to determine if adherence to the elements of an Indigenist Methodological Framework served to disrupt extractive, exploitative, and damage-centered practices in and portrayals of Indigenous communities (common in Western research methodologies). Further, we critically analyzed the findings of these studies to see if they offered more culturally responsive and strength-based conceptualizations of Indigenous families and communities. We uncovered applications and misapplications of Indigenous methodologies that impacted researchers’ commitments to and actions towards establishing and maintaining relational accountability throughout and beyond the research while also influencing findings that, in most cases, challenged narrow and deficit-based perceptions and portrayals of Indigenous students, families, and community members.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2024 05:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241279565?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Retraining professionals as STEM teachers: the potential and the challenges</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2024 02:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2409372?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Randomized Controlled Trial of the City Year Whole School Whole Child Model&#39;s Tier 2 Services in Five Urban School Districts</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2024 01:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2403995?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impacts of the Mindset Teams Programme on Teacher Outcomes and Pupil Educational Attainment: Secondary Data Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2024 01:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2403989?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acting on Totalities of infinite Processes: constructing facets of an Object conception</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We offer a new angle to explain the comprehension of mathematical infinity. We use Action—Process—Object—Schema (APOS) theory to explore the construction of different aspects of the cognitive Object related to this notion. We focus our attention on different ways of interacting with infinity, and how to act on infinite entities. Our aim is to shed light on the nature of mental constructions that take place when individuals deal with mathematical infinity. An infinite union of finite subsets of &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\({\mathbb{N}}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; provides the context for our theoretical analysis and the design of interviews conducted with graduate students and instructors. In this study we identify three types of Actions with different complexity levels. When these Actions are performed, they lead to the construction of different facets of the associated Object. We question the construction of an Object conception in infinity-related situations and offer an explanation that might change the way we think about the learning of certain mathematical concepts. We discuss the implications of our research for the advancement of APOS theory. We also offer pedagogical suggestions related to the comprehension of mathematical infinity.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01631-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher shortages: a social justice perspective on an Australian teacher education policy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2024 10:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2404831?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher use of multimodal signs to support kindergarten students’ developing understanding of mathematical equivalence</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Across multiple age groups and academic disciplines, research has shown that incorporating multimodal signs into instruction can enhance student learning. For instance, gesture might be synchronized with speech or written signs. The present study reports on the semiotic resources used by a teacher-researcher to support kindergarten students’ developing understanding of the equal sign. An analysis of seven classroom lessons designed to advance students’ understanding of the equal sign and equations in various forms revealed four categories of language and two categories of gesture used by the teacher-researcher that were specifically related to mathematical equivalence. Our findings contribute to understanding the role of multimodal signs in supporting instruction on mathematical equivalence.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00508-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Accelerated Postsecondary Pathways: The Longer-Term Impact of the Early College High School Model on Postsecondary Degree Attainment</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Utilizing a lottery-based natural experiment, this study assessed the longer-term impact of early colleges on postsecondary degree attainment. It found that early colleges significantly increased the overall degree completion and associate degree completion rates within 10 years of expected high school graduation. While the impact on bachelor’s degree or advanced degree attainment was no longer significant 10 years after high school, results from earlier years suggest that early college students attained these degrees at a higher rate and faster pace than control students. This study also found that the early college impact on bachelor’s degree attainment was significantly stronger for underrepresented minorities and that the impact on associate degree attainment was significantly stronger for students with higher prior achievement.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2024 12:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241276855?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Black Teacher Pipeline: Insights From a State Longitudinal Data System</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;We use longitudinal data across public postsecondary institutions in Tennessee to examine the stages at which potential Black educators disproportionately exit the teacher pipeline. Black and White bachelor’s graduates declare and complete teaching-related majors at similar rates, suggesting comparable levels of initial interest in teaching careers; moreover, newly certified Black college graduates are more likely than their White peers to gain employment in the state. However, in between those points, Black undergraduate program completers are substantially less likely to become licensed. Additionally, Black graduate students are less likely to complete master’s degrees in teaching-related majors and receive teaching licenses, though newly certified Black master’s graduates are again more likely to gain employment than their White peers. These results suggest that the largest loss of potential Black teachers occurs at the end of teacher preparation, which can be explained partially but not fully by inequities in certification exam passage rates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2024 01:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241280917?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publisher Correction: Contributions to the characterization of the Schema using APOS theory: Graphing with derivative</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01637-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student approaches to generating mathematical examples: comparing e-assessment and paper-based tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Example-generation tasks have been suggested as an effective way to both promote students’ learning of mathematics and assess students’ understanding of concepts. E-assessment offers the potential to use example-generation tasks with large groups of students, but there has been little research on this approach so far. Across two studies, we investigate students’ responses to a particular sequence of example-generation tasks, posed either on paper or through e-assessment. We identify a striking difference in students’ example-generation strategies and success, for e-assessment and paper-based versions of the same tasks. This suggests the use of example-generation tasks in e-assessment may not be straightforward, and we conclude by discussing the implications for teaching and research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10361-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining Enactments of Project-based Learning in Secondary English Language Arts</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Project-based learning (PBL) grounds instruction in authentic learning experiences where students engage in real-world explorations that culminate in a final product or performance. We report on a mixed methods study with 43 ninth-grade English language arts (ELA) teachers (22 PBL and 21 comparison) and 1,671 students exploring the feasibility of enacting PBL in ELA classrooms and examining how teachers and students perceived this approach to learning. PBL teachers enacted PBL design principles significantly more than comparison teachers. The majority of PBL teachers perceived positive instructional shifts including more student-centered and authentic learning, more student choice, and greater student engagement. Many teachers also expressed a sense of renewal and passion. Students in PBL classrooms reported more meaningful learning experiences, opportunities for collaboration, and other aspects of social and emotional learning. We discuss tensions, including the challenge of covering required content and skills within a PBL-focused classroom.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2024 04:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241269829?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Living in the Big Pond: Adding the Neighborhood as a Frame of Reference for Academic Self-Concept Formation</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research on the big-fish-little-pond effect demonstrates that class-average achievement negatively affects students’ academic self-concept via social comparison processes. The neighborhood-effects literature reports positive effects of advantageous socioeconomic neighborhood conditions on students’ academic development via collective socialization mechanisms. To investigate how socioeconomic neighborhood conditions affect academic self-concept, we separately and simultaneously analyzed classroom- and neighborhood-level composition effects on students’ academic self-concept, using two samples drawn from two grade levels ([math] = 3,906, [math] = 3,277). Analyses of the neighborhood level only indicate that socioeconomic neighborhood conditions negatively predict general, math, and German self-concept in Grade 5. In Grade 9, this holds only for math self-concept. In simultaneous analyses including classrooms and neighborhoods, socioeconomically advantageous neighborhood conditions negatively predicted general and math self-concept in Grade 5.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2024 04:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241269816?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A survey of Spanish research in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This survey paper presents recent relevant research in mathematics education produced in Spain, which allows the identification of different broad lines of research developed by Spanish groups of scholars. First, we present and describe studies whose research objectives are related to student learning of specific curricular contents and process-oriented competencies, namely arithmetic, algebra, geometry, functions and calculus, probability and statistics, and argumentation or proof in geometric contexts. Next, we present characteristics and foci of investigations dealing with different aspects of mathematics teacher education, encompassing a large part of Spanish research in mathematics education. The descriptions of other transversal lines of research complement the previous two big blocks: research on students with special educational needs and the effects of using technology in different curricular contents and educational levels. Finally, we report on the research activities and advances of Spanish research in mathematics education from two main theoretical frameworks created or developed by Spanish researchers. This plurality of research strands also corresponds to a wide range of international collaborations, especially with Latin American colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-26-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01638-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leaks in the College Access Pipeline: Examining Summer Melt in a Large Urban School District</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Some high school seniors who plan to attend college in the fall following graduation do not enroll. This phenomenon, known as summer melt, contributes to lower educational attainment, particularly among low-income students. We extend the literature on summer melt in two ways. First, we show that melt estimates can be sensitive to measurement decisions and local context, and in particular that estimates based on student-level National Student Clearinghouse data can overstate the extent of summer melt. Second, we show that aspects of students’ behavior and perceptions, such as their attendance rates, Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA) completion, and confidence about their intended college, predict summer melt. These results suggest ways that school staff and summer melt interventions could potentially target additional support to college-intending students to facilitate their successful transition to college.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 12:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241278314?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Application of Behavioral Economics to Teacher Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher professional development (PD) is among the most prominent levers used to improve teaching quality. The findings of research studies examining PD interventions are heterogeneous, with meta-analyses indicating mean positive impacts but also the existence of many ineffective programs. Educational Researcher has served as a critical platform for conversations on strengthening the research base on teacher PD. In this article, we argue that insights from behavioral economics have the potential to improve professional development research by pointing toward solutions that can strengthen the implementation of well-designed PD. We provide illustrative examples of how concepts from behavioral economics can inform our understanding of barriers to effective PD implementation and discuss behavioral-economics-based tools to mitigate these barriers. We conclude by discussing future applications and research directions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 12:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241282296?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>College Behind Bars: A Historiography of Higher Education in Prison</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article presents a synthesized historiography of higher education in American prisons, exploring interactions of federal, state, and institution-level policies within six specific states: California, Illinois, Massachusetts, Mississippi, New York, and Texas. We define considerations for researchers, policymakers, and advocates regarding efforts to sustain educational access for incarcerated students. Findings suggest access is inextricably linked to policies relying on the social construction of crime and incarceration. As such, sole reliance on federal support may be detrimental for programs. A focus on diversifying funding sources will likely better ensure the long-term durability of support for higher education in prison programming.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 12:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241283017?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Accumulation of Opportunities Predicts the Educational Attainment and Adulthood Earnings of Children Born Into Low- Versus Higher-Income Households</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Scholars theorize that “opportunity gaps” drive achievement disparities between children born into poverty versus affluence. In a 26-year longitudinal study (N = 814), we examine (a) economic disparity in children’s accumulation of opportunities—from birth through high school—at home, childcare, school, afterschool, and in the neighborhood; (b) the extent to which opportunity is linked with educational attainment and earnings in early adulthood; and (c) whether opportunity is most strongly associated with these adult outcomes for children from low-income households. We document large opportunity gaps between children from low- versus higher-income households. These opportunity gaps are strongly linked with educational attainment and earnings, particularly for low-income children, helping explain why household income in early childhood predicts these outcomes in adulthood.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 11:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241283456?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact and Implementation of Academic Interventions During COVID-19: Evidence from the Road to Recovery Project</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Pandemic-era disruptions to schooling resulted in academic setbacks for many students. To help students catch up, school districts nationwide are implementing a range of academic recovery interventions. In this paper, we use multiple data sources to evaluate the impact and implementation of academic recovery interventions in four school districts during the 2021-2022 school year. Our estimates suggest the interventions failed to reach the expected number of students and had little detectable impact on students’ test scores. Interviews with district officials highlight a host of challenges districts faced during the 2021-2022 school year. Considering the overall scale of pandemic learning loss, our results raise urgent questions about the adequacy of academic recovery efforts relative to students’ needs. The results also have implications for how districts might respond to disrupted learning in the future (e.g. in the wake of natural disasters).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-25-2024 10:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241281286?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
