<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining the role of emotion in culturally and linguistically diverse students’ classroom underlife</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 06:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2323781?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Feeling anti-racism: how neoliberal multiculturalism and racialized emotions impede equity in the aftermath of George Floyd</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 06:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2323773?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Devised theatre methodology to promote creativity in school</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2024 05:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2326602?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Distinguishing Subtypes of Self-Efficacy Among Secondary School Teachers: A Latent Profile Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher self-efficacy is a crucial factor in teaching and learning, yet there is limited understanding of its heterogeneity among the Asian population. Therefore, the objectives of this study were to (a) identify different self-efficacy patterns among 3,095 Singaporean lower secondary school teachers, (b) investigate potential variations in job satisfaction, constructivist beliefs, and teacher co-operation across different self-efficacy profiles, and (c) examine the predictions of teacher background characteristics in relation to profile membership. By employing latent profile analysis, four distinct self-efficacy profiles were identified: (a) Low Self-Efficacy, (b) Moderate Self-Efficacy, (c) High Self-Efficacy, and (d) Divergent Moderate Self-Efficacy. The results also revealed significant differences in job satisfaction, constructivist beliefs, and teacher co-operation among the self-efficacy profiles. Moreover, teaching experience emerged as a significant predictor of profile membership. These highlight the need for tailored professional development programs and interventions that consider teachers’ self-efficacy profiles, teacher outcomes, and teaching experience.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2024 05:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241234872?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Power Analyses for Estimation of Complier Average Causal Effects Under Random Encouragement Designs in Education Research: Theory and Guidance</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Random encouragement designs evaluate treatments that aim to increase participation in a program or activity. These randomized controlled trials (RCTs) can also assess the mediated effects of participation itself on longer term outcomes using a complier average causal effect (CACE) estimation framework. This article considers power analysis methods for such CACE analyses for a range of RCT designs, including nonclustered, clustered, and random block designs. The focus is on behavioral encouragements to promote action, such as text messaging, that are increasingly being tested in education trials. We derive asymptotic distributions of the CACE estimators using generalized estimating equations theory, which underlie the power formulas. We incorporate noncompliance from both the actual receipt of the encouragement and participation itself. An illustrative power analysis provides sample size guidance using an available Shiny R dashboard.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2024 04:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241233790?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“So That I May Hope to Honor You”: Centering Wholeness, Agency, and Brilliance in Qualitative Research With Multiply Marginalized Young Children</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Scholars of early childhood education have urged qualitative researchers to adapt their methods for use with young children. However, unjust social imaginations of childhood (e.g., who is considered a “child”) play out in qualitative research, particularly for young children who are made most vulnerable by intersecting oppressions (e.g., racism, linguicism, ableism). Extending Morrison’s metaphor of “the white gaze,” we argue that qualitative research is often framed through an “adult gaze,” which presumes children’s worth in terms of who they will ultimately become and differentially imagines who is considered a child in the present. Informed by theoretical understandings from the fields of critical childhood studies and early literacy studies, we consider how qualitative researchers might disrupt the adult gaze and honor multiply marginalized children by centering their wholeness, orienting toward their agency, and creating space for their brilliance.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2024 03:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241237533?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reckoning With the “Other” Pandemic: How Teachers’ Unions Responded to Calls for Racial Justice Amidst COVID-19</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;After George Floyd was murdered by police, teachers, alongside the leaders of their unions and professional associations, confronted urgent calls to address racism in their communities, schools, and classrooms, just as they were concluding an academic year rendered chaotic by COVID-19. This article leverages four waves of semistructured interviews with teachers’ union and association leaders embedded in 14 states and 45 school districts to investigate how and why teachers’ unions responded to those calls during 2020 and 2021. Local leaders were more likely to have taken concrete steps if they were serving urban or suburban and predominantly Democratic communities. Most commonly, unions offered symbolic gestures of support or sought to develop their capacity to recognize and understand bias.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2024 03:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241235634?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘Not ours’: Palestinian Arab students’ perceptions of the campus ethnonational climate in Israeli higher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2024 02:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2328282?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Navigating double marginalization: narratives of Asian (American) educators teaching and building solidarity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2024 01:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2328261?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Profiles of general, test, and mathematics anxiety in 9- and 12-year-olds: relations to gender and mathematics achievement</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As international focus increasingly turns to the need to build a future mathematics workforce, research has aimed to better understand the salient individual and contextual factors that influence maths engagement and achievement across development. This study investigates self-reported general anxiety, test anxiety, and maths anxiety in two cohorts of Australian students aged 9–10 years (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 158) and 12–13 years (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 115) and associations with maths achievement and gender. Test and maths anxiety were negatively correlated with maths achievement and there were no gender differences in maths achievement. Cross-sectional latent profile analyses established two anxiety profiles in the older cohort (low and high across all anxiety measures) and a more complex five-profile solution for the younger cohort (various combinations of anxiety). Members of profiles with higher levels of test and mathematics anxiety had lower maths achievement, with girls over-represented in these profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00485-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Conflation of Dual Language Bilingual Education With Gifted Programs in New York City Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;As neighborhoods across New York City gentrify, Dual Language Bilingual Education (DLBE) has become a big draw for gentrifier families. Our research contributes to growing literature on DLBE gentrification by examining how a racially diverse group of parents in two communities perceived DLBE as a school choice option. We found that schools with DLBE programs screened potential students via academic screening tests or school choice processes to determine admission into DLBE programs. This screening process has contributed to a) the conflation of DLBE with the city’s gifted programs, and b) a focus away from admitting and centering emergent bilinguals. While this screening served to further advantage gentrifier families, some parents resisted the opportunity hoarding behaviors of their peers through their alternative school choices and advocacy efforts. In this way, we show how all parents are constrained and impacted by the neoliberal logics of contemporary DLBE policy and school choice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2024 12:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241237724?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Degrees of Return: Estimating Internal Rates of Return for College Majors Using Quantile Regression</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Using data collected from more than 5.8 million high school and college graduates ages 18 to 65 years who participated in the American Community Survey between 2009 and 2021, the authors estimate the internal rates of return (IRRs) for individuals with college degrees in 10 broad majors compared with high school graduates. The analysis shows significant differences in the age-earnings trajectories and IRRs across college majors. Furthermore, quantile regression analyses show that IRR is generally higher at the high end of the earnings distribution compared with the low end. Finally, the authors observed a slight decrease in IRR during the study period, which is consistent with the flattening and even decline in college wage premiums following the 2008 Great Recession.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241231512?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Public Opinion on School Funding and Teacher Salaries: The Information Gap Explained?</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We evaluate public opinion on the sufficiency of school funding and teacher salaries in the United States, using a representative survey (n = 12,151). Data were collected during the COVID-19 pandemic (2020/2021), with schools and teachers having a reduced role due to homeschooling. While opinions are diverse for sufficiency of school funding, most respondents indicated that teacher salaries should increase. For respondents who received additional information about average school funding and teacher salaries, the overall opinion about funding and salaries being insufficient was less strong. Furthermore, this information effect differs as per respondents’ demographic variables.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2024 04:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241232939?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Excellence for All? University Honors Programs and Human Capital Formation</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Can public university Honors programs deliver the benefits of selective undergraduate education within otherwise nonselective institutions? We evaluate the impact of admission to the Honors College at Oregon State University, a large nonselective public university. Admission to the Honors College depends heavily on a numerical application score. Nonlinearities in admissions probabilities as a function of this score allow us to compare applicants with similar scores, but different admissions outcomes, via a fuzzy regression kink design. The first stage is strong, with take-up of Honors College programming closely following nonlinearities in admissions probabilities. To estimate the causal effect of Honors College admission on human capital formation, we use these nonlinearities in the admissions function as instruments, combined with course-section fixed effects to account for strategic course selection. Honors College admission increases course grades by 0.10 grade points on the 0 to 4 scale, or 0.14 standard deviations. Effects are concentrated at the top of the course grade distribution. However, course grades of first-generation students decrease in response to Honors admission, driven by low performance in natural science courses. Results suggest that selective Honors programs can accelerate skill acquisition for high-achieving students at public universities, but not all students benefit from Honors admission.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2024 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241232971?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Forging a Path to College Persistence: An Experimental Evaluation of the Detroit Promise Path Program</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Detroit students who obtain a college degree overcome many obstacles to do so. This article reports the results of a randomized evaluation of a program meant to provide support to low-income community college students. The Detroit Promise Path program was designed to complement an existing College Promise scholarship, providing students with coaching, summer engagement, and financial incentives. The evaluation found that students offered the program enrolled in more semesters and earned more credits compared with those offered the scholarship alone. However, at the 3-year mark, there were no discernable impacts on degrees earned. This article examines systemic barriers to degree completion and offers lessons for the design of interventions to increase equity in postsecondary attainment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2024 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241230474?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cultivating Students’ Agency by Infusing Number Talks with Notice and Wonder</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2024 03:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2321041?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Units Coordination, Combinatorial Reasoning, and the Multiplication Principle: The Case of Ashley, an Advanced Stage 2 College Student</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2024 03:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2319004?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of Blocked Practice versus Mixed Practice and the Strategy of Overlearning on Student Performance in Calculus</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-10-2024 05:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2321834?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of cultural supports for Indigenous students: spaces for and impediments to decolonizing education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-10-2024 01:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2328268?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Disaffected teachers: disrupting normalized feelings of race and gender in teacher education research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2024 12:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2323782?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Earning to Learning: Reasoning and Participation in Youth Co-design of Digital Badges</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2024 07:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2323474?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward the end of school counseling: visionary possibilities for counselors to build and practice abolition in education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2024 05:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2328263?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How and Why Teachers Taught About the 2020 U.S. Election: An Analysis of Survey Responses From Twelve States</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;This study explores social studies teachers’ self-reported instruction about teaching the 2020 election in U.S. secondary schools. We analyzed survey responses from 1,723 secondary social studies teachers from 12 states (3 left-leaning, 3 right-leaning, 6 battleground) collected in the weeks after the election, examining self-reported pedagogies, topics taught, and overall frequency of teaching about the election. Respondents reported teaching about the election more frequently if they taught courses in civics or government and/or if they had greater control over their curricula. Analyses indicated that teachers’ demographic characteristics, teaching contexts, and ideologies about civic education were related to the election-related topics they taught and the instructional practices they employed. Our findings have important implications for educators, administrators, policymakers, and others interested in strengthening civic learning.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2024 05:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241234884?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Literacy, racial capitalism, and the politics of good feeling</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2323783?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
