<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond the Parameters of “Choice”: An Obliterated Vision for Traditional Public Schooling and the Contamination of the New Orleans Charter Restart Model</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Departing from mainstream accounts of the post-Katrina New Orleans state takeover and the more recent “unification” of schools under local governance, this case study utilizes the plantation (Hartman, 1997; Woods, 1998, McKittrick, 2011) as a theoretical device and the silenced archive (Trouillot, 2015) as a method of inquiry to better understand why and how a Black public high school was obliterated. Data analysis indicates that despite the takeover and the damning of John McDonogh Senior High, this school was a lynchpin of struggle for democratic public schooling. Additionally, findings suggest that the charter school movement deployed community engagement, an evolving technology, to obliterate a collective vision that fell beyond the parameters of “choice.” In closing, the article points to an absence of empirical evidence on the all-charter structure, the ever-present use of the city as a laboratory for restructuring efforts elsewhere, and a pressing need for building and sustaining researchers who are accountable to African American communities in New Orleans.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231218204?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under The Law: Vouchers and the future of public education</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 62-64, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Until recently, few states offered vouchers to help families pay for private schools. But over the last two years, more states have begun enacting “universal” voucher laws, which permit any school-age child in the state to attend private schools using taxpayer funds that would or could otherwise support public education. Robert Kim and Jessica Levin discuss the legal and political trends undergirding the voucher movement and why the growth of vouchers will negatively affect public schools without offering help to the students who most need it.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230789?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Poll Points: What’s the public perception of teacher shortages?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 72-72, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The public is divided on the severity of teacher shortages: 51% call it either a crisis (16%) or a serious problem but not a crisis (35%). Nearly as many, 47%, call it either not a serious problem (31%) or not a problem at all (16%).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230800?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A crisis of mattering: A conversation with Angela Maiers</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 42-45, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The lessons Angela Maiers has learned from her students prompted her to explore the importance of mattering. She discovered that being valued is not a socioemotional or mental health issue. It is rooted in biology. Maiers has written four books on the concept of mattering and unleashing individual genius in students, including Genius Matters and Classroom Habitudes. She spoke with Phi Delta Kappan about what schools get wrong about student motivation, how mattering interventions take little time but yield big results, and what gives her hope.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230784?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engaging, motivating, and supporting students through feedback</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 46-53, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Learning is iterative. It takes time and effort. Real progress in any subject requires we engage, motivate, and support learners as they take next steps to improve their work. Brent Duckor and Carrie Holmberg show how teachers can use progress guides as a formative feedback tool to re-engage and support students where they are, while keeping the focus on concrete steps they can take to move forward in the learning cycle. Drawing from research and case study evidence, they highlight how students and teachers can move conversations forward in safe and respectful ways. Without relying on graded judgments, the progress guide approach preserves the goals of continuous improvement and recenters learning for all students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230785?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning with Leaders: Taking care of self and others: Melvin Brown</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Melvin J. Brown, superintendent of Montgomery Public Schools in Alabama, talks with PDK CEO James Lane about the importance of self-care and networks of support in times of crisis. He shares how he has prioritized listening to the community to develop a vision for his district and build programs that students are interested in so that all students can achieve their goals.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230787?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: How teachers and ed tech can help each other</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-61, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Education technology companies make millions of dollars from their education products and services. Ed tech companies could reinvest in school customers. Columnist Jonathan E. Collins suggests they could do this by incorporating teachers, especially teachers of color and teachers serving vulnerable subgroups of students, into their corporate board apparatus. They should start rotating teachers onto their corporate boards or develop advisory boards made up of current teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230788?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Screech owls, Super Soakers, and school gardens</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 26-31, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Project-based learning (PBL) is gaining momentum as a rich and multifaceted instructional approach that is motivating and engaging. Miranda S. Fitzgerald and Annemarie Sullivan Palincsar argue that PBL provides a particularly rich context for fostering students’ literacy motivation and engagement. One reason for this is that characteristic features of PBL closely align with research-supported instructional practices for fostering literacy motivation and engagement, such as peer collaboration, communicating with real audiences, and solving meaningful problems. They describe supporting research and share how educators can use the SMILE concept — sharing, me, importance, liking, engagement — to design and implement PBL to foster literacy motivation and engagement in K-12 classrooms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230781?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mentors’ recommendations for work-life balance</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 54-57, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;New teachers benefit from mentoring from more experienced colleagues, and the Wyoming Teacher Mentor Corps (WTMC) provides high-quality training for master teachers to provide this mentoring support. As part of the program, mentors learn about assessment, communication, feedback, and work-life balance. Colby Gull and Leslie Rush describe how, as part of the training, mentors identified and prioritized critical principles for maintaining work-life balance. Strategies include shutting down and disconnecting from work, acknowledging one’s own humanity when making mistakes, and prioritizing and saying no when needed. The authors discuss these and other suggestions and how they might be used in school settings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230786?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Key lessons from research about project-based teaching and learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 19-25, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;For many students, project-based learning (PBL) can be more engaging than more traditional instructional approaches. Over the past 15 years, Anna Saavedra and Amie Rapaport studied seven inquiry-based approaches. Their research shows that PBL has a positive effect on students’ achievement and development of important soft skills. Schools can maximize chances of success by providing expert-created, high-quality, adaptable materials; aligned professional learning opportunities; and a supportive schoolwide culture. Some of the challenges of PBL implementation include the tension between breadth and depth of content, keeping projects central to the curriculum, misalignment of standardized assessments with PBL, and financial requirements.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230780?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Motivating adolescents to read</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 37-41, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Motivating today’s adolescents to read is a challenge. Martha Abele Mac Iver, Marcia H. Davis, and Douglas J. Mac Iver discuss the kinds of literacy instructional practices that address what we know about adolescent motivation. They also review several evidence-based literacy interventions designed to engage and motivate adolescent readers that can potentially lead to improvements in student reading motivation and academic outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230783?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where is motivation in the science of reading?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 32-36, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Recently, the science of reading has garnered much attention in elementary schools across the U.S. The science of reading is a body of research on learning to read that has been accumulated through systematic inquiry. Seth A. Parsons and Joy Dangora Erickson argue that the way the science of reading is being implemented is missing a key ingredient: motivation. There is an expansive research base on the importance of motivation for learning. Using practical guidelines, they advocate infusing the science of reading with research on reading motivation to design instruction that optimally supports young learners.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230782?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘Why do I have to learn this?’</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 8-12, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Students’ valuing of academic content impacts their engagement in learning and plays a pivotal role in shaping their future academic and career choices. Fortunately, practicing educators can integrate many readily applicable strategies into teaching to enhance students’ valuing of academic content. Drawing from expectancy-value theory, Eric M. Anderman, Yue Sheng, and Wonjoon Cha present five evidence-based instructional strategies with concrete examples that aim to enhance students’ valuing of academic content. These strategies can be implemented with minimal additional work for teachers and at little or no additional financial cost to schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230778?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: Chasing what matters</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The articles in the February 2024 Kappan focus on motivation and engagement. Teresa Preston, Kappan’s editor in chief, reflects on the problems of using grades as a primary motivator for students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230774?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 7-7, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this regular column, Kappan authors share books and articles that have inspired and influenced them. Sarah Miles and Caitlin Ciannella discuss an article from Contemporary Educational Psychology. Seth Parsons describes Preparing Teachers for a Changing World: What Teachers Should Learn and Be Able to Do, edited by Linda Darling-Hammond and John Bransford.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230776?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Helping students to learn and grow</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 13-18, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research on engagement in schools as well as research from the Challenge Success-Stanford Survey of School Experiences on how high school studentsʼ perceptions of classroom practices correlate with their engagement levels shows that more students are engaged in school when educators emphasize practices that promote learning and mastery. Authors Sarah Miles, Denise Pope, and Caitlin Ciannella offer mastery-based strategies teachers can use to increase student engagement by tweaking some approaches to grading and assessment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230779?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: Heritage News</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 70-71, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Patty Lofgren shares her experiences as a judge at the Educators Rising conference. Educators Rising student officer Taylor Jenkins, scholarship winner McKenna Seay, and emerging leader Alexander Uryga are spotlighted.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230798?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Browsing: Further thoughts on this month’s theme</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 5-6, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;News, quotes, and insights from the past related to the theme of the February 2024 issue of Kappan, “Motivation &amp;amp; engagement.”
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230775?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: Teacher wants to support students with test anxiety</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 65-65, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Phyllis Fagell offers workplace advice for educators in this regular Kappan column. This month, a math teacher is looking for ideas to ease students’ test anxiety.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230790?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Backtalk: Teaching historical reasoning helps democracy thrive</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 66-67, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Beneath the turmoil over book bans, Advanced Placement courses, and teaching about race and slavery lurks a sobering fact about historical knowledge: History is not only about what happened in the past but also about how we know it. Understanding history means grasping both substance and method. If students are asked simply to memorize information about the past, rather than investigate it, then they have learned no way to distinguish historical claims from myths, legends, and lies. The work of history teachers is to build students’ historical reasoning skills so they can determine what is true.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230791?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: What keeps students motivated?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/5&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 68-68, February 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Educators Rising students share what keeps them motivated and what causes them to shut down.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241230792?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming Political Divides: How Student Identities and Campus Contexts Shape Interpartisan Friendships</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Recent evidence suggests that only about 1 in 5 U.S. adults has a friend on the political “other side” (Dunn, 2020). Although these interpartisan friendships are uncommon, they play a critical role in catalyzing empathy, reducing prejudice, furthering justice, and even restoring democracy, as suggested by the theory of civic friendship (Goering, 2003; Kahane, 1999; Rawlins, 2009). In the present study, we drew on national data from the Interfaith Diversity Experiences and Attitudes Longitudinal Survey (IDEALS) to examine the personal and contextual factors that predict interpartisan friendship formation among 5,762 college students attending 118 higher education institutions in the United States. The findings revealed the constellation of individual, social, and institutional contributors to students’ capacities to reach across political differences in their friendships. We offer guidance for how college educators can support the development of these relationships that may open a path toward empathy and healing in our polarized society.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2024 07:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231222475?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Yes, I Can!” A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Intervention Studies Promoting Teacher Self-Efficacy</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A high level of teacher self-efficacy is considered to be important for a successful and healthy teaching career. This preregistered meta-analysis focuses on whether and to what degree interventions can promote teacher self-efficacy. We included 115 studies representing 11,284 pre-service and in-service teachers in our meta-analysis. Interventions had a significant, positive effect on the promotion of teachers’ self-efficacy (g = 0.47, RVE SE = 0.04, 95% CI = [0.40, 0.54]) with no significant differences between pre- and in-service teachers. A fine-grained coding and systematic review of the targeted sources of self-efficacy according to Bandura’s sociocognitive theory revealed that overall interventions including mastery experiences did not significantly differ from those without. However, interventions targeting only mastery experiences were the most successful for pre-service teachers (g = 0.62, RVE SE = 0.11, CI = [0.35, 0.88]). Based on further moderator analyses, we recommend interventions to integrate reflective elements. Finally, future research should apply stricter study designs and more detailed intervention descriptions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-29-2024 11:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231221499?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparative study of cooperative-learning and lecture-based-learning in teaching classification of living things among Senior High School students in Tamale</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-29-2024 06:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2308160?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
