<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advancing Preservice Science Teachers’ Skills to Assess Student Thinking On-the-Fly Through Practice-Based Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers’ assessment of student thinking is both difficult to attain and essential for responsive teaching in ongoing interaction during science lessons. Principles of practice-based learning provide a basis for the design of learning environments which may equip prospective teachers for this challenging task. In an experimental study (N = 104), we examined the extent that the use of different media types as representations of practice (video and written cases), the number of rehearsals, and the complexity of student thinking contribute to preservice teachers’ acquisition of assessment skills. Our findings indicated that participants benefited equally well from video and written cases. The number of necessary rehearsals depended on the complexity of student thinking to be assessed. This finding implies that specifics of the content to be assessed need to be taken into consideration when designing learning environments for practicing assessment skills.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 12:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241237497?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I had no knowledge of this”: disrupting majoritarian narratives regarding Mexican American K12 students and employing documentary film in the preparation of equity-oriented school leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 12:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306410?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Boundary construction and education: un/belonging among Somali refugee students in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 04:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2327109?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating the impact of the race equality charter on diversity staff outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 04:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2328372?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engaging with literacies of resistance</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2024 03:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2324236?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond a sense of obliviousness: elite education and national identity among Palestinian students in Israel</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2024 11:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2328283?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Testing a Holistic Framework of Early Care and Education and K–12 Leaders’ Working Conditions and Well-Being</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The importance of leadership for key educational outcomes is well documented, yet leaders’ working conditions and well-being have received considerably less attention, particularly in the early care and education (ECE) sector. Job-Demands-Resources (JD-R) theory was used to develop a holistic conceptualization of leader well-being for the purpose of examining the associations among various job demands, resources, and well-being (i.e., physical, psychological, and professional well-being) for leaders of birth to 12th grade (B–12). We tested our conceptual model via structural equation modeling (SEM) with over 2,000 ECE and K–12 building leaders across the United States. We found substantially stronger effects between job demands and well-being relative to job resources and well-being, though resources were found to be directly associated with professional well-being. Further, our tested model was similar for both ECE and K–12 leaders. Overall findings suggest that a reduction in demands—not just increased resources—is needed to ensure improved leader well-being.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2024 04:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241235923?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘I am struggling to survive’: financial inequity in postgraduate teacher education in England</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2024 03:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2330543?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Plantation economy religion: Black male experiences with religious antiblackness in predominantly white conservative Christian schools</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2024 02:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2328269?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Validity of multiple-choice digital formative assessment for assessing students’ (mis)conceptions: evidence from a mixed-methods study in algebra</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Assessing students’ (mis)conceptions is a challenging task for teachers as well as for researchers. While individual assessment, for example through interviews, can provide deep insights into students’ thinking, this is very time-consuming and therefore not feasible for whole classes or even larger settings. For those settings, automatically evaluated multiple-choice (MC) items could be a solution. However, it is a challenge to design those items and to adapt them for other countries in a way that they adequately reveal students’ (mis)conceptions. In this article, we investigate the question whether it is valid to use a German adaption of a multiple-choice test developed in Australia for formative assessment of the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;letter-as-object&lt;/em&gt; misconception in Germany. For this, first semi-structured interviews with five German Year 8 students were conducted, and second, 616 students were asked for short written explanations. These data were analysed with regards to the students’ (mis)conceptions and compared with their automatic online diagnosis. In general, a high concordance between online SMART test results and students’ explanations was observed, confirming that useful diagnoses of student misconceptions can be obtained from such a short well-designed MC test.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01556-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Research on curriculum resources in mathematics education: a survey of the field</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This survey describes the structure of the field of research on curriculum resources in mathematics education in the period from 2018 till 2023. Based on the procedures of a systematic review relevant literature was identified using Web of Science as a database. The included literature was analyzed and categorized according to the type of curriculum resource and the area of study. Seven areas of studies were identified: studies on the role of curriculum resources, content analysis, user studies, studies on the effects of curriculum resources, studies on curriculum resource design, curriculum resources as data, and reviews. The areas were further subdivided into different subcategories based on the research questions of the included papers. The findings show that research on mathematics textbooks is still predominant in the field. The most popular areas of research are content analysis, user studies, studies on design, and studies on effects. Emerging areas are research on students’ use of curriculum resources and the employment of user data from digital curriculum resources as data basis in mathematics education research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01559-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collaboration and co-creation in autism research: a reflection on the challenges and benefits of participatory approaches in doctoral research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-14-2024 10:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2329195?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Femmenoir pedagogies: rescripting the reproduction of Black women’s marginalization in education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-14-2024 07:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2327110?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Poststructural Analysis of Anti-LGBTQ + Educational Policies</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We draw on several critical paradigms, disciplines, and theories to interrogate 13 anti-LGBTQ+ educational policy texts. Using Institutional Theory (Anagnostopoulos et al., 2010; Carpenter &amp;amp; Feroz, 2001) and Poststructural Policy Analysis (Bacchi &amp;amp; Goodwin, 2016), we explore how these texts may cause separations between policy and practice, how they construct “teachers” and “students” as subjects and objects of the state, and how they promote cisheteropatriarchy. The terms reactive evasion and identity evasiveness are presented to describe central discursive mechanisms in the texts. The term identity specificity, or the humanizing practices of recognizing diverse identities, is coined as a fundamental component of educational quality. We situate our work as an enunciation of critical resistance within anti-oppressive discourses and assert three main arguments: (a) these dictates will adversely affect educational institutions; (b) a fundamental component of educational quality is identity specificity; and (c) policy not centered on the humanizing testimony of those about whom that policy is generated reinforces oppressive regimes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-14-2024 06:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241237718?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student activists for racially equitable change: lessons for higher education leaders from a critical participatory action research project</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-14-2024 05:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2329172?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining the role of emotion in culturally and linguistically diverse students’ classroom underlife</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 06:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2323781?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Shared Responsibility for Multilingual Learners Across Levels of the Education System</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Educational change efforts that prioritize equity for multilingual learners (MLs) require attention to several interconnected components of the education system. We build on prior literature and our collective research to clarify the concept of shared responsibility for ML students and to operationalize the concept at the school, district, and state levels. Drawing on institutional theory and a racialized organizations lens, we argue that shared responsibility is embedded in the mindsets, norms, and structures that shape education systems. We also attend to the complexities of fostering shared responsibility in practice, such as grappling with pervasive educator burnout and developing innovative strategies that span levels of the system. We conclude with directions for future research, including studies examining effective approaches for shifting the mindsets, norms, and routines comprising shared responsibility, and recommendations for researchers to play a more active role in shaping shared responsibility for ML students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 06:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241227913?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Feeling anti-racism: how neoliberal multiculturalism and racialized emotions impede equity in the aftermath of George Floyd</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 06:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2323773?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging a University to Create Local Equity-Oriented K–12 Learning Opportunities: A Conversation Starter</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article shares our university center’s efforts to act as a boundary spanner supporting colleagues across our university to contribute collectively to more equitable educational opportunities for local K–12 students and their teachers. We focus here on the ongoing critical reflection and collaboration needed to tap such university resources to support K–12 students typically underresourced and underserved in K–12 systems. We consider examples and challenges of our work through five equity-oriented principles. We seek to highlight the role of research-practice teams on campuses that help (or could help) university partners contribute to local K–12 schools, programs, and systems with equity in mind. Finally, we hope to convince other higher education institutions to leverage their resources more to grow K–12 education opportunities locally where needs are greatest.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 05:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241227887?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Changes in Reported Social-Emotional Skills Just Noise? The Predictive Power of Longitudinal Differences in Self-Reports</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Prior work has shown that students’ self-reported levels on social-emotional measures predict achievement levels and gains, but we have little evidence on whether within-student changes in self-reports on social-emotional surveys are predictive of changes in theoretically related academic and behavioral outcomes. We use large-scale data from the California CORE districts to examine whether changes in individual reports on social-emotional measures from one school year to the next predict changes in state math and English language arts test scores and attendance. We show that changes in self-reported social-emotional measures predict changes in both achievement and attendance. These results are robust across model specifications. Moreover, the relationships between SEL and achievement and attendance outcomes are consistent across student subgroups.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 05:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241233277?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Quantifying and Predicting Variation in the Medium-Term Effects of an Oversubscribed Prekindergarten Program</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 05:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2286280?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mentor teachers’ achievement goal orientations for mentoring during the practicum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 04:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2328060?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Defending the Color Line: White Supremacy and the Legacy of Brown</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Building on W. E. B. Du Bois’s color line concept, I argue that white supremacy is deeply embedded in U.S. educational organizations and that White racial actors, opportunity hoarding, and the cultivation of racial ideology and racial ignorance help sustain it. In doing this, I seek to move away from the aspirational progress narratives often associated with Brown to the racial hierarchies and various forms of harm that schools reproduce, even when they are racially diverse. Taking the recent attacks against critical race theory as a backdrop, I argue that educational institutions not only contribute to educational inequity but also socialize people into relations of racial domination and subordination through organizational practices and individual actions. In the article’s conclusion, I highlight my efforts to disrupt these patterns and work toward the creation of more liberatory education spaces.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2024 03:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231216450?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Devised theatre methodology to promote creativity in school</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-12-2024 05:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2326602?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
