<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining preservice teachers’ sensemaking of teaching children through rigorous and appropriate practices: a case study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2023 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2265828?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Helping Students Become Powerful Mathematical Thinkers. Case Studies of Teaching for Robust Understanding</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-12-2023 09:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2261410?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Admissions Officers’ Perceptions When Undocumented Students Seek In-State Resident Tuition Policy</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Administrative burdens scholarship has explored the factors influencing bureaucrats’ perceptions and administrative discretion when entitled individuals seek policy benefits. Few studies, however, have recently investigated such phenomena with undocumented youth immigrants. Drawing from online web surveys and conducting a mixed methods study, I examine factors influencing admissions officers’ perceptions of requirements when undocumented youth claim in-state resident tuition benefits in U.S. colleges. The findings suggest that officers who interact more often with undocumented applicants and with more positive social constructions of them are less likely to support stringently applied administrative requirements when they seek in-state tuition benefits. However, such variables are insufficient to frame admissions officers’ decisions. State laws and organizational rules also constrain their administrative discretion regardless of their proclivity to facilitate access to in-state tuition benefits by undocumented youth. This study addresses the tension among public servants’ attitudes and bureaucratic factors mediating efficiency, equity, and integrity surrounding policy implementation. Findings contribute to higher education policy scholarship by exploring the roles of street-level bureaucrats as mediators among state policies, institutional rules, and the circumstances of undocumented applicants.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-12-2023 06:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231201789?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Helping or Hurting: The Effects of Retention in the Third Grade on Student Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We evaluate the effects of grade retention on students’ academic, attendance, and disciplinary outcomes in Indiana. Using a regression discontinuity design, we show that third-grade retention increases achievement in English Language Arts (ELA) and math immediately and substantially, and the effects persist into middle school. We find no evidence of grade retention effects on student attendance or disciplinary incidents, again into middle school. Our findings combine to show that Indiana’s third-grade retention policy improves achievement for retained students without adverse impacts along (measured) nonacademic dimensions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2023 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231197639?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Family-Centered Research: Reflections From a Zoom-Based Recording Method of Families Learning Together at Home</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although schools are a primary focus of education research, we have long known that families are equally critical in supporting children’s learning. However, many existing studies put families in situations that share little resemblance to what family learning looks like outside of school. These limitations undermine both the quality of the research and our commitments to equity. Based on our experiences during the global health pandemic, we reflect on these limitations and offer thoughts to motivate a new vision of family learning research. Among other things, the process revealed the power of allowing families to choose how and when they engage in learning experiences together and finding ways to capture more authentic family configurations beyond the parent-child dyad.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2023 09:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231204587?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Passing the torch: intergenerational capital transmission and the black legacy experience at a PWI</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2023 07:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2268002?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Facing and challenging language ideologies towards a more inclusive understanding of language in mathematics education research—the case of sign languages</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research on language in mathematics education is largely dominated by a ‘normalcy’ of spoken languages. This modal hegemony does not only affect a whole group of learners in failing to provide access that is epistemologically equitable—those using sign language as their preferred mode for mathematical discourse—it also obscures our view on the roles language can play in mathematical thinking and learning. As a field, we can only win from seeking to understand Deaf learners of mathematics beyond a disability, as learners of mathematics with a specific linguistic background that influences mathematical thinking and learning in peculiar ways. In this contribution, I suggest a shift in mindset towards a more inclusive view on language in mathematics education research and practice. I propose basic principles to inform a perspective for reconsidering the role of language in mathematics thinking and learning, inspired by work of philosopher Francois Jullien. This perspective counters a perspective that merely integrates sign language into existing research and instead searches for dialogue between linguistic modalities in learning mathematics, looking beyond language as spoken or written. This approach will be illustrated by the case of the modal affordance of iconicity foregrounded in signed mathematical discourse, its role in Deaf students’ mathematics thinking and learning, and how this can inform existing research and practice dealing with language in mathematics education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-10-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01526-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning to elicit student thinking: the role of planning to support academically rigorous questioning sequences during instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The use of questioning to elicit student thinking is one of the cornerstones of ambitious teaching; thus, supporting prospective teachers in this complex practice is a core objective of mathematics teacher education. In this paper, we examine the academic rigor of the sustained questioning sequences prospective teachers use during instruction to elicit student thinking and the possible factor lesson planning plays in enacted sequences involving academically rigorous questions. We analyzed the questions they asked during lessons in an early field experience and traced how prospective teachers prepared for those questions as represented in their lesson plans. From our analysis, we found prospective teachers used three types of sustained questioning sequences when eliciting student thinking in the enactment of the lesson. Further, we found evidence suggesting a connection between the questions asked during enactment of a lesson and the quality of questions prospective teachers incorporated into their lesson plan. These findings inform how mathematics teacher educators can support prospective teachers during lesson planning to prepare to elicit student thinking in productive ways.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-10-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09603-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impact of educational game development on students’ achievement and attitudes toward science</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-09-2023 08:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2265852?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We Don’t Teach Critical Race Theory Here”: A Sentiment Analysis of K-12 School and District Social Media Statements</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-09-2023 06:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2261318?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race at the Top</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Race at the Top addresses topical subjects about parental anxiety, racial discrimination, and migrant assimilation in an upper-middle-class suburb where White and Asian-origin families monopolize a high achieving public high school, Woodcrest. Behind the town’s progressive façade and without overt racialization, White parents mobilize to advantage their children through school policies that curtail the academics stressed by Asian-origin parents. By seeing this clash through the frame of American assimilation theories, this otherwise novel and well-written book does not address it as biopolitical clash of class created by the expansion of the global upper-middle-class, a plausible alternative hypothesis.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2023 10:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231204011?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Evolution of “Loaded Moments” Toward Escalation or De-Escalation in Student–Teacher Interactions</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;To minimize negative interactions and their impacts, teachers and students must successfully negotiate loaded moments, points in time when two or more parties realize that their needs differ and that they must confront that difference. In this literature review, we synthesize 30 studies, published from 2000 to 2020, that describe the evolution of loaded moments between teachers and students with the goal of identifying and explicating the co-construction of escalation and de-escalation during classroom interactions. We found that macro level social contexts and existing classroom patterns set the scene for the occurrence of a loaded moment. In addition, loaded moments emerge when specific instigating circumstances are co-constructed, which refer to incompatibilities between teacher and student(s). Furthermore, loaded moments (de)escalate, depending on the co-construction of the moment as it progresses, such as through mutual trade-offs, turnings, or refusals. Finally, these co-constructions can result in a specific long-term relationship- and bond-development. Implications of these findings for research concerning student–teacher conflict are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2023 09:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231202509?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the impact of distance teaching on mathematics educational values in Hong Kong: a study of in-service teachers’ perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study analyzed the variation in teachers’ mathematical educational values between distance and traditional face-to-face teaching. Enabled by the unique circumstances of the COVID-19 pandemic, the research explored the impact of remote teaching on primary and secondary mathematics education in Hong Kong. An online survey, completed by 109 practicing mathematics teachers, assessed their pre-existing educational values and their adaptability to the shift towards distance teaching, as well as their teaching practices. Findings indicated that despite the multitude of digital teaching tools, the implementation of most mathematical educational values was more restricted in distance teaching. Rationalism and Control were prioritized, reflecting the challenges of assessing student progress remotely. Among the 13 values identified, Fun and Engagement, along with Thinking and Problem-solving, Achievement, and Reasoning, were significantly diminished, highlighting the shortcomings of one-way and superficial concept-based teaching. The study concludes that distance teaching, when completely isolated from traditional methods, may not offer the benefits suggested in the literature, impacting student engagement, motivation, and higher-order thinking. This necessitates a unique curriculum development model to effectively incorporate blended and self-directed learning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00476-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impacts of maker technologies on classroom learning outcomes: A mixed methods explanatory study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/vjer20/116/4&quot;&gt;Volume 116, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, 2023, Page 198-205&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-05-2023 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2239185?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Three embodied voices speaking on/to research on language, mathematics, and the learner</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this literature synthesis, the three authors bring their embodied voices to collectively retrace the political-cultural-racialized-gendered topographies where key conceptualizations of language, mathematics, and the learner have emerged. Recognizing that they themselves have never been outside these landscapes as mere objective observers, the authors project their situated voices to critically consider—always with a sense of ownership and responsibility—what the field of language and mathematics research has done with/to these conceptualizations. These critical considerations are intended as a collective reminder that the field of language and mathematics education research can move forward by (re)engaging a dialogue between “what is” and “what could be” In this sense, the purpose of this literature synthesis is not to report yet another state of the art in the field, but rather to pierce through ongoing discourses to re-engage the field in reimagining possibilities for reopening, revising, and reimagining the concepts, methodologies, and philosophies that inform research in language and mathematics education. The synthesis concludes with a discussion of how and why our multivocal literature synthesis matters in the field of mathematics education research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01525-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Middle school students’ reflections on process oriented guided inquiry learning (POGIL®)1</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2023 12:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2265878?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching and learning in teacher education: agency, reflection and identity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2023 06:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2266256?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Who is attending training to comply with the expectations of the school management? A study among Romanian in-service teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2023 06:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2265547?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Undergraduate Students’ Psychological Stress in the Mathematics Classroom with Fitness Trackers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2023 06:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2259558?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Staying with difficulty: on the emotional and social uses of childhood objects in unbecoming a teacher</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2023 05:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2261383?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How about a round of applause: assets, dispositions and contributions of first-year teachers during parallel pandemics of 2020</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2023 05:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2260751?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching culturally and linguistically diverse students for the first time: a phenomenological inquiry into in-service teachers’ perceptions, lived experiences, and pedagogies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2023 02:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2265546?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Who Should Control Education Now? Revisiting Preferences for Local Control in Educational Decision Making</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2023 01:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2261315?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Good Citizenship and the “True and Inspiring Story of America”: A Critical Policy Analysis of the South Dakota Civics and History Initiative</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2023 01:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2261311?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
