<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Seeking Direct Accountability for Disproportionate Discipline and Dis/ability Classification</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Accountability for racially disproportionate discipline and dis/ability classification has conventionally spotlighted the disparate impact on students. Typically, findings such as “x% of African American students were suspended” or “y% of Latinx students were misidentified as having learning dis/abilities” reinforce this pattern. Our qualitative study sought the outlines of a different framing that locates accountability in practices, policies, and patterns of adult actors that produce those unjust outcomes. Practitioners, policy makers, researchers, and activists participated in this interview study by giving their perspectives on that reframing. Although their analyses fell short of directly holding the educational system accountable, they did highlight reforms such as increasing student agency in discipline and classification processes, expanding those processes to include a holistic analysis of students’ lives, and acknowledging that current accountability measures evade and obscure structural racism in discipline and dis/ability classification.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2023 04:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231206166?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Disaggregating the Effects of STEM Education and Apprenticeships on Economic Mobility: Evidence From the LaunchCode Program</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We conduct an impact analysis on a unique technology certificate and apprenticeship program offered by LaunchCode. We merge administrative data containing entrance exam scores with survey data for individuals that were (a) not accepted, (b) accepted but did not complete the course, (c) completed the course but not the apprenticeship, and (d) completed the course and the apprenticeship. By using entrance exam scores as an instrumental variable, we conduct an intent-to-treat model, finding that program acceptance was significantly associated with increased earnings and probabilities of working in a science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM) profession. Then, by using machine learning-generated multinomial propensity score weights, we conduct a treatment-on-treated analysis, finding that these increases appear to be primarily driven by the apprenticeship component.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231199985?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Exploring how to teach multiplication through the Japanese and Ibero-American theories. Masami Isoda &amp;amp; Raimundo Olfos (Eds.). (2021) Teaching multiplication with lesson study: Japanese and Ibero-American theories for international mathema</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2023 22:35</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10238-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Technology maker practices in mathematics learning in STEM contexts: a case in Brazil and two cases in Canada</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The act of making provides students with an opportunity to create and design by using materials and technologies. Scholars who examine learning through making maintain that maker approaches to solving problems, creating designs, and thinking about real-world ideas promote the development of abstract thinking skills, such as modeling, and computational thinking (CT) skills. Our goal is to research the use of specific methods of maker education—such as experimenting with tools and hands-on designs—in learning mathematics. We ask: what are the benefits and potential outcomes for designing and teaching learning activities which integrate technology maker practices and pedagogies in mathematics and other school concepts in STEM contexts? We analyzed qualitative data on the benefits and potential outcomes of maker practices and pedagogies from three cases in Canada and Brazil. The researchers designed and facilitated the tasks to study the experiences of participants. Participants were observed, interviewed (or asked interview questions via a questionnaire), and completed reflection prompts. Their activities were recorded. The results show that learning from maker practices and pedagogies augments the learning of individual STEM disciplines, with specific settings and activity designs offering varied foci on mathematics and technology, on science, engineering and mathematics, or on science, technology and mathematics. Students, preservice teachers and teachers benefit in cognitive, interdisciplinary and social (situated) ways. Further research is needed to explore how deeper and other benefits, including critical benefits, may be achieved for learning and teaching mathematics and to explore which practices and pedagogies are associated with more potential outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01534-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09608-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Factors impacting reading motivation: Insights from the bioecological model of human development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2023 07:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2265881?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating the predictive relations between self-efficacy and achievement goals on procedural and conceptual science learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2023 06:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2251415?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining the effects of an intervention on mathematical modeling in problem solving at upper elementary grades: a cluster randomized trial study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2023 01:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2270088?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Structure and associations of science vocabulary, general academic vocabulary, and science knowledge</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 12:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2269545?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploration of middle school students’ scientific epistemological beliefs and their engagement in argumentation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 12:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2265880?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Organizational Structure, Instructional Quality, and Student Achievement: The Case of Public and Private Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Influencing major education policies in the US such as school vouchers and charter schools, market theory assumes that organizational autonomy, parental choice, and competition between schools improve the quality of education. However, whether those policies can influence the instructional core of schools is not well understood. Comparing private and public schools offers an opportunity to examine whether market-oriented assumptions hold in practice. Relying on institutional theory, this study examines whether public and private schools differ in their instructional quality and whether such differences translate into achievement advantages in the US. Using Trends in International Mathematics and Science Study (TIMSS) surveys and achievement data, the study integrates structural equation modeling and propensity score matching to examine the latent construct of instructional quality and mitigate selection bias. Results indicate similar instructional quality in public and private schools explaining comparable student achievement by school type. Barriers to instructional change through market-oriented reforms are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 10:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231204810?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Banking on Dual Credit: Broadening Opportunities to Earn College Credit in High School and the Transition to College</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article studies state-developed courses in career and technical education (CTE) that offer students the opportunity to earn college credit during high school. Using a regression-discontinuity approach, we examine the effects of passing the end-of-course exam necessary to secure college credit on postsecondary enrollment and choice. We find that barely passing a CTE dual-credit exam increases the likelihood of attending a public, in-state, 2-year institution, with at least part of that increased propensity stemming from a reduction in the likelihood of attending a private in-state institution. Furthermore, we find suggestive evidence that the boost in the likelihood of attending a public, in-state, 2-year college is relatively larger for male compared to female students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 10:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231195345?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Language Views for Scientific Sensemaking Matter: A Synthesis of Research on Multilingual Students’ Experiences with Science Practices Through a Translanguaging Lens</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This synthesis examines recent science education research on multilingual students’ experiences with language-rich science practices. Adopting a translanguaging lens, we explore how researchers’ language conceptualizations impact the science practices they study and the ways multilingual students are positioned. This analysis helps us understand the extent to which recent research is disrupting, or sustaining, minoritizing narratives about multilingual students and how they sensemake in science. Based on our findings, we suggest researchers: (1) reflect upon and expand their views of language, which will enable the field to develop more nuanced understandings of how language use across linguistic and multimodal resources permeates all science practices, and (2) consider how to expand multilingual students’ language repertoires for sensemaking while also valuing students’ existing language resources and practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 10:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231206172?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘Taking knowledge on a journey’: Creating conditions for epistemic justice</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;When stakeholders in participatory action research [PAR] projects live in poverty, practices sometimes fail to recognize and draw on their capacity for critical reflection. This constitutes epistemic (knowledge-based) injustice. It is problematic for approaches rooted in covenantal ethics and beliefs that PAR should empower participants as ‘actors of knowledge.’ This paper reflects on a research project carried out by All Together in Dignity Fourth World [ATD]. To ensure co-production of knowledge, ATD made unconventional decisions about methodology, allocating resources, and interacting with academics. In many ways, these choices created conditions for epistemic justice. However ATD faced important challenges around North-South power dynamics, engagement with academia, and the comprehensibility of deeply personal conclusions reached by project participants. More positively, a dogged effort to invent conditions for epistemic justice transformed ATD’s governance, the ways some institutions address poverty, and the way participants addressed inter-generational traumas.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 03:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231205235?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: for Action Research Journal - Strangers in Their Own Land, by Arlie Russell Hochschild</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 03:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231212043?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher growth in exploiting mathematics competencies through STEAM projects</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article is aimed at educators concerned with curricular initiatives that foster STE(A)M projects in secondary education to promote mathematics competencies. Research has recently reported that these projects superficially address mathematics content, hampering the development of competencies the consensus deems necessary to prepare citizens for daily life. This study shows that learning goals may be achieved when teachers receive personalised training and sustained assistance in their project experiences. We examine how two Spanish teachers, with advisors’ support, progress in exploiting mathematics competencies within the implementation of a single project each over a period of 3 years. Their evolution was not the result of minor recommendations but of continuous interactions with the advisors. These interactions intended to maintain a balance between teacher confidence and project enhancements, which required commitment and constancy. Four of the five competencies considered in the Spanish curriculum emerged powerfully after sustained refinement. The frequently mobilised competencies were intra-mathematics, representations, as well as collaborative work and positive identity, followed by modelling. The last of which was difficult to address, but when it was, the other three emerged more naturally. Computational thinking was poorly represented mainly because of the advisors’ background and its recent incorporation into the reference curriculum. The teachers’ progress was influenced by the advisor’s academic background, pedagogical expertise, ability to transfer research outcomes into teaching, and experience supporting others.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01528-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of mathematics teachers&#39; previous professional experiences in their collaborative sensemaking: an ecological perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Educational researchers widely acknowledge the promises and impediments of teachers’ collaborative sensemaking, illuminating the need to recognize additional resources that are salient for teachers within professional interactions. In line with this overarching goal, this study explores the role of mathematics teachers&#39; previous professional experiences in their collaborative sensemaking. Theoretically, it is rooted in ecological theories of learning, highlighting that learning is always shaped by an interconnected set of environments. Empirically, it builds on data from a research–practice partnership with a professional development (PD) organization, where we used classroom video to support secondary mathematics teachers&#39; teams in improving their practice. The analysis first portrays two video-based conversations to illustrate the potential of inviting and building on teachers’ previous experiences and resources to support their collaborative reasoning. Then, it looks across nine video-based conversations of the same two teams and systematically describes experiences and resources that teachers spontaneously reference through six categories: PD workshops, conferences, PD organizations, online resources, research and policy, and curricula. These categories provide a framework for designers and facilitators who want to take seriously the practice of acknowledging that teacher learning happens through a complex web of learning experiences. The study brings forth the affordances of taking a learning ecology perspective on teacher collaborative sensemaking as professional development (CSPD) and provides guidance for designing, facilitating, and analyzing CSPD conversations in ways that center on teachers’ prior knowledge and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09604-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Studying a mathematics teacher’s documentational and identity trajectories over time</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We study the interactions over 22 years between one mathematics teacher and his resources for teaching, especially digital ones, with a dual focus on the teacher’s documentational and identity trajectories and professional development. We combined a theoretical framework on teachers’ work with resources—documentational approach to didactics (DAD)—with a framework based on social practice theory—patterns of participation (PoP). The DAD analysis provided rich descriptions of which digital resources the teacher interacted with and of the transformative evolution of these interactions over time. The PoP analysis offered explanations of how and why the teacher transformed his interactions with the resources through foregrounding affective and contextual factors as significant for the teacher’s formation of identity. We conclude that the combination of the two frameworks provided deeper and complementary insights into the teacher’s long-term professional development with digital resources, and that such networking is needed to develop balanced understandings of teachers’ long-term interactions with digital resources.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09605-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introduction to JEBS Special Issue on Diagnostic Statistical Models</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2023 02:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231210002?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Contradictions in the learning of Euclidean constructions with GeoGebra by pre-service mathematics teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper seeks to answer the question: How does the handling of the contradictions that emerge in activities of initial mathematics teacher education contribute to the learning of geometric knowledge when pre-service teachers and the teacher educator solve geometric construction problems with GeoGebra? A dialectical-materialist approach is used to analyze an episode in which pre-service teachers and the teacher educator discuss the solution to the task of drawing a line perpendicular to a segment given a point off that segment. The episode was video-recorded and transcribed in its totality. Evidence in this research comes directly from the transcription of the episode, and analysis was carried out in two stages. As a result, we identify three formative actions that show the manner in which the conceptual and emotional contradictions emerge and are handled and we offer an explanation of how the handling of these contradictions contributed to the learning of pre-service teachers. We conclude that the way of handling the conceptual contradiction favored the awareness of the mobilized knowledge and that the handling of this contradiction was not exempt from emotional tensions, the latter of which we interpret as the manifestation of a contradiction of the autonomy/dependence type.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09606-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Social Determinants of Learning: Implications for Research, Policy, and Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic revealed what educators, policymakers, and researchers have long known—namely, that learning opportunities and outcomes are intimately intertwined with other aspects of children’s and families’ lives. The list of social forces outside the education sector that can affect learning is endless and includes economic experiences that are inequitably distributed, such as housing security (Gallagher et al., 2020), income (Hoynes &amp;amp; Rothstein, 2019), and wealth (Pfeffer, 2018), as well as social experiences, such as interpersonal and structural racism, (dis)ability, and xenophobia (Anderson-Nathe, 2020; DeMatthews, 2020). Now, it is time to lock in this learning among policymakers, practitioners, and researchers. We posit that the concept of “social determinants of learning” can serve as a powerful reframing tool for promoting educational equity, similar to the conceptual shift and policy impact we have seen in public health as “social determinants of health” has become an accepted and eventually essential concept.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-25-2023 07:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231206087?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing the Costs of Online and Teacher-Directed Credit Recovery</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study compares the costs of a school-based online credit recovery model to more traditional teacher-directed credit recovery using rigorous cost analysis methods. Findings indicate that differences in the comprehensive costs for online and teacher-directed credit recovery classes are small. However, cost differences across the two models of specific types of resources are substantial and statistically significant. Online credit recovery classes resulted in higher district-incurred costs largely due to the purchase of online curricula and required technology. The online model incurred lower opportunity costs to teachers stemming from less out-of-class time devoted to grading, lesson planning, and developing course materials.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-25-2023 05:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231207084?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching and learning in uncertain times: thinking with multiple crises</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-25-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2265311?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preface to Special Issue on “Evaluation of Policy Conflicts towards Sustainable Development Goals”</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-25-2023 03:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231210669?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
