<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘A clear center but no clear boundaries.’ The construction of professional identities in spiritual care through boundary work in participatory action research within health care</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Spiritual care is increasingly seen as a task of all health care professionals. This is challenging for chaplains working in health care, who hold spiritual care at the heart of their profession but don’t feel rooted in a strong professional identity. In this article we discuss a participatory action research that aimed at strengthening the professional identity of health care chaplains by forming collaborative learning communities of chaplains and general practice mental health. The focus is on the ‘boundary work’ and how participatory action research contributes to this. Relational professionalism, Dialogical Self Theory and Boundary Theory are combined to interpret the complex relational-dialogical processes of negotiating one’s identity within the relationships with diverse others: clients, mental health nurses and society. The result is a more articulated and at the same time flexible professional identity for healthcare chaplains. Participatory action research contributes to these boundary processes by stimulating reflection, explicating, eliciting or encouraging different voices and facilitating the dialogue between these professionals.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-22-2023 10:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231195418?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>IRT Models for Learning With Item-Specific Learning Parameters</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We propose a new item response theory growth model with item-specific learning parameters, or ISLP, and two variations of this model. In the ISLP model, either items or blocks of items have their own learning parameters. This model may be used to improve the efficiency of learning in a formative assessment. We show ways that the ISLP model’s learning parameters can be estimated in simulation using Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC), demonstrate a way that the model could be used in the context of adaptive item selection to increase the rate of learning, and estimate the learning parameters in an empirical data analysis using the ISLP. In the simulation studies, the one-parameter logistic model was used as the measurement model to generate random response data with various test lengths and sample sizes. Ability growth was modeled with a few variations of the ISLP model, and it was verified that the parameters were accurately recovered. Secondly, we generated data using the linear logistic test model with known Q-matrix structure for the item difficulties. Using a two-step procedure gave very comparable results for the estimation of the learning parameters even when item difficulties were unknown. The potential benefit of using an adaptive selection method in conjunction with the ISLP model was shown by comparing total improvement in the examinees’ ability parameter to two other methods of item selection that do not utilize this growth model. If the ISLP holds, adaptive item selection consistently led to larger improvements over the other methods. A real data application of the ISLP was given to illustrate its use in a spatial reasoning study designed to promote learning. In this study, interventions were given after each block of ten items to increase ability. Learning parameters were estimated using MCMC.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-21-2023 06:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231193096?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Constructing an Educational “Quality” Crisis: (E)quality Politics and Racialization Beyond Target Beneficiaries</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this critical, political discourse analysis, we trace how two concepts, equity and quality, became discursively linked and contested in the administration of postsecondary education policy over time (1968–1994)—a developmental process we refer to as (e)quality politics. By engaging in a historical analysis, we investigate (a) the racialized political origins and discursive processes by which arguments over educational “quality” are advanced as part of an antiequity policy paradigm and (b) how this paradigm reinscribes racial inequity into administrative and organizational action over time. We illustrate how, once an (e)quality politics paradigm is established, racialized policy designs can persist, even in the absence of explicit references to racialized social constructions of target populations in later periods of policy development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-21-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231189478?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On the Shoulders of a Perfect Stranger: Knowledge Gap About the Indigenous Sámi in the Finnish Teacher Education Curriculum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-21-2023 02:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2249292?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Worlds and words: entangling mathematics, language, and context in newcomer classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This work studies mathematics word problems’ use in a classroom of recent immigrants, or newcomers, to a United States public elementary school. I study how word problems foster the recontextualization of mathematical concepts in a lived reality experienced by newcomer students in their new cultural and educational setting. In this study’s setting language plays a significant role in the process of meaning-making. I describe how language use in word problems remains intertwined with mathematics instruction. This opens a space for questioning word problems’ purpose and role in multilingual classrooms, and I highlight how the creative process of co-constructing problems’ meaning in this context can expand notions of genre applied to word problems. Throughout I adopt a theorization of translanguaging as a language practice and apply it in problem discussion. This helps probe how language use impacts students’ ways of understanding and utilizing mathematical concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-20-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01516-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fostering a growth mindset in secondary mathematics classrooms in the Netherlands</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-19-2023 12:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2241433?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The landscape of US elementary mathematics teacher education: course requirements for mathematics content and methods</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The adequate preparation of future teachers of mathematics is critical, requiring sufficient opportunities to develop both pedagogical skill and content knowledge. Yet, despite new recommendations for mathematics teacher preparation, we know little about the landscape of course-based learning opportunities in US elementary teacher education programs. To what extent do US elementary teacher education programs meet the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Standards for Preparing Teachers of Mathematics&lt;/em&gt; outlined by the Association of Mathematics Teacher Educators (AMTE) for mathematics content and methods courses? Based on an a priori power analysis, we gathered a random sample of 291 higher education institutions. Within these institutions, we analyzed 736 programs, including Bachelor’s, Master’s, and Credential programs. We found that overwhelmingly US elementary teacher education programs do not meet the aspirations outlined in the AMTE standards, with Master’s and Credential programs and those covering all elementary grades particularly falling short. Potential explanations for these challenges and implications for teacher education program design are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-19-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09593-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Revisiting “Radical Equations: Civil Rights from Mississippi to the Algebra Project&amp;quot; by Robert P. Moses and Charles E. Cobb, Jr.</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-18-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09596-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical knowledge for teaching and mathematics didactic knowledge: a comparative study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper compares and contrasts two approaches that are widely used in the English- and German-speaking discourse on mathematics teacher knowledge: ‘mathematical knowledge for teaching’ and ‘mathematics didactic knowledge’. It is proposed that these constructs are based on distinct theoretical and conceptual positions and origins. Mathematical knowledge for teaching is viewed as a utilitarian-pragmatic approach rooted in English-speaking traditions as it focuses on its use in teaching and represents a practice-based conceptualization of knowledge domains required for mathematics teaching. Mathematics didactic knowledge, on the other hand, is considered normative-descriptive as it is formulated based on didactic principles and broader theoretical perspectives, providing a theory-driven conceptualization of knowledge domains rooted in traditions of German-speaking didactics of mathematics. The paper further highlights similarities and differences in these two constructs through an examination of two central knowledge domains: specialized content knowledge (part of mathematical knowledge for teaching) and subject matter didactic knowledge (part of mathematics didactic knowledge).&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-18-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09598-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Immigrant Generation and Mentors in Educational Attainment</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Social capital, including engagement with mentors, facilitates educational attainment. However, engagement with mentors differs significantly across groups of adolescents with different backgrounds, including an immigrant background. We investigate how immigrant generation predicts adolescents’ engagement with mentors and different types of mentors (i.e., school-based and non-school-based), the association of mentors with educational attainment, and these estimates’ heterogeneity based on the immigrant generation. We analyzed nationally representative Add Health data from N = 11,242 adolescents by using school fixed-effect linear probability models. Results show that adolescents from immigrant generations 1 and 2 were less likely than those from generation 3+ to have a mentor, but there were no significant differences in engaging with school-based mentors. Mentors predicted educational attainment; school-based mentor effects were larger than non-school-based mentor effects. The associations between mentors and college attendance and graduation were largest for first-generation immigrants. Our findings indicate the importance of structures supporting relationship-building and mentorship in schools and wider communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2023 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231190380?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does Institutional Quality Matter for Foreign Direct Investment and Human Development?</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examines the relationship between foreign direct investment (FDI), institutional quality and human development) in host countries from 2002 to 2019, using the Human Development Index [HDI] as the measure of human development. This study utilized a panel dataset of 143 countries, including both developed and developing economies, over a 17-year period. Additionally, the study employed a GMM (generalized method of moments) estimator to address unobservable heterogeneity and simultaneity. This study reveals a significant positive relationship between FDI and human development, with a stronger effect observed in developing countries compared to in developed countries. Notably, the impact of FDI-HDI nexus is larger in countries with moderately high-quality institutions, irrespective of their income level. Furthermore, good governance plays a crucial role in enhancing human development, as developing economies with high governance quality experience a greater impact of FDI on HDI compared to other countries. The findings of this study suggest that attracting FDI can be beneficial for enhancing the HDI, especially in developing countries. Additionally, the study highlights governance as a moderating factor in the relationship between FDI and HDI. Improving governance quality can enhance the positive impact of FDI on human development in host countries, especially in developing countries.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2023 08:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231195798?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Adding Color to My Tears: Toward a Theoretical Framework for Antiblackness in School Discipline</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Persistent racial disparities in students’ disciplinary outcomes have been one of the most concerning educational policy and equity topics for decades. Despite the hypervisibility of Black students in school discipline conversations, research and practice evade a focus on anti-Black racism. In this essay, we draw from Black Critical Theory (BlackCrit) to present a theoretical framework that researchers and educational stakeholders can use to specify, study, and understand antiblackness in school discipline. We outline and discuss six interrelated theoretical constructs of the Antiblackness in School Discipline framework: (a) “Trading Away the Black,” (b) “Whites as Propertied,” (c) Intersecting Blackness, (d) Racial Neoliberalism, (e) La Petite Misère, and (f) Internalized Racism. Examples of studies providing empirical support for these theoretical tenets are also discussed, and suggestions for utilizing this framework in scholarship, policy, and practice are also offered.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2023 02:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231191448?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meta-mathematical aspects of definitions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The notion of definition is a central building block of mathematics. In addition to specific definitions, it is desirable that students learn about meta-mathematical aspects of definitions such as their role of classification, and about characteristics of definitions such as arbitrariness. We investigated how such meta-mathematical aspects emerge when students are led to construct a definition such as point of inflection or tangent line, and how the constructing process interacts with meta-mathematical aspects. We used Abstraction in Context as theoretical framework because of its suitability to analyze processes of knowledge construction. We found that meta-mathematical aspects of definitions influence and are influenced by students’ processes of constructing definitions. We argue that awareness of meta-mathematical aspects improves students’ conception of mathematical definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10252-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The racial role of mathematicians and mathematics in maintaining the Israeli military occupation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This essay focuses on the role of mathematics and Israeli mathematicians in serving the Israeli occupation of Gaza and the West Bank, including east Jerusalem, since 1967. It analyzes recently de-classified Israeli archival documents from the period 1967–1969, including minutes of ministerial meetings that discussed how to control the newly conquered people and land as discussed by Shafer Raviv (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Journal of Contemporary History&lt;/em&gt;, 55(1), 161–181, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r29&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Middle Eastern Studies&lt;/em&gt;, 57(2), 342–356, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r30&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/span&gt;) as well as mathematical formulas created 40 years later as part of an Israeli policy to restrict food supplies to the Gaza Strip. It sheds light on the way in which mathematicians and mathematics can be employed to maintain and justify a racialized system of control. Drawing on Bonilla-Silva’s (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;American Sociological Review&lt;/em&gt;, 62(3), 465–480, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r7&quot;&gt;1997&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Journal of Political Ideologies&lt;/em&gt;, 8(1), 63–82, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r8&quot;&gt;2003&lt;/span&gt;) racialized social systems approach, the essay argues that mathematics and mathematicians professionalize and legitimize the dominant racial discourse in the Israeli military which, in turn, shapes the social and racial discourse in Israeli society that privileges Israeli Jews over Palestinians.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10255-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The professional identities of prospective mathematics teachers who teach through programming</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As has been the case in many countries around the world, the new Norwegian curriculum from 2020 included programming as part of mathematics education. However, little is known about how prospective teachers perceive this addition in regard to their developing professional identities. When the results from an electronic survey of 394 prospective teachers showed unexpected findings, five of the subjects were asked to participate in a focus group interview in order to explore some of these results. The focus group interview was conducted to understand how prospective teachers considered the past, present and future aspects of their professional identities as teachers of mathematics through programming. The results reveal that, although the prospective teachers had little experience of programming, they were positive regarding its implementation in mathematics lessons because they identified themselves as digital natives; they therefore believed that learning to program would be easy. They aligned themselves with their students, as masters of technology, in contrast to their future colleagues, whom they implicitly described as digital immigrants. The findings of this study have implications for teacher education. Even if the prospective teachers have a positive attitude toward programming and consider themselves digitally competent, a limited understanding of how programming can be integrated into their mathematics teaching will affect the identities that they see for themselves as teachers who teach mathematics through programming.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-16-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09594-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reflective Goal-setting Improves Academic Performance in Teacher and Business Education: A Large-scale Field Experiment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-15-2023 12:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2231440?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Long-Term Effects of Grade Retention: Evidence on Persistence through High School and College</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-15-2023 03:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2240323?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effect of Worked Examples and Self-Explanation Prompts on Mathematics Standardized Assessments</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-15-2023 02:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2243254?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>High-Stakes Testing and Educational Careers: Exploiting the Differences in Cutoffs Between Test Recommendations in The Netherlands</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-15-2023 01:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2242342?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Shifts in student attention on algorithmic and creative practice tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In mathematics classrooms, it is common practice to work through a series of comparable tasks provided in a textbook. A central question in mathematics education is if tasks should be accompanied with solution methods, or if students should construct the solutions themselves. To explore the impact of these two task designs on student behavior during repetitive practice, an eye-tracking study was conducted with 50 upper secondary and university students. Their eye movements were analyzed to study how the two groups shifted their gaze both within and across 10 task sets. The results show that when a solution method was present, the students reread this every time they solved the task, while only giving minute attention to the illustration that carried information supporting mathematical understanding. Students who practiced with tasks without a solution method seemed to construct a solution method by observing the illustration, which later could be retrieved from memory, making this method more efficient in the long run. We discuss the implications for teaching and how tasks without solution methods can increase student focus on important mathematical properties.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-15-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10250-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Action Researching for Transformations is Anti Patriarchy Work</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-14-2023 08:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231195928?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educational neuroscience for literacy teachers: Research-backed methods and practices for effective reading instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-14-2023 05:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2244787?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The NREA Rural Research Agenda 2022-2027: An Examination of the Research Process and Findings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-14-2023 02:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2238527?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/31/3&quot;&gt;Volume 31, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, July 2023, Page 405-408&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-13-2023 06:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2233270?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
