<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Short-Term Effects of the Shift From Prior-Year to Current-Year Enrollment on School Inputs in Arizona</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Arizona shifted to using current-year enrollment, instead of prior-year enrollment, as the basis for determining state aid for school districts following the passage of Arizona Education Finance Amendment (AEFA) in 2017. This study examines the short-term effects of AEFA implementation on school inputs—namely, expenditures and district personnel, particularly teachers. We find that the average district does not seem to respond to AEFA. However, our heterogeneity analyses reveal that the highest-income districts significantly reduce more inputs than the lowest-income districts in response to AEFA. The differential impact between these two groups is most evident in instructional expenditures, administration expenditures, total full-time equivalent teachers, and particularly teachers with 1–5 years of experience.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-14-2023 05:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231210281?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Team teachers’ emotions and their antecedents in the classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2023 09:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2293634?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Offer It and They Will Come? An Investigation of the Factors Associated With the Uptake of School-Sponsored Resources</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In response to economic distress, schools are increasingly serving as providers and distributors of social service resources. However, even when schools offer resources that respond to needs, they struggle to attain high levels of uptake. We examine the family-level correlates of participation in school-sponsored resources during the early months of the COVID-19 pandemic and find that uptake increases with economic need. In addition, net of need, families who report maintaining communication with parents of their children’s classmates take up more resources; and take-up of key meal and digital technology resources is associated with higher levels of take-up of other resources. These findings contribute to efforts to reposition schools as social service hubs by highlighting promising practices to improve resource uptake.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2023 08:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231209231?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2023 07:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231218009?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do STEM Students Vote?12</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Pundits, politicians, and academics have long worried about potentially low rates of civic participation among STEM-oriented students. Does studying STEM actually decrease the odds that young people will be actively involved in democracy? To answer this question, we created a dataset of over 23 million students in the United States, matched to national validated voting records. This novel dataset is the largest known individual-level dataset in the United States, connecting high school and college students to voting outcomes. It also contains a rich set of demographic and academic variables, to account for many of the common issues related to students’ selection into STEM coursework. We consider two measures of STEM participation: Advanced Placement (AP) exam taking in high school and college major. Using both measures, we find that, across model specifications, the estimated relationships between STEM and voting are small in magnitude—about the same effect size as a single get-out-the-vote mailer. Our analyses demonstrate that, on average, marginally more STEM coursework in high school and college does not contribute noticeably to the low voting rates among young people in the United States.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2023 06:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231200232?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do New Forms of Reading Pay Off? A Meta-Analysis on the Relationship Between Leisure Digital Reading Habits and Text Comprehension</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Previous research has evidenced a strong positive relationship between leisure print reading habits and reading comprehension across the lifespan. The rapid evolution of new forms of leisure digital reading could modify such a relationship. This meta-analysis extends previous research by analyzing the relationship between leisure digital reading habits and reading comprehension. We analyzed 40 effect sizes using multilevel analysis. Data involved 469,564 participants from studies published between 2000 and 2022. The average effect size reflects a small significant effect on reading comprehension (r = .055), which contrasts with the medium size effects found in the literature related to print reading habits and comprehension. This relationship is significantly moderated by the reader’s educational stage. At early stages (primary and middle school) negative relationships are observed between leisure digital reading and text comprehension, while at later stages (high school and university) the relationship turns positive. We highlight the different contributions that reading modalities and technological contexts have on our reading comprehension, especially across the lifespan. In sum, leisure digital reading does not seem to pay off in terms of reading comprehension, at least, as much as traditional print reading does.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2023 05:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231216463?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Theorizing virtual counterspaces: how Latina graduate students build community online</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2023 02:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2292509?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers pose and design context-based mathematics tasks: what can be learned from product evolution?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study proposes a model of several dimensions through which products of teachers’ context-based mathematics problem posing (PP) can be modified. The dimensions are Correctness, Authenticity, Task Assortment (consisting of Mathematical Diversity, Multiple Data Representations, Question–Answer Format, Precision-Approximation, and Generalization), Task Flow, and Student Involvement. A study was conducted in the context of a professional development (PD) program in which eight secondary school teachers iteratively designed 22 context-based mathematics tasks. Using the variation theory of learning as a theoretical framework and qualitative content analysis methodology, we compared different versions of the same tasks, focusing on items participants added or revised. To demonstrate the usability of the resulting semi-hierarchical model, we apply it to characterize the teachers’ final products of context-based PP. We found that most items teachers composed did not deviate from what we call the “common item form”—items that require numeric, exact, particular-case-related, and close-form answers without involving students in decision-making. Our findings may inform teacher educators and researchers on planning and implementing context-based mathematics task development by teachers in PD.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10271-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Extrema points: concept images, mis-in and mis-out examples</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reports on students’ conceptions of minima points. Written assignments and individual interviews uncovered salient, concept images, as well as erroneous &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;mis-out examples&lt;/em&gt; that mistakenly regard examples as non-examples and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;mis-in examples&lt;/em&gt; that mistakenly grant non-examples the status of examples. We used Tall and Vinner’s theoretical framework to analyze the students’ errors that were rooted in mathematical and in real-life contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10273-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating Program Enhancement Strategies for Remedial Tutoring: A Cluster-Randomized Control Trial With Syrian Refugee Students in Lebanon</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Despite widespread enthusiasm for remedial education programming with refugee populations, there is little rigorous evidence on how to design and implement such programs. We employ a cluster-randomized design of non-equivalent treatment groups to test the impact of access to two types of program enhancement: longer program duration and the addition of skill-targeted social and emotional learning (SEL) activities for Syrian refugees enrolled in Lebanese public schools. We find that, compared to 10 weeks of programming, 26 weeks marginally increases students’ literacy skills (ES = 0.04) and significantly improves behavioral regulation (ES = 0.31), but students reported less positive perceptions of their public school environment (ES= −0.83 to −0.89) and remedial tutoring site (ES= −0.15 to −0.24). We also find that the addition of skill-targeted SEL activities to 26 weeks of programming results in higher student reports of school-related stress compared to programming without skill-targeted activities (ES = 0.21). Implications for program and policy are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2023 12:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231209268?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modelling as expert-guidance during teacher practitioner research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2023 02:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2282370?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Complex Terrain of Equity for Multilingual Learners in K–12 Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The field of multilingual learner education has become increasingly complex, with longstanding efforts focused on promoting access to multilingual learners being criticized for failing to transform systems responsible for these students’ marginalization. This essay brings clarity to the complex terrain of equity for multilingual learners in K–12 education by highlighting how conceptions of equity as access and as transformation underpin vexing issues in the field related to (a) how learners are categorized, (b) what is being learned, and (c) what instructional arrangements facilitate learning. The essay closes by proposing ways forward across research, policy, and practice toward shaping a field that is mutually engaged yet productively diverse as well as better positioned to foster interdisciplinary dialogue with other fields.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2023 01:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231215345?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical modelling as a vehicle for eliciting algorithmic thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Developing students’ competence in algorithmic thinking is emerging as an objective of mathematics education, but despite its inclusion in mathematics curricula around the world, research into students’ algorithmic thinking seems to be falling behind in this curriculum reform. The aim of this study was to investigate how the mathematical modelling process can be used as a vehicle for eliciting students’ algorithmic thinking. To achieve this aim, a generative study was conducted using task-based interviews with year 12 students (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 8) to examine how they used the mathematical modelling process to design an algorithm that solved a minimum spanning tree problem. I observed each students’ modelling process and analysed how the task elicited the cognitive skills of algorithmic thinking. The findings showed that the students leveraged their mathematical modelling competencies to formulate a model of the problem using abstraction and decomposition, designed their algorithms by devising a fundamental operation to transform inputs into outputs during the working mathematically transition, and debugged their algorithms during the validating transition. Implications for practice are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10275-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Development of Prospective Elementary Teachers´ Beliefs About Mathematics During Their First Semester at University, and the Impact of Inquiry-Based Tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;An important aim of teacher education in mathematics, especially for prospective elementary teachers, is to develop desirable beliefs about mathematics that positively affect teachers’ professional practice. Thus, we subdivide our study into two parts. First, we examine whether, and how, beliefs of prospective elementary teachers develop in their first semester. In this part, we consider beliefs as relatively stable constructs (Liljedahl et al., in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Nordic Studies in Education&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;(3–4), 101-118 &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r23&quot;&gt;2012&lt;/span&gt;) and examine whether the first semester stimulus is strong enough to change these beliefs. Second, we examine a teaching approach based on inquiry-based tasks for first-semester prospective elementary teachers. The tasks encourage prospective elementary teachers to actively engage in mathematics by exploring basic mathematical structures, relations, and patterns. To assess the two parts, we conducted a pre-post-test study. We collected data at two universities with different teaching approaches (inquiry-based teaching approach and classic teaching approach). We administered a questionnaire both at the beginning and at the end of the semester to measure the beliefs changes of prospective elementary teachers. The study is considered a natural experiment because students were not randomly selected. Comparability for university-specific data sets was achieved through the procedure of propensity score matching. The results suggest that the first semester of prospective elementary teachers contributes to changes in their beliefs about the nature of mathematics. In addition, the data provide evidence that inquiry-based teaching approaches may contribute to the desirable development of certain beliefs of prospective elementary teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00232-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Graders’ Definitions, Generalizations, and Justifications of Even and Odd Numbers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we explore the following research questions: How do first-grade students define even and odd numbers? What types of justifications do they use to support their generalizations using these definitions? We report the ways in which first-grade students define even and odd numbers and how they justify generalizations that use their definitions. While we focus on definitions and explanations of those definitions, the targeted underlying thinking practices at hand are generalizing and justifying. The instruction used in this study was aimed at supporting students in providing definitions, and then reasoning with their definitions by using them in new problem contexts in which they were asked to generalize a relationship about sums of evens and odds or justify that relationship. Our study shows that students shifted from using pattern-based definitions of parity to using structure-based definitions of parity. When justifying the parity of sums of even and odd numbers, students shifted away from using examples through empirical arguments towards using generic examples and in some cases a general argument.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-12-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00297-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ensuring Educational Continuity in the Midst of Crisis: Policy and Planning During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;As the COVID-19 crisis disrupted schooling, recovery efforts in California included the adoption of Senate Bill (SB) 98, which mandated local educational agencies to complete Learning Continuity and Attendance Plans (LCPs). These plans act as critical snapshots of sensemaking and local policy implementation during crisis; however, their details have yet to be explored statewide. Through a multiphase, mixed methods approach, this study examines the legislative requirements of a state-level policy that orchestrated large-scale local planning. Results reveal that SB-98 recombined prior educational routines to fit the pandemic context. Moreover, district plans generally adhered to policy guidance and described a range of resources to support students. However, the limited details contained in most plans—particularly about the actions and services for students that may need additional supports—proffer suggestive evidence of local capacity and will during the global pandemic and the implications for those seeking to implement similar policy measures.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2023 12:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231215488?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Free Market Logic Fails in Schooling—And What It Means for the Role of Government</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Market-based policies, especially school vouchers, are expanding rapidly and shifting students out of traditional public schools. This article broadens, deepens, and updates prior critiques of the free market logic in five ways. First, although prior articles have pointed to some of the conditions necessary for efficient market functioning, I provide a more comprehensive list. Second, with an up-to-date literature review, I show that all of these conditions fail to hold to an unusual extent in schooling relative to other markets. Third, because of these failures, I argue that the most potent critique of the free market approach to schooling comes from the intellectual home of markets—economics. Fourth, I show that the issues leading to inefficiency are the same ones leading to inequity. Fifth, I argue that the analysis points to specific roles for government that go well beyond those included in new universal school voucher policies but are also narrower than the roles of government encompassed in traditional public education. For these reasons, the current policy direction is off track and apparently inconsistent with the main criteria on which we evaluate education policy and even with the values that voucher advocates profess.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2023 11:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231216953?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engaging with Engagement: Interrogating Preservice Teachers’ Theories of Engagement in Their Literacy Planning and Reflection</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2023 07:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2293184?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Applying an Equity Framework to Develop Inclusive Visions of STEM Teaching: Honoring the Voices of Students with Dis/Abilities</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2023 07:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2290250?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A call to reshape our desires: contesting the “inevitable answer” of inclusion within empire</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2023 06:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2292513?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of an Undergraduate Led Mathematics Summer Camp on High School Students’ Interest in Mathematics and Mathematics Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2023 06:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2291944?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Core Requirements, Structured Flexibility, and Local Judgment: Balancing Adherence and Adaptation in the Design and Implementation of District-Wide Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Professional development (PD) for teachers is a ubiquitous feature of the American educational landscape. Yet we know little about how districts navigate the variation in teacher learning needs when designing and implementing district-wide PD programs. In this paper, we describe how the District of Columbia Public Schools implemented an ambitious PD program called LEAP (LEarning together to Advance our Practice). Aligned with best practices, LEAP consisted of weekly group learning in content-specific teams, followed by individualized coaching support, all guided by a district-provided professional learning curriculum. We capitalize on both quantitative and qualitative data to understand how the program was implemented and how the district’s implementation efforts shaped what happened on the ground. Finally, we highlight implications for other districts interested in implementing complex PD.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2023 05:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231210285?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of Race to the Top on Teacher Qualifications, Work Environments, and Job Attitudes</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We estimate the effects of Race to the Top (RTTT) on teacher qualifications, work environments, and job attitudes. Drawing on the Schools and Staffing Survey and the National Teacher and Principal Survey, we create a nationally representative data set of public school teachers from 1988 to 2018. We adopt an event study difference-in-differences research design to estimate the dynamic effect of RTTT on several teacher outcomes. We find evidence that, following RTTT, teachers were more worried about job security relative to prereform years. We find smaller and less consistent evidence of a relationship between RTTT and decreased teacher certification levels and increased levels of cooperation with colleagues.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231210291?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Engineering Design-Based Integrated STEM in Rural Contexts: Nurturing Future Designers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;There is a notable shift towards prioritizing the teaching of engineering design within K-12 education, coupled with a strong recommendation for engineering design-based integrated STEM education. This approach underscores the sharing of science and engineering practices as a means to facilitate the learning of various STEM disciplines. Nonetheless, the implementation of integrated STEM education in rural schools poses challenges due to constrained resources and a shortage of high-quality programs. To present a tangible instance of design-based integrated STEM education within a rural setting, this study presents a model lesson that showcases the integration of interdisciplinary problem-solving skills within a genuine real-world context. This study examined how teacher collaboration for engineering and science shared practices influenced students’ design process. Concurrent Think-Aloud (CTA) protocol data and design sketches produced by the student design teams during the protocol sessions display how they elicited their design thinking skills and STEM domain knowledge acquired from the integrated STEM lesson in an engineering design task. This study found that the students learned the model lesson through the fully integrated instruction between students and teachers utilized more balanced design cognitions than the silo approach of integration. The findings highlight that the utilization of engineering design in K-12 education to cultivate integrated problem-solving skills should be accompanied by domain-integrated instructions for effective implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-11-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00290-1</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
