<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ Understanding of Riemann Sums and Double Integrals: The Case of Task Design in APOS Theory</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, we investigate students’ understanding of the relation between a double integral of a continuous function over a rectangle and the corresponding Riemann sums. To do so, we explore the relation between (1) a proposed model (genetic decomposition) of mental constructions that students may do to understand the relation between Riemann sums and double integrals, (2) tasks designed to help students make these constructions, and (3) the results of semi-structured interviews with eleven students who completed the tasks. We focus on the construction differences between students who engaged in tasks designed according to the genetic decomposition and those in a previously studied lecture-based course. The study aimed to underscore the task&#39;s effect on students&#39; learning in order to refine the genetic decomposition if needed. This study contributes a set of tasks that enable students to relate Riemann sums and double integrals. The results showed that students using the proposed materials in class and a collaborative didactical strategy provided evidence of constructing the structures proposed in the genetic decomposition. The tasks are based on a genetic decomposition, so the study also contributes by showing that it is an effective model to guide instruction. The constructions inferred from students’ work are discussed in detail and compared to those proposed in the genetic decomposition and those resulting from previous research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00250-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estimating the Reliability of Skill Transitions in Longitudinal Diagnostic Classification Models</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Diagnostic classification models (DCMs) have grown in popularity as stakeholders increasingly desire actionable information related to students’ skill competencies. Longitudinal DCMs offer a psychometric framework for providing estimates of students’ proficiency status transitions over time. For both cross-sectional and longitudinal DCMs, it is important that researchers estimate and report reliability so stakeholders and end-users can evaluate the trustworthiness of results. Over the past decade, researchers have developed and applied various metrics for reliability in the DCM framework. This study extends these metrics onto the longitudinal DCM context and consists of three parts: (a) the theory and development of the new longitudinal DCM reliability metrics, (b) a simulation study to examine the performance of the developed metrics and establish thresholds, and (c) an empirical data analysis to illustrate an application of the developed metrics. This paper concludes with a discussion of our recommendations for applying the developed metrics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 11:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241256032?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measurement and Uncertainty Preserving Parametric Modeling for Continuous Latent Variables With Discrete Indicators and External Variables</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Research in education and behavioral sciences often involves the use of latent variable models that are related to indicators, as well as related to covariates or outcomes. Such models are subject to interpretational confounding, which occurs when fitting the model with covariates or outcomes alters the results for the measurement model. This has received attention in models for continuous observable variables but to date has not been examined in the context of discrete variables. This work demonstrates that interpretational confounding can occur in models for discrete variables, and develops a multistage Bayesian estimation approach to deal with this problem. The key features of this approach are that it is (a) measurement preserving, in that it precludes the possibility of interpretational confounding, and (b) uncertainty preserving, in that the uncertainty from the earlier stage of estimating the measurement model is propagated to the second stage of estimating the relations between the latent variable(s) and any covariates or outcomes. Previous work on these methods had only considered models for continuous observed variables, and software was limited to models with a single latent variable and either covariates or outcomes. This work extends the approach and software to a more general class of solutions, including discrete variables, illustrating the procedures with analyses of real data. Functions for conducting the analyses in widely available software are provided.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241254348?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What it Takes to Be an Advocate: Teachers’ Perceptions of Their Strengths and Challenges</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 08:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2383744?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Catholic Schools in the Marketplace: Changing and Enduring Religious Identities</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 08:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2381393?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Charting the Path to the Outsourcing of Discrimination Through School Choice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 07:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2381378?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Black Teachers Matter</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Black teachers are critical resources for children and schools. In experimental data, I document large effects of Black upper-elementary teachers on the self-efficacy (0.9 SD) and classroom engagement (0.7 SD) of their Black but not non-Black students, potentially driven by role modeling. Black teachers also benefit the test scores (0.2 SD) and absences (over 20% decrease) of all students—no matter their race/ethnicity—that often persist years later in high school. Furthermore, Black teachers bring unique mindsets and practices to their work (differentiated instruction, growth mindset beliefs, well-organized classrooms) that mediate a moderate to large share of effects on student outcomes. These findings help bridge the quantitative race/ethnicity-matching literature with theoretical discussion and qualitative exploration on why Black teachers matter.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 05:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241261336?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Returns to Experience for School Principals</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Despite increasing recognition of the importance of high-quality school leadership, we know remarkably little about principal skill development. Using administrative data from Tennessee, Oregon, and New York City, we estimate the returns to principal experience as measured by student outcomes, teacher hiring and retention patterns, and teacher and supervisor ratings of principals. The typical principal leads a school for only 3 to 5 years and leaves the principalship after 6 to 7 years. We find little evidence that school performance improves as principals gain experience, despite substantial improvement in supervisor ratings. Our results suggest that strategies intended to increase principal retention are unlikely to improve school outcomes absent more comprehensive efforts to strengthen the link between principal skill development and student and school outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241266216?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We Still Have a Long Way to Go”: How State Education Leaders’ Understanding and Engagement Shapes English Learner Identification of Indigenous Students</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Federal law defines English learner (EL) eligibility differently for Indigenous, compared to non-Indigenous, students, allowing for broader entry into the EL category, along with its accompanying resources and services. We interviewed EL leaders from 25 state departments of education to learn about their level of understanding of the differentiated definition and their work to interpret and implement it. Drawing upon and expanding recent conceptual frameworks, we explored how EL leaders’ knowledge about and engagement with EL constituents influence their ability to interpret and implement policy in equity-expansive ways. We found that many EL leaders had little understanding of the federal law and weak engagement with Indigenous Tribes and communities, both of which limited their work. In states where leaders had deeper knowledge and engagement, they were more actively interpreting and implementing federal law, particularly with the aim of increasing Indigenous EL-classified students’ access to heritage language and culturally-sustaining programs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 05:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241263849?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating Thirdspace: Indigenous Learning Lab to Transform a School Discipline System</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Racial disproportionality in school discipline is an enduring systemic problem. This study is based on a collaboration with 14 school stakeholders: American Indian students, parents, community members, and educators at a high school in a community-driven problem-solving process called Indigenous Learning Lab (ILL). ILL members addressed the root causes of the racialized school discipline and created a new school discipline system. Using critical geography and decolonizing methodology as the theoretical and analytical framework, this study aimed to unpack the emergence of Thirdspace—a space of resistance, possibilities, and hopes—in ILL to address enduring racial disproportionality. Members challenged race-neutrality of data sense-making, mapped out dystopia, revitalized American Indian epistemology, and mapped out a real utopian vision of schooling.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 04:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241260322?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of Educational Technology Interventions on Literacy in Elementary School: A Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Educational technology is ubiquitous, and educational technology interventions often target literacy. However, there is insufficient information about the effects of these interventions on literacy outcomes in elementary school. Therefore, we conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of quasi-experimental and experimental studies published between 2010 and 2023 that evaluated the effects of educational technology interventions on the literacy outcomes of K–5 students. The meta-analysis across 119 studies from 105 manuscripts revealed positive effects for decoding (0.33), language comprehension (0.30), reading comprehension (0.23), and writing proficiency (0.81). However, when isolating effects for standardized measures, effects for decoding (0.23), language comprehension (0.12), reading comprehension (0.14), and writing proficiency (0.34) were reduced. Moderator analyses suggested that effects can depend on outcome, intervention, and participant characteristics. In the discussion, we describe and contextualize findings and call for more research to further unpack moderator effects. We also discuss possible implications for practice and policy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 01:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241261073?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promoting Numeracy in University and Beyond</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teaching and even designing a numeracy course in university is certainly not like teaching a mathematics course. Curriculum, goals, focus, examples, prerequisites, and especially students are all very, very different. This is why, in this commentary, I explore questions such as what is numeracy, who is numerate, why teach numeracy, what is the difference between a mathematics task and a numeracy task, and how to create a numeracy curriculum. I share my work and observations in the numeracy course that I have taught. Discussions and examples are provided for instructors to gain a better grasp on how to think about and teach numeracy and to help their students develop and improve numeracy skills. My perspectives are drawn from my own personal experiences teaching mathematics and numeracy and writing numeracy tasks, as well as research and collaborations with both mathematics and numeracy educators.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00324-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Synthesis of Research on Principal Internships</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The internship is a crucial component of principal preparation. This systematic research review aims to build on two prior syntheses of existing research on principal internships. We employed an exhaustive review of five search engines for empirical studies on principal internships in the United States between 2010 and 2023. Our search yielded 92 studies. We extracted key characteristics from each study as well as the main findings. We distributed the findings across the following themes: policy, program redesign, program value, diverse perspectives, coaching and mentoring, internship activities, and internship effects. The literature on internship policy, diverse perspectives, and internship activities is relatively limited. In contrast, there was much more research on program redesign and value, coaching and mentoring, and internship effects. We conclude the review by comparing our findings to two prior research reviews and offering recommendations for future research and practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 11:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241261984?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effectiveness of Flipped Classrooms for K–12 Students: Evidence From a Three-Level Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Flipped classrooms (FCs) in K–12 schools are growing in popularity. However, previous studies have reported inconsistent findings on the effects of FCs, and the conditions under which FCs are effective remain unclear. This three-level meta-analysis synthesized the effects of FCs versus traditional classrooms (TCs) on various learning domains among K–12 students based on 129 studies with 399 effect sizes (N = 12,727). The results revealed that FCs have a significant positive effect on K–12 students’ overall performance (without outliers: g = 0.53 [0.44,0.62], 95% prediction interval [–0.60, 1.66]) and on both the cognitive domain and the affective domain. Moderator analyses showed that region, measured outcome, outcome dilution, instructor equivalence, and publication type were significant predictors. In addition, the educational context and research methodology characteristics accounted for a significant proportion of the variability in overall effects. These findings provide valuable evidence-based recommendations for future research and practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 11:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241261732?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participatory action research: A tool to develop occupational health and safety education for new immigrant workers</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Immigrant workers are a growing segment of Canada’s labour force, essential to its economy and society. Yet, they face occupational health and safety (OHS) challenges due to communication barriers, limited training, scarce resources, and workplace discrimination. This study sought to design learning resources to enhance the understanding of OHS in Canadian workplaces among new immigrant workers, drawing from their personal experiences. Through participatory action research, nine immigrant workers took part in six online sessions over three months, where they identified problems, discussed education, reflected, and decided on actions. Key issues raised included inadequate training, unawareness of OHS rights, hesitation in reporting safety concerns due to fear of backlash, and facing psychological threats like discrimination. This research illuminated the complex interplay of cultural and communication differences in OHS. Consequently, five education modules, rooted in real-world insights, were developed, emphasizing the significance of OHS, psychological risks, Canadian workplace norms, communication, and vital resources. This PAR successfully developed OHS learning modules, which not only tackle challenges and provide solutions for new immigrant workers but also craft with cultural sensitivity and lived expertise. These tools are tailored to equip new immigrant workers with the knowledge and confidence needed to enhance their OHS practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 08:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241267895?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“He’s Probably the Only Teacher I’ve Actually Learned From”: Marginalized Students’ Experiences With and Self-Perceptions of High School Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Understanding how marginalized students experience and perceive mathematics is critical to achieving the goal of inclusive and equitable math pedagogy. We report on 67 focus groups with 251 predominantly Black high schoolers experiencing economic marginalization in the Southern United States and attended to their achievement level and race-gender identities. Students often shared concerns about their teacher’s math knowledge for teaching and effectiveness in supporting academic success. Their self-perceptions of math identities varied, and students often did not value advanced math even when they expressed career interests that require advanced math. We discuss practical implications for supporting the math development of marginalized high schoolers, including centering the needs and strengths of Black girls, and propose an expanded inclusive and equitable pedagogical framework.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 05:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241266242?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Socioeconomic Differences Among Low-Income and Racially Minoritized Students Shape Their Engagement and Access in School Choice Systems?</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Socioeconomic differences among low-income and racially minoritized students may be consequential for understanding the dynamics of school choice—especially in high-poverty and racially segregated urban contexts that are often targeted by school choice policies. Yet school choice research largely focuses on differences between groups and relies on measures that broadly categorize students as low-income or not. Drawing on parent interviews in Detroit, this study describes socioeconomic differences among low-income and racially minoritized families and examines how those differences relate to their engagement in the school choice process. While families faced a similar landscape of choice, relied on similar types of resources, and did not have drastically different preferences, relative socioeconomic disadvantages translated to more constrained access and engagement in school choice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241263307?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sustaining quantitatively-grounded meanings for definite integrals in high school calculus</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 02:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2384689?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading program curriculum reform: reflections on challenges and successes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 02:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2385410?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparison of online, blended and face-to-face modes for in-service discipline-specific professional development in primary science</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2024 12:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2385047?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Agency in negotiating partnerships in initial teacher education: shifting sands</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2024 10:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2384477?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using the TIMSS curriculum model to develop a framework for coherence and its role in developing mathematical connections</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2024 04:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2371026?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measuring and Visualising Space in Elementary Mathematics Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2024 01:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2384012?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ Beliefs About Language Diversity and Multilingual Learners: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers’ beliefs influence their teaching practices. Given the U.S. Secretary of Education’s push to increase multilingualism, this systematic literature review examines teachers’ beliefs about language diversity and multilingual learners in relation to teacher experiences, teaching practices, and external factors. Using 17 search terms, we searched seven databases for empirical, peer-reviewed studies that examined K–12 teachers’ language beliefs. We analyzed 63 studies that met our criteria using a framework of teacher beliefs. Our findings indicate that researchers use myriad terms to capture the participating teachers’ beliefs. These terms could be grouped into dominant language, subtractive, additive, and pluralist beliefs. We also found connections between teachers’ beliefs on one side and their life experiences, instructional practices, and external factors, such as high-stakes tests and school contexts, on the other side. We added teachers’ beliefs about families, content and knowledge, and diversity to the framework, as well as external factors.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 10:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241257533?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
