<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We Still Have a Long Way to Go”: How State Education Leaders’ Understanding and Engagement Shapes English Learner Identification of Indigenous Students</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Federal law defines English learner (EL) eligibility differently for Indigenous, compared to non-Indigenous, students, allowing for broader entry into the EL category, along with its accompanying resources and services. We interviewed EL leaders from 25 state departments of education to learn about their level of understanding of the differentiated definition and their work to interpret and implement it. Drawing upon and expanding recent conceptual frameworks, we explored how EL leaders’ knowledge about and engagement with EL constituents influence their ability to interpret and implement policy in equity-expansive ways. We found that many EL leaders had little understanding of the federal law and weak engagement with Indigenous Tribes and communities, both of which limited their work. In states where leaders had deeper knowledge and engagement, they were more actively interpreting and implementing federal law, particularly with the aim of increasing Indigenous EL-classified students’ access to heritage language and culturally-sustaining programs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 05:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241263849?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating Thirdspace: Indigenous Learning Lab to Transform a School Discipline System</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Racial disproportionality in school discipline is an enduring systemic problem. This study is based on a collaboration with 14 school stakeholders: American Indian students, parents, community members, and educators at a high school in a community-driven problem-solving process called Indigenous Learning Lab (ILL). ILL members addressed the root causes of the racialized school discipline and created a new school discipline system. Using critical geography and decolonizing methodology as the theoretical and analytical framework, this study aimed to unpack the emergence of Thirdspace—a space of resistance, possibilities, and hopes—in ILL to address enduring racial disproportionality. Members challenged race-neutrality of data sense-making, mapped out dystopia, revitalized American Indian epistemology, and mapped out a real utopian vision of schooling.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-31-2024 04:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241260322?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Synthesis of Research on Principal Internships</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The internship is a crucial component of principal preparation. This systematic research review aims to build on two prior syntheses of existing research on principal internships. We employed an exhaustive review of five search engines for empirical studies on principal internships in the United States between 2010 and 2023. Our search yielded 92 studies. We extracted key characteristics from each study as well as the main findings. We distributed the findings across the following themes: policy, program redesign, program value, diverse perspectives, coaching and mentoring, internship activities, and internship effects. The literature on internship policy, diverse perspectives, and internship activities is relatively limited. In contrast, there was much more research on program redesign and value, coaching and mentoring, and internship effects. We conclude the review by comparing our findings to two prior research reviews and offering recommendations for future research and practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 11:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241261984?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effectiveness of Flipped Classrooms for K–12 Students: Evidence From a Three-Level Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Flipped classrooms (FCs) in K–12 schools are growing in popularity. However, previous studies have reported inconsistent findings on the effects of FCs, and the conditions under which FCs are effective remain unclear. This three-level meta-analysis synthesized the effects of FCs versus traditional classrooms (TCs) on various learning domains among K–12 students based on 129 studies with 399 effect sizes (N = 12,727). The results revealed that FCs have a significant positive effect on K–12 students’ overall performance (without outliers: g = 0.53 [0.44,0.62], 95% prediction interval [–0.60, 1.66]) and on both the cognitive domain and the affective domain. Moderator analyses showed that region, measured outcome, outcome dilution, instructor equivalence, and publication type were significant predictors. In addition, the educational context and research methodology characteristics accounted for a significant proportion of the variability in overall effects. These findings provide valuable evidence-based recommendations for future research and practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 11:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241261732?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participatory action research: A tool to develop occupational health and safety education for new immigrant workers</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Immigrant workers are a growing segment of Canada’s labour force, essential to its economy and society. Yet, they face occupational health and safety (OHS) challenges due to communication barriers, limited training, scarce resources, and workplace discrimination. This study sought to design learning resources to enhance the understanding of OHS in Canadian workplaces among new immigrant workers, drawing from their personal experiences. Through participatory action research, nine immigrant workers took part in six online sessions over three months, where they identified problems, discussed education, reflected, and decided on actions. Key issues raised included inadequate training, unawareness of OHS rights, hesitation in reporting safety concerns due to fear of backlash, and facing psychological threats like discrimination. This research illuminated the complex interplay of cultural and communication differences in OHS. Consequently, five education modules, rooted in real-world insights, were developed, emphasizing the significance of OHS, psychological risks, Canadian workplace norms, communication, and vital resources. This PAR successfully developed OHS learning modules, which not only tackle challenges and provide solutions for new immigrant workers but also craft with cultural sensitivity and lived expertise. These tools are tailored to equip new immigrant workers with the knowledge and confidence needed to enhance their OHS practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 08:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241267895?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“He’s Probably the Only Teacher I’ve Actually Learned From”: Marginalized Students’ Experiences With and Self-Perceptions of High School Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Understanding how marginalized students experience and perceive mathematics is critical to achieving the goal of inclusive and equitable math pedagogy. We report on 67 focus groups with 251 predominantly Black high schoolers experiencing economic marginalization in the Southern United States and attended to their achievement level and race-gender identities. Students often shared concerns about their teacher’s math knowledge for teaching and effectiveness in supporting academic success. Their self-perceptions of math identities varied, and students often did not value advanced math even when they expressed career interests that require advanced math. We discuss practical implications for supporting the math development of marginalized high schoolers, including centering the needs and strengths of Black girls, and propose an expanded inclusive and equitable pedagogical framework.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 05:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241266242?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Socioeconomic Differences Among Low-Income and Racially Minoritized Students Shape Their Engagement and Access in School Choice Systems?</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Socioeconomic differences among low-income and racially minoritized students may be consequential for understanding the dynamics of school choice—especially in high-poverty and racially segregated urban contexts that are often targeted by school choice policies. Yet school choice research largely focuses on differences between groups and relies on measures that broadly categorize students as low-income or not. Drawing on parent interviews in Detroit, this study describes socioeconomic differences among low-income and racially minoritized families and examines how those differences relate to their engagement in the school choice process. While families faced a similar landscape of choice, relied on similar types of resources, and did not have drastically different preferences, relative socioeconomic disadvantages translated to more constrained access and engagement in school choice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241263307?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sustaining quantitatively-grounded meanings for definite integrals in high school calculus</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 02:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2384689?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading program curriculum reform: reflections on challenges and successes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-30-2024 02:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2385410?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparison of online, blended and face-to-face modes for in-service discipline-specific professional development in primary science</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2024 12:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2385047?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Agency in negotiating partnerships in initial teacher education: shifting sands</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2024 10:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2384477?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using the TIMSS curriculum model to develop a framework for coherence and its role in developing mathematical connections</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2024 04:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2371026?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measuring and Visualising Space in Elementary Mathematics Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-29-2024 01:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2384012?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ Beliefs About Language Diversity and Multilingual Learners: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers’ beliefs influence their teaching practices. Given the U.S. Secretary of Education’s push to increase multilingualism, this systematic literature review examines teachers’ beliefs about language diversity and multilingual learners in relation to teacher experiences, teaching practices, and external factors. Using 17 search terms, we searched seven databases for empirical, peer-reviewed studies that examined K–12 teachers’ language beliefs. We analyzed 63 studies that met our criteria using a framework of teacher beliefs. Our findings indicate that researchers use myriad terms to capture the participating teachers’ beliefs. These terms could be grouped into dominant language, subtractive, additive, and pluralist beliefs. We also found connections between teachers’ beliefs on one side and their life experiences, instructional practices, and external factors, such as high-stakes tests and school contexts, on the other side. We added teachers’ beliefs about families, content and knowledge, and diversity to the framework, as well as external factors.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 10:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241257533?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dually Noted: Examining the Implications of Dual Enrollment Course Structure for Students’ Course and College Enrollment Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Dual enrollment (DE)—where students earn college credits during high school—is expanding rapidly. To facilitate DE, institutional actors across K-12 schools and colleges must build or repurpose structures across separate organizations to determine course offerings, assignments, modality, and composition. Yet the organization and implications of those structures remain a black box. Using statewide administrative data from Texas, we describe DE coursetaking and course characteristics for traditional Texas public high school students and examine how DE course characteristics predict students’ course performance and subsequent college enrollment. Our descriptive analyses illuminate striking differences between academic and career and technical education DE, both in students’ backgrounds and course structures. Our regression analyses illustrate how several malleable DE course characteristics predict student outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 10:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241257453?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Competing practice-based mentoring frameworks for student-teachers: between quasi-residency and expedited alternative teacher preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 03:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2384480?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can we TRU-ly infrastructure instructional change? Book review ofmathematics teaching on target and helping students become powerful mathematical thinkers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 02:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2384013?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming learning opportunities in linguistically diverse secondary classrooms through promoting discussions: results of an intervention</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 02:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2383803?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of an online learning environment in teacher care for secondary mathematics students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students’ mathematical learning is bolstered when they have caring relationships with their teachers, yet there is little research on how learning environments may constrain or facilitate teacher care. In this study, I investigate how secondary mathematics teachers understood their care for students online during the COVID-19 pandemic. Through analysis of interview and focus group transcripts, I theorize the role of the learning environment in how teachers care for students and their dispositions toward that work. Findings show how an online learning environment both constrained and facilitated teacher care. An obscuration of student thinking online made it difficult for teachers to care for students’ mathematical thinking. The online learning environment contributed to a curtailment of collaborative problem-solving, which in person had supported teacher care for student–student relationships. Teachers described greater privacy with some students online but difficulty getting to know most students. Teachers also reported their care to be conditional on students’ relational initiation or reciprocity. This study highlights the need for professional development for teachers when learning environments shift and future research about learning environments and relational power.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10350-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ techniques for approaching defining properties of functions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Functions are an essential concept in mathematics. The studies that have examined functions in advanced contexts have primarily focused on students’ reasoning about specific types of functions (such as binary operations and isomorphisms) but not on the core characteristics of well-definedness and everywhere-definedness. Here, we report on a study in which we conducted task-based clinical interviews to gain insight into students’ techniques for addressing “is the given relation a function?” tasks. We found that the techniques students employed necessarily extended far beyond those reported in the literature (such as the vertical line test) and relied on the previously undocumented notions of sameness, convention, and ambiguity (for well-defined) and notions of containment, existence, and set operations (for everywhere-defined). These techniques coordinated the domain, codomain, and rule, which previous research has highlighted the importance of but stopped short of directly investigating. Two contributions of this work include identifying successful techniques (as the landscape of functions literature predominantly focuses on challenges and difficulties) and identifying techniques for everywhere-definedness (which had not previously received any direct attention in the literature).&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10344-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Multivariable Calculus Instructors’ Reports of Resource use</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Given the challenge of visualizing the main constructs of two-variable functions and their differential and integral calculus, it is essential to consider instructional resources’ use and perceived potential to contribute to students’ understanding. This case study considers how four instructors selected and used digital and physical resources in multivariable calculus and their motivations for doing so. We use the teaching triad of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;sensitivity to students&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;mathematical challenge&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;management of learning&lt;/em&gt; to consider the reasons for resource adoption, studying how these instructors think about the resources they use. We also consider how instructors, students, and resources are reported to interact in multivariable calculus. Findings suggest that the instructors’ concern for students’ learning and their conviction that visualization is crucial in multivariable calculus moved them to explore and adopt different resources, especially ones that were free and easy to use. However, visualization was not the only spatial literacy aspect considered. As the instructors gained more experience with the instructional resources they were using, they reported adopting more student-centered use of these resources that allowed them to do more than facilitate visualization during a lecture. The resources began serving as referents for students as they communicated and reasoned about tasks with the instructor as well as among themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00243-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessment in Online Mathematics and Statistics Courses During COVID-19: Insights from Students and Teaching Staff at a Canadian University</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic has brought the rapid transition to online quantitative education, leading to unique challenges and opportunities in assessments for both students and instructors. Focusing on undergraduate students and teaching staff at a Canadian university, this study investigates and compares their experiences and perspectives regarding assessment in online mathematics and statistics courses during the pandemic. Framed by the theory of community of inquiry, our analysis highlights how assessment affected the cognitive, social, and teaching aspects of their learning and teaching experiences. The analysis was based on interview data from the focal student and teaching staff participants. Findings indicated that students and teaching staff had complex experiences with the assessments designed and administered in the online courses during the pandemic. Such complexity was attributed to varied factors, such as technology integration, uncertainty during the pandemic, assessment structure, alignment with course content, and connection with real-life applications. Implications for transforming the assessment practices to meet the demands of students and instructors in online mathematics and statistics education were also provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00322-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The edTPA as a Barrier to Preparing Antiracist Teachers in California</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper explores the policy, pedagogy, and practice affordances and constraints of teacher education as an environment to develop pre-service teachers’ antiracism commitments. Through critical analysis of interviews with pre-service teachers and teacher educators at three social justice-oriented teacher preparation programs, research findings indicate that the material consequences of passing the edTPA can lead pre-service teachers to deprioritize the antiracist or equitable frameworks that were emphasized in their program. The edTPA’s inattention to racism and antiracist practice signals an irrelevance to some pre-service teachers. These findings have implications for how teacher educators may approach the edTPA in social justice-oriented programs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2024 12:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241258732?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Divisive” Education Legislation in the Midwest: A Critical Epistemic Policy Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This interview-based study examines how justice-oriented K-12 administrators and teachers in Iowa make sense of the recent state-level education policy, H.F. 802. Synthesizing literature on Critical Policy Analysis and epistemic justice, we introduce Critical Epistemic Policy Analysis to understand the micro-level impact of divisive education legislation on efforts to create just and inclusive schools. Findings highlight a sociopolitical terrain with ambivalent and shallow equity commitments, deteriorating support for equity work in schools, and a need to grapple with questions of divisiveness and solidarity in justice-oriented educational activism.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-26-2024 12:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241263844?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
