<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publisher Correction: How can university mathematics overcome Klein’s second discontinuity? Specific course design</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01634-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teachers’ beliefs about their roles in teaching mathematics: orchestrating scaffolding in cooperative learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teaching methods to promote cooperative learning may shape mathematics teachers’ roles in the classroom, requiring a shift from direct supervision to delegating authority to small groups of students. While it is widely acknowledged that mathematics teachers’ beliefs play a crucial role in shaping their instructional practices and behaviors, there is limited research on how mathematics teachers’ beliefs about their professional roles influence their scaffolding behaviors in cooperative learning environments. The aim of this qualitative study is to investigate mathematics teachers’ beliefs about their roles in cooperative learning and the relationships between their beliefs and instructional scaffolding practices, which are highly important in cooperative learning environments. In this study, we investigate the teaching practices of four middle school mathematics teachers in Beijing, China, through videotaping of their teaching and semi-structured in-depth interviews. The results show that the participating in-service mathematics teachers held conflicting beliefs about their roles, oscillating between direct supervision (as specialist and controller) and delegation of authority (as observer and facilitator). These beliefs could be identified in different patterns of teacher–student interaction, including unidirectional interactions, non-scaffolding interactions, and scaffolding interactions. In this paper, we critically examine these findings and conclude with a reflection on the limitations of this study and its implications for future research and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10359-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher–child interactions during shared book reading in the domain of early mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study examined the teacher–child interactions during shared book reading (SBR) in the domain of early mathematics. We investigated preschool teachers’ and children’s talk in terms of (1) communicative acts, mathematical focus, and level of abstraction (literal versus inferential), (2) the sequential relation between teacher’s talk and children’s mathematical inferential talk, and (3) the contribution of the type of picture book (mathematical versus non-mathematical) and teachers’ pedagogical content knowledge (MPCK) to the amount of mathematical inferential talk and the strength of the sequential relation. Twelve preschool teachers read one mathematical and one non-mathematical picture book to their preschoolers, resulting in 24 reading sessions. All 24 sessions were video-recorded, transcribed, and coded. Our analyses revealed that teachers’ mathematical talk was dominated by initiations, follow-ups and comments, and children’s mathematical talk by responses and comments. About 30% of teachers’ mathematical initiations and children’s mathematical responses were inferential; approximately 25% of children’s mathematical comments were inferential. Next, we observed a strong sequential relation between teachers’ mathematical inferential prompts and children’s mathematical inferential responses. Finally, the type of picture book, but not preschool teachers’ MPCK, contributed to the SBR interaction: preschool teachers formulated more inferential elaborative follow-ups when reading a mathematical compared to a non-mathematical picture book, and the sequential relation between teacher’s mathematical inferential prompts and children’s mathematical inferential responses was stronger for mathematical picture books.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00503-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing Item Fit Using Expected Score Curve Under Restricted Recalibration</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In item response theory applications, item fit analysis is often performed for precalibrated items using response data from subsequent test administrations. Because such practices lead to the involvement of sampling variability from two distinct samples that must be properly addressed for statistical inferences, conventional item fit analysis can be revisited and modified. This study extends the item fit analysis originally proposed by Haberman et al., which involves examining the discrepancy between the model-implied and empirical expected score curve. We analytically derive the standard errors that accurately account for the sampling variability from two samples within the framework of restricted recalibration. After derivation, we present the findings from a simulation study that evaluates the performance of our proposed method in terms of the empirical Type I error rate and power, for both dichotomous and polytomous items. An empirical example is also provided, in which we assess the item fit of pediatric short-form scale in the Patient-Reported Outcome Measurement Information System.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-04-2024 12:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241268604?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Theory Use in Project Management Research: An Exploratory Content Analysis Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The frequency and richness of the theories developed, tested, and used by researchers in an academic discipline exemplify several pertinent factors, namely, the growth, the maturity, the independence, the legitimacy, and the influence of the discipline. Although organizations have been working on projects for centuries, Project Management (PM) is a considerably new academic discipline with emerging research themes, models, methodologies, frameworks, and paradigms. These PM concepts are anchored on or reinforced by new or existing theories. This exploratory study aims to add to the existing PM body of knowledge by investigating the prevalence of theory use in PM research. A systematic content analysis of 9200 PM research articles published from 2000 to 2019 (20 years) in the leading PM journals identified 248 unique theories. These results reveal that the PM discipline is increasingly embracing the use of theories with game theory, fuzzy theory, agency theory, contingency theory, and stakeholder theory emerging as the most dominant theories in the reviewed research articles. Also, although PM is developing its theories, the results revealed that PM researchers continue to heavily use theories borrowed from other academic disciplines such as psychology, sociology, mathematics, and economics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-04-2024 09:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241279706?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Profiling mathematics teacher educators&#39; readiness for digital technology integration: evidence from Zambia</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research on Mathematics Teacher Educators (MTEs) is crucial for enhancing the professional development of prospective mathematics teachers. However, there is a dearth of recent studies focusing on MTEs’ preparedness for technology integration, particularly within the Zambian educational context, and the wider Sub-Saharan African region. This study assessed the readiness of MTEs in Zambia to effectively integrate digital technology into mathematics education, examining their perceived technological proficiency and familiarity, perceived usefulness, and perceived ease of use. Using a predominantly quantitative cross sectional research design, responses were gathered from 104 MTEs across 16 colleges of education and 12 universities in Zambia through an online semi-structured questionnaire. The findings revealed that, on average, MTEs exhibited low to moderate familiarity with various mathematics-related software applications, e-learning management systems, and web-based video conferencing tools. Although technological proficiency and perceived ease of use were somewhat lacking, MTEs demonstrated awareness of the value of digital technology and expressed willingness to ensure that preservice mathematics teachers acquire the necessary information and skills for technology integration in mathematics teaching and learning. Furthermore, willingness to use technology in the classroom was significantly predicted by perceived usefulness of, and proficiency with, various digital tools. The study also revealed that individuals tend to perceive technology as easier to use as they become more technologically proficient. In light of these findings, it is suggested that access to technological support not only enhances MTEs’ perception of technology’s ease of use but also positively influences their inclination to incorporate it into instructional strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09657-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Cultivation of Classroom Statistical Modeling Practice: A Case Study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-03-2024 12:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2397969?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racist targeting and denial in academia: the ineffectiveness of current policies and practices to address evolving forms of racism</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-03-2024 11:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2394072?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Becoming Linguistically and Culturally Responsive Educators: Teacher Candidates’ Perspective Shifts in an Introductory Linguistics Course</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-03-2024 03:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2392733?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using academic mathematical knowledge when working on interface tasks–analyses of pre-service teachers’ arguments about rotationally symmetric figures</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Special tasks for pre-service teachers (PSTs) in university mathematics courses (“interface tasks”) are a common innovation in recent years to overcome the second discontinuity. By this, we mean tasks that are situated by typical everyday challenges of mathematics teaching and in which PSTs must use their mathematical knowledge and skills in a professionally relevant way. In this paper, we analyze answers that PSTs have created to an interface task on symmetry. The PSTs were asked to clarify a student’s question from a mathematical perspective and then give a suitable elementarized answer. We situate these two steps theoretically and reconstruct the mathematical reasoning in PSTs&#39; answers. Through qualitative content analysis, we examined how PSTs justify figures&#39; symmetries from a university mathematics perspective and when responding to the fictitious student. The scenario of a student questioning the existence of 100° rotationally symmetrical figures elicited rich and varied responses, proving suitable for an interface task. We compared PSTs&#39; reasoning related to mathematical clarification with the reasoning related to elementarization. In many cases, this revealed a productive use of course content. An interesting result is that there is no uniform picture as to whether the arguments are more detailed in the mathematical clarification or in the elementarization.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01633-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing Computational Thinking Using LYNX for Loom Beading Designs in Grade 5</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, a research team made up of Métis artists and knowledge keepers, Anishinaabe and non-Indigenous educators, and a non-Indigenous university mathematics education researcher co-designed and delivered an Indigenous cultural mathematical inquiry in a Grade 5 classroom. We explored the connections between loom bead designs and computational thinking of students using the LYNX coding platform to create and refine bracelet designs. Results indicate this investigation supported the development of (1) incremental and iterative approaches to coding, (2) testing and debugging, (3) reusing and remixing code, and (4) abstracting and modularizing. More importantly, students gained an appreciation of Métis culture and the importance of experiencing multiple cultural perspectives when learning mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00330-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Black women academics and intersectional erasure in the Netherlands</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 12:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2394196?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measuring the Efficacy of Zearn Math in Louisiana</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;This study examines the impact of an online math learning program on third through fifth grade math achievement in Louisiana. Employing Zearn Math usage metrics and administrative data from the Louisiana Department of Education, the results indicate that grade levels that programmatically used Zearn Math scored, on average, about .03 standard deviation units higher on Louisiana’s statewide math assessment. A placebo test using English-language arts scores and several robustness checks suggests that this may be an underestimate of the true effect. These findings come at a crucial time because pandemic-related school closures have led to a 20-fold increase in public school spending on Zearn-related materials between July 2019 and July 2021, and its presence continues to expand across the nation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 12:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241269825?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing contrasting instructional approaches: a way for research to develop insights about backward transfer</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 11:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2388067?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reinterpreting the numerical discourse: a commognitive study of teachers’ support of students’ transition into the proving discourse</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 11:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2388064?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impacting teaching and learning through collaborative reflective practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 09:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2394933?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What do adults know about public education?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/1&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 8-14, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Adults’ beliefs and knowledge about the state of the U.S. education system drive decisions about policy, funding, program adoption, student participation in programs, and the selection of decision makers to elected positions. Amie Rapaport and Anna Rosefsky Saavedra share national survey data showing that U.S. adults have little knowledge about what is being taught in schools, express neutrality about belief systems undergirding education policy, and report experiences misaligned with hard-data trends on student academic progress in recent years. With adults reporting they learn about issues crucial to our education system mainly from “personal experience,” better information has the potential to improve U.S. education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 02:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241282189?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: Pandemic recovery will depend on political rediscovery</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/1&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 52-53, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The current culture wars have been showing up in schools and districts, making local school board races increasingly partisan. The 2024 presidential race is placing even more attention on the partisan divide in local education policies and decisions. Columnist Jonathan E. Collins writes that education advocates can leverage this focus and help put aside partisan politics and meet the post-pandemic challenges students face.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 02:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241282200?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Browsing: Further thoughts on this month’s theme</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/1&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 5-6, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Additional resources and discussion questions related to the September 2024 Kappan theme, “Public perception of schools.”
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 02:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241282187?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/1&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 7-7, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this regular column, Kappan authors recommend books and articles that have influenced them. In the September Bookshelf, Maia Cucchiara recommends Trust in Schools: A Core Resource for Improvement by Anthony Bryk and Barbara Schneider. Amie Rapaport recommends Becoming by Michelle Obama.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 02:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241282188?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under the Law: Title IX and the SCOTUS power grab</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/1&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 54-55, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;New Title IX regulations issued by the Department of Education expand the types of sexual harassment schools must address and give schools greater flexibility in how they handle hearings. But the Supreme Court’s recent ruling in Loper Bright Enterprises v. Raimondo expands courts’ roles in how federal agencies interpret and enforce regulations like Title IX. Robert Kim considers how the Loper Bright ruling might affect Title IX.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 02:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241282201?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: Connecting over cursive</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/1&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Kappan editor-in-chief Teresa Preston discusses ideas related to public perceptions of schools presented in the September 2024 issue.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 02:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241282186?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: What people should know about schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/1&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-60, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Students in PDK’s Educators Rising program share what they wish the public knew about schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 02:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241282205?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: Organizational news about PDK International</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/1&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 61-63, September 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this month’s PDK Connection, CEO James F. Lane offers an update on the association; a unique family connection from the 2024 Educators Rising National Conference is highlighted; and PDK members Michael Odell and Jordan R. Melton Jr. share their insights on change in education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2024 02:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241282206?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
