<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Process Evaluation of an Acute-Care Nurse-Centred Hand Hygiene Intervention in US Hospitals</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper describes a process evaluation of a ‘wise’ intervention that took place in six acute care units in two medical-surgical teaching hospitals in the United States during 2016–2017. ‘Wise’ interventions are short, inexpensive interventions that depend on triggering specific psychological mechanisms to achieve behaviour change. This study sought to increase the hand hygiene compliance (HHC) rates before entering a patient’s room among nurses. The intervention centred on the use of threat to professional identity to prompt improved HHC. Through questionnaires administered to intervention participants and the implementation facilitator, together with independent observation of intervention delivery, we examined whether the steps in the Theory of Change occurred as expected. We found that aspects of the implementation—including mode of delivery, use of incentives, and how nurses were recruited and complied with the intervention—affected reach and likely effectiveness. While components of the intervention’s mechanisms of impact—such as the element of surprise—were successful, they ultimately did not translate into performance of the target behaviour. Performance was also not affected by use of an implementation intention as repeated performance of HHC over years of being a nurse has likely already established well-ingrained practices. Context did have an effect; the safety culture of the units, the involvement of the Nurse Managers, the level of accountability for HHC in each unit, and the hospitals themselves all influenced levels of engagement. These conclusions should have implications for those interested in the applicability of ‘wise’ interventions and those seeking to improve HHC in hospitals.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-24-2023 10:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231197253?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming the future of quantitative educational research: a systematic review of enacting quantCrit</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-24-2023 07:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2248911?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring a framework for integrated STEM: challenges and benefits for promoting engagement in learning mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Advocacy of STEM curricular approaches is based on a concern to engage students in authentic disciplinary and interdisciplinary practices in the STEM (science, technology, engineering, mathematics) disciplines, and the need to promote participation in STEM pathways. The &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;STEM Academy&lt;/em&gt; professional learning program was developed to support teachers to engage and motivate students by creating real-world, challenging problems. The initiative involved interdisciplinary teams of secondary STEM teachers attending workshops and working with university experts to design, implement and evaluate STEM curricular experiences. This paper focuses on case studies undertaken in two of the twelve schools involved in the initiative, using interview data from teachers and students, to explore the nature of their programs and their experiences. We investigate key features of these two schools’ approaches, using a conceptual framework for integrated STEM, and explore the challenges and benefits of different features of integrated STEM that promote different dimensions of engagement in learning mathematics. We explore how the framework characteristics can be reframed into four dimensions that promote mathematics engagement in integrated STEM education - design thinking in authentic contexts, content integration, STEM practices and 21st Century skills, and exposure to professional practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-24-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01519-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racialized deviance as an axiom in the mathematics education equity genre</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this conceptual paper, the author argues that equity research in mathematics education is a genre that operates according to certain implicit ideological and rhetorical rules and assumptions—or discursive formations—that form how one can think about equity and inequity. One such rule that forms the basis of this paper is the axiom of racialized deviance, a logical tool developed by whiteness to establish its dominance and to justify physical, psychic, and epistemic violence against blackness. The author takes up &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;whiteness&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;blackness&lt;/em&gt; related to global systems of racialization beyond the reference to white and Black people that is more typical in the United States. The author proposes three ways that the deviance axiom shows up in equity research in mathematics education: ethnomathematics, repair orientations, and success counternarratives. This issue of racialized deviance unveils equity research in mathematics education as a project whose logical foundations undermine its stated aims. The logic of global white supremacy under which school mathematics operates creates a situation where it is impossible for equity in mathematics education to exist outside because the genre requires that anyone who elects to participate accepts the axiom of racialized deviance on some level.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-24-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10260-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of School Infrastructure and Teachers’ Human Capital on Academic Performance in Brazil</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;To improve one of the lowest rates of literacy and numeracy in the world, the government of Brazil has targeted public education reform, given the strong link between an educated population and economic growth. This study examines the academic performance of the Brazilian public primary school system. It addresses the empirical shortcomings of prior research to examine the dynamics of the relationship between academic performance scores and several demographic and institutional variables, such as socioeconomic characteristics, variations in school infrastructure and school complexity, and teachers’ human capital. We employed quantile regression to explore the determinants of academic performance across 35,490 schools in rural and urban environments in Brazil. The dependent variable in our analysis captures the academic performance score, as measured by Brazil’s education authorities, of each school in our dataset. The model includes several education-related indices used in prior research and, as explanatory factors, measures of teachers’ human capital and the students’ socioeconomic level, which synthesizes information on parents’ education and household income. The results suggest that several institutional variables, including access to school libraries, computer facilities, projectors, and televisions, are positively and significantly related to the academic performance of primary students in Brazil’s system of public education. Furthermore, students’ socioeconomic level is positively associated with their academic performance.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-23-2023 11:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231197741?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Instruction Increases Canadian Students’ Preference for and Use of Lateral Reading Strategies to Fact-Check Online Information</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Canadian middle and high school students (N = 2,278) completed a “CTRL-F” curriculum teaching them how to evaluate online information by reading laterally to investigate sources, check claims, and trace information to original contexts. A subset of CTRL-F students (N = 316) were in classes with teacher-matched control groups (N = 287). Some CTRL-F students (N = 994) completed a delayed posttest. At pretest, students indicated preference for some lateral reading strategies, but preference rarely translated into use. Following instruction, CTRL-F students showed greater preference for and use of lateral reading than controls and greater alignment between preference and use. The curriculum’s impact varied by demographic factors but not by differences in implementation. Gains were maintained from posttest to delayed posttest. Direct instruction and practice in lateral reading appear to strengthen connections between students’ preferences and utilization of these strategies to evaluate online content relevant to academic and personal life.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-23-2023 07:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231192106?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing Licensure Test Performance and Predictive Validity for Different Teacher Subgroups</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We investigate the predictive validity of teacher licensure tests using data from the Massachusetts Tests for Educator Licensure (MTEL). MTEL scores predict teachers’ in-service performance ratings and contributions to student test scores (i.e., value added). We then explore whether these relationships vary for teacher candidates of color. Although candidates of color have lower first-time pass rates and are less likely to retake licensure tests, we do not find consistent evidence that MTEL scores are less predictive of student achievement gains. Finally, we find that some evidence that MTEL scores are more predictive of teacher performance ratings for teachers of color than for White teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-23-2023 06:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231192365?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of the Triple Q Intervention on Argument Writing: Findings from a Small-Scale Cluster-Randomized Controlled Trial</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-23-2023 02:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2231941?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Researching “what went wrong” in professional development (PD) for mathematics teachers: What makes it so important, and so difficult?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-23-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09599-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Shifting the ways prospective teachers frame and notice student mathematical thinking: from deficits to strengths</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract &lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Noticing the strengths in students’ mathematical thinking is a critical skill that teachers need to develop, but it can be challenging due to the prevalence of deficit-based thinking in mathematics education. To address this challenge, a teacher education course was designed to encourage prospective teachers to engage in critical reflection on their own and others’ framings of students’ thinking and shift their focus towards noticing students’ strengths. The study analyzed written responses from the prospective teachers, collected at the beginning and end of the course, to investigate their framing and noticing of students’ mathematical thinking. The analysis focused on the aspects of students’ thinking that the prospective teachers paid attention to, the stances they took when interpreting students’ thinking, and the instructional moves they proposed in response to their thinking. Furthermore, the study established a spectrum of deficit-based and strength-based framings on students’ mathematical thinking. This spectrum allowed for the identification of each participant’s written noticing responses within a range of possibilities, contributing to a more nuanced understanding of the changes in teachers’ framing and noticing of students’ thinking over time.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-22-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10235-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A method for assessing students’ interpretations of contextualized data</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Learning to interpret data in context is an important educational outcome. To assess students’ attainment of this outcome, it is necessary to examine the interplay between their contextual and statistical reasoning. We describe a research method designed to do so. The method draws upon Toulmin’s (&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r48&quot;&gt;1958&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r49&quot;&gt;2003&lt;/span&gt;) model of argumentation for the first stage of qualitative data analysis and the Structure of the Observed Learning Outcome (SOLO) (Biggs &amp;amp; Collis, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r6&quot;&gt;1991&lt;/span&gt;) model for the second stage. Toulmin analyses help identify the justifications and expressions of uncertainty students provide in their interpretive arguments. Subsequent analyses based on the multi-modal conceptualization of SOLO help characterize the quality of student arguments relative to one another. Existing literature and an empirical example are drawn upon to explain how the Toulmin and SOLO models can be used in tandem to analyze students’ interpretations of contextualized data. We also explain how pairing Toulmin and SOLO can address theoretical and practical limitations that arise when using just one of the two models on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-22-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10234-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘A clear center but no clear boundaries.’ The construction of professional identities in spiritual care through boundary work in participatory action research within health care</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Spiritual care is increasingly seen as a task of all health care professionals. This is challenging for chaplains working in health care, who hold spiritual care at the heart of their profession but don’t feel rooted in a strong professional identity. In this article we discuss a participatory action research that aimed at strengthening the professional identity of health care chaplains by forming collaborative learning communities of chaplains and general practice mental health. The focus is on the ‘boundary work’ and how participatory action research contributes to this. Relational professionalism, Dialogical Self Theory and Boundary Theory are combined to interpret the complex relational-dialogical processes of negotiating one’s identity within the relationships with diverse others: clients, mental health nurses and society. The result is a more articulated and at the same time flexible professional identity for healthcare chaplains. Participatory action research contributes to these boundary processes by stimulating reflection, explicating, eliciting or encouraging different voices and facilitating the dialogue between these professionals.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-22-2023 10:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231195418?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What is a good explanation in integrated STEM education?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Explaining is a vital spontaneous process for human beings, as through explanations we make sense of the surrounding phenomena. While the role and structure of explanations have been explored in each science, technology, engineering and mathematics (STEM) area, little is still known regarding what counts as a good explanation for a STEM problem. This study seeks to address this void by examining the nature of 82 explanations of a STEM challenge produced by 9th grade students (years 14–16) who participated in a learning sequence designed with an integrated STEM education perspective (I-STEM). We aim to find out which types of explanations are produced by 9th grade students when engaged in an I-STEM learning sequence, as a strategy to establish/identify the core features of a good I-STEM explanation. As a subsidiary aim, we intend to propose an analytical framework that enables the characterization and understanding of the students’ explanations to an integrated STEM problem, based on the combination of a theoretical view on I-STEM explanations and the qualitative analysis of explanations produced by students. Results show that a majority of the students produced STEM explanations, either descriptive or relational, that failed to demonstrate knowledge or procedures from the four STEM areas. About a quarter of the solutions entailed I-STEM explanations, thus recognizing the role of knowledge or procedures of each area, concurring to obtain the solution, from the creation of the artefact to the understanding of the underlying law. We further propose a conceptualization of a good I-STEM explanation as involving the mobilization of conceptual knowledge and processes from all STEM areas in an explicit and intentional way to present the solution devised to the STEM challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-22-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01517-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>IRT Models for Learning With Item-Specific Learning Parameters</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We propose a new item response theory growth model with item-specific learning parameters, or ISLP, and two variations of this model. In the ISLP model, either items or blocks of items have their own learning parameters. This model may be used to improve the efficiency of learning in a formative assessment. We show ways that the ISLP model’s learning parameters can be estimated in simulation using Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC), demonstrate a way that the model could be used in the context of adaptive item selection to increase the rate of learning, and estimate the learning parameters in an empirical data analysis using the ISLP. In the simulation studies, the one-parameter logistic model was used as the measurement model to generate random response data with various test lengths and sample sizes. Ability growth was modeled with a few variations of the ISLP model, and it was verified that the parameters were accurately recovered. Secondly, we generated data using the linear logistic test model with known Q-matrix structure for the item difficulties. Using a two-step procedure gave very comparable results for the estimation of the learning parameters even when item difficulties were unknown. The potential benefit of using an adaptive selection method in conjunction with the ISLP model was shown by comparing total improvement in the examinees’ ability parameter to two other methods of item selection that do not utilize this growth model. If the ISLP holds, adaptive item selection consistently led to larger improvements over the other methods. A real data application of the ISLP was given to illustrate its use in a spatial reasoning study designed to promote learning. In this study, interventions were given after each block of ten items to increase ability. Learning parameters were estimated using MCMC.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-21-2023 06:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231193096?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Constructing an Educational “Quality” Crisis: (E)quality Politics and Racialization Beyond Target Beneficiaries</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this critical, political discourse analysis, we trace how two concepts, equity and quality, became discursively linked and contested in the administration of postsecondary education policy over time (1968–1994)—a developmental process we refer to as (e)quality politics. By engaging in a historical analysis, we investigate (a) the racialized political origins and discursive processes by which arguments over educational “quality” are advanced as part of an antiequity policy paradigm and (b) how this paradigm reinscribes racial inequity into administrative and organizational action over time. We illustrate how, once an (e)quality politics paradigm is established, racialized policy designs can persist, even in the absence of explicit references to racialized social constructions of target populations in later periods of policy development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-21-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231189478?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On the Shoulders of a Perfect Stranger: Knowledge Gap About the Indigenous Sámi in the Finnish Teacher Education Curriculum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-21-2023 02:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2249292?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Worlds and words: entangling mathematics, language, and context in newcomer classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This work studies mathematics word problems’ use in a classroom of recent immigrants, or newcomers, to a United States public elementary school. I study how word problems foster the recontextualization of mathematical concepts in a lived reality experienced by newcomer students in their new cultural and educational setting. In this study’s setting language plays a significant role in the process of meaning-making. I describe how language use in word problems remains intertwined with mathematics instruction. This opens a space for questioning word problems’ purpose and role in multilingual classrooms, and I highlight how the creative process of co-constructing problems’ meaning in this context can expand notions of genre applied to word problems. Throughout I adopt a theorization of translanguaging as a language practice and apply it in problem discussion. This helps probe how language use impacts students’ ways of understanding and utilizing mathematical concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-20-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01516-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fostering a growth mindset in secondary mathematics classrooms in the Netherlands</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-19-2023 12:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2241433?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The landscape of US elementary mathematics teacher education: course requirements for mathematics content and methods</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The adequate preparation of future teachers of mathematics is critical, requiring sufficient opportunities to develop both pedagogical skill and content knowledge. Yet, despite new recommendations for mathematics teacher preparation, we know little about the landscape of course-based learning opportunities in US elementary teacher education programs. To what extent do US elementary teacher education programs meet the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Standards for Preparing Teachers of Mathematics&lt;/em&gt; outlined by the Association of Mathematics Teacher Educators (AMTE) for mathematics content and methods courses? Based on an a priori power analysis, we gathered a random sample of 291 higher education institutions. Within these institutions, we analyzed 736 programs, including Bachelor’s, Master’s, and Credential programs. We found that overwhelmingly US elementary teacher education programs do not meet the aspirations outlined in the AMTE standards, with Master’s and Credential programs and those covering all elementary grades particularly falling short. Potential explanations for these challenges and implications for teacher education program design are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-19-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09593-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Revisiting “Radical Equations: Civil Rights from Mississippi to the Algebra Project&amp;quot; by Robert P. Moses and Charles E. Cobb, Jr.</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-18-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09596-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical knowledge for teaching and mathematics didactic knowledge: a comparative study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper compares and contrasts two approaches that are widely used in the English- and German-speaking discourse on mathematics teacher knowledge: ‘mathematical knowledge for teaching’ and ‘mathematics didactic knowledge’. It is proposed that these constructs are based on distinct theoretical and conceptual positions and origins. Mathematical knowledge for teaching is viewed as a utilitarian-pragmatic approach rooted in English-speaking traditions as it focuses on its use in teaching and represents a practice-based conceptualization of knowledge domains required for mathematics teaching. Mathematics didactic knowledge, on the other hand, is considered normative-descriptive as it is formulated based on didactic principles and broader theoretical perspectives, providing a theory-driven conceptualization of knowledge domains rooted in traditions of German-speaking didactics of mathematics. The paper further highlights similarities and differences in these two constructs through an examination of two central knowledge domains: specialized content knowledge (part of mathematical knowledge for teaching) and subject matter didactic knowledge (part of mathematics didactic knowledge).&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-18-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09598-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Immigrant Generation and Mentors in Educational Attainment</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Social capital, including engagement with mentors, facilitates educational attainment. However, engagement with mentors differs significantly across groups of adolescents with different backgrounds, including an immigrant background. We investigate how immigrant generation predicts adolescents’ engagement with mentors and different types of mentors (i.e., school-based and non-school-based), the association of mentors with educational attainment, and these estimates’ heterogeneity based on the immigrant generation. We analyzed nationally representative Add Health data from N = 11,242 adolescents by using school fixed-effect linear probability models. Results show that adolescents from immigrant generations 1 and 2 were less likely than those from generation 3+ to have a mentor, but there were no significant differences in engaging with school-based mentors. Mentors predicted educational attainment; school-based mentor effects were larger than non-school-based mentor effects. The associations between mentors and college attendance and graduation were largest for first-generation immigrants. Our findings indicate the importance of structures supporting relationship-building and mentorship in schools and wider communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2023 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231190380?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does Institutional Quality Matter for Foreign Direct Investment and Human Development?</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examines the relationship between foreign direct investment (FDI), institutional quality and human development) in host countries from 2002 to 2019, using the Human Development Index [HDI] as the measure of human development. This study utilized a panel dataset of 143 countries, including both developed and developing economies, over a 17-year period. Additionally, the study employed a GMM (generalized method of moments) estimator to address unobservable heterogeneity and simultaneity. This study reveals a significant positive relationship between FDI and human development, with a stronger effect observed in developing countries compared to in developed countries. Notably, the impact of FDI-HDI nexus is larger in countries with moderately high-quality institutions, irrespective of their income level. Furthermore, good governance plays a crucial role in enhancing human development, as developing economies with high governance quality experience a greater impact of FDI on HDI compared to other countries. The findings of this study suggest that attracting FDI can be beneficial for enhancing the HDI, especially in developing countries. Additionally, the study highlights governance as a moderating factor in the relationship between FDI and HDI. Improving governance quality can enhance the positive impact of FDI on human development in host countries, especially in developing countries.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2023 08:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231195798?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Adding Color to My Tears: Toward a Theoretical Framework for Antiblackness in School Discipline</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Persistent racial disparities in students’ disciplinary outcomes have been one of the most concerning educational policy and equity topics for decades. Despite the hypervisibility of Black students in school discipline conversations, research and practice evade a focus on anti-Black racism. In this essay, we draw from Black Critical Theory (BlackCrit) to present a theoretical framework that researchers and educational stakeholders can use to specify, study, and understand antiblackness in school discipline. We outline and discuss six interrelated theoretical constructs of the Antiblackness in School Discipline framework: (a) “Trading Away the Black,” (b) “Whites as Propertied,” (c) Intersecting Blackness, (d) Racial Neoliberalism, (e) La Petite Misère, and (f) Internalized Racism. Examples of studies providing empirical support for these theoretical tenets are also discussed, and suggestions for utilizing this framework in scholarship, policy, and practice are also offered.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2023 02:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231191448?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
