<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Units Coordination in Preservice Elementary Teachers&#39; Mathematical Knowledge for Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2024 11:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2370178?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School gardens as sites for community, empowerment, and justice: a participatory action research study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 12:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2374746?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting students’ participation in collective argumentation: Use of displays in a secondary mathematics classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 04:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2371515?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Development of prospective elementary teachers’ knowledge to teach early algebra through case discussions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigated the development of prospective elementary teachers (PETs)’ subject matter and pedagogical content knowledge for teaching early algebra through participation in case discussions. PETs attended five weeks of intervention as part of a method course, which included case discussions. During the intervention, the participants were presented with big ideas of equivalence and equations, generalized arithmetic, and functional thinking as the content of early algebra through text-based classroom cases. Data were collected through one-hour individual interviews before and after the early algebra lessons. The analysis of the pre-interviews indicated that prospective elementary teachers may not be ready to foster algebraic thinking in elementary grades in terms of the required knowledge for teaching. We found that PETs needed more development of required subject matter knowledge to guide algebraic thinking in elementary grades, such as the relational meaning of the equal sign, generalizing, representing, or justifying arithmetic or functional relationships, and reasoning with them. Likewise, PETs were found to lack in pedagogical content knowledge related to students’ conceptions and misconceptions and effective teaching strategies to promote early algebraic thinking. However, we found that specifically designed method courses could help develop PETs’ knowledge of teaching early algebra. Following early algebra lessons centered around case discussions, PETs showed progress in multiple aspects of knowledge across all big ideas, though their improvement in generalized arithmetic was somewhat less pronounced. This progress was observed in their subject matter and pedagogical content knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09642-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A proposal for the study of mathematics teachers’ beliefs through the analysis of their practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In recent years, research on mathematics teachers’ beliefs has increasingly shifted its focus toward understanding their connection with instructional practices. This article introduces a model designed to explore mathematics teachers’ beliefs through a comprehensive analysis of their practices. The contributions of models that study the relationship between beliefs and practices of teachers, such as those from Schoenfeld (Journal of Mathematical Behavior, 18(3), 243–261, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r27&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/span&gt;) and Cobb and Yackel (Educational Psychologist, 31(3), 175–190, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r5&quot;&gt;1996&lt;/span&gt;), were reviewed and considered. Additionally, it includes methodological considerations from Leatham and Speer for studying beliefs. These approaches are integrated by utilizing the notions of practice, types of didactic-mathematical practices and norms, derived from the onto-semiotic approach, as the central organizing axis. Furthermore, we demonstrate the application of these stages of analysis for exploring teachers’ beliefs by analyzing the beliefs of a prospective mathematics teacher. The findings enable us to identify the beliefs held by this prospective teacher regarding the use of introductory activities characterized by a high motivational level but a low mathematical level. Additionally, these results provide insights into potential avenues for developing training programs aimed at instigating a shift in these beliefs, thereby fostering an enhancement in teaching practices. These outcomes show the feasibility of the analytical model proposed in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00496-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building mathematical micro-identities through supporting productive struggle</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 11:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2372711?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Focusing on foundational Calculus ideas to understand the derivative concept via problem-solving tasks that involve the use of a Dynamic Geometry System</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of this paper is to review recently calculus curriculum reforms and research studies that document what types of understanding students develop in their precalculus courses. We argue that it is important to characterize what difficulties students experience to solve tasks that include the use of foundational calculus concepts and to look for possible ways for students to develop a way of reasoning to work on problems that involve variational phenomena. Thus, we identified tasks in which calculus students exhibit limited understanding of essential concepts to approach and solve those tasks. The purpose is to illustrate and discuss how the systematic use of a Dynamic Geometry System (DGS) could provide a set of affordances for students to develop ways of thinking to grasp calculus foundational ideas and to study the derivative concept. Here, we relied on Thurston’s seminal work that emphasizes the relevance for learners to identify, connect, and coordinate different dimensions and meanings (intuitive, symbolic, algorithmic, geometric, physical, and formal) to construct, understand, and apply the concept of derivative.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01607-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Catherine P. Vistro-Yu &amp;amp; Tin Lam Toh (eds.) (2019) School mathematics curricula – Asian perspectives and glimpses of reform</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10338-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Aligning school mathematics with a manufactured crisis: re-rendering neoliberal and neoconservative discourses as commonsensical in a rural place</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;School reform efforts are situated within social and political contexts and, as such, are susceptible to the commonsense discourses circulating through, and shaping, society. Two discourses prevalent in US education reform are those perpetuating the ideologies of neoliberalism and neoconservatism. These ideologies are inherently contradictory—with the former promoting a small state and the latter a strong state—but converge to promote their agendas, shaping school reform efforts. &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; this occurs is not always clear, especially in rural contexts, where there has been limited attention to ideological discourses’ relation to schooling. In this analysis, we describe how dominant, yet contradictory, discourses of neoliberalism and neoconservatism are resolved in a rural context. We find that the leaders of one rural, public school district identified fifth-grade number sense as a problem of practice needing improvement—framing the cause of their problem as misalignment and the solution as consistency within and across grade levels. In doing so, district leaders’ conversations were limited to those of standardization (e.g., state-mandated mathematics standards, approaches to timed-fact tests, and curriculum between grade levels). Alignment as a frame excluded conversations related to deeper considerations, such as students’ experiences in mathematics or issues of equity. We find that dominant discourses constrain the ways district leaders frame their mathematics-related problem and work through the frame (in this case, one of alignment) to resolve inherent contradictions and advance their agendas. We suggest that these discourses serve to distract from potentially more pressing issues in education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10340-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First- and second-grade prospective teachers reconstructing definitions of polygon diagonals</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The current study examined how prospective first- and second-grade mathematics teachers define the polygon diagonals concept, how they reconstruct their definition during and following an intervention, and how their concept images develop over time. Twenty-three prospective teachers participated in the study, during which they were asked to analyze mathematical events involving a conflict that could be resolved using a precise mathematical definition of a polygon diagonal. Data were collected from prequestionnaires, postquestionnaires, and observations of class discussions. The study findings indicate that before the intervention, all participants provided incorrect definitions and struggled to identify nonprototypical examples of polygon diagonals in the prequestionnaire. However, the process of analyzing mathematical events helped the participants reconstruct their definitions of polygon diagonals and identify the critical attributes of this concept, which improved their ability to extend the concept’s image to include nonprototypical examples. The participants’ improved understanding was evident in the significant improvements in the postquestionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00495-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The development of elementary teachers’ personal meanings of problem-solving through engaging in open-ended tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, we explored elementary school teachers’ experiences working on open-ended mathematics tasks during a 10-day professional development (PD) workshop. Teachers engaged with the tasks daily in a session call Morning Math (MM). Thirty-two elementary teachers from three school districts in the USA participated in a 2-year professional development (PD) program. Analysis of videos of teacher engagement in the tasks and interviews shows that the use of open-ended mathematics tasks embedded within problem-solving focused PD could shape elementary school teachers’ personal meanings about learning mathematics through problem-solving. The findings indicate that the teachers’ take-aways from the PD were not limited to the mathematical content of the MM problems (i.e., mathematical residue), instead teachers’ experiences with open-ended mathematics tasks engendered personal meanings reflecting pedagogical residue with cognitive, affective, and social components. This result shows the crucial  role of PD in shaping teachers’ mathematics-related personal meanings  which research suggests that it will subsequently influence their beliefs and instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00493-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Children’s mathematical engagement based on their awareness of coding toy design features</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2024 11:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2371513?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘I just want to get my degree and leave’: psychosocial experiences of black male students navigating a historically white South African university</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2024 01:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2371969?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating the difficulty level of aspects of teaching during field placement: from coursework to practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 01:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2370887?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The MTSK model as a tool for designing tasks for teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper studies the knowledge developed by a group of sixty-two pre-service primary teachers during a training session on the definition of a polygon and the mathematical practice of defining. We explore the knowledge developed by pre-service teachers when they carry out a series of training tasks oriented around the practice of defining with primary pupils, within the theoretical framework of the Mathematics Teachers’ Specialised Knowledge model, and using videos of an authentic lesson as prompt. Data were collected by means of video recordings of the implementation of the training tasks, in conjunction with the pre-service teachers’ own written observations as they watched the recorded lesson. A content analysis was carried out on the collected data using the Mathematics Teachers’ Specialised Knowledge model. The results highlight the way in which knowledge of the mathematical practice of defining is constructed, along with the mathematical objects involved in this practice, and pedagogical aspects of defining with young pupils. They also illustrate how a sequence of tasks oriented around a model of teachers’ knowledge can contribute to the development of this knowledge in initial training programmes, and more especially provide orientation about the training of pre-service teachers in the mathematical practice of defining.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01605-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking anti-Asian racism in mathematics education: the hidden racism made visible through AsianCrit</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Racism against Asians is often ignored worldwide, and the field of mathematics education is no exception. The anti-Asian racism unveiled during the COVID-19 pandemic necessitates that we rethink the current discussions of equity and social justice in mathematics education regarding how the needs of many Asian students have been forgotten and often excluded from these discussions. When Asian students are mentioned, it is often for the purpose of reifying a racial hierarchy of mathematical ability (Martin, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teachers College Record&lt;/em&gt; 111(2):295–338, 2009; Martin et al., 2017). Based on an analysis of the particularities of the U.S. context, this essay argues that the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;model minority myth&lt;/em&gt; and other covert forms of anti-Asian racism, such as yellow peril and forever foreigner myths, racialize Asian Americans and create a monolithic view of diverse groups of people with different histories and needs, including within mathematics education. While incorporating current race and racism concepts from Asian Critical Theory (Iftikar &amp;amp; Museus, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;International Journal of Qualitative Studies in Education&lt;/em&gt; 31(10):935–949, 2018), we aim to conceptualize the racialization that Asian-American students experience in mathematics classrooms and how it affects their well-being, and propose implications to (re)construct Asian-American students’ counterstories and identities in mathematics education. We also scrutinize mathematics education researchers’ and educators’ roles in advancing equity for all students by countering the hidden racism toward Asian Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10335-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating a space for them through autoethnography</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Researchers in education have begun to address inclusivity for gender-diverse populations, but the authentic experiences of gender-variant students presented directly by the students themselves are largely unheard in the literature of mathematics education. In this co-authored report, we include the experiences of a genderqueer preservice mathematics teacher over the course of a semester at university through their autoethnography and the reflections of a mathematics teacher educator supervising the research. Through this study, we provide educators a window into some ways that gender-variant students may experience the classroom and academia. One goal of this research is to create a space for the authentic voice of gender-variant individuals in the discussion of gender-inclusive education. We highlight implications for mathematics teacher educators involving gender-variant students’ gender journeys as processes instead of moments of coming out, the interdependent process of building relationships of trust, and the importance of trying and failing and trying again as we seek to be more inclusive educators.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09643-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student Interpretations of Eigenequations in Linear Algebra and Quantum Mechanics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This work investigates how students interpret various eigenequations in different contexts for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(2 \times 2\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; matrices: &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(A\vec {x}=\lambda \vec {x}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; in mathematics and either &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq3&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\hat{S}_x| + \rangle _x=\frac{\hbar }{2}| + \rangle _x\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq4&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\hat{S}_z| + \rangle =\frac{\hbar }{2}| + \rangle\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; in quantum mechanics. Data were collected from two sources in a senior-level quantum mechanics course; one is video, transcript and written work of individual, semi-structured interviews; the second is written work from the same course three years later. We found two principal ways in which students reasoned about the equal sign within the mathematics eigenequation and at times within the quantum mechanical eigenequations: with a functional interpretation and/or a relational interpretation. Second, we found three distinct ways in which students explained how they made sense of the physical meaning conveyed by the quantum mechanical eigenequations: via a measurement interpretation, potential measurement interpretation, or correspondence interpretation of the equation. Finally, we present two themes that emerged in the ways that students compared the different eigenequations: attention to form and attention to conceptual (in)compatibility. These findings are discussed in relation to relevant literature, and their instructional implications are also explored.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00241-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Opening up creative resources: towards age-friendly communities through rhizomatic thinking and doing</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-27-2024 08:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2370277?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: Mathematics teaching and teacher education against marginalisation, or towards equity, diversity and inclusion</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01608-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transitioning to proof via writing scripts on the rules of a new discourse﻿</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Coming from the commognitive standpoint, we consider proof-based mathematics as a distinct discourse, the transition to which requires special rules for endorsement and rejection of mathematical statements. In this study, we investigate newcomers’ learning of these rules when being taught them explicitly. Our data come from academically motivated high-school students who took a special course in undergraduate mathematics. The course teacher dedicated three academic hours to introducing and explaining selected rules of proof to support students’ shift to the new discourse. The homework assignment consisted of typical proof-requiring problems and a scriptwriting task, asking students to compose a dialogue between fictional characters about a proof-related mistake of their choice. We analyzed the differences and similarities between the rules discussed in the classroom and those that students addressed and implemented in their proofs. The analysis showed that while students’ solutions to proof-requiring problems required rule implementation, fictitious dialogues opened the space for rule formulation and substantiation. In many cases, the students discussed the rules presented in the classroom, extending, elaborating, and specifying the teacher’s formulations. Furthermore, while the students’ proofs were mainly consistent with the teacher’s expectations, some of their rule formulations were more radical and overgeneralized than expected. These findings suggest that newcomers’ communication about the rules of proof may lag behind their capability to implement those rules to prove mathematical statements.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10324-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Growth on 2019 State Achievement Tests: Empirical Benchmarks and the Role of Scale Choice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-26-2024 08:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2360534?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Candidate Learning of Interdisciplinary Controversial Issues: Linking Social Studies and Science in the Elementary School Curriculum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-26-2024 08:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2368503?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of knowledge, attitude, and emotions in Spanish pre-service teachers’ willingness to engage in climate change education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-26-2024 07:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2370885?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
