<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Who do they think they are? Professional identity of Chinese university-based teacher educators</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2023 10:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2191814?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking Elementary Preservice Teachers’ Ways of Reflecting on Conceptual Mistakes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2023 04:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2187167?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Principal Beliefs Predict Responses to Individual Students’ Misbehavior</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;National policies have targeted widespread exclusionary discipline in schools which is associated with negative academic outcomes. Principals play an important role in making disciplinary decisions, yet little is understood about how their mindsets might impact these decisions. We hypothesized that principals’ mindsets regarding the purpose of discipline (exclusion vs. prevention) would predict their responses to misbehavior. In a random, nationwide sample (N = 234), principals responded to misbehavior by a hypothetical Black or White student. Exclusion beliefs predicted more severe discipline, whereas prevention beliefs predicted greater endorsement of referring the student to a school counselor. Principal mindsets also predicted exclusionary discipline in real-world contexts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2023 04:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231158389?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of movement in young children’s spatial experiences: a review of early childhood mathematics education research</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Young children’s spatial reasoning is critical to mathematics learning from an early age. Recent reviews have drawn attention to the importance of mathematical experiences in the early years; however, an explicit focus on research in spatial reasoning can contribute to a more coherent account of the field. This paper reports a scoping review of qualitative studies (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 37) during the years 2009–2021. The studies analysed in this review provide insight into children’s embodied spatial concepts and non-verbal expressions such as gesture and the relationship between spatial reasoning and mathematics learning in early childhood (birth to 8 years). Four main themes were found: (i) children’s manipulation and transformation of objects, (ii) children’s bodily engagement with and within spaces, (iii) children’s representation and interpretation of spatial experiences, and (iv) contexts for spatial learning. While the review illuminates a deeper awareness and a more holistic and embodied view of children’s spatial competencies, there remains few studies focussed on children under three years of age. Future directions for ongoing research are identified.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-16-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00446-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interactions and tensions between mathematical discourses and schoolwork discourses when solving dynamic geometry tasks: what is internally persuasive for students?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2023 08:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2177882?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Changing the Odds: Student Achievement after Introduction of a Middle School Math Intervention</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2023 07:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2170937?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The earlySTEM Program: An Evaluation Through Teacher Perceptions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Conceptually grounded curricular materials in the context of professional development programs facilitate teachers’ adoption of new pedagogies. Even though science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) professional development opportunities for early grade level teachers continue to receive attention, one existing challenge is to support teachers further in implementing well-defined integrated STEM curricula. The earlySTEM program supports K–4 teachers with the systematically developed earlySTEM curriculum, its associated curricular materials, and year-long mentoring. The program was implemented in 26 schools. This mid-evaluation investigated teacher perceptions of the earlySTEM program with a focus on contributions and challenges. A total of 134 teachers from the 26 schools responded to a survey with open-ended questions. Survey data were analyzed using a descriptive approach. The findings indicated that the teachers had positive experiences with the earlySTEM program. The results revealed that the earlySTEM program is perceived to have contributed to (a) teachers’ STEM teaching skills and STEM conceptualizations and (b) students’ skills development and awareness on the connection of the curriculum content to real-world problems. The results also document the perceived challenge in implementing the earlySTEM curriculum: need for more classroom time. The conclusions offer insights for similar program designs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-15-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00264-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Expansion of Title V: A Historical Analysis of the Promoting Postbaccalaureate Opportunities for Hispanic Americans Program</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Understanding the development of major educational policies is essential, especially federal policies integral to Hispanic-Serving Institutions (HSIs)—one of the fastest-growing types of postsecondary institutions in the United States, which collectively serve over two-thirds of Latina/o/x-identified college students. Accordingly, in this archive-based study, we explore the expansion of Title V, specifically the creation of the Postbaccalaureate Opportunities for Hispanic Americans Program, and how advocates framed the need for this program. Specifically, employing McBeth et al.’s policy narrative framework, we story how Congress came to enact this program, describing the setting, characters, and plot of this policy process. In doing so, we make visible via narration how federal policy unfolds and the relationship between federal and state-level policy. Additionally, we show that nationalist, capitalist, and democratic logics are often used to justify programs to support the Latina/o/x community. Considering the findings, we conclude with implications for policy and future research. Ultimately, using this innovative lens, we expand the HSI literature and complexify the understanding of Title V.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2023 10:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231153608?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Counts as a Minority-Serving Institution? Toward the Utilization of a Standardized and Uniform Definition and Typology</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Minority-serving institutions (MSIs) are unique in their ability to support the educational advancement of students of color. Approximately one in five postsecondary institutions are eligible for funding under an MSI designation, yet more than half of all undergraduate students of color are enrolled in such colleges and universities. However, there continues to be great disagreement and confusion about how to define MSIs. Researchers, policymakers, advocacy organizations, and even institutions themselves have advanced different and inconsistent definitions as to what might be considered an MSI. Given these contrasting constructions of MSIs, the purpose of this article is to offer a uniform definition and typology as to how MSIs should be defined and to construct an MSI dataset based upon this approach. We assert that this approach will yield more accuracy to the description and study of MSIs, which will greatly benefit and inform the work of institutional leaders, advocates, policymakers, and the broader MSI research community.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2023 07:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221105861?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Plight of Persistently Disciplined Students: Examining Frequent Flyers and the Conversion of Office Discipline Referrals Into Suspensions</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Racial inequality in exclusionary discipline is a salient educational equity issue. The implications of educators’ discretion in administering discipline and the complexity of repeated office discipline referrals (ODRs) and suspensions are reflected in school discipline policy debates nationwide. This brief uses New York City to learn more about persistently disciplined students. Black students are more likely to be persistently referred than other students. The disparities in the students who are persistently suspended are not as stark as the disparities in the students who are persistently referred. School characteristics play an essential role in predicting persistently disciplined students and the findings reinforce the value of teachers’ diversity and experience and school climate for reducing racial inequality in school discipline.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231155155?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Out of proportion or out of context? Comparing 8- to 9-year-olds’ proportional reasoning abilities across fair-sharing, mixtures, and probability contexts</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;
      Findings on children’s proportional reasoning abilities strongly vary across studies. This might be due to the different contexts that can be used in proportional problems: fair-sharing, mixtures, and probability. A review of the scientific literature suggests that the context of proportional problems may not only impact the difficulty of the problem, but that it also plays an important role in how children approach the problems. In other words, different contexts might elicit different (erroneous) thinking strategies. The aim of the present study was to investigate the role of context in third graders’ (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 305) proportional reasoning abilities. Results showed that children performed significantly better in a fair-sharing context compared to a mixture and a probability context. No evidence was found for a difference in performance on the mixture and the probability context. However, the kind of erroneous answers that were given in the mixture and probability context differed slightly, with more additive answers in the mixture context and more one-dimensional answers in the probability context. These findings suggest that the type of answers elicited by proportional problems might depend on the specific context in which the problem is presented.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10212-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rejoinder to The Role of Empathy in Teaching Culturally Diverse Students: A Qualitative Study of Teachers’ Beliefs</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;After 20 years, the research on empathy in teacher education has grown tremendously. This concept originally explored in our article 20 years ago, raised questions regarding the type of empathy and its potential implications for preparing culturally responsive teachers. Though research on empathy has increased 3-fold, teacher educators still struggle in our preparation of effective teachers for all children. One positive step forward in this recent line of research has been the centering of empathy in a more critical frame cautioning us against the concept of inauthentic or false empathy, as well as questioning whether empathy is enough.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2023 06:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231160376?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining the key factors affecting teachers’ translation of a theoretical framework from English into a native language: the Turkish case</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study was aimed at exploring the key factors affecting postgraduate students-teachers’ translation of a theoretical framework from English into their native language. The research was carried out with 21 Turkish postgraduate students who were also mathematics teachers, based on the theoretical framework of the documentational approach to didactics. The research was designed as a case study. The data were obtained from postgraduate students’ weekly translation papers, the recordings of collective translation sessions, and the researchers’ and the postgraduate students’ reflective notes over a period of 7 weeks. The data were analyzed using descriptive and content analysis in order to investigate the factors influencing difficulties the postgraduate students had while translating. The analyses showed that the task of translating a theoretical framework at the postgraduate level led student-teachers to work on the meaning of the concepts and the unity of the framework and to reinterpret the source text. The research showed that the translation of the theoretical framework was strongly influenced by syntactic, sociocultural, and academic/educational differences, and these factors were interrelated.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01475-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting mathematics and science teachers in implementing intercultural learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Our current multicultural societies require that education addresses diversity and promotes cultural awareness and intercultural learning. Mathematics and science education can also contribute to this aspect of citizenship education and create a culture of belonging for all students. Professional development that integrates intercultural learning with educational practices is still uncommon in the field of science and mathematics teacher preparation and support. This study explores the possibilities to support science and mathematics teachers in implementing intercultural learning through a professional development course. The course was developed in a European setting, based on a theoretical analysis, and tried out with 319 teachers from six participating countries. The impact of the course on teachers’ take up of intercultural learning was measured with a pre-post questionnaire. We found that the course strengthened teachers’ self-efficacy beliefs and extended their teaching practices with opportunities created by cultural diversity among their students or in their subjects. In addition to that, teachers’ self-efficacy beliefs and the perceived cultural diversity in class appeared to be influencing factors for teachers’ practices. Based on our findings we recommend that the combination of intercultural learning with educational practices of mathematics and science might be a suitable gateway to provide new intercultural learning opportunities for students.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01478-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Algebra-focused features of instruction: an integrated investigation of curricular guidance and instructional enactment</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;To be successful in algebra, students need access to high-quality instruction that includes opportunities to develop their algebraic understanding. Yet research on algebra teaching suggests that instruction remains procedurally focused, indicating that teachers may need additional support to provide students such opportunities. One possible lever for improving instruction may be through curricular guidance provided to teachers, specifically through educative materials that provide support for teacher as well as student learning. This study aims to understand how curricular guidance supports teachers to enact the types of instructional practices that support students’ learning opportunities in algebra specifically, and how teachers enact that guidance. We draw from a sample of 29 video observations from six teachers of the same three textbook lessons and use aligned analytic frameworks to examine the curriculum materials and enacted lessons in tandem. We investigate how the curricular guidance provides opportunities for algebra-focused instructional features, how these opportunities are taken up by teachers, and how and in what ways differences in instructional enactments might be related to the curricular opportunities. We find differences in which instructional features varied more by lesson and which varied more by teacher and describe sources of this variation. Curricular guidance supported teachers’ enactments, but teacher-level variation was largely due to teachers going beyond the support provided. This study suggests how curriculum materials can better support teacher learning and provides insight into taking a content-focused approach to studying curricular enactment.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-11-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09573-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Classroom Data Visualization: Tracking Individuals During Group-Centered Instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Understanding students’ participation in collaborative classroom settings is important in a variety of educational contexts, with implications for teaching, research, and equity. Using data from a group-centered developmental mathematics class, this research brief illustrates novel quantitative representations of students’ group participation and their instructor’s classroom activity. Presenting an overview of classroom activities based on audio data, the diagrams show a variety of patterns, including each group’s progression through assigned tasks, some students’ exclusion from discussions of those tasks, and the teacher’s patterns of interaction with groups. The representations provide new ways that researchers might approach and present multilayered classroom data.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-10-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231158374?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Integrated Framework for Studying How Schools Respond to External Pressures</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The changing educational landscape requires new organizational frameworks to understand how schools and universities make sense of and respond to broader institutional forces like accountability, diversity, and the market. In this article, we draw on recent innovations in organizational theory to propose a model that identifies two general processes through which pressures from the environment shape educational practice in schools: filtering and local adaptation. We review three areas where researchers have studied filtering and local adaptation—routines, sensemaking, and networks—to illustrate how these processes are currently being applied in education and how this work can be extended. We also identify studies that have begun to integrate these different areas of scholarship and propose directions for future research. This article offers education researchers new to the field conceptual tools for guiding their analysis and assists more seasoned researchers in situating their studies in a broader context of institutional maintenance, change, and heterogeneity.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-10-2023 03:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231159599?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do So-Called Critical Race Theory Bans Say?</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In the wake of racial justice protests in the United States, many states adopted policies to constrain the discussion of racism, particularly contemporary and systemic racism, in K-12 classrooms. Discursively framed as “critical race theory bans,” these policies enumerate lists of “prohibited concepts” to be eliminated from classroom instruction and curriculum materials. This brief document analysis provides an overview of first-wave prohibited concepts policies among the states to adopt such policies during the 2020-2022 legislative sessions. The analysis summarizes the prohibited concepts, teaching practices that remain allowed, and the nature of the prohibitions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-10-2023 03:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231159382?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Enduring Problems, Rethinking Process, Fulfilling Promises: Reflections on the Continuing Shortage of Teachers of Color</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Thirty years ago, “Problems, process, and promise: Reflections on a collaborative approach to the solution of the minority teacher shortage” (Goodwin, 1991) offered a perspective on an approach to the minority teacher shortage. That piece represented the start of the author’s life-long work on teacher preparation, with a particular focus on the recruitment and retention of teachers of color in response to growing numbers of students of color juxtaposed against a predominantly white teaching force. Now, several decades later, this article is her opportunity to reflect on those early thoughts, framed by the question: What progress have we made (or not) as a profession, and a society, in addressing this imperative? In pondering this question, this piece returns to the focus of the original article to think anew about problems, process, and promise as conceptual lenses for assessing how far we have come and where we now need to go.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2023 09:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231160372?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Literacy Intervention in Secondary Schools: Exploring Educators’ Beliefs and Practices about Supporting Adolescents’ Literacy Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;There is a need to better understand the complex landscape of adolescent literacy intervention as a shared responsibility across all educational stakeholders. To address this need, we examined the self-reported literacy beliefs and practices about secondary readers and literacy intervention among a group of educators (including administrators, teachers, and specialists) who participated in a year-long professional learning series focused on providing adolescents with rich and responsive literacy learning opportunities. We found that educators’ beliefs and practices shifted as they developed shared understandings of asset-based mindsets and ways of supporting students’ situated literacy learning and comprehension within disciplinary contexts. We offer suggestions for how to create shared learning opportunities for educators across roles and discuss implications for future research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2023 08:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231156371?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How narratives about the secondary-tertiary transition shape undergraduate tutors’ sense-making of their teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Drawing on the commognitive framework, we construe the secondary-tertiary transition (STT) as a distinctive element in the pedagogical discourses of various communities. Our interest rests with university tutors in light of the emergent recognition of their impact on undergraduates’ mathematics learning in many tertiary contexts worldwide. We aim to understand the roles of STT communication in tutors’ reflections on incidents that took place in their tutorials. Our participants were undergraduate students in the advanced stages of their mathematics degrees in a large New Zealand university and who were enrolled in a mathematics education course. Throughout the semester, the participants led tutorial sessions for first-year students and wrote reflections on classroom incidents that drew their attention. Our data corpus consisted of 58 reflections from 38 tutors collected over four semesters. The analysis revealed that STT communication featured in tutors’ descriptions of classroom incidents, assisted them in making sense of unexpected events, positioned their instructional actions as replications of what was familiar to them from their own STT experience, and contributed toward generating new pedagogical narratives. We situate these findings in the literature concerning undergraduate tutoring and teachers’ perspectives on STT.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10211-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“If you’re a dude, you’re a chick, whatever the hell in between, you need to know about maths”: the Australian and Canadian general public’s views of gender and mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research on gender issues and mathematics education is often conducted in classroom settings and/or with teachers, students, and parents. However, perspectives about mathematics from adults beyond teachers and parents can have an impact on students. Thus, we conducted research in Australia and Canada about the general public’s views of gender and mathematics. Participants (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 405) were surveyed using a questionnaire in which all questions were worded in a non-binary manner. In this article, we focus on participants’ views about gender and mathematics ability, and the importance of studying mathematics by gender. We report both overall trends and trends by demographic group (country, gender, age, and education level). The majority of participants indicated that there was no relationship between gender and mathematics ability or between gender and the importance of studying mathematics. Participants with gendered views typically felt that boys/men/males are better at mathematics and that it was more important for girls/women/females to study mathematics. Although the findings were generally encouraging, the existence of sexist, stereotyped views highlights the need for additional work to probe people’s views of gender and mathematics. Our study is an example of mathematics education research conducted in a gender-inclusive way.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00448-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘There’s no such thing as a clean line’: an award-winning history teacher’s racial ideologies-in-pieces</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-08-2023 12:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2181330?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We All Sort of Jump to That Relationship Piece”: Science Teachers’ Collaborative Professional Learning about the Role of Relationships in Argumentation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-08-2023 05:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2180006?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
