<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: Leadership takes practice</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt; Kappan editor-in-chief Teresa Preston presents an overview of the May issue on student leadership.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251872?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: Policy, not politics</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 62-63, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The 2024 presidential election features a rematch from four years ago: President Biden and former President Trump. While all presidential elections matter, columnist Jonathan E. Collins argues that this election is especially pivotal to K-12 education policy. Collins poses major education policy questions that we should be asking heading into the upcoming election.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251891?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under The Law: The Israel-Hamas war and U.S. classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 64-65, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Students’ reactions to the Israel-Hamas war have contributed to conflict in higher education institutions and in K-12 schools. There have been numerous reports of protests, bullying, fights, violence, and anti-Semitic and anti-Islamic rhetoric. Robert Kim discusses the legal boundaries regarding free speech and the obligation to protect students from harassment and discrimination.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251892?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: How students are learning to lead</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 68-69, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Educators Rising students describe the most valuable leadership opportunities they’ve had at school, why those opportunities were so important, and what they learned from them.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251894?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 7-7, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this regular column, Kappan authors recommend books and articles that have influenced them. In the May Bookshelf, Thomas Capretta and Barbara Boone recommend Just Schools: Building Equitable Collaborations with Families and Communities by Ann Ishimaru. Lisa DaVia Rubenstein recommends Directing Actors by Judith Weston.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251874?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Backtalk: The harm in assessment-backward practices</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 66-67, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The deprofessionalization and mechanization of teaching that comes from teaching to the test and scripted instruction is prevalent in the United States. Teachers now enter their careers in schooling contexts where they are often expected to apply scripted curriculums with high fidelity, sometimes at odds with the pedagogy and methods they learned in teacher education programs. Amanda S. Frasier argues that the shift to assessment-backward design and the focus on controlling actions and micromanaging behavior of teachers is harming the profession and public education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251893?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: Organizational news about PDK International</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 71-71, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Joni Cordell, a PDK International member from Tensed, Idaho, has volunteered as a competition judge at the association’s annual Educators Rising conference since 2018. She also endowed a PDK International scholarship, the Ladder to Opportunity Scholarship, dedicated to first-generation college students who demonstrate financial need, are English leaders, or are Dreamers — the term for undocumented youth who were brought to the US as children.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251896?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Browsing: Further thoughts on this month’s theme</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 5-6, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research summaries, past articles, quotes, and discussion questions related to the May 2024 Kappan theme, “Students as Leaders.”
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251873?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Empowering everyday leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 8-13, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Leadership is often conceptualized and taught through famous, world-changing individuals; however, leadership spans levels of influence, from small-group projects to global initiatives. While student leaders are present at every level, existing leadership research and programs center adults. Within this article, Lisa DaVia Rubenstein, Sydney Johnson, Allison Southworth, and Gerardo Ramirez propose the 4L Continuum of Leadership, which recognizes the distinct processes and skills necessary at each level of leadership. With an emphasis on little-l leadership, they integrate specific interpersonal and strategic skill development opportunities into existing curriculum areas. This work empowers all learners to cultivate their leadership potential.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251875?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Possibilities of student voice</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 14-19, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Student voice initiatives like surveys, student councils, and classes focused on leadership and agency all provide youth a way to share their opinions about school-based issues and take action to rectify them to some degree. But the way each initiative is leveraged, the experiences of the young people and educators involved, and the initiatives’ varied goals complicate a singular definition of student voice. Dane Stickney and Julissa Ventura identify levels of student voice to help educators and school leaders in assessing current student-centered approaches and create new, more transformative options that deeply motivate and engage youth.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251876?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: Parents blaming teacher for child’s misbehavior</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 70-70, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Phyllis L. Fagell offers workplace advice to educators. In this month’s column, a teacher is frustrated by parents who blame her for their son’s misbehavior instead of partnering with her to help him. How can she avoid approaching them in anger?
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251895?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student leadership in family-school partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 20-25, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Thomas J. Capretta, Jingyang (Max) Zhang, Eric M. Anderman, and Barbara J. Boone revisit Joyce Epstein’s 1995 Kappan article on overlapping spheres of influence and family-school partnerships. They highlight one idea from the article that has been largely overlooked — the role of student voice and leadership. To refocus researchers’ and practitioners’ attention to the role of students in family and community partnership, they synthesize existing research to elaborate on Epstein’s original models and ideas. They provide three levels of research-based, practical recommendations for districts and schools to elevate student roles and cultivate student leadership in family-school engagement efforts. Finally, they illustrate what these practices look like in schools using an Ohio school district as an example.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251877?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating student leaders through civics</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 26-31, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Building on the literature of student leadership development, Natalie Sew, Adrianne Billingham Bock, and Danielle Allen share an approach to civic education: Deeper Civic Learning. This approach offers students the opportunity to develop the knowledge, skills, and key civic dispositions needed to engage in their communities and develop their leadership capacities. This article shares insights from the authors’ work co-designing an 8th-grade civics curriculum with Massachusetts educators. It highlights student perspectives on their experiences with the curriculum through extended stories of the application of civic skills and dispositions in their lives.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251878?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Poll Points: What’s the public perception of teacher shortages?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 72-72, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The public divides on the severity of teacher shortages: 51% call it either a crisis (16%) or a serious problem but not a crisis (35%). Nearly as many, 47%, call it either not a serious problem (31%) or not a problem at all (16%). Partisanship and ideology are big factors; having a child younger than 18 at home is not.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251897?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Good conflict</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 32-37, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The capacity to navigate conflict and solve problems will persist as an essential skill of the future, even if today’s students will be doing jobs that haven’t been invented yet. What are we doing in schools right now to ensure students have these skills? For nearly a decade, a program called Speak Truth has taught students to use their voices, concerns, and capacity to build bridges as tools for understanding different viewpoints and collaborating to lead change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251879?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Authentic student voice at the board table: A conversation with Jennifer Tran of the National Student Board Member Association</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 38-41, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Jennifer Tran, the first student board member in California’s Garden Grove Independent School District, is an advocate for authentic student participation in the governance of school districts. She successfully petitioned her school district to add a student member to the board of education. In this Kappan interview, she discusses the challenges of serving on the board as a student, how her status as a preferential voter affected her ability make change, and how the National Student Board Member Association (NSBMA) helps to advocate for and provide training to student board members.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251880?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Invigorating principal/assistant principal relationships</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 44-47, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Relationships between and among school administrative team members are critical components of school culture. They serve as a guidepost for the behaviors and attitudes of staff and students. To invigorate these relationships, three embodied practices have high yield not only for the relationships among administrators, but also for fostering a healthy school climate. These practices include intellectual work, communicative collaboration, and inspiration-seeking practices. Sonja Gedde, a high school assistant principal, describes how these practices have been central to the administrative team’s professional relationship with their principal.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251881?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An AI wishlist from school leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 48-51, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;To better understand the current challenges surrounding the use of artificial intelligence (AI) in K-12 schools, a team of researchers (Raffaella Borasi, David E. Miller, Patricia Vaughan-Brogan, Karen DeAngelis, Yu Jung Han, and Sharon Mason) interviewed 36 western New York school leaders in late 2023. Their concerns moved beyond potential cheating, as they instead identified four main priorities: receiving guidance to inform their decisions about AI, empowering all stakeholders to better understand AI and its implications, capitalizing on AI to support the work of teachers and staff, and enabling better technology solutions. These should inform future interventions aiming at leveraging AI in K-12 education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251882?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Addressing inconsistencies in grading practices</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 52-57, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;School leaders struggle in their efforts to implement standards-based grading reforms in large part because they fail to address the inconsistency in grading practices among individual teachers. This article describes three crucial steps necessary to gain greater consistency in teachers’ grading practices: (1) Reaching consensus on a purpose statement for grading; (2) using grading scales with four to seven categories of student performance; and (3) reporting multiple grades to describe academic achievement and non-academic aspects of students’ performance separately. These steps provide the necessary foundation for successful implementation of standards-based and competency-based grading reforms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251883?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Person: Learning to have difficult conversations as a school leader</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;One of the greatest challenges for school administrators is navigating the difficult conversations that come with the territory of the role. Maury Grebenau shares his own path as an administrator who feared such conversations to someone who embraces them.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251884?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning with Leaders: Education is the way: Tony Thurmond</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/8&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 8&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-61, May 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Tony Thurmond, California’s state superintendent of public instruction, talks with James F. Lane about student leadership, the teacher shortage, and Thurmond’s recent announcement that he is running for governor of California.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241251885?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Research Hidden in Plain Sight: Theorizing Latent Use as a Form of Research Use</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Calls for evidence-based practice are pervasive. In response, extensive scholarship has employed four categories of research use—instrumental, symbolic, conceptual, and imposed—to examine how research is used in schools and districts. We draw on sociocultural learning theory and empirical data from one school district to newly theorize latent use as another category of research use. We define latent use as when educators participate with a research-embedded tool in ways that guide their work practice. We call this “latent” use because educators use research via their participation with tools embedded with research quotes, citations, and/or summaries rather than directly engaging with traditional research products (e.g., journal articles). We then discuss latent use&#39;s potential merits and limitations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 06:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241237455?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>IJRUME Celebrates its 10th Volume!</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-29-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00238-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Deficit to Difference: Understanding the Relationship Between K–12 Teacher Training and Disability Discussion</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;One major responsibility of K–12 teachers in United States public schools is to meet the needs of disabled students. While many preservice and in-service teacher training programs present educators with information related to service delivery as outlined in a student’s Individualized Education Program or 504 plan, they rarely address how to talk about disability with all students. This qualitative study examines 50 in-service teachers’ experiences related to disability training and explores the implications of this training on teachers’ disability discussion practices. Findings reveal that teacher training is primarily focused on compliance and “fixing” disability; training and prior experiences affect how teachers define disability; and training affects the framework that teachers use when discussing disability with their students. Based on the findings of this study, we offer recommendations to help programs reimagine training and view disability as a minoritized identity. Results of this study address a significant gap in preparing teachers for disability discussion.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-27-2024 10:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241245089?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
