<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>US and Chinese elementary teachers’ noticing of cross-cultural mathematics videos</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study aims to explore teacher noticing differences of the sampled US and Chinese elementary teachers from cross-cultural mathematics videos. A total of 34 expert teachers commented on 25 video clips online. We coded what and how teachers noticed from the videos both quantitatively and qualitatively. Findings reveal teachers’ strong interests and profound reflections, especially in the teaching domain including representations, communication, and teacher questioning/guide. Cross-cultural differences in teacher noticing were identified, which were discussed based on possible cultural influences. Implications in research and practice, teacher support, and methodology are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 16:29</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09526-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The use of carefully planned board work to support the productive discussion of multiple student responses in a Japanese problem-solving lesson</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we analyse a grade 8 (age 13–14) Japanese problem-solving lesson involving angles associated with parallel lines, taught by a highly regarded, expert Japanese mathematics teacher. The focus of our observation was on how the teacher used carefully planned board work to support a rich and extensive plenary discussion (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;neriage&lt;/em&gt;) in which he shifted the focus from individual mathematical solutions to generalised properties. By comparing the teacher’s detailed prior planning of the board work (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;bansho&lt;/em&gt;) with that which he produced during the lesson, we distinguish between aspects of the lesson that he considered essential and those he treated as contingent. Our analysis reveals how the careful planning of the board work enabled the teacher to be free to explore with the students the multiple alternative solution methods that they had produced, while at the same time having a clear overall purpose relating to how angle properties can be used to find additional solution methods. We outline how these findings from within the strong tradition of the Japanese problem-solving lesson might inform research and teaching practice outside of Japan, where a deep heritage of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;bansho&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;neriage&lt;/em&gt; is not present. In particular, we highlight three prominent features of this teacher’s practice: the detailed lesson planning in which particular solutions were prioritised for discussion; the considerable amount of time given over to student generation and comparison of alternative solutions; and the ways in which the teacher’s use of the board was seen to support the richness of the mathematical discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 16:29</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09511-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An analysis of elementary prospective teachers’ noticing of student pattern generalization strategies in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, hypothetical samples of students’ work on a task involving pattern generalizations were used to examine the characteristics of the ways in which 154 elementary prospective teachers (PSTs) paid attention to students’ work in mathematics. The analysis included what the PSTs attended to, their interpretations, and their suggestions for supporting students’ further learning. While the findings showed that the PSTs noticed a wide range of aspects of mathematical learning, their analyses of students’ thinking and their ideas for supporting students’ learning lacked sophistication. Also, there was considerable divergence between the students’ thinking as evidenced in the hypothetical problem solutions and the PSTs’ suggested support. Based on these findings, we provide some suggestions for teacher education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 16:29</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09520-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Providing a video-case-based professional development environment for prospective mathematics teachers to notice students’ misconceptions in measurement</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This qualitative study examined how prospective mathematics teachers attend to, interpret, and respond to student misconceptions through providing them a video-case-based professional development environment. A sample of 30 prospective teachers attending an elective course was asked to watch video cases about student misconceptions related to the concept of measurement. Then, class discussions were held on the misconceptions, reasons, and suggestions to remedy the misconceptions. Thereafter they individually wrote down their response to an open-ended question asking them how to remedy the misconceptions. Data obtained from the discussions and individual reports were analyzed using the content analysis technique with the framework of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;professional noticing of children’s mathematical thinking&lt;/em&gt;. Findings indicated that the professional development environment provided prospective teachers with an opportunity to attend to, interpret, and then decide how to respond to student misconceptions. We found that while prospective teachers generally understand how students think and why misconceptions arise, they mostly provided partial evidence for interpreting. Moreover, their suggestions for addressing mathematical misconceptions were generally based on conceptual understanding. Our findings suggested that in order to acquire skills in noticing student thinking, it is important that prospective teachers have sufficient opportunity to reflect on likely misconceptions in a professional context.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 16:29</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09525-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Doing the math together: coaches’ professional learning through engagement in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics coaching is complex work, and coaches must be supported to become experts in mathematics, mathematics instruction, and mathematics coaching. Using video and interview data from 12 mathematics coaches and one district administrator in one public school district in the southeastern USA, this qualitative study explores how the performative aspect of one group of mathematics coaches’ &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;doing the math&lt;/em&gt; routine opened up conversations about mathematics, mathematics instruction, and mathematics coaching. Findings indicate that as the coaches engaged in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;doing the math&lt;/em&gt; together, opportunities to discuss mathematics and mathematics instruction were opened up, while conversations about mathematics coaching rarely surfaced. In interviews, participants discussed the benefits and drawbacks of participating in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;doing the math.&lt;/em&gt; Implications for future research and practice are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 16:29</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09527-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collaborative identity development during a global pandemic: exploring teacher identity through the experiences of pre-service high school teachers in England</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 09:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2175663?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ate scholars: Cultivating community amongst multiracial women of color in graduate school</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 05:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2192950?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘This is almost like Ruby Bridges’: young children’s demonstration of racial literacy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 05:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2192948?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/31/2&quot;&gt;Volume 31, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, April 2023, Page 175-179&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 05:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2186662?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Optimizing Diagnostic Classification Models Application Considering Real-Life Constraints</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article provides a process to carefully evaluate the suitability of a content domain for which diagnostic classification models (DCMs) could be applicable and then optimized steps for constructing a test blueprint for applying DCMs and a real-life example illustrating this process. The content domains were carefully evaluated using a set of defined criteria, which are purposely defined to improve the success rate of DCM implementation. Given the domain, the Q-matrix is determined by a simulation-based approach using correct classification rates as criteria. Finally, a physics test on the final Q-matrix was developed, administered, and analyzed by the author and the subject-matter experts (SMEs).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 05:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231159137?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Finding the Right Grain-Size for Measurement in the Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article introduces a new framework for articulating how educational assessments can be related to teacher uses in the classroom. It articulates three levels of assessment: macro (use of standardized tests), meso (externally developed items), and micro (on-the-fly in the classroom). The first level is the usual context for educational measurement, but one of the contributions of this article is that it mainly focuses on the latter two levels. Co-ordination of the content across these two levels can be achieved using the concept of a construct map, which articulates the substantive target property at levels of detail that are appropriate for both teacher planning and within-classroom use. This article then describes a statistical model designed to span these two levels and discusses how best to relate this to the macrolevel. Results from a curriculum and instruction development project on the topic of measurement in the elementary school are demonstrated, showing how they are empirically related.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 05:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231159006?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Restricted DINA Model: A Comprehensive Cognitive Diagnostic Model for Classroom-Level Assessments</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The nonparametric classification (NPC) method has been proven to be a suitable procedure for cognitive diagnostic assessments at a classroom level. However, its nonparametric nature impedes the obtention of a model likelihood, hindering the exploration of crucial psychometric aspects, such as model fit or reliability. Reporting the reliability and validity of scores is imperative in any applied context. The present study proposes the restricted deterministic input, noisy “and” gate (R-DINA) model, a parametric cognitive diagnosis model based on the NPC method that provides the same attribute profile classifications as the nonparametric method while allowing to derive a model likelihood and, subsequently, to compute fit and reliability indices. The suitability of the new proposal is examined by means of an exhaustive simulation study and a real data illustration. The results show that the R-DINA model properly recovers the posterior probabilities of attribute mastery, thus becoming a suitable alternative for comprehensive small-scale diagnostic assessments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 05:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231158829?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Gauging 21st Century Competencies of Chinese Students: A Rural-Urban Comparative Perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 02:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2181245?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Students Benefit from Computer-Based Individualized Instruction? Experimental Evidence from Public Schools in India</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 01:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2191604?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>New insights about the secondary–tertiary transition in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this concluding commentary, I embed the articles of the special issue “Transition from school into university mathematics: experiences across educational contexts” into the current landscape of research on secondary–tertiary transition, and discuss the advancement they made related to the synthesis published in 2008 by Gueudet. My aim is to elaborate a new synthesis across the topics of affect and the use of sociocultural perspectives that have framed the work of all contributions. For that, I focus on four major themes. First, I consider the complex relationship between affect and socio-cultural dimensions in the papers, which raises the need for theory networking in further research clarifying mutual roles of the two dimensions. Second, international diversity is only partially expressed in the collection of papers, thus should be a major topic of research in future that would provide a more comprehensive view on the transition from school to university mathematics. I thirdly discuss how the collection of papers deepens our understanding of the complexity and diversity related to the students’ experience with the secondary–tertiary transition and its potential impact for teaching. Finally, I propose and justify the need for systematic design and evaluation of interventions targeting a change in students’ affect related to the transition. In sum, the wide range of the significant findings in this special issue and their mutual relations add new perspectives to the research on secondary–tertiary transition and evidence a new spectrum of research directions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-31-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10223-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the impacts of the Rebel mascot: insights gained from school-based helping professionals</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2023 08:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2192951?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Just go to the office! An intersectional exploration of the role of race and gender in discipline referral reasons</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2023 06:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2192946?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>(Mis)educating England: eurocentric narratives in secondary school history textbooks</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2023 06:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2192945?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racial Literacy Development (RLD) via ethnic studies: Latinx youth speaking back to and resisting Racism</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2023 06:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2192914?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Universal Early Childhood Education and Care for Toddlers and Achievement Outcomes in Middle Childhood</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2023 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2187325?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“That is Still STEM”: Appropriating the Engineering Design Process to Challenge Dominant Narratives of Engineering and STEM</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2023 01:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2022.2156512?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Landscape Analysis of State-Level School Counseling Policy: Perspectives from State Officials</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study explores the prevalence and implementation of four key school counseling policies at the state level and to what extent they are monitored for positive impact on the school counseling profession. Drawing on an analysis of state school counseling policy documents and interviews with school counseling leaders from 30 state education agencies, we found that policies vary considerably across states. Within states, the constrained authority of state counseling officials and lack of funded counseling mandates contributed to differences in policy implementation at the local level. These barriers can unintentionally reduce the efficacy of counseling policies and thus their impact on students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2023 01:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231163803?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“The Good Struggle” of Flexible Specificity: Districts Balancing Specific Guidance With Autonomy to Support Standards-Based Instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examines implementation of college-and-career-ready (CCR) education standards across five school districts in Ohio, Texas, California, Pennsylvania, and Massachusetts. Drawing on the policy attributes theory, we found that the specificity of districts’ approaches to two long-recognized policy levers, curriculum and professional learning, was critical in shaping how stakeholders implemented and experienced CCR policies. We identified an approach we called “flexible specificity”—flexibility informed by ongoing data collection and evaluation that allowed districts to develop specific, useful guidance about curriculum and professional learning based on stakeholder needs. We present four shared practices characterizing this approach in two districts, analyzing why those districts seemed to find the right balance of specificity and flexibility while others struggled.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2023 01:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231161037?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting adults to become numerate citizens: a study of adult numeracy provision in Ireland</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper revisits and reanalyses data from a study carried out in the further education and training sector in the Republic of Ireland to investigate (1) how adults access and participate in numeracy courses and (2) how adult numeracy provision might support active citizenship. We analysed 45 interviews with adult education providers, adult numeracy tutors, and adult learners to identify themes that connect adult numeracy with a human rights conception of citizenship as access to and participation in economic, social, and community life. This analysis found that the most common barriers to accessing adult numeracy courses arose from dispositional factors relating to fear, anxiety and lack of confidence with mathematics, largely due to negative experiences in formal schooling. To overcome these barriers, adults’ participation in numeracy courses was encouraged by integrating numeracy learning activities into real world contexts in a non-threatening learning environment. The interview analysis also illustrated ways in which adult numeracy education supported active citizenship in the economic, social, and community spheres, by (i) enhancing financial literacy and preparing adults for employment; (ii) fostering individual empowerment, family learning and social inclusion; and (iii) enabling civic engagement. Policies for promoting adult education typically aim to develop active citizenship, but without specifying how this is to be achieved. Our study is valuable because it illuminates potential connections between citizenship and numeracy as a dimension of adult education that is separate from literacy. The findings lead to recommendations for translating national and international policy frameworks into research-informed adult education programs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01480-9</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
