<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Decentring research on mathematics teacher education: Why does it matter?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-19-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09655-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining the role played by resources, goals and orientations in primary teachers’ decision- making for problem-solving lesson plans</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The decisions that teachers make in transforming the curriculum into specific lesson plans determine the real enactment or otherwise of curricular ideals. These decisions are shaped by the resources available and by each teacher’s goals and orientations. This exploratory study employs Schoenfeld’s decision-making model to examine how resources, goals and orientations influence lesson planning for mathematics problem solving, for different profiles of primary teachers in Chile. To this purpose, a survey was conducted among 40 teachers of varying degrees of ability and experience: some were beginning teachers, others were experienced but had no further training in teaching problem solving and a third group was composed of experienced teachers with specific training in this question. Interviews with two teachers from each profile revealed important differences between the three groups. Beginning teachers relied more heavily on official resources such as the official curriculum and standard textbooks, aligning themselves with school requirements. Experienced teachers with problem solving training demonstrated a strong inclination towards teaching through a problem solving approach. While beginning teachers acknowledged the importance of promoting problem solving strategies, they did not usually adapt problems to the mathematical content or to the age/competence of their students. Interestingly, all three groups under-utilised sections of curricular resources that emphasise the present curricular focus on problem solving. Finally, the study found that experience alone is not enough to develop a problem solving approach and that focused professional development programmes are needed to equip teachers with the necessary skills. In addition, a diagnostic teaching approach should be incorporated into initial teacher training.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01614-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Contributions to the characterization of the Schema using APOS theory: Graphing with derivative</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study contributes to Action, Process, Object, Schema (APOS) theory research by showing two approaches used by advanced mathematics students to construct relations between higher-order derivatives to solve complex problems. We show evidence of students’ ability to perform Actions on their graphing derivative Schema, that is, of its thematization. It also contributes to the literature on the learning of differential calculus by showing how advanced students use their knowledge to construct relations between concepts when facing complex situations. The work of three graduate students on transforming complex graphs and determining their properties and their relation to the domain structure is analyzed to determine their solution approaches. Their graphing derivative Schema is analyzed in depth in terms of the construction of relations among the Schema structures and assimilation and accommodation mechanisms involved in thematization in APOS theory. These findings are important in informing and developing didactic strategies to foster university students’ understanding of derivatives, which can smoothe the transition to the study of advanced mathematics courses.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01615-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Salience and feasibility of enacting rough draft math: Teachers’ voices about productive and powerful variations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Rough draft math [RDM] (Jansen, 2020a) occurs when a teacher invites students to share their in-progress thinking and provides opportunities for students to revise their thinking. RDM could be viewed as an approach to ambitious teaching because it is a practice when teachers elicit and respond to students’ thinking to support their learning, which is productive, and their positive identity development, which is powerful. The purpose of this study was to identify salient and feasible enactments of rough draft math, as described by teachers after they have learned about RDM through a book study and/or professional development. We interviewed 32 teachers in eight states in the USA, and we identified variations among the two most feasible and salient enactments of RDM: (1) inviting students to revise and (2) purposeful task selection and implementation. Variations in revising enactments included providing students with structured or unstructured revision opportunities and different ways teachers incorporated revising into their assessment practices (either test corrections or student self-assessment). Variations in task selection included modifying curricular tasks or using instructional routines intentionally. Variations in task implementation included implementing tasks to reinforce content or develop new understandings. We developed conjectures about the ways in which these variations could provide powerful or productive opportunities for students.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09650-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluation Policy Study of the Second Round of the Taiwan Teacher Preparation Program Evaluation</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study focuses on the second round of Taiwanese teacher preparation program (TPP) evaluation (2012–2017) to analyze how evaluation policy shapes TPPs. In-depth interviews were conducted with 13 stakeholders, which included professors, administrators, researchers, and staff involved in TPP evaluation. First, the findings revealed that neoliberalism influences evaluation policy and restricts the diversity of TPP development. Second, different evaluation approaches may be used to bring more inclusiveness and flexibility to evaluation standards. Third, evaluation plays an important role in TPP development, and a professional organization responsible for evaluation should be established in Taiwan in the future. To conclude, it is significant for TPP evaluation policy to consider policy ideology, evaluation standards, and program diversity to aid in improving the quality of teacher education not only in Taiwan but also internationally.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-16-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241276023?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Profiles in Research: Lawrence J. Hubert</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-16-2024 06:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241265095?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How visualization and argumentation are articulated in research on teaching and learning geometry</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Visualization and argumentation are central processes in the learning of geometry, giving rise to specific lines of research in mathematics education. However, it is worth asking whether they should be developed independently or if it is possible and in what way an articulation between them can be promoted. The objective of this paper is to search for this articulation within the most recent advances in empirical research on the teaching and learning of geometry in Spain. The analysis is approached through the tasks used in research employing two theoretical frameworks which have been developed in Spain, the Onto-Semiotic Approach and Configurational Reasoning. Two main types of task were found in the selected studies: visual tasks and conjecture-and-proof tasks. The results show that in visual tasks the articulation between visualization and argumentation is only necessary in some tasks, in which argumentation aims to justify or to describe the external representation provided as a solution. However, in conjecture-and-proof tasks the articulation between visualization and argumentation must always be present to resolve the task. Analyzing this articulation helps to detect and gain a better understanding of the difficulties that students encounter in solving these types of task. In visual tasks, argumentation helps to understand difficulties associated with the use of visualization. In conjecture-and-proof tasks, visualization determines the argumentation followed, in such a way that many of the difficulties originate more from the visualization than from the process of argumentation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-16-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01619-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Addressing Missing Data Due to COVID-19: Two Early Childhood Case Studies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-15-2024 07:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2321438?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking Contradictions and Inconsistencies in Teachers’ Sensemaking and Actions</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher education research, by and large, has been profoundly influenced by psychological interpretations of beliefs, particularly the assumption that teachers attempt to reconcile, rationalize, minimize, or avoid contradictions. Building on research across multiple disciplines, which demonstrates that people live harmoniously with contradictions in many situations, we argue that suppositions that people feel compelled to address contradictions have obscured the multitude of inconsistencies that teachers navigate without notice in their everyday lives. Through a multisited, in-depth analysis of a teacher across planning, teaching, debrief and interview contexts, we show that what appears to be contradictory from the perspective of researchers is not necessarily inconsistent for teachers. We explore the theoretical, methodological, and professional learning implications of this shift in interpreting teacher contradictions and inconsistencies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-15-2024 06:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241268593?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mechanisms and evidence of prospective teachers’ learning through enquiry-oriented practices: the case of a lesson study intervention</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Existing research has highlighted the key role of observation and reflection in teacher learning during lesson study interventions, and how challenging it can be for pre-service teachers. This study focuses on the post-lesson discussion phase and on the observation of the research lesson of a lesson study process. It is carried out with early childhood education pre-service teachers who studied the Theory of Didactical Situations. The aim of our research is two-fold: finding evidence of the activation of pre-service teacher knowledge during the post-lesson discussion, and identifying mechanisms that may explain said activation as well as the potential development of their professional knowledge. To model pre-service teacher knowledge, the notion of teachers’ praxeological equipment from the Anthropological Theory of the Didactic, specified in the Theory of Didactical Situations, is used. It is hypothesised that potential teacher learning is mainly connected to the identification of particularly relevant episodes during the observation phase, henceforth referred to as critical events. The analysis of a group discussion on three critical events shows the activation and development of mathematical and didactic components of pre-service teachers’ praxeological equipment. However, it is found that it depends on the degree of dissonance these events can provoke, and on the quality and depth of the discussion that takes place around them. It is therefore concluded that the identification of critical events followed by productive discussion is a mechanism that explains teacher learning through lesson study, which can be enhanced by the intervention of teacher educators as mediators.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01620-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Examination of Content-Specific Leadership: District-Level Mathematics Specialists’ Sense-Making and Enactment of Their Leadership Role</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-14-2024 12:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2391257?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Politics and Children&#39;s Books: Evidence From School Library Collections</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The recent spike in book challenges has put school libraries at the center of heated political debates. I investigate the relationship between local politics and school library collections using data on books with controversial content from a sample of 6,631 public school libraries. Libraries in conservative areas have fewer titles with LGBTQ, race/racism, or abortion content and more Christian fiction and discontinued Dr. Seuss books. This is true even though most libraries have at least some controversial content. State laws that restrict curricular content are negatively related to access to some LGBTQ and race/racism titles. Finally, I present short-term evidence that book challenges in the 2021–22 school year are associated with decreases in the acquisition of new LGBTQ materials.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-14-2024 04:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241248512?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical literacy in context</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-13-2024 08:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2390744?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Interactive Television Instruction (ITV) to Reduce the Propensity to Engage in Substance Abuse and Drug Trafficking Among Vulnerable Adolescents in Nigeria</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examined the impact of ITV intervention on reduction in the propensity to abuse substances and engage in drug trafficking. The researcher conducted this study using an experiment of 517 vulnerable adolescents aged 10–19 years. The participants were randomly assigned to control (n = 258) and treatment (n = 259) groups. The researchers found a significant main effect of treatment conditions on reduction in the propensity to engage in substance abuse and drug trafficking among vulnerable adolescents. That is, before the intervention, there was no significant statistical difference between the control and treatment groups on the propensity to engage in substance abuse and drug trafficking. However, vulnerable children who received the intervention reported a significant reduction in propensity after the intervention. The results highlight the usefulness of ITV as a behaviour change strategy for vulnerable children.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-13-2024 07:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241273288?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Intention to Action: How Preservice Teachers Use Technology-Enabled Learning During Student Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This qualitative, embedded single case study provides a rich description exploring the evolution of preservice teachers’ intention to use and actual use of technology-enabled learning (TEL) during student teaching. The study followed four middle-level education majors at a mid-size public teaching university in the southeastern United States during their student teaching experience (spring 2021). Ajzen’s Theory of Planned Behavior (TPB) guided this qualitative inquiry. Interviews, observations, and analysis of teaching artifacts (e.g., lesson plans, lesson reflections, and TEL artifacts) were conducted to support data triangulation. In addition to applying theory-based qualitative codes to the data, open coding was conducted to identify themes across the body of evidence. Findings extended previous TPB research regarding preservice teachers’ intention to use TEL in application use cases and yield practical implications for teacher educators seeking to increase TEL intention and use in preservice teacher populations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-13-2024 06:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241268577?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The College Mathematics Beliefs and Belonging Survey: Instrument Development and Validation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reports on the development and validation process of a new measure—the College Mathematics Beliefs and Belonging (CMBB) survey. The CMBB provides a contemporary measurement of undergraduate students’ perceptions of their mathematical practices and reasoning, beliefs about mathematics, and sense of belonging in mathematics. Primarily first- and second-year undergraduate students in five mathematics courses at a large public university in the United States completed multiple surveys to provide the data used for survey development. Confirmatory factor analysis (N = 935) along with additional psychometric evidence detailed here indicate that the CMBB is a survey with fifteen factors that adequately measure various aspects of perceived mathematical practices and reasoning, beliefs, and sense of belonging. The CMBB survey is intended for use by researchers and instructors to assess undergraduate students’ perceptions across these three domains with the aim of improving students’ experiences in college mathematics courses.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00247-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematicians’ Conceptualizations of Differentials in Calculus and Differential Equations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The symbol &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(dx\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; is one example of a differential, a calculus symbol that is found in multiple settings and expressions. Literature suggests that students have both many and varied conceptualizations of these differentials. For example, is &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(dx\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; a very small quantity? How small does it have to be? Is it merely notation? For our study, we interviewed ten mathematicians to determine how experts conceptualize differentials presented in multiple mathematical contexts, such as differentiation, integration, and differential equations. Using thematic analysis, we analyzed their responses and found that our interview subjects’ conceptualizations were likewise many and varied, with many different interpretations offered for the same differentials. In this paper, we present results from our study and the initial classification system that emerged from this data, while understanding that ongoing and future research may expand and deepen our initial classification system.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00254-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Digital Experiences of Mathematical Cognitive Functions in Learning the Basic Concepts of General Topology</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper aims at defining and exploring design principles in a distance technological setting for an educational activity for mathematics undergraduate students, devoted to the construction of basic concepts in general topology, the promotion of problem-solving processes, the development of metacognitive aspects, and, in general, the development of the students’ mathematical identity. The design exploits the production of examples and investigation of variations and invariants, exploration of problems and generation of conjectures, and an extension intertwining of the ‘inside-out’ model from the Digital Interactive Storytelling in Mathematics with the Thinking Classroom model at university education. We present a didactic activity based on the identified design principles and discuss the preliminary results of a pilot carried out with fifty mathematics undergraduate students, attending their second year of the mathematics degree.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00245-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Long Winter</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00327-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘A teacher’s work is many things, but one thing it is not is easy’: pre-service teachers’ conceptions of teachers’ work</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-12-2024 10:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2388630?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student teachers’ reactions to formative teacher and peer feedback</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-12-2024 10:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2385717?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Harnessing AI for Educational Measurement: Standards and Emerging Frontiers</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The surge of AI in education raises concerns about measurement downsides. Calls for clear standards are warranted. Fortunately, the psychometrics field has a long history of developing relevant standards—like sample invariance and item bias avoidance—crucial for reliable, valid, and interpretable assessments. This established body of knowledge, not unlike traffic laws for self-driving cars, should guide AI assessment development. Measuring new constructs necessitates stronger construct validity research. Instead of rewriting the rulebook, our focus should be on educating AI developers about these standards. This commentary specifically addresses the concern of empowering instructors not with high-stakes testing but with effective item writing through AI. We explore the potential of AI to transform item development, a key area highlighted by researchers. While AI tools offer exciting possibilities for tackling educational challenges, equipping instructors to leverage them effectively remains paramount.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-12-2024 06:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241264033?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Iterative Attribute Hierarchy Exploration Methods for Cognitive Diagnosis Models</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Attribute hierarchies are commonly assumed to exist in many fields of psychological and educational assessment. Several theory-driven and data-driven approaches have been used to validate or explore attribute hierarchies, such as validating attribute hierarchies in the cognitive diagnostic model (CDM) through statistical hypothesis testing or even learning attribute hierarchies directly from data. A class of structural parameter standard error estimation methods for CDMs is useful for exploring attribute hierarchies, with the limitation that the information matrices of some model parameters may be unstable or singular, leading to biased hypothesis testing. An iterative method of attribute hierarchy testing was proposed to modify the original z-statistic method. The simulation study systematically compares the performance of the z-statistic and the iterative z-statistic in exploring the attribute hierarchy. The results show that the iterative z-statistic provides a better Type I error control rate and statistical power, and it partially solves the problem that the z-statistic is too conservative. In addition, the iterative z-statistic method also achieves satisfactory results on real data.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-12-2024 06:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241268906?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The “scenario” as a key educational tool in the simulation centre</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-12-2024 01:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2389285?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
