<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Family Child Care Program Closure in Alabama During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Family child care (FCC) is uniquely positioned to address challenges with insufficient early care and education supply and access in the United States. FCC programs were steadily declining before COVID-19, and many child care programs, both center- and home-based, were at risk of closure early in the pandemic. This study examines closure among Alabama FCC providers during COVID-19. Specifically, we examine the timing and predictors of FCC providers’ closure using discrete time-hazard modeling. We analyze administrative data for the 788 FCC programs licensed in March 2020. Over the following 28 months, FCC closure risk was closely linked with COVID-19 disease spread trends. Providers who participated in child care subsidy or national accreditation had lower closure risk than those who did not. The protective effects of subsidy participation were amplified in lower-opportunity communities. Results have implications for mitigating FCC decline and identifying resources to support FCC providers’ continued operation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 10:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231213083?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The accountability paradigm post-NCLB: Policy Ideas and Moral Narratives</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;For decades, policymakers in the U.S. have leveraged accountability policy as a governing tool to lift school performance and close the achievement gap. Accountability become so widespread that it arguably became a “policy paradigm” with the passage of the federal No Child Left Behind (NCLB) Act in 2002. Yet after just 13 years of implementation, policymakers replaced NCLB with the Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA), which gave states more control over the policy tools and mechanisms to regulate school improvement. This qualitative project captured the evolution of the accountability paradigm by studying the policy ideas and moral narratives of policy elites in California and Tennessee during the transition period between NCLB and ESSA. The study finds that interview participants legitimized the core design features of ESSA, but attached their underlying worldviews and beliefs to the flexible design features, which created unique accountability models with different institutional arrangements.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231215487?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Person: Make every child the brightest star</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this personal column, Educator Shanshan Wang recounts her experience helping Jack, an 8-year-old student, become more confident in the classroom. Despite myriad academic struggles, including dyslexia, the student’s hands-on abilities and rich imagination showed through in his devotion to crafting the perfect paper airplane. Wang’s experiences with Jack inspired her to create opportunities for all students to share their knowledge and skills with their classmates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219407?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reducing harm for the LGBTQ+ community</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 46-51, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Despite progress in recent years, members of the LGBTQ+ community remain underrepresented and underserved in the school system. Ferial Pearson and Steven Gill draw on research literature and their own experiences as out queer educators to recommend a set of actions educators can take to reduce harm to members of these communities in school. They call for explicit safe/brave spaces and school cultures, support for LGBTQ+ educators, greater representation in school curricula, and professional development for teachers. Current research shows the benefits of these approaches, but more research is needed to learn what school-level practices and policy changes will be most beneficial to students in different regions and with different intersecting identities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219405?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A new North Star</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 52-56, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Leadership gurus often put creating a “shared vision” at the top of their pyramid of what successful leaders do. These visions are best when they are an anchor or a North Star – unwavering goals that the district works toward. Author Jon Saphier proposes this North Star for districts: Make every school an engine for continuous improvement of high-expertise teaching for equity. Saphier writes that the statement conjures concrete images of what to do to improve the experience of children and their learning. It comes with deep anchors in the research base on instructional improvement, deep roots in the literature of healthy organizational culture, and direct ties to the lived experiences of students in school.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219406?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning with Leaders: Rally around the kids: Angélica Infante-Green</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-61, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In the Learning with Leaders column, PDK CEO James F. Lane talks with Angélica Infante-Green, the Rhode Island commissioner of elementary and secondary education. She shares how the students in her state have seen success in CTE programs. She also talks about how Rhode Island is changing the high school credit structure and suggests ways to create a robust pipeline for teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219408?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conflict-competent leadership</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 37-41, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Conflict management is one of the most stressful and frustrating aspects of a school leader’s job. An inability to overcome conflicting viewpoints, ever more palpable in today’s polarized climate, stymies innumerable school reform efforts. Yet, the subject is rarely examined in graduate-level leadership preparation programs or in-service professional development. Robert Feirsen and Seth Weitzman explain that conflict in schools is normal and discuss why knowing how to manage conflict can strengthen leaders and build capacity for school improvement. They offer specific strategies to build conflict resolution skills and embed collaborative problem solving in school culture.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219403?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The path of a principal: A conversation with Sham Bevel</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 42-45, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Sham Bevel, principal of Bayside Sixth Grade Campus in the Virginia Beach City Schools, is one of three finalists for the 2024 National Principal of the Year award. The honor, awarded annually by the National Association of Secondary School Principals, recognizes outstanding school leaders who make exemplary contributions to their schools, staff, students, and the profession. Phi Delta Kappan spoke with Bevel about her path to becoming a principal, how principals keep their schools aligned and focused on their goals, and the importance of modeling expectations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219404?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: Organizational News about PDK International</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 71-71, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;PDK members can share their expertise with future educators by presenting a session at the 2024 Educators Rising National Conference.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219561?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Designing teacher leadership for school improvement</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 26-30, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;While the demands of teaching continue to escalate, teacher development has changed relatively little over time, leaving many of today’s teachers feeling underprepared, overwhelmed, or demoralized with few opportunities to make real change. Teacher leadership holds promise for both addressing challenges within schools and empowering teachers. Wesley L.C. Henry, Bryan A. VanGronigen, Meredith L. Wronowski, and James L. Olive highlight how a large urban school district in the United States created, resourced, and implemented a program to develop a corps of teacher leaders who used what they were learning to analyze and critique local school improvement plans. They then presented their ideas to administrators and collaborated with their colleagues to implement more responsive improvement efforts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219401?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Structures for continuous improvement in principal preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 32-36, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The requisite knowledge and skills of principals are in a constant state of flux. Principal preparation programs need to proactively create systems and structures for continuous improvement and create pathways for information-sharing in order to remain responsive to the needs of local districts. James Coviello, Joan I. Birringer-Haig, and Katherine C. Aquino share how their university has created structures for continual improvement that principal preparation programs can use to in ensure leaders are prepared to face the dynamic tempo of change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219402?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: The work of leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Leading a school or district requires a complex array of skills, yet leadership development programs have not always given leaders the skills they need. Teresa Preston, Kappan’s editor-in-chief, gives an overview of the December 2023/January 2024 issue, which focuses on preparing school and district leaders.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219374?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Equity-centered school leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 20-25, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Ohio’s Columbus City Schools developed a new urban grow-your-own principal pipeline. This pipeline emphasizes the cultivation of equity-centered principals who can address educational and social disparities in transformative and sustainable ways. Drawing from research and professional literature and from district and stakeholder engagements, author James C. Eslinger outlines six interrelated critical dispositions that need to be nurtured within school leaders. He demonstrates how these dispositions are integrated in the recruitment, preparation, and induction of aspiring and novice school leaders in the district. These dispositions are key drivers for leaders’ beliefs and practices to advance equity in schools and beyond.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219400?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: What makes a great school administrator?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 70-70, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Educators Rising students describe the qualities that are most important in school administrators and share stories of administrators who made a difference in their lives.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219559?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Poll Points: Who should influence what’s taught?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 72-72, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Majorities across the political spectrum say teachers should have substantial say in what’s taught — 75% of Democrats, 64% of independents, and 60% of Republicans.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219562?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Backtalk: Removing artificial barriers to licensure could ease the teacher shortage</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 66-67, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this opinion essay, Jori S. Beck argues that current teacher shortages could be mediated by rethinking candidate licensure. She shares various examples of how local, state, and federal policy have prevented talented candidates from earning teacher licensure. She unpacks some of the requirements for licensure, including costs, and discusses actionable steps that could be taken by state and federal government agencies to support teacher licensure.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219556?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: Can teacher ‘come back’ after telling principal to f**k off?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 68-69, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Phyllis L. Fagell offers work-related advice to educators. This month, a teacher wants to know how she can recover after telling an administrator to f**k off. A teacher candidate wonders why so many districts require in-person interviews when virtual options are available.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219557?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Train new principals like THEY work</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 14-19, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Without proper training, the realities of leading a school can overwhelm principals. Specifically, the challenges of leading a school will test principals’ abilities to manage operations and implement effective initiatives. Despite knowledge of these demands, author Craig Hochbein writes that aspiring principals often engage in training experiences that do not align with principals’ work. By focusing on how principals spend their time, aspiring principals, school district administrators, and principal training faculty can improve their contributions to principal training.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219399?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: Should superintendents be elected?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 62-63, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Research shows that student achievement is higher when the district leadership is stable. Superintendent turnover, especially in urban areas, continues to rise, and many blame education politics for the leadership churn. Columnist Jonathan E. Collins proposes turning the superintendency into an elected position would solve the problem. Elections would give superintendents a guaranteed term of office and they could run as an incumbent on their record.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219411?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Browsing: Further thoughts on this month’s theme</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 5-6, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;News, quotes, and insights from the past related to the theme of the December 2023/January 2024 issue of Kappan, “Preparing school and district leaders.”
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219375?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What do excellent school leader preparation programs look like?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 8-13, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Principal leadership is a crucial element in high-performing schools. Research reveals that principals are second only to teachers in impacting student achievement at school. Accordingly, how school leaders are prepared has received increasing attention in recent years. Drawing from the findings of recent reports highlighting exemplary programs and best practices, authors Bonnie C. Fusarelli and Lance D. Fusarelli identify several research-based best practices for improving principal preparation. They include recommendations to scale up best practices nationwide.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219398?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 7-7, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this regular column, Kappan authors recommend books that have influenced them. This month, Ferial Pearson recommends Case Studies on Diversity and Social Justice Education (2nd ed.) by Paul Gorksi and Seema Pothini. Bonnie C. Fusarelli and Lance D. Fusarelli recommend Savage Inequalities: Children in America’s Schools by Jonathan Kozol.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219376?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under The Law: The incredibly shrinking zone of teacher free speech</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/4&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 64-65, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Schools, districts, and states are able to place some limits on what teachers can and cannot teach, but what of teachers’ free speech rights outside the classroom? Robert Kim examines long-standing U.S. Supreme Court rulings regarding free speech in school and considers how they might apply specifically to teachers’ free speech rights. He then surveys some recent district courts cases in which teachers were penalized for speech inside and outside the classroom. These cases suggest that it’s time to reexamine the role of teachers as representatives of the state.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231219552?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assigning Students to Schools in an Era of Public School Choice: Patterns in Enrollment, Applications, and Offers in Chicago</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Districts with expansive school choice must decide how to match students and schools. Increasingly, districts are centralizing applications on one-stop portals that feature information about schooling options, admission requirements, and a single application and deadline with the hope of increasing transparency and streamlining the enrollment process. After Chicago Public Schools introduced a centralized platform (GoCPS), students were more likely to enroll in high-performing high schools, although this continued as a pre-existing upward trend. Enrollment declined slightly at charter schools and increased at neighborhood schools, mirroring shifts in applications. GoCPS reduced the number of admission offers, likely lessening uncertainty around ninth-grade enrollment. Districts implementing similar systems should consider the availability of seats at high-demand schools and reduce barriers to navigating choice systems.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231206777?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
