<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Black Children’s Refusal in a “Hege-Mindful” World</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;This case study examines the connections between mindfulness activities and related benefits, including wellness, as 13 Black fifth graders embarked on an 8-week mindfulness program in their public-school classroom. The children responded well to the program and exhibited some wellness outcomes associated with mindfulness. However, hegemonic school and classroom practices emphasizing adult control and minimal child agency prevented the children from practicing new mindfulness skills or sustaining feelings of wellness, mattering, and harmony throughout the school day. We found that classroom mindfulness efforts, when not supported by all classroom teachers and administrators, necessarily limit Black children’s ability to develop a sense of self-awareness and self-efficacy and can in fact reinforce feelings of self-blame. Our findings suggest that mindfulness programs can have a positive impact for Black children when paired with antiracist practices, allowing space for the children to practice refusal and prioritize their right to matter.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2025 06:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241311237?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pre-service mathematics teachers’ experiences and insights into the benefits and challenges of using explanatory videos in flipped modelling education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Explanatory videos play an important role in the flipped classroom (FC) approach, which has become highly important especially since the COVID-19 crisis. In this qualitative study, we explore the potential of using explanatory videos (EVs) in mathematical modelling education as important component of FC and assess its merits and deficiencies. We focus on the perspectives and experiences of 44 preservice mathematics teachers (PSTs) attending a German university in their master phase. Considering EVs in an interactive FC context, we employed a multifaceted approach to data collection that included interviews, online surveys with open-ended questions, EVs generated by the PSTs, and written documents resulting from collaborative group activities. The findings show that the EVs used in FCs in modelling can enhance understanding and simplifying modelling content and real-world situations. Moreover, PSTs report that using EVs in flipped modelling seminars can offer personalized learning, optimize teaching hours, decrease anxiety, and increase learners’ attention. PSTs also improved their skills in developing EVs on modelling and evaluating their quality in terms of structure, content, and focus. The experienced challenges include time-consuming content development, workload, technical hurdles, and feasibility of FC implementations. Although these challenges are important, they are not content-specific issues, and we conclude that the notable benefits of using EVs in FCs have the potential to promote technology-enhanced modelling education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01650-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identifying and describing generic, specific, and catalytic enablers of mathematical modelling</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this article, we report on an Australian study in which generic, specific, and catalytic enablers of mathematical modelling are identified and described. The study adopted a design-based research approach involving six secondary teachers, and their intact classes, over three years. Data was generated from 60 pre/post-teacher and student (Years 9–11) interviews, which was subject to reductive thematic analysis, consistent with the principles of inductive category formation&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; This analysis led to the development of a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Typology for Instructional Enablers of Mathematical Modelling&lt;/em&gt; which identifies and describes both enablers and un-enablers of modelling activity. These are related to external/internal/personal learning goals, classroom expectations and ways of working, management of the learning process, and instructional anticipation. Enablers/un-enablers are further categorised into generic, specific, and catalytic dimensions. Implications for both practice and future research are discussed, including the nature of catalytic enablers and the connections between enablers and specific aspects of the modelling process.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01653-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collaborating with mathematicians to use active learning in university mathematics courses: the importance of attending to mathematicians’ obligations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we discuss our experience in collaborating with mathematicians to increase their use of active learning pedagogy in a proof-based linear algebra course. The mathematicians we worked with valued using active learning pedagogy to increase student engagement but were reluctant to use active learning pedagogy due to time constraints. Our mathematicians perceived obligations in their teaching that increased the time it would take to implement some of the active learning pedagogy that we suggested, leading them to view this pedagogy as inviable. By attending to mathematicians’ obligations, we were able to design active learning strategies that met the interests and needs of the mathematics educators and mathematicians collaborating on this project.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10381-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Overlooked Explanation for Increasing Suicidality: LGBQ Stressors Felt by More Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Recent data show rising suicidality among high school girls. We posit this increase may be related to an overlooked factor: more girls identifying as LGBQ. Using four cohorts of national Youth Risk Behavior Survey data (N = 22,562 females, N = 22,130 males), we found that LGBQ identification among females rose from 15% in 2015 to 34% in 2021. LGBQ females consistently reported higher suicidality, although rates remained stable within both LGBQ and heterosexual groups. The rise in females’ suicidality may stem from social pressures faced by LGBQ youth. Male suicidality and LGBQ identification showed smaller changes. More support for LGBQ students is essential to address this trend.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2025 08:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241305329?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Middle School Math: Cool Problems to Get Students Thinking and Connecting</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This book is designed to enhance students’ learning experience in mathematics. It provides valuable resources for developing engaging mathematics learning in junior high school, focusing on students’ conceptual understanding and connections between concepts. The book’s approach, which includes various contextual problems and strategies such as Know, Want to know, Conditions (KWC); representation; analytical thinking; and reading integration, is discussed in this summary. The seven main chapters are highlighted, along with their concepts, example problems, and the implications of various approaches. Educators can feel reassured that their efforts will be rewarding in developing meaningful mathematics learning for their students.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00339-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 11:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2025.2453306?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educators’ interventions in gendered harassment: the importance of school culture</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 10:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2442935?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hands-on Consensus Building: Leveraging Deep Learning Models to Unveil Hand Gestures in Consensus-Building Discourses</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2448797?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promoting mathematical competence development through programming activities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The reasons for teaching programming in school are indeed manifold. Programming can for example be utilized as a vehicle for understanding and learning particular mathematical subject matter, or as a tool for solving mathematical problems. In this paper, however, we propose to utilize programming as a vehicle for developing mathematical competencies such as problem-solving, exploration, modeling, reasoning, representation, generalization, and abstraction. We perform a design study utilizing a systematic, iterative development process for designing teaching sessions, focusing on one mathematical competence at a time. We apply the proposed methodology on a set of teaching sessions that are developed, implemented, and tested in a range of classroom settings. Based on this development process, we conclude that programming can be used to develop mathematical competencies. Furthermore, we identify a set of teacher practices that can be used to facilitate mathematical competence development in programming activities.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10380-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Works for Whom: Exploring the Students, Settings, and Outcomes in What Works Clearinghouse Study Data</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-14-2025 04:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2427762?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Empirical Benchmarks for Effect Size Interpretation and Study Planning with Social and Behavioral Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-14-2025 04:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2427767?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Addressing teacher shortages in an international context: implications for the quality and status of teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 12:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2025.2447968?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rera/95/1&quot;&gt;Volume 95, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 154-170, February 2025. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 10:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241308357?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supervising, Coaching, and Preparing Dual Language Bilingual Education Teachers: A Collaborative Autoethnography</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Feedback and preservice teachers’ (PSTs’) clinical practice/field experiences are vital for their learning. Understanding influences on field supervisors’ feedback is critical, especially for preparing dual language bilingual education (DLBE) teachers because it requires specialized knowledge—yet systematic guidelines and programs for DLBE teacher preparation are lacking. We conducted a collaborative autoethnography to determine how our identities and experiences with language and DLBE related to our feedback and supervision of DLBE PSTs. We analyzed and discussed the narratives we wrote about our experiences and the feedback we provided while supervising 13 Spanish–English bilingual PSTs in elementary DLBE classrooms. Our identities and experiences, which were influenced by families, education, language histories, geography, and sociopolitical contexts, influenced our feedback. Considering identities and experiences illuminates what is (sometimes unconsciously) prioritized and ignored in feedback. Engaging in deep reflection is important for continued support of supervisors and PSTs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 10:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241312351?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Democracy on the Sidelines: The Erosion and Potential of Youth Sports as Democratic Education</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;In this philosophical paper, we argue that youth sports, both in and out of schools, are a largely unrealized space for democratic/civic education. Where youth sports leagues used to be low cost, local, and inclusive, much has changed over the last several decades. We are now in the neoliberal era of exclusive, privatized, and professionalized youth sports. Drawing on Dewey’s robust conception of democracy and Talisse’s concerns about partisan polarization, we argue that youth sports should be spaces to develop democratic habits, dispositions, and values. We explore the benefits of youth sports as well as current challenges, including excessive costs and pressure, disrupted families, and hyperindividualism. We end by offering suggestions for reforming youth sports to recenter their educational and democratic potential and value, including supporting loosely structured play, modeling democratic behavior, teaching democratic habits directly, and learning from more progressive national sports models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 09:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241311810?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inscribing proportional relationships using partitioning, co-occurrence, and same extent</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 08:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2025.2450408?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using video case studies to provide prospective secondary teachers in Kenya opportunities to notice and reflect on pedagogical practices</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2025 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2446289?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can We Learn From Qualitative Impact Evaluations About the Effectiveness of Lobby and Advocacy? A Meta-Evaluation of Dutch aid Programmes and Assessment Tool</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Official development agencies are increasingly supporting civil society lobby and advocacy (L&amp;amp;A) to address poverty and human rights. However, there are challenges in evaluating L&amp;amp;A. As programme objectives are often to change policies or practices in a single institution like a Government Ministry, L&amp;amp;A programmes are often not amenable to large-n impact evaluation methods. They often work in strategic partnerships to foster change; hence, contribution may be a more relevant evaluation question than attribution. Small-n qualitative approaches are available to measure the effectiveness of L&amp;amp;A which use the theory of change as their analytical framework. We conducted a meta-evaluation of 36 evaluations of multi-component international programmes to support civil society L&amp;amp;A across Asia, Africa and Latin America, comprising the majority of programmatic support from one international donor. We assessed the confidence in causal claims in the evaluations using a new tool that we developed. Assessments of the contribution of the programmes to the changes in outcomes were not provided in many of the evaluations, nor were predictable sources of bias addressed. Given that L&amp;amp;A programmes are likely to adopt an influencing approach where many different inside-track and outside-track engagement objectives, opportunities and strategies are attempted, many of which might be expected to fail, there appeared to be a clear bias in the evaluations towards reporting outcomes that were achieved, ignoring those that were not. We provide guidance on how to improve the design, conduct and reporting of small-n qualitative evaluations of aid effectiveness.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2025 04:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X251314731?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inferences, mastery, and objectivity: examining student understanding of mathematical concepts with inferentialism</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Inferentialism has emerged as a valuable theoretical resource in mathematics education. As a theory of meaning about the use and content of concepts, it offers a fresh perspective on traditional epistemological and linguistic questions in the field. Despite its emergence, important inferentialist ideas still need to be operationalized. In this paper, I operationalize multiple inferentialist concepts to analyze prospective secondary mathematics teachers’ learning about graphs and quantitative and covariational reasoning in a mathematics content course. I use Robert Brandom’s ideas about upstream, downstream, and incompatible inferences to illustrate the inferentialist mastering metaphor for learning and Brandom’s ideas about objectivity. My analysis shows (a) inferentialism’s capacity to address epistemological issues like objectivity and conceptual understanding, (b) the importance of attending to different types of inferences to assess learning from an inferentialist perspective, and (c) how the development of mastery is associated with virtues. I conclude by identifying the study’s potential limitations and trajectories for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10377-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Refining” Our Understanding of Early Career Teacher Skill Development: Evidence From Classroom Observations</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Novice teachers improve substantially in their first years on the job, but we know remarkably little about the nature of this skill development. Using data from Tennessee, we leverage a feature of the classroom observation protocol that asks school administrators to identify an item on which the teacher should focus their improvement efforts. This “area of refinement” overcomes a key measurement challenge endemic to inferring from classroom observation scores the development of specific teaching skills. We show that administrators disproportionately identify two skills when observing novice teachers: classroom management and presenting content. Struggling with classroom management, in particular, is associated with early career attrition. Using a returns to experience framework, we observe improvement in these skills among teachers who remain.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 12:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241303146?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Service-user research and Peter Kropotkin: a personal note of thanks to Professor Carol Munn-Giddings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 08:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2444099?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Speaking Up, Pushing Back, Closing the Door: Agency of Open and Covert Teacher Resistance in Dual-Language Bilingual Education</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;The increasing prominence of dual-language bilingual education (DLBE) in the United States necessitates deeper understanding of institutional roles and professional identities of DLBE teachers, particularly when incongruent. We qualitatively analyzed teacher resistance in discordant situations as discussed in conferences between DLBE teachers and a bilingual instructional coach in two districts over 2 years. In these conversations, we found a distinction between nonconfrontational and open, direct resistance. We applied an agentive triad model of teacher identity, agency, and power to understand how DLBE teachers navigated discordant situations in their schools. Teachers acted from different identity positions, including agentive compliance, anagentive compliance (without agency), and nonconfrontational resistance. Findings and theorization demonstrate that DLBE programs present special considerations for teacher identity, role, and resistance. Moreover, context-specific characteristics, including program age, model, and administration, may impact teachers’ approach to resistance. Findings and theorization are relevant to successful DLBE program implementation and equity focused instructional coaching.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 08:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241311818?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/50/1&quot;&gt;Volume 50, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 180-182, February 2025. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2025 08:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241308335?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
