<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The nature and impact of literacy interest in preschool children: Comparing teacher, parent, and child report measures</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-21-2024 06:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2355108?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Profiles of teachers’ assessment techniques and their students’ involvement in assessment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-20-2024 12:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2354410?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Mamá en inglés se dice ‘pre-med’”: bilingual Mexican-origin first-generation college undergraduates aspiring for medical careers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-20-2024 08:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2349879?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From reflective practice to action research and positive change: securing high levels of wellbeing among learners with autism spectrum condition in the mainstream setting</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-20-2024 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2355925?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of Unified School Enrollment Systems on School Demographics and Outcomes: Evidence From New Orleans’ Transition to a Centralized School Lottery</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Unified enrollment (UE) systems were designed to improve efficiency, equity, and transparency in school choice processes, but research has focused on efficiency gains. This study examines whether moving from decentralized enrollment processes to UE mitigates or exacerbates racial segregation that often occurs in choice systems. Specifically, we examine a subset of charter schools in New Orleans that had enrolled disproportionately high numbers of White students prior to entering UE. We find that UE entry was associated with increased enrollment of non-White students in these schools without offsetting declines in White enrollment, facilitated by schools also increasing total enrollment after entering UE. We find no meaningful impacts of UE on school accountability measures, student or teacher mobility, or student discipline.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-20-2024 01:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241248513?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging Physical Activities to Support Learning for Young People via Technologies: An Examination of Educational Practices Across the Field</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Many technological interventions have leveraged physical activity (PA, i.e., activities that involve whole-body movements) to provide young people with active and productive learning experiences. However, there is a lack of systematic understanding of how PA can serve as a learning medium—for example, how PA can support learning and how to design technologies to support PA-based learning. This paper conducts a systematic literature review (N = 141) of PA-based, technology-mediated learning experiences for young people with a focus on how PA supports learning, what technologies are involved, and the associated challenges. Through content analysis, we identified four approaches of how PA and learning were combined (i.e., PA embodied learning content, served as a functional input method for learning tasks, guided learners through different learning sites, and generated data for learning activities) and supporting technologies like full-body interaction learning environments and mobile apps. However, many challenges might arise, such as balancing learning and PA, as well as the scalability and reliability of technologies. We conclude with a discussion and reflection on design implications for more PA-based learning experiences and technologies. Overall, this paper provides a systematic overview of the different ways to design physically active learning experiences for young people and can serve as a reference for future designs of physically active learning experiences and technologies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-18-2024 07:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241248464?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Major Selection as Iteration: Observing Gendered Patterns of Major Selection Under Elective Curriculums</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Social scientists have long recognized field of study as an important mechanism of gender differentiation and stratification in U.S. higher education, but they have rarely attended to how elective curriculums mediate gender differentiation in major selection. Under elective curriculums, major selection is an iterative process, in which students select courses in stepwise fashion at the beginning of each academic term, and are able to change majors early in their undergraduate careers. We observe how an elective curriculum mediates gendered patterns of major selection, using a novel data set describing 11,730 students at a large public research university. We find (a) gender and intended major are strongly correlated upon college entry; (b) large proportions of students change majors between entry and declaration; (c) because most changes are to academically adjacent fields, gendered patterns in field of study persist through the undergraduate career. Findings suggest the value of an iterative conception of major selection and offer tractable means for intervening in the process through which students select majors.JEL codes: I21, I24, I26, J16.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-18-2024 06:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241249600?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing Mathematical Deductive Reasoning Competence of Eighth-Grade Students from China</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study aims to develop an evaluation framework to assess the mathematical deductive reasoning competence (MDRC) of eighth-grade students in China based on Program for International Student Assessment (PISA) and Trends in International Mathematics and Science Study (TIMSS). The framework includes four dimensions of MDRC: cognitive level, reasoning context, reasoning form, and reasoning content. A sample of 58,532 students took the test entitled MDRC Assessment in 90 min. Their MDRC was classified into four levels, and the percentages of students who were at level 1 to level 4 are 17.3%, 25.2%, 26.7%, and 30.8%, respectively. Girls performed significantly better than boys in total and in each of the dimensions of the evaluation framework, but the differences were at a low practical level. Students from urban schools outperformed students from rural schools at a significant level and a higher percentage of students in rural areas were at level 1 (poorest performance) than of students in urban areas. This research proposed a framework for assessing MDRC levels of students and used it with Chinese as well as international studies. Implications of gender and geographical inequalities in this performance were also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-18-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00315-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Corrigendum to Spare the Rod, Spoil the Child? A Critical Discourse Analysis of State Corporal Punishment Policies &amp; Practices</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 09:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241257935?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Methodology for a time of eco-social planetary crisis: Action research helping transformations happen</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 06:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241255488?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improving Teaching at Scale: Can AI Be Incorporated Into Professional Development to Create Interactive, Personalized Learning for Teachers?</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Scalable and accessible professional development programs have the potential to address the opportunity gap many teachers experience. Yet many asynchronous online programs lack interaction with and timely feedback to teachers. We addressed this problem by developing a virtual, interactive program that uses intelligent tutoring systems to provide just‐in‐time feedback to teachers. We conducted a randomized controlled trial with teachers across the United States in which teachers were assigned to either this program or no additional training. We found that teachers who completed our program (N = 29) used mathematically richer tasks and created a more coherent, connected learning environment for students to build conceptual understandings than did teachers who were in the business‐as‐usual condition (N = 23).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 06:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241248514?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reading in Relation: Youth Mentors and Adults Co-Constructing Teaching and Learning in a High School Literacy Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 05:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2349298?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fostering participation and change through action research conducted with youth in the foster care system – A note from the field</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The purpose of this note from the field is to review the current state of action research studies involving young people currently or recently involved in the foster care system in the United States. Young people in foster care often report feeling that they have little opportunity for advocacy or self-directed change during their time in the system. Action research is presented as an approach to research that appears to provide opportunities for self-advocacy and real-world change among youth in the foster care system. While noting some challenges associated with recruitment and attrition while working with youth in foster care, this note emphasizes the promising potential of action research as a tool to increase youth autonomy and well-being while generating meaningful knowledge and social change within the U.S foster care system. The note, based on a database search that included 636 articles 2013–2023, hopes to contribute to advancing youth-led research in foster care.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 03:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241253371?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A critical look at the anthropological theory of the didactic</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 03:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2344754?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining teachers&#39; relational noticing: promoting equity through positive interactions in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;How teachers attend to and interpret positive relational interactions shapes how they enact instructional practices for equity. We draw on frameworks from equitable mathematics instruction, relational interactions, and teacher noticing to conceptualize mathematics teachers’ relational noticing. Using noticing interview and classroom observation data from a research collaborative between secondary mathematics teachers and university-based teacher educators, we document the range and diversity of ten teachers’ relational noticing. We use this analysis to examine how teachers’ relational noticing supports enacting equitable instructional practices. Our findings indicate five themes of teachers’ relational noticing that are informed by their personal histories, understanding of dominant narratives of mathematics education, and their local sociopolitical school context. Additionally, teachers enacted a range of practices for creating positive relational interactions, with attending to student thinking being the most enacted practice. Our findings suggest that mathematics teachers’ relational noticing can support the three axes of equitable instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09635-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Centering on power relations in collaboration among mathematics teacher educator-researchers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics education research tends to center on what Mathematics Teacher Educators-Researchers (MTERs) work on or the people (teachers and students) they work with. Rarely, research in mathematics education focuses on MTERs working with one another. This article decenters from these traditional foci and instead examines a heterogeneous group of MTERs describing their research collaborations for professional development efforts on social justice issues in mathematics education. The MTERs’ paired conversations focused on their retrospective stories of their collaborations were analyzed using an Anzaldúan framework to name the different spaces of collaboration that MTERs identified. Results provide insight into how MTERs’ identified binarized spaces linked to their identities and compounded by issues of power. Nevertheless, MTERs also identified spaces where boundaries were blurred promoting a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;nos/otras&lt;/em&gt; space of collaboration. We discuss how collaboration reaches beyond doing the same research work and sharing talent but also understanding the work of one another.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09634-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advanced Students’ Actions for Operationalizing Multiply-quantified Relationships</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Based on analysis with four graduate students’ proof productions, this paper characterizes eight ways of operationalizing quantification for reasoning about and constructing proofs. We call these quantification operationalizations quantops. These constructs describe the actions and meanings these students attributed to quantified relationships that rendered them useful for proving. We position these graduate students as experienced provers such that these quantops represent aspirational goals for the learning of more novice students that might be targeted by instruction. Some of these constructs build upon prior studies of quantification, such as fixing and varying an object (The Journal of Mathematical Behavior, 61, 100802 Sellers et al., &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r21&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/span&gt;) or reasoning about dependence or independence between related objects (Educational Studies in Mathematics, 60(2), 149–172 Durand-Guerrier &amp;amp; Arsac, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r9&quot;&gt;2005&lt;/span&gt;). Other quantops such as cardinality, notation, or multiply-quantified packages represent novel contributions to the literature. A key feature of these quantops was how they allowed students to foreground quantification to construct meaning or to background quantification to manage working memory. We accordingly identify a foregrounding and a backgrounding form of each quantop.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00236-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student teachers’ classroom management learning process and outcomes during the internship</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-15-2024 04:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2353178?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Trends in mathematics education and insights from a meta-review and bibliometric analysis of review studies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Review studies are vital for advancing knowledge in many scientific fields, including mathematics education, amid burgeoning publications. Based on an extensive consideration of existing review typologies, we conducted a meta-review and bibliometric analysis to provide a comprehensive overview of and deeper insights into review studies within mathematics education. After searching Web of Science, we identified 259 review studies, revealing a significant increase in such studies over the last five years. Systematic reviews were the most prevalent type, followed by meta-analyses, generic literature reviews, and scoping reviews. On average, the review studies had a sample size of 99, with the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analysis (PRISMA) guidelines commonly employed. Despite certain studies offering nuanced distinctions among review types, ambiguity persisted. Only about a quarter of the studies explicitly reported employing specific theoretical frameworks (particularly, technology, knowledge, and competence models). Co-authored publications were most common within American institutions and the leading countries are the United States, Germany, China, Australia, and England in publishing most review studies. Educational review journals, educational psychology journals, special education journals, educational technology journals, and mathematics education journals provided platforms for review studies, and prominent research topics included digital technologies, teacher education, mathematics achievement, and learning disabilities. In this study, we synthesised a range of reviews to facilitate readers’ comprehension of conceptual congruities and disparities across various review types, as well as to track current research trends. The results suggest that there is a need for discipline-specific standards and guidelines for different types of mathematics education reviews, which may lead to more high-quality review studies to enhance progress in mathematics education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01587-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cultivating mindfulness through conditional tasks in mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Following psychologist Langer’s theory, this study aimed to examine the influence of conditional tasks containing inherent uncertainty on the cultivation of mindfulness. It used preceding research to develop conditional mathematics tasks corresponding to integers and rational numbers, within a 10-lesson curriculum. It divided a total of 182 middle school students in South Korea into three groups: a control group (49 participants), experimental group 1 (62 participants), and experimental group 2 (71 participants). During each of the 10 lessons, experimental group 1 was given a conditional task, while experimental group 2 received 3–4 conditional tasks. Mindfulness was measured before and after the 10 lessons, and a two-way repeated measures analysis of variance was conducted. This study’s results revealed that the average scores of the subfactors of mindfulness—novelty seeking and flexibility—increased for both the experimental groups (1 and 2), but decreased for the control group. These findings empirically demonstrate the significance of conditional tasks with inherent uncertainty, in influencing students’ psychological state.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10323-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Accelerating Literacy for Adolescents (ALFA): Evaluating ALFA Lab Using a Regression Discontinuity Study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-14-2024 07:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2338129?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward a Better Understanding of the Nature of Pedagogical Content Knowledge for Fractions: The Role of Experience</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-14-2024 07:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2350909?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Actualizing the virtuality of the cauchy-riemann equations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this case study we explored how a mathematician’s teaching of the Cauchy-Riemann (CR) equations actualized the virtual aspects of the equations. Using videotaped classroom data, we found that in a three-day period, this mathematician used embodiment to animate and bind formal aspects of the CR equations (including conformality), metaphors, himself, and his students. We found that the mathematician’s creative introduction of matrices led to a discussion of transformations which made the CR equations mobile and hence gave him a space to virtualize the CR equations. In our results we summarize how the mathematician&#39;s assemblage of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;unusual&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;unexpected, and unscripted&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;without given content&lt;/em&gt; creative acts with materials embedded in algebraic and geometric inscriptions and metaphors &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;introduced or catalyzed the new&lt;/em&gt;—the virtuality of the CR equations. In our discussion, we highlight how the mathematician bridged the virtual with the abstract via his conceptualizations of the CR equations. Didactic implications include adopting the mathematician’s conceptualizations and asking students to bind them. This could stress the mobility of conformal maps which are generally not taught in an undergraduate class. We propose offering professional development for educators focused on learning how to engineer didactic practices that showcase mobility, support binding, and exhibit animation of mathematical concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-14-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01588-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Towards a definition of “mathematical digital competency for teaching”</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When students engage with a digital tool to tackle a mathematical task, the interplay between their digital competencies and mathematical abilities gives rise to what is termed mathematical digital competency (MDC). Recognising the significance of MDC as an integral component for contemporary students, the relevance of cultivating mathematical digital competency for teaching (MDCT) becomes apparent. We posit that for teachers to effectively guide students in the development of their MDC, possessing MDCT is imperative. In this paper, drawing upon the theoretical frameworks of instrumental orchestration, the documentational approach to didactics, and the Danish competencies framework’s six didactico-pedagogical competencies of mathematics teachers, we propose a theoretical conceptualization of teachers’ mathematical and digital competencies in the context of teaching mathematics with technology. Expanding upon the preliminary definition of students’ MDC, we incorporate pedagogic, theoretical elements tailored to teachers, encapsulating it as MDCT. To expound on the various facets of MDCT, we provide an illustrative example featuring a mathematics teacher proficient in the utilisation of digital technologies and programming.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-14-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01585-9</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
