<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bridging the Gap Between Imagined and Plausible Futures for Refugees: What Students Wish Their Teachers Knew</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;There is a gap between the futures that refugee young people imagine will be possible through their education and the plausible futures in exile, where opportunities are truncated by social, economic, and political exclusions. Our study examines how education can narrow this gap. Through interviews with Syrian students in Lebanon, we document fixed and malleable elements of education that refugee students identify as bridging their current education and their futures. Students experience the structures and content of schooling in Lebanon as both exclusionary and immutable, yet their teachers use what we call relational pedagogies rooted in predictability, explaining, fairness, and care to support students’ learning and navigation toward future opportunities. While our research focuses on refugees, it has conceptual implications for educators and school systems in other settings where teachers support their marginalized students to make sense of disconnects between what they imagine is possible through school and their future opportunities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-08-2024 01:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241230062?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Generalizing actions with the subtraction-compensation property: primary students’ algebraic thinking with tasks involving vertical towers of blocks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;An important approach for developing children’s algebraic thinking involves introducing them to generalized arithmetic at the time they are learning arithmetic. Our aim in this study was to investigate children’s attention to and expression of generality with the subtraction-compensation property, as evidence of a type of algebraic thinking known as relational thinking. The tasks involved subtraction modelled as difference and comparing the heights of towers of blocks. In an exploratory qualitative study, 22 middle primary (9–11-year-old) students from two schools participated in individual videoed interviews. The tasks were designed using theoretical perspectives on embodied visualization and concreteness fading to provide multiple opportunities for the students to make sense of subtraction as difference and to advance their relational thinking. Twelve out of 22 students evidenced conceptual understanding of the comparison model of subtraction (subtraction as difference) and expression of the compensation property of equality. Four of these students repeatedly evidenced relational thinking for true/false tasks and open equivalence tasks. A proposed framework for levels of attention to/expression of generality with the subtraction-compensation property is shared and suggestions for further research are presented.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10303-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pedagogies of collective intersectional care: Witnessing the spiritual and affective rigor of carework within daily classroom life</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-07-2024 06:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2324237?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interrupting the hegemony of SEL: The productive potential of anger in Young Adult Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-07-2024 05:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2323780?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Structure recognition and generalization by second-graders in direct and inverse forms of a linear function</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-07-2024 04:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2324492?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BSRLM day conference proceedings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-07-2024 03:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2315026?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bayesian Adaptive Lasso for the Detection of Differential Item Functioning in Graded Response Models</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The detection of differential item functioning (DIF) is important in psychological and behavioral sciences. Standard DIF detection methods perform an item-by-item test iteratively, often assuming that all items except the one under investigation are DIF-free. This article proposes a Bayesian adaptive Lasso method to detect DIF in graded response models (GRMs), where the DIF effects for all items can be identified simultaneously. The multiple-group GRMs are specified, and the possible DIF effects for each item are reparameterized using the increment components. Then, a Bayesian adaptive Lasso procedure is developed for parameter estimation, in which DIF effects can be automatically obtained. Our method is evaluated and compared with the commonly used likelihood ratio test method in a simulation study. The results show that our method can recover most model parameters well and has better control of false positive rates in almost all conditions. An application is presented using data from the National Longitudinal Study of Adolescent to Adult Health (Add Health).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-07-2024 01:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241233777?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher-Student Race Match and Identification for Discretionary Educational Services</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A host of recent literature suggests benefits to Black children of being matched to same-race teachers. We extend this literature to explore whether being matched to a Black teacher is related to Black students’ likelihood of being identified for two types of discretionary educational services in the following academic year: gifted education and special education. While we do not find that access to Black teachers affects students’ likelihood of gifted identification, Black students matched to Black teachers are less likely to be identified for special education. The results are strongest for Black boys, particularly those who are also economically disadvantaged and are strongest for disabilities with more discretion in identification.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-06-2024 11:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241229413?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estimates of Teach for America Effects on Student Test and Nontest Academic Outcomes Over Time</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;This article examines the impact of Teach for America (TFA) on following-year student test and nontest outcomes in Miami-Dade County Public Schools. Using data from 2010 through 2021, this article measures the extent to which student exposure to TFA is followed by improved outcomes in the future, relative to students with other early-career teachers in the same school. In particular, this article measures days missed due to absences or suspensions, course grades in each core subject, and progression in math courses. We find that students taught by TFA math teachers go on to have higher grades in math courses in the following year and are less likely to miss school due to being absent or suspended. However, while students in TFA classrooms score higher on math and ELA assessments in a given year, these test score gains fade out by the following year.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-06-2024 09:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241234874?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impact of online lesson study on students’ achievement in mathematics in China</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-06-2024 01:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2325665?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Parents and teachers collaborating to disrupt asymmetrical power positions in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper describes an innovative mathematics learning partnership that engages teachers and parents of multilingual children ages 7–10 from schools in underserved communities. At the center of this transformative work is the use of two complementary approaches to advancing equity in education– funds of knowledge and positioning theory. While both theories have been applied in mathematics education, they have not been integrated in a parent-teacher partnership program aimed at enhancing collaboration between multilingual families and teachers. We describe how the theories informed key features of our partnership model, including mathematical tasks and lesson planning activities for parents and teachers. Our research questions focused on how parents and teachers learned about each other’s experiences and strengths, and disrupted traditional power differentials between them as they participated in these collaborative activities. Our findings are structured around two in-depth cases that illustrate patterns in our analysis, including features of activities that supported collaborative interactions and co-construction of knowledge. We end with implications for future mathematics education focused partnerships between multilingual families and schools.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-06-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01555-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Self-efficacy in teaching mathematics and the use of effective pedagogical practices in New Zealand primary schools</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study explored teachers’ self-efficacy in teaching mathematics (SETM) as related to their teaching profile and pedagogical practices. Using data from 327 New Zealand primary teachers, a multilevel structural equation model was constructed and analyzed that looked at the relationships among SETM and effective pedagogical practice scales and included characteristics related to the teachers and their schools. No significant gender, year level, or school socioeconomic differences were found with teachers’ SETM. Experienced teachers had significantly higher SETM scores than their inexperienced colleagues. Teachers who were self-efficacious in their mathematics teaching reported pedagogical practices known to be effective in the mathematics classroom in contrast to their low self-efficacy colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-06-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09623-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Vision for the Future of Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, based on my Presidential Address for the 2022 American Educational Research Association (AERA) Annual Meeting, I offer some thoughts on the education and learning systems we need for the future. Specifically, I take up two core questions: (1) How do we organize education and learning systems for a multicultural democracy? (2) How do we build systems that transcend and transform how we have been doing “education” and that are designed to support rich and engaging learning and critical thinking skills and to fully educate young people in ways that honor their whole humanity, their developmental needs, and their families and communities? As I take up these questions, I draw on multiple pieces of research literature and craft a vision for the future of learning rooted in the hope of what is possible.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 12:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231222223?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A square peg in a round hole: reflecting on using a participatory health research approach during my PhD</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 10:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2325058?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘Where the Good Ideas Are’: 75 Years of the Journal of Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/75/2&quot;&gt;Volume 75, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 129-140, March/April 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Taking our lead from Karl Mannheim’s sociology of knowledge theory, and utilizing qualitative content analyses of data extracted from editorials, articles, and public-facing documents, this current editorial details the story of how the myriad of editors for the Journal of Teacher Education (JTE) safeguarded a space to highlight ideas essential to research of preservice and inservice teacher education within an ever-changing global context for nearly 75 years. Fourteen JTE editorships over four eras—competency, reformation, legitimization, and resilience—are laid bare.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 09:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241232033?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Equivalencies Between Ad Hoc Strategies and Multivariate Models for Meta-Analysis of Dependent Effect Sizes</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Meta-analyses of educational research findings frequently involve statistically dependent effect size estimates. Meta-analysts have often addressed dependence issues using ad hoc approaches that involve modifying the data to conform to the assumptions of models for independent effect size estimates, such as by aggregating estimates to obtain one summary estimate per study, conducting separate analyses of distinct subgroups of estimates, or combinations thereof. We show that these ad hoc approaches correspond exactly to certain multivariate models for dependent effect sizes. Specifically, we describe classes of multivariate random effects models that have likelihoods equivalent to those of models for effect sizes that have been averaged by study, classified into subgroups, or both. The equivalencies also apply to robust variance estimation methods.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 08:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241232524?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Florida’s HB7: A Policy of Intimidation by Confusion</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;“Divisive Concepts” laws have sprung up around the nation as a backlash to the widespread commitments to anti-racist education that emerged in summer 2020. This critical policy analysis examines the concepts central to Florida’s “Individual Freedom Act” [HB7] of 2022, to determine its intent and impact in ameliorating or exacerbating persistent educational inequities. Through an analysis of the language of the law for what is and is not banned as well as the discrepancies between language of the legal text juxtaposed with the “Anti-Woke” political rhetoric accompanying HB7, this study reveals the law’s ideological underpinnings and political intent. The law’s concepts serve as a manufactured pretext to villainize teachers, misrepresent Critical Race Theory, cause confusion and fear, thereby chilling educator practice. The analysis also reveals how, despite the law’s intent, the concepts can be reframed to support educational equity. Implications for equity-minded practitioners within K-20 education contexts are explored.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 07:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241235405?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The effect of the mathematics bag early education program</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 06:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2324718?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Moving beyond the ‘budget dance’</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/6&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 48-52, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The annual budgeting process is a valuable opportunity for districts to systematically examine both resource use and programming. They can then use the findings to optimize resource use and improve program efficacy in ways that will lead to increased student achievement. Bo Yan and Thomas Aberli discuss three root causes for districts’ inability to accomplish the goals (reliance on problem-driven needs as the dominant factor of budgetary decisions, disconnect between financial management and performance management, as well as human nature). They propose a cycle-based approach to district budgeting that rests on differentiating investment from operation expenditures.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 03:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241238108?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Letting go of what doesn’t work in education: A conversation with Rick Ginsberg and Yong Zhao</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/6&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 38-41, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Rick Ginsberg and Yong Zhao want educators to question the status quo and clear out ineffective practices to make room for K-12 reforms that work. Their 2023 book, Duck and Cover: Confronting Dubious Practices in Education, Ginsberg and Zhao examine kindergarten readiness, college- and career-readiness, reading proficiency by 3rd grade, social and emotional learning, education technology, class size, dress codes, state standardized testing, meta-analysis, and more.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 03:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241238106?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Parents’ rights, yes. But parent responsibilities, too</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/6&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 53-57, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;While there are plenty of people who decry the parents’ right push, viewing it as manufactured and mean-spirited, Frederick M. Hess and Michael Q. McShane think it has been a healthy and overdue development. Yet while parents have rights, they also have a responsibility to send students to school ready to learn. Schools are ultimately reliant on parents being active partners in preparing their children to be responsible students and citizens. With clear communication and a willingness to listen, families and schools can form more productive partnerships to help students learn.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 03:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241238109?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf:Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/6&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 7-7, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this regular column, Kappan authors share books and articles that have inspired and influenced them. Arielle Lentz discusses Faces at the Bottom of the Well: The Permanence of Racism by Derrick Bell. Sharon Greenberg recommends Solito: A Memoir, by Javier Zamora.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 03:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241238100?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What a study of educator evaluation taught us about professional learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/6&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 42-46, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;After years evaluating teacher professional learning programs, researchers Andrew J. Wayne, Jordan Rickles, Mengli Song, Seth Brown, and Michael S. Garet describe a study that changed their perspective. The study’s takeaways about the design of teacher professional learning are important for everyone who seeks to create systems to support teaching and learning. The findings call attention to the value of streamlined, high-quality programs for improving performance outcomes for teachers and students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 03:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241238107?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Changes that stick</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/105/6&quot;&gt;Volume 105, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 8-11, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Many education leaders may wonder how to implement sustainable policy changes that will benefit youth, families, and the community. Arielle Lentz, Laura Desimone, Amy Stornaiuolo, Katie Pak, Nelson Flores, Philip Nichols, Morgan Polikoff, and Andy Porter share findings from school change efforts in more than 170 districts in five states. They present six key strategies based on this work, and they share examples of how districts employed the success factors of specificity, consistency, power, and stability to help build authority, which in turn led to successful implementation of new policies, curriculums, and professional learnings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2024 03:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241238101?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
