<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working with an instructional video on mathematical modeling: upper-secondary students’ perceived advantages and challenges</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Many instructional videos in mathematics education target knowledge of procedures and algorithms. To design instructional videos that support students in a non-algorithmic domain, such as mathematical modeling, we developed a framework based on research on heuristic worked examples and instructional videos. Because students’ perceptions play an important role in whether they will engage with a learning resource, our research questions focus on the advantages and challenges students perceive when they work with an instructional video on mathematical modeling and solve a subsequent related modeling problem. Using a video based on the developed framework, we conducted an interview study with 14 pairs of upper-secondary students. The results of the qualitative text analysis showed that the perceived advantages and challenges were related to certain design features and to the processes of self-regulated learning with the video. The students experienced challenges regarding the video’s duration, the transfer to a subsequent related modeling problem, the absence of a teacher, and self-discipline. Hence, further learner support is necessary to guide the transition from working with a video to autonomous modeling, such as combining the video with strategic instruments and teacher support. In addition, interactive video features may be essential, as the students enjoyed how those features involved them in the process of watching the video. Overall, the results indicate that instructional videos are promising for providing heuristic worked examples, offering an innovative approach for teaching and learning mathematical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01546-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Trends, insights, and developments in research on the teaching and learning of algebra</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper addresses the recent body of research in algebra and algebraic thinking from 2018 to 2022. We reviewed 74 journal articles and identified four clusters of content areas: (a) literal symbols and symbolizing, (b) equivalence and the equal sign, (c) equations and systems, and (d) functions and graphing. We present the research on each of these content clusters, and we discuss insights on effective teaching practices and the social processes supporting algebraic reasoning. The research base shows that incorporating algebraic thinking into the elementary grades, emphasizing analytic and structural thinking processes, and emphasizing covariational reasoning supports students’ meaningful learning of core algebraic ideas. We close with a discussion of the major theoretical contributions emerging from the past five years, offering suggestions for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01545-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Education lead(her)ship: Advancing women in K-12 administration</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2024 06:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2311470?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the concept of energy through definitions, drawings, and metaphors</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2024 06:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2308150?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impact of realistic mathematics education on secondary school students’ problem-solving skills: a comparative evaluation study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2024 04:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2306633?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An exploratory study of the relation between teachers’ implicit theories and teacher noticing</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Despite interest in how students’ implicit theories—their growth and fixed mindsets about their own learning—affect students as learners, relatively little research on mindset has looked at &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;teachers&lt;/em&gt; as learners. This study explores elementary teachers’ implicit theories about the malleability of mathematics intelligence and teaching ability. It also examines how implicit theories of learning relate to teacher noticing, a construct that has been linked to teachers’ classroom practice and their students’ learning outcomes. Findings from the present investigation indicate that teachers generally reported growth mindsets concerning mathematics intelligence and teaching ability. For both mathematics intelligence and teaching ability, teachers’ reporting of more growth—compared to more fixed—mindsets was associated with more expert noticing, as measured by comments they wrote about elementary mathematics video clips on the dimensions of mathematics and student thinking. These findings point to intriguing possibilities about whether fostering growth mindsets (of mathematics intelligence and of teaching ability) in professional development settings might be leveraged to promote expert teacher noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09617-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Coaching Teachers in Document-Based History Instruction: Practices That Support Teacher Facilitation of Student Discourse</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Instructional coaching is increasingly regarded as an essential feature of professional development, but no research exists on content-specific instructional coaching for history teachers. The study examines data from a coaching program in which history teacher leaders served as novice coaches for their colleagues. We found that coached teachers, as a whole, improved in discussion facilitation. Case analysis of two successful and two less successful coach–teacher pairings revealed that successful coaches were more likely to focus on eliciting students’ argumentative discourse whereas less successful coach planning sessions focused on discrete historical content knowledge and the disciplinary heuristics of historical thinking. It appears that coaching that emphasized a conceptual redirection toward inquiry and a pedagogical toolkit for fostering student discourse was more closely tied to growth in discussion facilitation and opportunities for student historical reasoning than a coaching approach more narrowly focused on historical concepts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 11:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231223443?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Revealing the Known: The Invisibilized Bias of Commercial Literacy Curricula</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 03:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2309858?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hiding and Seeking: The Educational and Socioemotional Needs of Asylum Seeker and Refugee Students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 03:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2308436?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Marginalization at the Intersection of Language, Culture, and Disability: Systemic Contradictions Perceived by Special Education Teachers in Serving Culturally and Linguistically Diverse Students with Disabilities in South Korea</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 02:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2307800?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modelling individuality but advising universality: ethnography of mentoring pre-service teachers with regard to student diversity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 02:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2311694?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking discourses about the transition from school to university mathematics: an intensive reading</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper has two main goals: first, to analyze current research related with transition to identify the foci being produced and reproduced by research through a literature review and, second, to map the connections between circulating discourses to unfold the discursive network that supports them via an intensive reading. Specifically, we are interested in how social and economic factors, educational background, and cognitive development impact the transition process and the documented potential challenges students may face. In this fashion, the questions that guide the development of the paper are as follows: What are the dominant narratives in mathematics education research about the transition from school to university mathematics? How do dominant narratives entangle particular rationalities to configure a discursive network about the transition from school to university mathematics? As a result, we identify three dominant narratives entangled, which shape a system of reason that regulates what is possible to do, act, and think.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10288-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher identities and teacher identity change in pre-service mathematics teachers’ metaphors</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2024 11:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2306928?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racialized Early Grade (Mis)Behavior: The Links Between Same-Race/Ethnicity Teachers and Discipline in Elementary School</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Studies persistently show disparities in exclusionary discipline across racial/ethnic groups in U.S. schools. Using administrative data from kindergarteners through fifth graders in Indiana, we examine the effects of student-teacher race/ethnicity matching on disciplinary outcomes. We find that Black students exhibit lower rates of suspension and expulsion when they study with Black teachers—driven mainly by fewer defiance and profanity offenses. By contrast, for Latinx and White students, having a teacher of the same race/ethnicity is not associated with suspension and expulsion. In light of the shortage of Black teachers in the teacher workforce, our findings underscore the vulnerability of Black students to exclusionary discipline in the early stages of schooling.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2024 07:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231222185?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Relationship between science teachers’ teaching motivations and career development aspirations</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-05-2024 10:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2311698?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A longitudinal inquiry of sources of teacher self-efficacy: from the professional experience into the first year of teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-05-2024 10:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2311695?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does the Use of Concept Maps Affect the Defining and the Understanding of Inclusion Relationships?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-05-2024 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2310038?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Early Warning for Whom? Regression Discontinuity Evidence From the Effect of Early Warning System on Student Absence</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Many schools across the United States use the Early Warning System (EWS) to identify chronically absent students on time and intervene. The prediction power of the EWS is well examined but more evidence is needed about their effectiveness at reducing student absence. This study examines the effect of EWS on student absence in a large urban school district using a multiple-cutoff regression discontinuity design. Findings indicate that EWS reduces chronic absence among socioeconomically advantaged students. However, it has no significant effect on chronic absence among socioeconomically disadvantaged students. Furthermore, EWS has no significant effect on moderate absence. These results suggest that schools should consider social and institutional barriers to improving attendance, especially among socioeconomically disadvantaged students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-05-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231221503?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participation and Educational Conservatism Among Lower Secondary School Students in a Disadvantaged Neighborhood in Finland: A Request for Visible Pedagogies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-05-2024 04:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2307797?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Regularization to Identify Measurement Bias Across Multiple Background Characteristics: A Penalized Expectation–Maximization Algorithm</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Testing for differential item functioning (DIF) has undergone rapid statistical developments recently. Moderated nonlinear factor analysis (MNLFA) allows for simultaneous testing of DIF among multiple categorical and continuous covariates (e.g., sex, age, ethnicity, etc.), and regularization has shown promising results for identifying DIF among many covariates. However, computationally inefficient estimation methods have hampered practical use of the regularized MNFLA method. We develop a penalized expectation–maximization (EM) algorithm with soft- and firm-thresholding to more efficiently estimate regularized MNLFA parameters. Simulation and empirical results show that, compared to previous implementations of regularized MNFLA, the penalized EM algorithm is faster, more flexible, and more statistically principled. This method also yields similar recovery of DIF relative to previous implementations, suggesting that regularized DIF detection remains a preferred approach over traditional methods of identifying DIF.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-05-2024 01:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231226439?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Adult education in mathematics and numeracy: a scoping review of recent research</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The paper responds to the need for understanding trends and gaps in extant research related to adult education in mathematics and numeracy, given changing skill demands and skill gaps regarding adults, and related policy, theorizing, and practice trends. This paper presents the results of a scoping review of recent empirical research related to adult education in mathematics and numeracy, published in 22 selected journals from 2019 to 2022, including 15 journals in adult education and seven in mathematics education. The results show that only 39 relevant empirical studies were found among over 2300 research papers reviewed, and that few of those focus on practice-related of adult education in mathematics and numeracy. The results provide quantitative evidence suggesting that the field of adult numeracy education is under-researched, and help to identify gaps in empirical research involving adult numeracy, including on emerging topics such as on modeling and critical interpretation. The results also point to research opportunities that can strengthen theorizing and practice in both mathematics education and adult numeracy education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01549-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>You’re nobody until somebody kills you: the ingredients of black death for social justice and D̶E̶I̶ DIE</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2024 01:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306681?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improving the Usefulness and Use of Meta-Analysis to Inform Policy and Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This chapter begins with an overview of recent developments that have encouraged and facilitated greater use of research syntheses, including Meta-Analysis, to guide public policy and practice in education, workforce development, and social services. It discusses the role of Meta-Analysis for improving knowledge of the effectiveness of programs, policies, and practices and the applicability and generalizability of that knowledge to conditions other than those represented by the study samples and settings. The chapter concludes with recommendations for improving the potential of Meta-Analysis to accelerate knowledge development through changing how we design, conduct, and report findings of individual studies to maximize their usefulness in Meta-Analysis as well as how we produce and report Meta-Analysis findings. The paper includes references to resources supporting the recommendations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2024 09:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241229885?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racial gaslighting as affective injustice: a conceptual framework for education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2024 03:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306680?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
