<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Experienced teachers talking about their mathematics teaching with linguistically disadvantaged learners</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Learners of mathematics who are linguistically disadvantaged for a variety of reasons, including impoverished socioeconomic status, continue to be educationally disadvantaged and at considerable risk of school failure and early dropout. This is the case in many parts of the world. While much has been researched on linguistically disadvantaged learners in the fields of sociology and general pedagogy, little is known about the classroom teaching of mathematical content in language-responsive ways for all learners in school. Experienced mathematics teachers draw on a wealth of knowledge of content teaching in language-responsive ways developed through their practices working with linguistically disadvantaged learners in their classrooms. In this paper we report on interviews with some of these experienced mathematics teachers from seven educational contexts focusing on teaching probability in language-responsive ways. We focus on what we can learn from these teachers that could inform our practice as mathematics teacher educators and our research. We identify three challenges and three practices that add nuance and depth to theoretical research findings and recommendations on language in mathematics teaching, which can potentially develop these findings in more practical and accurate ways.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09628-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tensions in Teaching Chinese International Students: A Self-Study of Cultural Competence in an Educational Foundations Course</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-10-2024 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2339882?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Against Teaching Home As Housing in School: Examining How Teachers Teach Home</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-10-2024 07:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2335891?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of a Learning Trajectory for statistical inference on 9th-grade students’ statistical literacy</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In our data-driven society, it is essential for students to become statistically literate. A core domain within Statistical Literacy is Statistical Inference, the ability to draw inferences from sample data. Acquiring and applying inferences is difficult for students and, therefore, usually not included in the pre-10th-grade curriculum. However, recent studies suggest that developing a good understanding of key statistical concepts at an early age facilitates the understanding of Statistical Inference later on. This study evaluates the effects of a Learning Trajectory for Statistical Inference on Dutch 9th-grade students’ Statistical Literacy. Theories on informal Statistical Inference and repeated sampling guided the Learning Trajectory’s design. For the evaluation, we used a pre-post research design with an intervention group (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 267). The results indicated that students made significant progress on Statistical Literacy and on the ability to make inferences in particular, but also on the other domains of Statistical Literacy. To further interpret the learning gains of this group, we compared students’ results with national baseline achievements from a comparison group (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 217) who followed the regular 9th-grade curriculum, and with international studies using similar test items. Both comparisons confirmed a significant positive effect on all domains of Statistical Literacy. These findings suggest that current statistics curricula for grades 7–9, usually with a strong descriptive focus, can be enriched with an inferential focus.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00487-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Arab teacher educators and the moral work of teaching in Israel</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-09-2024 10:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2337636?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interrogating the role of emotion and race in anti-oppressive language and literacy practices in education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cree20/27/3&quot;&gt;Volume 27, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, May 2024&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-09-2024 10:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2323772?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Relocating assessment in pre-service teacher education: an emerging model from activity theory lens</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-09-2024 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2339522?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A feasible balance? The Italian teachers’ standpoint on assessment literacy, assessment practice, and teacher professional development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-09-2024 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2338853?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching quality in kindergarten: professional development and quality of adaptive learning support enhances mathematical competency</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Adaptive learning support provided by kindergarten teachers before and after (macro-adaptive learning support) as well as during mathematical learning activities (micro-adaptive learning support) is a cross-cutting concept of teaching quality. Effective adaptive learning support enhances children’s learning. However, providing it is challenging and teachers need professional development (PD) to improve the quality of their support. This study investigates the mediating role of teaching quality between PD programs for kindergarten teachers and the development of children’s mathematical competency. 122 kindergarten teachers and their 825 pupils participated in the study. The teachers were randomly assigned to three groups. Two groups attended PD sessions designed to foster either macro- or micro-adaptive learning support. The third was the materials-only control group. The data was analyzed using a self-developed rating instrument focusing on generic and domain-specific elements of teaching quality related to macro- and micro-adaptive learning support. The multilevel latent change model analysis revealed that the PD programs had positive and significant effects on the teaching quality of kindergarten teachers. A significant positive relationship was also found between micro-adaptive learning support and changes in children’s mathematical competency. However, an indirect effect of teaching quality could not be detected, and the PD programs did not have a total effect on children’s mathematical competency. The study reinforces the importance of PD that specifically targets macro- and micro-adaptive learning support for kindergarten teachers. The mediation between PD and mathematical competency development requires further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01566-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collaborative Troubleshooting in STEM: A Case Study of High School Students Finding and Fixing Code, Circuit and Craft Challenges in Electronic Textiles</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 06:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2334697?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Novel Numerical Method for Solving Unknown Statistical Quantities in Multivariate Regression Models</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Simulation studies are the basic tools of quantitative methodologists used to obtain empirical solutions to statistical problems that may be impossible to derive through direct mathematical computations. The successful execution of many simulation studies relies on the accurate generation of correlated multivariate data that adhere to a particular model with known parameter values. In this article, we use a kernel inspired by path tracing rules to algebraically solve unknown causal effects in the context of a multivariate general linear model. The algebraic solution is the basis of the mathematical extension, which integrates a model solver. Examples are used to illustrate a range of applications, where information regarding parameter values and predictor correlations can be partially specified. Code for examples is provided.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 04:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241240083?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Extant Data to Improve Estimation of the Standardized Mean Difference</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article presents methods for using extant data to improve the properties of estimators of the standardized mean difference (SMD) effect size. Because samples recruited into education research studies are often more homogeneous than the populations of policy interest, the variation in educational outcomes can be smaller in these samples than is reflective of the true variation in the population. This affects effect size estimation since the sample standard deviation is used in the denominator of the SMD. We propose leveraging extant data on sample variance estimates from multiple studies, made available via clearinghouse databases such as the What Works Clearinghouse, to standardize a mean difference. This allows effect sizes to be benchmarked across a common and broad population, thus enabling better comparability across studies and interventions. We derive the new estimators of the population variance and the corresponding SMD, which pool sample variances from multiple studies using both an analysis of variance and a meta-analytic framework. We demonstrate the properties of these estimators via analytic and simulation results and offer recommendations for when these estimators are appropriate in practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 04:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241238478?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strive for Measurement, Set New Standards, and Try Not to Be Evil</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;I consider recent attempts to establish standards, principles, and goals for artificial intelligence (AI) through the lens of educational measurement. Distinctions are made between generative AI and AI-adjacent methods and applications of AI in formative versus summative assessment contexts. While expressing optimism about its possibilities, I caution that the examples of truly generative AI in educational testing have the potential to be overexaggerated, that efforts to establish standards for AI should complement the Standards for Educational and Psychological Testing and focus attention on the issues of fairness and social responsibility, and that scientific advance and transparency in the development and application of AI in educational assessment may be incompatible with the competitive marketplace that is funding this development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 04:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241238479?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improving Researchers’ Capacity to Address Injustice: An Introduction to the Special Issue</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Many education policy researchers have turned to critical policy analysis as a means to better understand and examine injustices in education and beyond. However, such work is still uncommon in educational journals. In this introduction, we describe the purposes of this special issue and offer readers a framework for understanding critical approaches to education policy research, its general tenets, and how it differs from other kinds of policy research. We then outline the contributions of the articles in this special issue. We highlight analytic moves that researchers of all kinds can make based on the critical education policy research tenets we discuss. The introduction concludes with suggestions for where we hope the field will go next.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241239982?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The key-roles of the expert during classroom discussions aimed at fostering formative assessment processes through the use of digital technologies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We study the experts’ practices developed with the support of digital technologies (DT), when they take aware in-the-moment decisions during classroom discussions to promote the development of effective formative assessment (FA) processes. In this investigation, we complement a macro-analysis of paradigmatic examples of classroom activities, focused on the functionalities of DT and on the implemented FA strategies, with a micro-analysis, developed with reference to a theoretical construct useful for interpreting and analysing expert teachers’ roles during classroom discussions (the Model of Aware and Effective Attitudes and Behaviours, M&lt;sub class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;AE&lt;/sub&gt;AB). More specifically, we explore how the expert uses DT to empower these roles with the aim of promoting FA processes. This study has two implications: (1) at the theoretical level, the study will introduce a model aimed at characterising the ways in which the expert can promote FA during classroom discussions when they are mediated by the use of DT; (2) at the pragmatic level, the use of this model to analyse paradigmatic examples from teaching experiments will introduce potential guidelines for teacher professional development aimed at promoting teachers’ autonomous use of DT to carry out effective FA practices.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01572-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Heterogeneous Patterns of Family Engagement With Educational Technology to Inform School-Family Communication in Linguistically Diverse Communities</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We leverage log data from an educational app and two-way text message records from over 3,500 students during the summers of 2019 and 2020 and in-depth interviews in Spanish and English to identify patterns of family engagement with educational technology. Based on the type and timing of technology use, we identify several distinct profiles of engagement, which we group into two categories: independent users who engage with technology-based educational software independently and interaction-supported users who use two-way communications to support their engagement. We also find that as the demands of families from schools increased during the COVID-19 pandemic, Spanish-speaking families were significantly more likely than English-speaking families to engage with educational technology across all categories of families, particularly as interaction-supported users.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2024 03:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241238651?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does Aid Matter? A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of the Effects of Grant Aid on College Student Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The College Board reported that, in 2022–2023, about two thirds of $177 billion in U.S. financial assistance awarded to undergraduates through programs sponsored by the federal government, state governments, colleges and universities, philanthropic organizations, and other entities was in the form of grants. While researchers have examined the effects of individual grant aid programs on particular college student outcomes, results have indicated varied effects. Moreover, individual study findings have not been widely synthesized or examined to understand why some programs succeed where others do not. We conducted a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis to provide structure to this varied field and better understand programmatic effects. The results of the systematic searching and screening yielded 86 studies, across seven outcome domains, and the meta-analysis synthesized findings from 709 effect sizes from study samples representing 7,656,062 individuals. The meta-analytic results found small but meaningful positive average effects on college enrollment, credit accumulation, persistence, and completion. We cannot conclude from available studies that grant aid increased academic achievement or postcollege labor market outcomes. We also found that grants had larger positive effects on credit accumulation for studies with samples of students at 2-year institutions and studies that combined samples of 2- and 4-year students than for studies with samples of students at 4-year institutions only. Using a relatively new method called an evidence gap map, we illustrate where researchers should focus on producing new evidence.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2024 02:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241239955?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fostering student teachers’ research-based knowledge of effective feedback</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2024 02:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2338841?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Disentangling Person-Dependent and Item-Dependent Causal Effects: Applications of Item Response Theory to the Estimation of Treatment Effect Heterogeneity</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Analyzing heterogeneous treatment effects (HTEs) plays a crucial role in understanding the impacts of educational interventions. A standard practice for HTE analysis is to examine interactions between treatment status and preintervention participant characteristics, such as pretest scores, to identify how different groups respond to treatment. This study demonstrates that the identical patterns of HTE on test score outcomes can emerge either from variation in treatment effects due to a preintervention participant characteristic or from correlations between treatment effects and item easiness parameters. We demonstrate analytically and through simulation that these two scenarios cannot be distinguished if analysis is based on summary scores alone. We then describe a novel approach that identifies the relevant data-generating process by leveraging item-level data. We apply our approach to a randomized trial of a reading intervention in second grade and show that any apparent HTE by pretest ability is driven by the correlation between treatment effect size and item easiness. Our results highlight the potential of employing measurement principles in causal analysis, beyond their common use in test construction.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2024 01:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241240085?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: Expanding on prior conceptualizations of teacher noticing</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01570-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participants’ perceptions of video-enhanced dialogic assessment as reflective practice in international teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 12:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2338847?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student-driven teaching and educational action research combined: an approach to teaching development and student empowerment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 10:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2337213?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reconceptualizing Parents as Policy Agents Within Special Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Existing research on the implementation of special education (SE) has consistently documented racial inequities in the law’s implementation. We present a new theoretical framework to guide future research. SE law requires parents to act as initiators, developers, and enforcers in the implementation of SE policy. Drawing from law and society research, we demonstrate how the law’s design contributes to structural inequalities because it conscripts parents to work as policy agents. Parents may not be adequately resourced for their role, which contributes to inequalities and makes structural changes difficult. We argue that this framework may shift approaches to research within and beyond SE, helping to reorient approaches to understanding parents’ roles and the reproduction of inequities within educational policy implementation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 04:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241238679?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Situating Teacher Movement, Space, and Relationships to Pedagogy: A Visual Method and Framework</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In conversations about pedagogy, researchers often overlook how physical space and movement shape teacher sensemaking. This article offers a comparative case study of classroom videos using a dynamic visual method to map embodied interaction called “interaction geography.” Our analysis proposes an integrative framework to study classroom interactions and teacher movement over space and time comprised of four salient characteristics within lessons: trails, landmarks, material routines, and circulation patterns. We discuss how this visual method and framework can be used and expanded by classroom researchers and teachers as a starting point to better understand teaching as a situative and spatial practice, a crucial step in characterizing responsive forms of instruction. This work has implications not only for teachers and teacher educators but also for architects, administrators, and researchers concerned with the physical design of classrooms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 04:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241238698?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
