<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Constructed Pathways: How Multiply-Marginalized Students Navigate Food Insecurity at Selective Universities</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Studies about collegiate food insecurity show its prevalence as a national issue that disproportionately affects students from marginalized groups. This study further contextualizes this work, examining the ways that multiply-marginalized students navigate systems of privilege and opportunity at selective, normatively affluent universities to meet food needs and pursue personal goals. Findings from this multi-institutional qualitative study highlight asset-based approaches by which students leverage institutional interest in their marginal identities as navigational strategies. Conclusions point to the value of “student pathways navigation” as a conceptual and analytic approach to understanding how students manage collegiate environments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-08-2024 05:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231217751?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Status Quo or Innovation? Transforming Teacher Education in Hostile Times</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher education is at a critical crossroads as colleges and schools of education contend with decreased student enrollment, legislative strategizing to limit what is taught, and general pushback regarding what teachers should learn about teaching and their students. As such, the field of teacher education must examine how to collectively rebuff the current movement by policy makers and elected officials who have formalized their desire to maintain the status quo in education. They continue to lobby against social justice in education, critical race theory, multicultural perspectives in teaching, and culturally responsive and relevant pedagogical approaches to classroom instruction, among others. This paper examines the current moment in educational history and highlights opportunities that may transform teacher education policy to become more justice centered.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-08-2024 05:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231220059?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Characteristics of mathematics coaches’ suggestions to teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2024 03:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2300862?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Positionality in the Politics of Education: Mapping the Strategies and Constraints of Education Reformers</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The success and failure of education reform policies often depend on the strategies of reformers. This article suggests a framework to understand the positionality of reformers, as they vary in their strategy (i.e., technical vs. relational) and focus for change (i.e., process- vs. outcomes-focused). Using the case of individuals who initiated new data systems in Chicago, Philadelphia, and New York City, the study discusses four groups of reformers: Engineers privilege efficient technical fixes that may be resisted by people on the ground. Capacity-builders focus on empowering schools but may lead to variable successes. Framers research and disseminate ideas to reframe policy and political discourses. Table-setters leverage their social networks and financial resources but may challenge democratic decision-making. As schools continue to be sites of political debates and challenges, the concept of positionality can clarify how reformers promote particular changes and can suggest possibilities for positions to constructively complement each other.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2024 12:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231220038?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pre-Service Teachers Notice Student Thinking: Then What?</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Research has demonstrated that pre-service teachers (PSTs) can learn to notice students’ thinking in sophisticated ways by analyzing videos of classroom interactions. What is less clear is how PSTs use what they notice about student thinking to inform how they respond. Secondary math and science PSTs from three teacher preparation programs were invited to analyze a video clip identifying noteworthy moments of student thinking and describing an instructional move they might make and why. A qualitative analysis of their responses indicates that the PSTs overwhelmingly noticed both the substance and the source of students’ ideas. However, the patterns in their responses to these moments varied. These findings suggest that PSTs would benefit from spending more time unpacking what it means to respond to students’ thinking. The study provides implications for teacher education with respect to the careful selection of classroom clips and tools to support novice teachers developing responsive teaching practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2024 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231220604?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student participation in teachers’ action research: teachers’ and students’ engagement in social learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2024 06:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2301335?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Statistical Power Analysis for Univariate Meta-Analysis: A Three-Level Model</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2024 03:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2290544?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Regards d’enseignants du secondaire au Québec sur l’enseignement et l’apprentissage par projet en sciences et technologie: place, significations et visées</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article presents the results of a study aimed at understanding potential implications of the project-based approach to teaching science and technology (S&amp;amp;T). A survey of 221 secondary teachers shows that the meaning of this approach hangs on attributes that make it difficult to characterize and differentiate from other pedagogical approaches (e.g. the problem-based approach, interdisciplinarity, strategic teaching, explicit teaching). The objectives that respondents associated with the project-based approach have more to do with socialization than instruction; non-disciplinary skills are perceived to take precedence over teachings specific to S&amp;amp;T. Moreover, the degree to which teachers use this approach trails far behind other approaches that do not compete with subject-specific learning (explicit teaching in particular). The challenges reported by the respondents—especially by the segment of teachers who claimed to have never used this approach—show the need for teacher training on the didactic foundations of this approach and the production of resources that would encourage its use in a way that promotes better learning in S&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00305-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On the Interplay of Motivational Characteristics and Academic Achievement: The Role of Need for Cognition</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;While intelligence and motivational variables are well-established predictors of academic achievement, Need for Cognition (NFC), the stable intrinsic motivation to engage in and enjoy challenging intellectual activity, has not yet been considered comprehensively in this field, especially not longitudinally. By applying latent change score modeling, we examined the incremental value of NFC, considering well-established motivational constructs and prior achievement in the prediction of academic achievement across different subjects in a longitudinal approach across two time points in a sample of secondary school students ([math] = 271, [math] = 255). Correlations of NFC with grades were comparable to those of established predictors. NFC incrementally predicted academic achievement over and above prior achievement and ability self-concept. A mutual influence of NFC and academic achievement was found pointing to skill development as well as self-enhancement processes taking place in this interplay. Consequently, we propose to include NFC in models for the comprehensive explanation of academic achievement in school.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 12:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231218961?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Robots’ Social Behaviors for Language Learning: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although robots’ social behaviors are known for their capacity to facilitate learner–robot interaction for language learning, their application and effect have not been adequately explored. This study reviewed 59 empirical articles to examine the contexts and application of various social behaviors of robots for language learning, and conducted a meta-analysis of 18 study samples to evaluate the effect of robots’ social supportive behaviors on language learning achievement. Results indicate that robots’ social behaviors have mostly been applied in the studies with K–12 students, for learning vocabulary in English, including small sample sizes of below 80 participants, and lasting for one session. Second, various verbal and non-verbal behaviors of robots have been identified and applied, showing mixed results on language learning achievement. Third, robots’ social supportive behaviors have produced a positive effect on language learning achievement compared to neutral behaviors (g = 0.269). Finally, detailed suggestions for future research are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 11:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231216437?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Multidimensional Framing of Environments Beyond Blocks and Texts in K–12 Programming</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Computer programming provides a framework for interdisciplinary learning in sciences, arts and languages. However, increasing integration of programming in K–12 shows that the block-based and text-based dichotomy of programming environments does not reflect the spectrum of their affordance. Hence, educators are confronted with a fundamental hurdle of matching programming environments with learners’ cognitive abilities and learning objectives. This study addresses this challenge by analyzing 111 articles evaluating the affordances of programming environments to identify both structural and theoretical models to support educators’ choice of programming environments. The following dimensions of programming environments were identified: connectivity mode, interface natural language, language inheritance, age appropriateness, cost of environment, output interface, input interface, and project types. For each of these dimensions, the synthesis of the literature ranged from examining its nature and effect on learning programming to the implications of choosing an environment and the critical gaps that future studies should address. The findings offer instructors useful parameters to compare and assess programming environments’ suitability and alignment with learning objectives.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 11:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231216958?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Empirical Analysis of Energy Consumption and Economic Growth in Post-Soviet Eurasia: Do They Matter for Foreign Policy?</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study aims to evaluate the relationship between renewable and non-renewable energy consumption and economic growth in post-Soviet Eurasian countries by employing panel data from 15 countries from 1996 to 2018. The results reveal that the contribution of renewable energy consumption (REC) to economic growth is greater than non-renewable energy consumption. The overall findings imply that the transformation of energy consumption from non-renewable to renewable offers environmental advantages and growth opportunities. Furthermore, the transition to renewables may also expand the range of foreign relations policy options available for these countries, which, in turn, might contribute to a better alignment with evolving global regimes. Transition demands towards the long-term sustainability of global energy sources put pressure on countries to expand their domestic policy efforts and join international cooperation efforts. Therefore, post-Soviet Eurasian countries should develop strategic policy mechanisms and reforms designed to accelerate investments in renewable energy technologies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 09:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231224756?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Law Schools Cream-Skimming to Bolster Their Bar Exam Pass Rates? A Multilevel Regression Approach to Estimate How Attrition and Transfer Rates Affect Bar Passage</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Law schools are held accountable on many fronts to achieve and maintain high bar passage rates. While the course of legal education itself, along with various interventions, is a key driver of bar exam performance, Bahadur et al. (2021) suggests that obscure institutional practices might be inflating institutional bar passage performance. Such practices could include recruitment and admission of transfer students and academic attrition. We examine this hypothesis to assess the influence of both attrition and transfer on law schools’ bar passage differential using fixed-effects and between-within models. We also utilize Poisson regression to explore the effect of geographical proximity to other law schools on transfer rates. We find that, on average, neither attrition nor transfer activity substantively affect bar passage performance, and that although geographic proximity to other schools is related to transfer rates, this relationship does not result in notable differences in bar passage.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 09:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231214526?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Redefining Populations of Inference for Generalizations from Small Studies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 09:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2290546?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estimating Treatment Effects with the Explanatory Item Response Model</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 08:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2287601?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impacts of a Standards-Based Grading System Emphasizing Formative Assessment, Feedback, and Re-Assessment: A Mixed Methods, Cluster Randomized Control Trial in Ninth Grade Mathematics Classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 08:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2287594?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Intervention Effect or Measurement Artifact? Using Invariance Models to Reveal Response-Shift Bias in Experimental Studies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 08:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2284768?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reading Aloud to Children, Social Inequalities and Vocabulary Development: Evidence from a Randomized Controlled Trial</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 08:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2283475?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reimagining and remaking teacher education: priorities, practices and dilemmas</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 06:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2298632?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Sociological Analysis of Structural Racism in “Student List” Lead Generation Products</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Colleges identify prospective students by purchasing “student lists.” Student list products are selection devices that use search filters to select students. Drawing from the sociology of race, we conceptualize some filters as “racialized inputs,” defined as inputs that are correlated with race because disadvantaged racial groups have historically been excluded from the input. Using a national sample of high school students, we explore the relationship between racialized search filters and the racial composition of included versus excluded students. Using data about actual lists purchased by public universities, we investigate how college administrators utilize racialized search filters. We discuss implications for federal and state policy. We motivate policy research about structural racism embedded in selection devices that allocate students to opportunities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 06:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231210894?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Emergence and Escalation of Online Racial Discrimination in Digital Spaces: A Systematic Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;COVID-19 required educators and students to rapidly move to online learning. Simultaneously, while navigating the pandemic in lockdown, citizens were exposed to the brutal murder of George Floyd. The increased exposure to online activity and discrimination generated a hyperawareness of the potential link between the two. Our interest was to examine that linkage as we considered the prevalence and escalation of online racial discrimination (ORD) as a student phenomenon. Filtering for adolescent and young adult students, this systematic review ultimately employed 21 articles. Our results reflect that ORD as defined, changed over time, as did the ways it manifested. Importantly, the impacts of ORD on student learning and well-being were revealed. This review further indicates that the expansion of online instruction created a complex intersection between online social interactions and academic outcomes ripe for vigilance. Our work adds to the ORD literature while informing future education researchers, educators, and stakeholders of its harmful impacts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 05:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231217459?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measuring the Interdisciplinarity and Collaboration Perceptions of U.S. Scientists, Engineers, and Educators</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Interdisciplinarity has the potential to lead to more innovation and advances in knowledge than are possible from a single discipline. Yet, little is known about interdisciplinary collaborations and the perceptions of those involved. This quantitative study investigated the perceptions of U.S. faculty, staff, postdocs, and graduate students involved in education and science/engineering collaborations. Exploratory factor analysis was conducted for two modified scales, Collaboration Perceptions (CP; n = 117; 17 items; α = .923) and Interdisciplinarity Perceptions (IP; n = 119; 11 items; α = .852). Participants’ perceptions of collaboration and interdisciplinarity were strongly positive and did not significantly differ based on demographic factors (e.g., gender, discipline, role). Perceptions were influenced by collectivist orientation; the high collectivism group had significantly more positive perceptions of collaboration and interdisciplinarity, and collectivist orientation was positively and significantly correlated with CP and IP scores. Implications and recommendations for interdisciplinary collaborations will be discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 05:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231218952?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>YPAR and powerful partnerships for change: reconceptualisations of youth-led participatory action research and catalytic validity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2024 01:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2299311?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impact of service learning supported by the ePortfolio on the development of professional competencies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-02-2024 01:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2281396?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
