<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Synthesisability and optimising exploratory action research for continuing professional development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-03-2024 08:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2362706?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing the role of being an advocate in mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics teacher education is often described in terms of the mathematical content and pedagogy that teachers need. However, recent calls for equity in mathematics education demand a broadening of this view. In this article, we articulate a theoretical description of what the role of being an advocate in language-diverse classrooms could involve and some of the practical challenges that mathematics teacher educators may have when introducing it, using empirical examples from our teacher education courses for teachers of Grades 1–7 in Norway. In the theoretical description of the role of being an advocate into mathematics teacher education, we distinguish between in-class advocacy and advocacy beyond the classroom and what these different kinds of advocacy might entail in language-diverse classrooms. The practical issues that we identified in raising different aspects of the role indicate the need for further research into how to raise preservice teachers’ awareness about the role of being an advocate, in and outside of the classroom, in different cultural settings and how this knowledge could be used in teacher education to challenge preservice teachers’ language ideologies and raise non-trivial issues.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09629-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Profiles of teachers’ expertise in professional noticing of children’s mathematical thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study contributes to the growing body of research that highlights the usefulness of professional noticing of children’s mathematical thinking for understanding the complexity and variability in teaching expertise. We explored the noticing expertise of 72 upper elementary school teachers engaged in multi-year professional development focused on children’s fraction thinking. Our assessment addressed the three component skills of professional noticing of children’s mathematical thinking: (a) attending to children’s strategy details, (b) interpreting children’s understandings, and (c) deciding how to respond on the basis of children’s understandings. We used a latent class analysis to empirically identify three distinct “profiles” of noticing expertise—subgroups of teachers who responded similarly to each other and differently from teachers in other profiles. The profiles differed in their overall noticing expertise as well as their patterns of strengths and areas for growth across the component skills. Thus, the profiles provide a concise, multi-dimensional characterization of noticing expertise that integrates expertise in each of the component skills. The profiles also provide tools for differentiating learning opportunities for teachers in professional development. In addition, our design allowed us to compare teachers’ expertise in two common forms of deciding how to respond: deciding on follow-up questions and deciding on next problems. In all three profiles, teachers demonstrated more expertise when deciding on follow-up questions than when deciding on next problems, suggesting not only a starting point for teacher learning but also the need for a line of research focused on different forms of this component skill.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09558-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Documenting two emerging sociomathematical norms for examining functions in mathematics teachers’ online asynchronous discussions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigated novice mathematics teachers participating in an online teacher education course focused on covariational reasoning and understanding the behavior of functions. The analysis centered on documenting the emergence of participants’ sociomathematical norms for engaging in online asynchronous discussions. In this paper, we characterized participants’ initial mathematical discourse and documented two emergent sociomathematical norms, namely &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;explaining why&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;emergent shape discourse&lt;/em&gt;. When participants &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;explained why&lt;/em&gt;, they used specific quantities or symbolic representations of functions to justify why function graphs have particular visual features. When participants engaged in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;emergent shape discourse&lt;/em&gt;, they coordinated change between covarying quantities to justify why function graphs behave in certain ways. This study provides evidence that online settings can provide context for mathematics teachers engaging in legitimate collaborative mathematical activity and that activity can be enhanced by participation in discourse featuring specific sociomathematical norms. We discuss conjectures regarding the potential of reflective discussion activities paired with the Notice and Wonder Framework to support the emergence of generative sociomathematical norms. We also discuss potential relationships between characteristics of participants’ mathematical discourse and their membership with the core and periphery of a social network.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09563-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice elementary teachers’ mathematical achievement and attitudes: A study of blended learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The primary purpose of this quasi-experimental mixed-methods study was to examine whether a blended learning approach was more effective than traditional face-to-face instruction in improving the mathematical achievement and attitudes of preservice elementary teachers. The secondary purpose was to determine what specific features of blended learning were deemed most helpful to prospective teachers’ learning of mathematics. Sixty-three prospective teachers participated in a foundational mathematics course in either a face-to-face (F2F) traditional or blended learning format. At pre- and post-test, participants completed a researcher-developed mathematics achievement test and the Dutton’s Attitude Scale (Dutton in ESJ 68:259–264, 1968) . Blended learning participants also completed a post-course researcher-developed questionnaire on their perceptions of blended learning. Results indicated that participants who were enrolled in the blended learning format had significantly better attitudes at post-test than teachers in the F2F format, but no condition differences were found for mathematical achievement. Participants in the blended learning condition valued the flexibility of course structure and control over instructional pace but expressed that time management and decreased physical presence of the instructor were challenges. These findings suggest important elements to consider when designing blended learning courses.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09565-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Some mathematicians’ perceived and envisioned instructional relationships in secondary teaching and teaching secondary teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When it comes to content courses for prospective secondary teachers, mathematics faculty’s intentions conflict with teachers’ experiences: while faculty aim to influence teachers’ future teaching, many teachers find these courses irrelevant to teaching. In this study, we investigate mathematics faculty’s goals for content courses for prospective secondary teachers and how these goals connect to their vision of secondary teaching. This study makes two contributions. First, drawing on data from an interview study (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 5) of faculty who have taught secondary teachers, we articulate these mathematicians’ rationales with respect to teaching secondary teachers, particularly in capstone courses. Second, we contribute a conceptual framework that supports inferences about connections between content course activities and instructors’ beliefs about secondary teaching. We conclude by suggesting that the dual triad that depicts our framework may support professional development and programmatic design.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09567-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The use of a scriptwriting task as a window into how prospective teachers envision teacher moves for supporting student reasoning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The development of mathematical reasoning skills has increasingly been of focus for the teaching and learning of mathematics. This research utilizes a teaching simulation using the methodology of scriptwriting, in which prospective teachers are asked to complete a script of a dialogue from a classroom simulation involving fraction multiplication and division with justification, assisting fictional students to work through their difficulties and helping them to justify their reasoning. Such tasks allow for the examination of the prospective teacher moves to support student reasoning through their imagined action and choice of words. Scripts from forty-one prospective primary teachers were examined for the study, and five clusters based on the type of teacher move for supporting student reasoning were found. Overall, the prospective teachers emphasized the elicitation and facilitation of students’ ideas. The cluster analysis, however, provided a nuanced examination of the cohort’s teacher moves. While cluster one saw the highest incident of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;eliciting&lt;/em&gt; teacher moves, albeit only in the low potential category, clusters two and three mostly used &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;facilitating&lt;/em&gt; teacher moves, but varied in their use of high and low potential moves. Cluster four concentrated moves on &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;facilitating, eliciting,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;responding to student reasoning&lt;/em&gt;. Cluster five employed teacher moves from all main categories, with some instances of high potential moves in all categories except &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;extending student reasoning&lt;/em&gt;, which can better support reasoning. The prospective mathematics teachers’ scripts and the five clusters that were found during analysis are discussed with implications for future teacher education and the support of building mathematical reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09570-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Secondary mathematics preservice teachers’ perceptions of program (in)coherence</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teacher educators globally have argued that developing coherent programs can combat the fragmentation that often characterizes teacher education and better support teacher learning. Yet, there is little research on coherence in mathematics teacher education, especially from the perspectives of preservice teachers. To that end, in this article, we report how 13 secondary mathematics preservice teachers (PSTs) from one teacher education program perceived their program as coherent, specifically attending to the ideas and practices PSTs engaged with and the settings in which they engaged with those ideas/practices. Based on participatory diagramming interviews and network analysis, we found that PSTs experienced two main sources of incoherence. First, although PSTs had opportunities to learn about equity from multiple settings, they did not perceive that equity and other aspects of mathematics instruction together were coherently organized. Second, PSTs reported learning about two opposing instructional approaches—direct instruction and inquiry-based instruction. PSTs reported that opportunities to learn about inquiry-based instruction were primarily isolated to courses taught by the mathematics education program and were contradicted by learning and experiencing direct instruction in their special education courses, mathematics courses, and field and student teaching experiences. Findings highlight a need to attend to issues of equity, as well as connections among university coursework and between coursework and field. Based on our findings, we conclude with implications for how teacher education programs might respond to and engage with incoherence to support PST learning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09575-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What do mathematicians wish to teach teachers about the discipline of mathematics?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigates what mathematicians, who teach academic mathematics courses to secondary school mathematics teachers, want to teach them about the discipline of mathematics. Data sources included interviews with five research mathematicians. The data analysis revealed that expanding teachers’ knowledge about the discipline of mathematics was one of the interviewees’ main objectives. The mathematicians referred to nine characteristics that can be grouped into three key aspects: (1) essence of mathematics, (2) doing mathematics, and (3) worth of mathematics. The characteristics of the discipline of mathematics generated in our study are in line with ideas and practices widely advocated in the last decades for the teaching and learning of mathematics, and with contemporary philosophical approaches regarding mathematics. The potential of the characteristics to serve as a conceptual framework in studies that focus on teacher knowledge about the discipline of mathematics is discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09577-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>I find this task interesting, so do you? Preservice teachers’ judgments of students’ enjoyment, boredom, and situational interest regarding tasks with and without a connection to reality</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students’ emotions (e.g., enjoyment, boredom) while doing math and their situational interest in mathematics are important for their learning of mathematics, but examinations of teachers’ judgments of students’ emotions and interest while solving tasks are rare. Moreover, we do not know much about the predictors of teachers’ judgments of students’ emotions and interest. In this study, we addressed preservice teachers’ judgments of students’ task-specific enjoyment, boredom, and situational interest and analyzed whether such judgments are related to preservice teachers’ own enjoyment, boredom, and interest. Furthermore, we aimed to analyze whether preservice teachers’ judgments differ between the two types of tasks under investigation (tasks with and without a connection to reality). To achieve these aims, 182 preservice teachers were randomly assigned to one of two study conditions. In one condition, preservice teachers&#39; judgments of task-specific emotions and situational interest for fictitious 9th-grade students were measured, and in the second condition, preservice teachers&#39; own task-specific emotions and situational interest were measured. The results show that preservice teachers&#39; judgments of students’ task-specific emotions and situational interest differ for tasks with and without a connection to reality. Further, our findings indicate that preservice teachers’ judgments of students’ task-specific emotions and interest differ from preservice teachers&#39; own task-specific emotions and interest. Implications for theoretical models of teachers’ judgments and consequences for teacher education are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09581-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A prospective teacher’s conceptions about the nature of mathematical tasks and professional knowledge within task unfolding</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This qualitative study aimed to identify the changes in a prospective’ conceptions about the nature of mathematical tasks and pedagogy in video cases and to investigate the characteristics of the prospective’ professional knowledge and views during task design/modification. The study used the mathematical task demand engagement process, which includes task-sorting activity, selecting tasks, reflecting on illustrative cases, and teaching and reflecting on tasks as enacted. The findings regarding one prospective, Kar, were reported. Focus group interviews, individual interviews, and two recorded lessons were used as data sources. The content analysis method was employed for the in-depth analysis of the data. The findings suggested a change in Kar’s ideas about the nature of mathematical tasks, particularly about what characteristics low and high-level tasks possess and the efficiency of the Task Analysis Guide. Kar also generated detailed ideas on the pedagogy of high and low tasks and realized the role of teachers as facilitators while enacting high-level tasks. Another finding is that Kar’s decisions regarding task adaptation and her reasons catalyze both situated and global knowledge and views. Our findings suggest that providing an opportunity for prospective to reflect on and discuss the nature of mathematical tasks as planned, implemented, and revisited in a professional context is beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09584-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Objects of study in research on mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09631-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Graduate Teaching Assistants’ Perception of Student Difficulties and Use in Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Given the important role graduate teaching assistants (TAs) play in undergraduate students’ learning, we investigated what TAs identified as students’ difficulties from students’ written work, their plans to address them, and implementation of their plans in class. Since the difficulties that TAs identified in general matched errors that students made, we analyzed what TAs identified in terms of literature on error handling. We examined levels of specific details of students’ work involved in TAs’ identifying, planning, and teaching. Our results show that (a) TAs often did not identify the most frequent errors students made, which reflected well-documented difficulties from the literature, (b) the errors TAs identified were mainly procedural in nature, (c) specific details of students’ work were mainly included in procedural errors, and (d) the level of specificity of students’ work was generally consistent but showed some drops when going from identifying to planning, then to teaching. Our results highlight interesting questions for future research and could be used as resources to design professional development that helps TAs use students’ errors in teaching to promote students’ learning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00239-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The research circle: a possible utopia? Possibilities and constraints of knowledge development within a research-circle practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-31-2024 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2359426?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Time in School: A Conceptual Framework, Synthesis of the Causal Research, and Empirical Exploration</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We examine the fundamental and complex role that time plays in the learning process. We begin by developing a conceptual framework to elucidate the multiple obstacles schools face in converting total time in school into active learning time. We then synthesize the causal research and document a clear positive effect of additional time on student achievement typically of small to medium magnitude depending on dosage, use, and context. Further descriptive analyses reveal how large differences in the length of the school day and year across public schools are an underappreciated dimension of educational inequality in the United States. Finally, our case study of time loss in one urban district demonstrates the potential to substantially increase instructional time within existing constraints.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-31-2024 05:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241251857?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing Finnish and Chinese national teacher education frameworks from the teacher competency perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-31-2024 01:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2361108?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to achieve ‘egalitarian’ interaction between student teachers and mentor teachers? A study of a one-school-year teacher practicum in Germany</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-31-2024 01:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2359708?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Response Times in Answer Similarity Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Recent decades have seen a tremendous growth in the development of collusion detection methods, many of which rest on the assumption that examinees who engage in collusion will display unusually similar scores/responses. In this article, we expand the definition of answer similarity to include not only the item scores/responses but also the item response times (RTs). Using detailed simulations and an experimental data set, we show that (a) both the new and existing similarity statistics are able to control the Type I error rate in most of the studied conditions and (b) the new statistics are much more powerful, on average, than the existing statistics at detecting several types of simulated collusion.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 09:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241248770?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Quotas Constructed from Auxiliary Data to Guide the Recruitment of Sites for Randomized Controlled Trials</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 08:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2342852?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The “Who” of Teacher Residencies: Preservice Teachers’ Motivations for Selecting a Teacher Residency Program</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 08:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2358921?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dignity-Affirming Care in Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 05:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357008?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>(Trans)formation of student teachers’ professional identity through problem-based learning in Korea</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-30-2024 01:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2360555?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/32/3&quot;&gt;Volume 32, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, July 2024, Page 327-331&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-29-2024 11:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2357959?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Any Other Thoughts?”: Establishing Third Space in a Family-School-University STEM Partnership to Center Voices of Parents and Teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-29-2024 03:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357010?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
