<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Classroom Data Visualization: Tracking Individuals During Group-Centered Instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Understanding students’ participation in collaborative classroom settings is important in a variety of educational contexts, with implications for teaching, research, and equity. Using data from a group-centered developmental mathematics class, this research brief illustrates novel quantitative representations of students’ group participation and their instructor’s classroom activity. Presenting an overview of classroom activities based on audio data, the diagrams show a variety of patterns, including each group’s progression through assigned tasks, some students’ exclusion from discussions of those tasks, and the teacher’s patterns of interaction with groups. The representations provide new ways that researchers might approach and present multilayered classroom data.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-10-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231158374?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Integrated Framework for Studying How Schools Respond to External Pressures</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The changing educational landscape requires new organizational frameworks to understand how schools and universities make sense of and respond to broader institutional forces like accountability, diversity, and the market. In this article, we draw on recent innovations in organizational theory to propose a model that identifies two general processes through which pressures from the environment shape educational practice in schools: filtering and local adaptation. We review three areas where researchers have studied filtering and local adaptation—routines, sensemaking, and networks—to illustrate how these processes are currently being applied in education and how this work can be extended. We also identify studies that have begun to integrate these different areas of scholarship and propose directions for future research. This article offers education researchers new to the field conceptual tools for guiding their analysis and assists more seasoned researchers in situating their studies in a broader context of institutional maintenance, change, and heterogeneity.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-10-2023 03:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231159599?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do So-Called Critical Race Theory Bans Say?</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In the wake of racial justice protests in the United States, many states adopted policies to constrain the discussion of racism, particularly contemporary and systemic racism, in K-12 classrooms. Discursively framed as “critical race theory bans,” these policies enumerate lists of “prohibited concepts” to be eliminated from classroom instruction and curriculum materials. This brief document analysis provides an overview of first-wave prohibited concepts policies among the states to adopt such policies during the 2020-2022 legislative sessions. The analysis summarizes the prohibited concepts, teaching practices that remain allowed, and the nature of the prohibitions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-10-2023 03:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231159382?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Enduring Problems, Rethinking Process, Fulfilling Promises: Reflections on the Continuing Shortage of Teachers of Color</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Thirty years ago, “Problems, process, and promise: Reflections on a collaborative approach to the solution of the minority teacher shortage” (Goodwin, 1991) offered a perspective on an approach to the minority teacher shortage. That piece represented the start of the author’s life-long work on teacher preparation, with a particular focus on the recruitment and retention of teachers of color in response to growing numbers of students of color juxtaposed against a predominantly white teaching force. Now, several decades later, this article is her opportunity to reflect on those early thoughts, framed by the question: What progress have we made (or not) as a profession, and a society, in addressing this imperative? In pondering this question, this piece returns to the focus of the original article to think anew about problems, process, and promise as conceptual lenses for assessing how far we have come and where we now need to go.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2023 09:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231160372?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Literacy Intervention in Secondary Schools: Exploring Educators’ Beliefs and Practices about Supporting Adolescents’ Literacy Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;There is a need to better understand the complex landscape of adolescent literacy intervention as a shared responsibility across all educational stakeholders. To address this need, we examined the self-reported literacy beliefs and practices about secondary readers and literacy intervention among a group of educators (including administrators, teachers, and specialists) who participated in a year-long professional learning series focused on providing adolescents with rich and responsive literacy learning opportunities. We found that educators’ beliefs and practices shifted as they developed shared understandings of asset-based mindsets and ways of supporting students’ situated literacy learning and comprehension within disciplinary contexts. We offer suggestions for how to create shared learning opportunities for educators across roles and discuss implications for future research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2023 08:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231156371?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How narratives about the secondary-tertiary transition shape undergraduate tutors’ sense-making of their teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Drawing on the commognitive framework, we construe the secondary-tertiary transition (STT) as a distinctive element in the pedagogical discourses of various communities. Our interest rests with university tutors in light of the emergent recognition of their impact on undergraduates’ mathematics learning in many tertiary contexts worldwide. We aim to understand the roles of STT communication in tutors’ reflections on incidents that took place in their tutorials. Our participants were undergraduate students in the advanced stages of their mathematics degrees in a large New Zealand university and who were enrolled in a mathematics education course. Throughout the semester, the participants led tutorial sessions for first-year students and wrote reflections on classroom incidents that drew their attention. Our data corpus consisted of 58 reflections from 38 tutors collected over four semesters. The analysis revealed that STT communication featured in tutors’ descriptions of classroom incidents, assisted them in making sense of unexpected events, positioned their instructional actions as replications of what was familiar to them from their own STT experience, and contributed toward generating new pedagogical narratives. We situate these findings in the literature concerning undergraduate tutoring and teachers’ perspectives on STT.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10211-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“If you’re a dude, you’re a chick, whatever the hell in between, you need to know about maths”: the Australian and Canadian general public’s views of gender and mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research on gender issues and mathematics education is often conducted in classroom settings and/or with teachers, students, and parents. However, perspectives about mathematics from adults beyond teachers and parents can have an impact on students. Thus, we conducted research in Australia and Canada about the general public’s views of gender and mathematics. Participants (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 405) were surveyed using a questionnaire in which all questions were worded in a non-binary manner. In this article, we focus on participants’ views about gender and mathematics ability, and the importance of studying mathematics by gender. We report both overall trends and trends by demographic group (country, gender, age, and education level). The majority of participants indicated that there was no relationship between gender and mathematics ability or between gender and the importance of studying mathematics. Participants with gendered views typically felt that boys/men/males are better at mathematics and that it was more important for girls/women/females to study mathematics. Although the findings were generally encouraging, the existence of sexist, stereotyped views highlights the need for additional work to probe people’s views of gender and mathematics. Our study is an example of mathematics education research conducted in a gender-inclusive way.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-09-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00448-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘There’s no such thing as a clean line’: an award-winning history teacher’s racial ideologies-in-pieces</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-08-2023 12:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2181330?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We All Sort of Jump to That Relationship Piece”: Science Teachers’ Collaborative Professional Learning about the Role of Relationships in Argumentation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-08-2023 05:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2180006?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>John Heron 1928-2022: A personal memoir by Peter Reason</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/arja/21/1&quot;&gt;Volume 21, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 144-150, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-08-2023 04:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231157925?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An action research evaluation using films in a workshop for nursing clinical educators</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-08-2023 01:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2187855?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Action research in initial EFL teacher education: emerging insights from a CAR project</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-07-2023 12:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2187854?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Charter Authorizing, Applications, and the Needs of Historically Marginalized Students: A Cross State Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Charter school authorizers shape which charter schools open, where they open, and who they serve. We draw on principal agent theory to investigate how the priorities and practices of nine authorizers intersected with charter school applications’ attention to the needs of historically marginalized students. Using data from interviews and applications, we find authorizers vary in orientations toward equity and the ways in which they signal that orientation to charter applicants. Our analysis suggests a robust relationship between authorizer mission and the content found in charter applications, demonstrating the influence of authorizing practices on the contents of charter school applications.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-07-2023 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231153596?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching the concept of zero in a Malawi primary school: illuminating the language and resource challenge</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper we discuss findings of a study that investigated the resources and language that teachers in Malawi use to teach the concept of zero. In Malawi primary schools, textual resources available to teachers are mainly the curriculum materials in the form of syllabus, teacher guides and learner textbooks. The syllabus and teacher guides are in English while the learner textbooks are in Chichewa as teaching is in Chichewa or other local language in the first 4 years of primary school. We used the Mediating Primary Mathematics framework (Venkat and Askew in Educ Stud Math 97:71–92, 2018) and a qualitative case study of two teachers to explore the resources used, how the teachers interacted with the resources and how they moved between the two languages. Our findings include that the language and resources that the teachers used provided affordances as well as constraints for learning the concept of zero. We identified two types of challenges for the teachers; that of naming and that of representing the concept of zero. We discuss what the Malawi context illuminates about teaching zero in post-colonial multilingual settings.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01473-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The university mathematics lecture: to record, or not to record, that is the question</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;While recordings of lectures proved invaluable for students’ learning during the pandemic, as our university transitioned back to in-person teaching there was a call from many lecturers to remove the requirement to provide lecture recordings due to the perceived negative impact on attendance. To examine in detail the relationship between recordings and the corresponding face-to-face lectures, we conducted a study on the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;formats&lt;/em&gt; of lectures across our undergraduate mathematics programmes pre- and post-lockdown in March 2020, and students’ perceptions of how beneficial they felt each was for their learning. In May 2020, 156 mathematics students completed a survey containing both quantitative and qualitative questions. Findings indicate that pre-pandemic almost 70% of the lecture formats classified by students were traditional in nature, with 20% classified as containing some interactions, and the remainder as including group work. While students did not perceive &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; differences in terms of the benefits to learning between the face-to-face and online lecture formats in the majority of modules, those who experienced interactions or group work in lectures before lockdown, reported a greater drop than those who experienced a traditional lecture. Irrespective of preferences for face-to-face or online learning, students were clear about the value of lecture recordings and interactions with peers and lecturers to their learning. Based on our findings, and those of others, we discuss implications for mathematics lecturers’ practice. Specifically, we argue for the provision of lecture recordings or short pre-recordings, especially when the lecture is traditional in nature.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00444-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How long-term emancipatory programming facilitates participatory evaluation: Building a methodology of participation through research with youth in Honduras</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Empowerment and participation are promoted as critical factors in meaningful development processes; however, action-oriented researchers face challenges in fostering genuine empowerment and meaningful participation within traditional funding cycles and research timelines. This case study illustrates a participatory methodology employed by researchers in partnership with one Honduran non-governmental organization (NGO) to conduct ‘practical’ participatory evaluation with rural Honduran youth. Through collaborative autoethnography, two components of this methodology are identified and described. The first component – ‘foundational elements’- includes the NGO’s culture of transformative participation and the organization’s attention to synergies in the insider/outsider identities of research partners. The second component includes the ability of the research team to leverage this foundation for the participatory evaluation with rural youth. Importantly, this ability was grounded in and shaped by long-term, trust-based relationships between research partners. These relationships were the catalyst for success in this participatory initiative, connecting the ‘foundational elements’ identified to the collaborative outcomes experienced. Overall, this case study contributes to current and ongoing scholarly discussions on how to facilitate meaningful participation and capability expansion in research and evaluation contexts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-06-2023 09:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231160960?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Perceptions of Past Classroom Behaviors Influence Adolescents’ Receptivity and Responsiveness to a Belonging Intervention</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study shows how receptivity and responsiveness can influence the efficacy of an intervention helping adolescents reappraise worry or uncertainty following the difficult transition to middle school. The intervention was implemented at-scale in a diverse sample of sixth-grade public school district students followed through eighth grade (N = 1,180; 41% Black or Latinx; 44% low socioeconomic status). Results suggest the intervention’s effects on grade point average are confined to a racially and socioeconomically diverse subgroup of adolescents who had high teacher evaluations of their classroom behaviors in kindergarten that declined over the early elementary school years (i.e., “Disengagers”). These findings suggest that adolescents’ past school experiences with educators may bound the extent to which interventions can promote success in school.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-06-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231154605?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/31/1&quot;&gt;Volume 31, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, February 2023, Page 1-3&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-06-2023 02:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2168105?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Action research in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA)</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/31/1&quot;&gt;Volume 31, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, February 2023, Page 98-101&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-06-2023 02:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2168104?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>High school mathematics teachers&#39; noticing of inequitable talk</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;To make instructional decisions that interrupt inequitable talk in the classroom, teachers must notice it in the first place. In a two-year Professional Learning Experience (PLE) focused on the core practice of facilitating equitable discussions, we found that two different groups of math teachers took up the work of noticing for equity in different ways and with varying degrees of success. We analyzed teachers’ written goals for teaching, videos of their in-person classroom instruction, video recordings of their coaching sessions, and sets of video annotations. Our findings indicate that teachers who noticed for equity: (1) engaged in conversations about status and identity (2) had more student-centered goals, and (3) were more likely to select “bumpy moments” of their instruction to discuss in coaching sessions. These findings have implications for instructional coaches, teacher educators, and professional learning facilitators interested in supporting teachers with noticing inequitable talk in their classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09572-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Design of Making Pre-K count and High Fives: Two-Stage, Multiyear Random Assignment at Different Levels</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The Making Pre-K Count and High 5s studies represent a recent application of a phased two-stage, multi-level design, which was used to examine the effects of two aligned math programs implemented in early childhood settings. The purpose of this paper is to describe the challenges encountered in implementing this two-stage design and to describe approaches to resolving them. We then present a set of sensitivity analyses the study team used to examine the robustness of the findings. During the pre-K year, pre-K centers were randomly assigned either to receive an evidence-based early math curriculum and associated professional development (Making Pre-K Count) or to a pre-K-as-usual control condition. In the kindergarten year, students who had been in Making Pre-K Count program classrooms in pre-K were then individually randomly assigned within schools to small-group supplemental math clubs that were designed to sustain the gains from the pre-K program, or to a business-as-usual kindergarten experience. Making Pre-K Count took place in 69 pre-K sites, comprising 173 classrooms across New York City. High 5s took place in the 24 sites that were part of the public school treatment arm of the Making Pre-K Count study and included 613 students. The study focuses on the effect of the Making Pre-K Count and High 5s programs on children’s math skills at the end of kindergarten as measured by two instruments, the Research-Based Early Math Assessment-Kindergarten (REMA-K) and the Woodcock–Johnson Applied Problems test. The multi-armed design, while logistically and analytically challenging, balanced multiple considerations of power, the number of research questions that could be answered, and efficiency of resources. Robustness checks suggest that the design created groups that were both meaningfully and statistically equivalent. Decisions to use a phased multi-armed design should consider both its strengths and weaknesses. While the design allows for a more flexible, expansive research study, it also introduces complexities that need to be addressed both logistically and analytically.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-04-2023 11:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231159472?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Achieving SDG-13 in the Era of Conflicts: The Roles of Economic Growth and Government Stability</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Establishing effective climate control and reducing the ecological footprint (EF) are necessary for pursuing Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), in particular Goal 13. In this context, it is required to enhance the understanding of various factors that can either decrease or enhance the EF. In the literature to date, limited studies on external conflicts (EX) have reported diverse results, and also the impacts of government stability (GS) on EF are less explored. This study explores the roles of external conflicts, economic growth, and government stability on EF in the context of SDG-13. The study also contributes to the literature by examining the environmental effects of government stability and external conflicts for the first time in Pakistan. This research uses time-series methodologies on data from Pakistan from 1984 to 2018 for exploring the long-run relations and causal dynamics. The results unfolded that external conflicts stimulate and Granger cause EF and therefore expand environmental deterioration. Thus, limiting conflicts is in the favor of Pakistan to achieve SDG-13. Surprisingly, government stability also poses harmful impacts on environmental quality by enhancing the EF, indicating that stable governments focus on improving economic conditions rather than environmental quality. Moreover, the study proves the validity of the environmental Kuznets curve. Policy suggestions are made to move forward in achieving SDG-13 and to evaluate the effectiveness of government environmental policies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-04-2023 01:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231160626?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The “Turn Once Again Toward Practice-Based Teacher Education” Revisited</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper provides an analysis of how work on practice-based teacher education has evolved and remained the same since 2012.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-03-2023 09:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231160401?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Response to How Teacher Education Matters</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This response to “How Teacher Education Matters” (2000) notes that the evidence base about the features of teacher education that matter for teacher effectiveness was substantial at that time and has grown stronger since. However, federal policy over the last two decades has reduced support for both preservice teacher education programs and for candidates’ financial assistance, while increasing support for alternative certification pathways that generally omit student teaching and often truncate coursework as well. One-third of teachers in recent years have entered without having completed preparation and are disproportionately assigned to schools serving low-income students and students of color. Meanwhile, recent research emphasizes the critical importance of well-designed clinical experiences with strong mentoring in high-quality settings, connected to applied coursework, as key to effectiveness. Residency programs are one emerging model that combines such experiences with financial supports, showing promise for recruiting and retaining a diverse, well-prepared set of candidates in high need fields and locations. High-performing countries like Finland and Singapore make these kinds of investments in teacher education routinely and shed light on the policy strategies needed to create a universally strong teacher education system.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>03-03-2023 09:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231160378?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
