<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Approaches to Statistical Efficiency When Comparing the Embedded Adaptive Interventions in a SMART</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Sequential, multiple assignment randomized trials (SMARTs), which assist in the optimization of adaptive interventions, are growing in popularity in education and behavioral sciences. This is unsurprising, as adaptive interventions reflect the sequential, tailored nature of learning in a classroom or school. Nonetheless, as is true elsewhere in education research, observed effect sizes in education-based SMARTs are frequently small. As a consequence, statistical efficiency is of paramount importance in their analysis. The contributions of this manuscript are twofold. First, we provide an overview of adaptive interventions and SMART designs for researchers in education science. Second, we propose four techniques that have the potential to improve statistical efficiency in the analysis of SMARTs. We demonstrate the benefits of these techniques in SMART settings both through the analysis of a SMART designed to optimize an adaptive intervention for increasing cognitive behavioral therapy delivery in school settings and through a comprehensive simulation study. Each of the proposed techniques is easily implementable, either with over-the-counter statistical software or through R code provided in Supplemental Material.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-28-2024 07:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241251419?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Research-Practice Partnerships Advance Multilingual Learner Equity? A Case Study of Partnership with State-Education-Agency Leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-28-2024 05:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357036?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Unexpected Benefits of a Research-Practice Partnership’s Efforts to Strengthen Budgetary Decision-Making</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-28-2024 05:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357039?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Rising Tide That Lifts All Boats? Effects of Competition on Child Care Quality and Medium-Term Student Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Using administrative data of center-based child care providers in North Carolina from 2005 to 2018, we provide the first direct evidence on the effects of competition on provider quality and student outcomes in the context of early care and education, taking advantage of quality measures from the state’s Quality Rating and Improvement System (QRIS). We found that competition was associated with higher quality ratings and a higher probability to achieve a five-star rating—the highest tier in the QRIS. More competition increased providers’ probability to improve their rating and reduced the time to improve. Compared to public schools, private providers were responsive to competition. However, we did not find any effects of competition on district-level student third-grade academic performance.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 11:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241252413?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Holistic Capital Model: Time and Body Capital as Sources of Inequity</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;We present a model of capital that expands existing models to introduce two new forms of capital (time and body capital) as sources of inequity in education. The aim is to (a) make visible core resources that are relevant to educational outcomes and also (often hidden) sources of inequity, (b) identify commonalities across diverse empirical and theoretical research strands, and (c) reconceptualize existing research from an asset rather than deficit framework. We explain how time and physiological resources can be conceptualized as forms of capital and link this to extant empirical and theoretical research across fields. Then, we describe how students may have different amounts and types of time and body capital, as well as different drains on capital, and how this may lead to educational inequities. We close by describing the affordances of using this theory as a lens for analyzing existing educational structures, policies and practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 06:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241255626?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Individual to Collective Logics of Thriving: Redesigning K–12 Learning Ecosystems to Support Equitable Civic Futures</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 536-567, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The concept of “thriving” in educational policy refers to a loosely defined mix of academic, socioemotional, and civic outcomes associated with youth well-being. In this chapter, we analyze three focus areas in K–12 education—social emotional learning, 21st-century skills, and digital citizenship—and conclude that they are currently built on an individualistic neoliberal paradigm of learning and success. We argue that this paradigm is incommensurate with the personal, social, and civic flourishing necessary to sustain equitable multiracial democratic futures and offer instead an alternative collective logic of thriving. Our critical metasynthesis of the emergent field of social-design-based experimentation offers design principles educators can use to reorganize collective learning environments to support expansive youth thriving in schools and society.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231210257?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Science of Learning and Development: A View of the Issues</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page ix-xviii, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241244741?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Science of Learning and Development: A Commentary</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 155-160, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Transforming difficulties into opportunities for thriving is at the heart of this volume on the science of learning and development. This chapter brings the perspective of European research and the Global North and South and discusses some of the challenges included in the call to create the conditions for promoting sustainable and equitable futures for all. Among others, globalizing transformative knowledge by recreating, replicating, and scaling up success stories in education research can overcome methodological or epistemological limitations. Examples of cocreation and interdisciplinary work are included to produce socially relevant knowledge and be effective in tackling the real problems affecting children and youth. Dialogic learning and successful educational actions illustrate how educational success and transformation can happen.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231218731?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inclusive and Ameliorative Theorizing for Redressing 21st-Century Structural Inequities</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 167-172, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In analyzing the disseminated call, the commentary suggests the need for a consciousness consistent with a quote from Maya Angelou concerning identity. It is applied—in this case—to the situation of social science and specifically developmental science vis-à-vis published scholarship pertaining to communities of color. Questioned is the field’s long-term positionality regarding the persistent marginalization of Blacks. Suggested is the need to be candid in acknowledging the redundant “embracing of the lie of Black inferiority.” Argued is that the field’s positionality when it comes to representations of communities of color (i.e., embodied in “scholarly efforts”) serves as an untoward, incentivized, and under acknowledged contributor to the science of learning and development, which has problematic consequences for all.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231218878?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting Civic Reasoning, Discourse, and Problem Solving That Is Political Without Being Partisan</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 568-605, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This chapter focuses on effective preparation for civic reasoning, discourse, and problem solving. It reviews literatures, including major synthetic reviews and studies from the science of learning and development (SoLD), civics education, and mathematics education. Based on these reviews, the authors make the case for a more comprehensive form of civic education in which reasoning, discourse, and problem solving permeate the curriculum across grades and subject matter. As an example, the authors illustrate how mathematical tools and techniques inform powerful fact-based civic reasoning and discourse and how SoLD informs both. This approach to learning engages students in politically relevant issues in a nonpartisan way as they prepare to become democratic decision-makers and problem solvers of the future.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231219989?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bringing the Science of Learning and Development Into the South African Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 161-166, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Transforming the South African education system after decades of apartheid remains a dream for all. This chapter contributes on how this dream can be achieved. To this end, I raise two arguments. First, transformation will require young people to become adept at handling tensions and dilemmas. Second, I propose that the science of learning and development (SoLD) has a possibility to develop such competences. I begin with a look at the colonial education curricula in South Africa until the dawn of a democratic dispensation in 1994. This is followed by a critique of the post-1994 curriculum. In closing, I propose the SoLD model as an alternative to the classroom in South Africa as a route to equity and justice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241226917?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward Just and Sustainable Futures: Human Learning and Relationality Within Socio-Ecological Systems</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 218-273, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This chapter explores how learning to be in relation is core to human learning. Reductive views of cultural variation and individualized conceptualizations of thriving overlook the processes through which human beings learn to live relationally in ways that support systems transformation and collective well-being. Synthesizing literature on learning and development, we provide a conceptual model that examines four interrelated dimensions of relationality: (a) embodiment, mobilities, attention, and place; (b) affect, awe, and emotion; (c) pedagogical interactions, supports, and participation; and (d) reimagining learning and the disciplines. We argue that attending to relationality in ways that include between-persons + place + more-than-human relations helps conceptualize learning as deeply tied to the ongoing forms of adaptation, ethical relations, and worldmaking required for socio-ecological well-being.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231223505?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Learning Is Made Consequential: A Methodological Note on Repertoires</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 84-99, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This chapter focuses on the utopian methodological approach taken up by social design-based experiments, their conceptual underpinnings, and commitments. The methods are drawn from Gutiérrez’s empirical work and detail ways of seeing and capturing human learning activity crucial to envisioning and enacting new social futures with radical possibilities for those from historically nondominant communities. It elaborates methodological commitments to seeking complexity in human learning activity as it centers equity understood as worldmaking. A review of a range of methodological tools employed across Gutierrez’s studies is presented—from an analytical focus on ensembles and the multiplicity of social spaces in learning ecologies to attending to how people’s repertoires of practices are constituted through participation in everyday activity, as they move in and across the ecologies of everyday life.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231219981?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Science of Learning and Development: A Translational and Transactional Science in Service of Human Development and Well-Being</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 185-193, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This commentary describes several key principles from the science of learning and development (SoLD) and illustrates them using concepts and ideas from social and emotional learning (SEL). Emphasizing the importance of ecological systems in shaping developmental pathways and challenging the individual-centric approach, the first concept focuses on the centrality of developmental relationships. The second underscores the significance of stage-salient tasks in SEL, advocating for practices targeting developmental systems aligned with specific stages. Shifting the focus from product-driven to process-oriented interventions, the third concept highlights the need to prioritize understanding underlying processes for effective interventions. Lastly, the commentary emphasizes simplifying and localizing complex developmental science for practical application, distilling adaptable practices resonant with diverse contexts. Throughout, examples from SEL research and practice illustrate these concepts’ potential to bridge the research-practice gap in human development and education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231220271?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Implications of the Science of Learning and Development for the Field of Literacy</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 194-201, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this chapter, I consider how research in the field of literacy illuminates convergences of understandings about how people learn culled from the fields of biology, psychology, and neuroscience. I further consider how research in the field of literacy could be enhanced by drawing more deeply on state-of-the-art findings about how human learning unfolds. To support this discussion, I examine emerging understandings about literacy learning and development in the areas of reading and multiliteracies and across transnational contexts. I conclude by suggesting an equity-oriented agenda for literacy research and practice that leverages and advances existing knowledge about how people learn.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231222478?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introduction to Methodological Frameworks</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 46-48, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241236778?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Implications of Dynamic Systems for Future Methodology in Developmental and Learning Science</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 100-115, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Children develop and learn within dynamic contexts, yet the simplifying assumptions of common statistical methods often relegate such complexity to unexplained error. This chapter discusses ideas from the dynamic systems literature, which focuses on the interplay within and between components of complex systems, such as individuals and their multitiered contexts. This chapter presents three scenarios highlighting knowledge from the dynamic systems literature. These scenarios have implications requiring reconsidering common approaches to explaining the variance associated with change, the conceptualization of effect sizes, and the use of between-person data and analyses to make within-person inferences. The final section provides resources for moving beyond dynamic metaphors and principles, so theories can be translated into testable hypotheses.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231218728?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward a Coherent and Comprehensive Approach to Teacher Well-Being: A Synthesis of Theory and Review of Intervention Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 274-310, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers in the United States report persistently high levels of stress and burnout. In response, teacher well-being interventions have become increasingly prevalent in educational settings. To advance the development of a rigorous science of teacher well-being, our chapter offers a bioecological framework for understanding this construct; synthesizes findings from 15 years of peer-reviewed, published interventions; and critiques gaps in the literature. Of the 24 studies reviewed, most used experimental methodologies to evaluate mindfulness-based approaches aimed at bolstering teachers’ individual skills of both a positive and negative valence. Ultimately, far more attention to the unique experiences of teachers of color is needed, as is more focus on essential components of interventions and contextual-level factors related to the school system.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231210246?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Centering the Margins: Dynamic Systems, Targeted Universalism, and Special Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 213-217, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This commentary outlines the potential benefits of applying advances in the science of learning and development to special education service delivery and research. Building from a dynamic ecological systems perspective of development, it is argued that special education should focus on the whole child in context to leverage the correlated contributions of multiple factors in the learning and development of students with disabilities. The concept of targeted universalism is presented as a framework for creating universal service delivery structures that are centered on tailoring supports to the daily experiences and functioning of students who receive special education. Person-oriented analysis and longitudinal, idiographic designs are considered as an approach to guide the development and evaluation of such frameworks.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231218883?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Growing Points for a Synthesis Between the Sciences of Learning, School Reform, and Inequity: Insights From Complex Dynamical Systems Theory</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 606-635, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The growing differentiation of specialties in education creates the need for a common framework. This chapter discusses the basic premises of complex dynamical systems theory (CDST), its intellectual foundations, and its applicability to the field of education, with a particular focus on the areas of learning and development, school reform, and the persistence of inequity in society. The vocabulary of CDST is reviewed and applied to these problem areas to help deepen our understanding of the challenges facing policymakers and practitioners and provide growing points for the integration of these areas of knowledge into a coherent basis for further research and exploration. The differences between CDST and traditional research paradigms are also duly considered.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231209980?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Running Toward Network Models of Individuals and Their Contexts</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 181-184, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We note two possibilities for how our science might capitalize on advances in computing that harness and weave “big data” into the rich tapestry of how human development unfolds. First, we propose that the classic theoretical models that have guided developmental research since the 1970s and the hierarchical analytical models used to operationalize those theories might both be replaced with new network models that capture multidirectional interplay among many facets of a person and their context. Second, we suggest that contemporary person-specific (idiographic) network models based on newly available streams of data about a human’s ongoing activities and experiences can reshape what we discover about individuals and how those discoveries are injected back into people’s lives.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231219237?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making Connections to and From Out-of-School Experiences</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 443-473, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This chapter surfaces examples of the ways educators, programs, and families are making connections to and from out-of-school time (OST) experiences and into other contexts in learners’ lives, including additional programs, homes, communities, and schools. Through a review, the authors test, refine, and expand a design framework for connections across settings described in connected learning scholarship and identify shared goals and outcome indicators for collectively fostering equity through connective OST practices. The review has implications for practice in terms of offering design principles, examples, and outcome indicators for making connections that policymakers, program leaders, and educators can take up and for research by investigating and theorizing the role connective practices in OST programs can play in learning ecosystems.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231211271?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Sociogenesis of Representations and Ideas: Coordinating Archival, Ethnographic, Interview, and Experimental Methods</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 49-59, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Relationships between individual development and historical change are understudied, and yet an understanding of these relationships is foundational to understanding human development. The chapter provides a case study model for investigating individual-historical relations that coordinates archival, ethnographic, interview, and experimental methods. The methodological approach is illustrated in studies on numerical cognition conducted in Papua New Guinea. Two generalizable methodological assumptions are articulated: that the emergence of novel representations and ideas is rooted in individuals’ activities in collective practices and that the dynamic sociogenetic processes in collective practices provide the context for individual development. The chapter concludes by pointing to extensions of the framework to additional studies conducted in a wide range of communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231220886?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Weaving a Colorful Cloth: Centering Education on Humans’ Emergent Developmental Potentials</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1-45, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We integrate work from human development, psychology, education, and neuroscience to argue for five interrelated developmental principles that together provide the conceptual basis for a fundamental shift in thinking in education about the nature of learning, and hence the work of teaching, and the purpose and design of schools and youth-facing policies. These principles foreground humans’ natural agency, subjectivity, and variability and the dynamic, adaptive interdependence of body, mind, and culture in development and learning. We take the analogy of weaving cloth to highlight the properties and valuable variations of effective educational systems. We argue that reconceptualizing learning is necessary to meaningfully improve schooling and its outcomes, support equity and human dignity, and ultimately, build a sustainable democratic society.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-27-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X231223516?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
