<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Progression in units coordination: initial counterevidence for a transition that transcends mathematical domains</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2024 12:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2421055?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Need-Based Promise Programs, Performance Funding Bonuses, and the Enrollment of Low-Income Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Certain statewide promise programs require students to demonstrate financial need, while state performance funding policies sometimes incorporate a financial bonus that incentivizes colleges to enroll or graduate low-income students. We use data on public, 4-year colleges from 2007–2008 to 2019–2020, and incorporate difference-in-differences analyses and event studies. We find that colleges affected by promise programs in Louisiana, New York, and Washington observed no changes to the number and percent of first-time, full-time (FTFT) Pell grant recipients. Colleges in states subject to a performance funding bonus experienced no changes to the number and percent of FTFT Pell grants recipients, and colleges in Louisiana subject to both policies experienced no changes to either outcome.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2024 07:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241287410?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Attendance Practices in High-Absenteeism Districts</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Though researchers have documented the consequences and causes of chronic absenteeism, there is limited empirical evidence about what schools and districts are actually doing to improve attendance. This study presents evidence about the types of attendance practices that forty-seven high-absenteeism districts in Michigan are planning and implementing, using data from principal surveys, case studies, observations, and school improvement plans. In 2022-2023, principals reported using communication practices, incentives, and to an extent providing resources to address barriers to attendance. In improvement plans, districts planned to create new organizational infrastructure and hire new personnel, with less emphasis on specific practices. These findings highlight frequent use of communication-based strategies and limited existing organizational infrastructure for addressing attendance. It is unclear whether planned practices will address social and economic inequalities at the root of high absenteeism rates. I conclude with recommendations for monitoring new attendance practices, addressing root causes, and avoiding counterproductive practices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 09:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241288504?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under the Law: Virtually an education</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 52-53, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The closure of school buildings during the pandemic made virtual instruction necessary. Since schools have reopened, its use has become more normalized than it was pre-COVID. Bob Kim discusses some of the civil rights issues education leaders and policy makers must consider if they choose to assign certain students to virtual instruction. Some students, particularly students from low-income families, students with disabilities, and English learners, may have difficulty accessing virtual instruction or receiving the full benefit of instruction when it is delivered virtually.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295433?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Person: The Happy Farm: Igniting the flame of knowledge in children</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 48-49, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher Shanshan Wang took the opportunity to transform an empty area near her school into a vegetable and fruit garden with her students, which they dubbed the Happy Farm. Students planted the seeds and tended the plants. They kept journals about the growing plants and worked together to solve problems when they arose. The produce from the garden is served in the school cafeteria. Wang writes that the students value being out in nature and learning through activities rather than just in their classrooms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295431?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Backtalk: Where are the teachers of color? Getting cut out and lured away</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 54-55, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research has shown that having a diverse teacher workforce benefits students, but the population of teachers remains predominantly white, even as the student population becomes increasingly diverse. Andrew Kwok and Brendan Bartanen analyzed data from college applications in Texas and found that interest in teacher certification has declined in the past decade more than interest in other professions. Promisingly, the racial makeup of college applicants interested in teaching is relatively diverse. However, at every stage in the process toward becoming a teacher, the diversity decreases. They recommend that education leaders and schools of education make intentional efforts to reach out to students of color early about the possibility of becoming a teacher.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295434?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: The case for sensory civics education</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 50-51, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Civics education should include ways for students to experience civic life and to understand how voting affects their lives. Jonathan E. Collins writes that civics education is currently perceived as a luxury. It is, instead, a societal necessity that will help build and maintain our civic infrastructure.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295432?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Employing School Librarians: What Decision-Makers Tell Us</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 42-46, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Although research has shown that having a school librarian benefits students, librarian positions are being cut in schools across the U.S. SLIDE — The School Librarian Investigation: Decline or Evolution? — examined federal data on school library staffing and interviewed 49 district leaders about their decisions to eliminate or add librarian positions. Keith Curry Lance, Debra E. Kachel, and Caitlin Gerrity report that of 54 total decisions leaders made related to changes in librarian staffing, 28 resulted in librarian increases and 26 resulted in librarian decreases. Decisions to add or eliminate positions were generally related to changes in district priorities. Although leaders expressed that they value librarians’ role in providing information literacy instruction and support and had positive experiences with librarians, some had to allocate resources to other positions. Others had trouble finding librarians with the necessary qualifications. When making staffing decisions, leaders need to consider what benefits librarians offer and how to meet student and staff needs for information and media literacy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295430?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: Organizational news about PDK International</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-63, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this month’s PDK Connection, CEO James F. Lane highlights a visit to a new Educators Rising site in Pennsylvania by U.S. Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona. Lane also addresses AI in the classroom and promotes new lesson assessments for Education Rising Curriculum users. Elsewhere in this regular department, PDK members share the one change they’d like to see in today’s schools and recount this summer’s trip to Vietnam with the PDK International Travel Program.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295437?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: Veteran educator wonders, ‘Is it too late to start over?’</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 56-57, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Educator Starr Sackstein gives workplace advice to educators. In this month’s column, an experienced teacher is feeling bored and wonders if it’s time to make a career pivot.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295435?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Poll Points: Public opinion on AI in schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 64-64, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;PDK International, Educators Rising, AI, PDK International Travel Program.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295438?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 7-7, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this regular column, Kappan authors recommend books that have influenced their thinking about education. In this issue, James Paul Gee recommends The Ignorant Schoolmaster: Five Lessons in Intellectual Emancipation by Jacques Rancière, and Ayesha Hashim recommends Suddenly Diverse: How School Districts Manage Race and Inequality by Erica O. Turner.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295422?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: Why come to school?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Workplace advice, Advice for educators, Career change, Student motivation, Teacher burnout
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295436?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editor’s Note: Nationwide problems, local solutions</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Kappan’s editor-in-chief shares highlights from the November 2024 issue, which focuses on student attendance and absenteeism.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295420?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>No one-size-fits-all solution to chronic absenteeism</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 8-12, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;As chronic absenteeism fails to ease from post-pandemic high levels, schools can turn to many reforms to promote school attendance. Commonly recommended strategies involve increasingly targeted and intensive tiers of interventions. Researcher Thomas S. Dee writes that the research base of many of these interventions is not strong. Schools facing financial and capacity restraints may have difficulty putting interventions in place. Dee suggests that educators obtain information on attendance barriers in their schools and base solutions on those data. Sharing information about attendance with families is one promising intervention.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295423?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Browsing: Further thoughts on this month’s theme</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 5-6, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Additional resources and discussion questions related to the November 2024 Kappan theme, “Attendance and Absenteeism.”
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295421?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cybersapien literacy: Integrating AI and human</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 32-38, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The landscape of writing is evolving in the era of generative AI. James Paul Gee introduces the concept of “cybersapien writing literacy,” which emphasizes a synergistic partnership between humans and AI. He outlines four essential types of writing and discusses their potential benefits for personal growth, critical thinking, and societal engagement. Integrative writing combines these writing types to foster what Gee calls “expansive cognition.” This vision of writing already exists in out-of-school learning environments like affinity spaces, but schools face challenges when implementing similar practices. Shifting away from time-based assessments toward individualized, achievement-based learning models will give students opportunities to leverage AI as a tutor, co-teacher, and partner in integrative writing work.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295428?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How do we teach honesty in a dishonest world?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 39-41, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;A civic society depends on people’s ability to reason together, which requires them to seek and tell the truth. However, Sarah Stitzlein argues that schools spend too little time deliberately teaching students the value of honesty. Far from being simply a personal virtue, honesty enables citizens to think and act together for the benefit of all. The rise in populism has led some people to define truth as what feels true to their own experience and the beliefs of their in-group, often dismissing the knowledge of experts. Schools can help students learn to discern truth by engaging in inquiry in which they consider their own beliefs and those of others, as well as information from experts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295429?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educating youth who don’t have a place to sleep</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 23-27, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Because housing instability can make it difficult for students to attend school, students experiencing homelessness (SEH) may become chronically absent. For this reason, SEH have lower graduation rates than their housed counterpants. Germany’s second-chance schools give students an opportunity to catch up on their learning so they can take final exams and earn diplomas. Kerri Tobin and Matthias Fischer studied 12 second-chance schools and found that they hold to four basic principles to counter the consequences of irregular attendance: low barriers, flexibility, a needs orientation, and positive motivation. While some of these principles may be difficult to implement in traditional U.S. and German schools, educators can adopt a more positive and compassionate attitude to encourage students to continue attending school, even when it’s difficult.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295426?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Connections and choice for high schoolers</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 28-31, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Chronic absenteeism is a symptom of a lack of student engagement. Many students feel that schools are not welcoming places and that what they learn in the classroom is not applicable in the real world. Schools like Metropolitan Regional Career and Technical Center (the Met) in Rhode Island offer an alternative to educating high school students that taps into their need for connection to adults and the world outside the classroom. The Met is the first school founded by Big Picture Learning, which has grown into a network of public schools across the country and internationally. Its interest-based learning approach gives students opportunities to explore internships and projects based on their interests and passions. The students devote two days a week to internships during the school year.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295427?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School and family partnership can reduce chronic absenteeism</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 13-18, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Families are critical partners in addressing chronic absenteeism. Drawing from research, authors Thomas J. Capretta, Jingyang (Max) Zhang, and Barbara J. Boone present four throughlines and six strategies for schools to improve attendance by building trust and partnering with families. In view of chronic absenteeism’s association with negative academic and life outcomes and disproportionate impact on underserved student populations, addressing absenteeism with families as partners is essential in building shared expectations and identifying unique solutions to unique barriers. The authors outline practical, accessible, and research-informed guidance for schools to tackle the persistent challenge of student attendance in education through high-quality partnerships with parents and community members.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295424?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Re-engaging students in the post-pandemic era</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/3&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 19-22, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The pandemic responses of Guilford County Schools in Greensboro, North Carolina, offer insights on how navigating the COVID-19 crisis can inform district and school practices to curb student absenteeism and support student engagement in learning. Guilford used ESSER money to develop pandemic response programs that addressed wide-ranging and shifting student needs stemming from the pandemic. Authors Ayesha K. Hashim, Clark Wright, Sonya Stephens, and Miles Davison discuss seven key insights into how the district transitioned those programs to help engage students after the pandemic while working to ease absentee rates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 03:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241295425?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Open mathematical tasks conceived, designed, and reflected upon by preservice elementary teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As part of the research on mathematical tasks, the literature on the advantages of using open tasks has been steadily growing. However, limited research exists on the types of open mathematical tasks considered by elementary preservice teachers and their abilities to create those tasks. This study explores the preconceptions of open mathematical tasks held by 56 preservice elementary teachers, as reflected in a survey where they described the characteristics and design of such tasks. The study also examines their reflections on implementing open mathematical tasks in one-on-one interviews with elementary students. Our analysis found that elementary preservice teachers described characteristics of open mathematical tasks that match aspects identified in the literature. They also showed the ability to create an open task to a certain degree. However, the open tasks they designed were predominantly procedural and focused on a few aspects of task openness. This finding indicates that the preservice teachers prefer a narrower spectrum of openness when creating open tasks compared to their preconceptions. Preservice teachers also reported challenges they faced when implementing the open tasks with elementary students. These findings suggest the need for mathematics teacher education to provide opportunities where future teachers design a broad spectrum of open mathematical tasks, while addressing on-the-ground challenges in classroom settings.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-29-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09661-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Anticipating the Side Effects of Educational Reform Using System Dynamics Modeling</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1-27, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;There have been countless efforts to improve academic achievement in public schools across the United States, especially in urban school districts. Few efforts, however, use rigorous analytic modeling tools to anticipate and prevent the potential side effects of change. This chapter proposes the application of system dynamics on educational reform efforts by offering a conceptual model, literature review, and research agenda to identify and mitigate the potential side effects of reform. The model is based on interviews and workshops with public school leaders, teachers, and parents in a midsized midwestern urban city. We identify a “capability trap” that may lead to policy resistance with educational reforms. Limitations to this approach are noted, and future areas of research are identified.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241260012?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
