<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ and kindergartners’ perceptions of children’s participation in interactive book reading</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2024 10:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2436879?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An appropriate problem – considerations behind pre-service mathematics teachers’ problem posing in combinatorics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2024 06:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2435616?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking the gender equality paradox: narratives about mathematics and gender among teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2024 06:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2435016?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging Home Reading to Strengthen Literacy Development: Applying Principal Stratification to Explore Efficacy Trial Effects</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 07:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2430583?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing Teachers’ Disciplinary Knowledge for High School STEM Integration: A Review of a Decade of Educational Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Increasing calls for greater STEM-integrated experiences in K–12 education have spawned numerous studies on teacher beliefs, educational goals, and practices for teaching and learning. However, how the field proposes to support the development of teachers’ STEM-integrated disciplinary knowledge appears to be underresearched. In this systematic review, we analyzed 110 articles to determine (a) in what ways has the literature focused on teacher learning, (b) to what extent the literature addressed the development of teachers’ STEM-integrated disciplinary knowledge, and (c) to what extent the literature identified mechanisms for developing teachers’ STEM-integrated disciplinary knowledge. Results reveal needs that include, among others, more studies focused on developing teacher disciplinary knowledge; studies that differentiate teacher needs at different grade levels; studies that differentiate mechanisms aimed at developing teachers’ pedagogical knowledge, pedagogical content knowledge, and disciplinary knowledge; and studies that explicitly examine the mechanisms being used to support the development of teachers’ STEM-integrated disciplinary knowledge.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241289566?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The practicum in initial teacher education – enduring challenges, evolving practices and future research directions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/47/5&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2024&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2428031?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>POLICY SOLUTIONS: Should school board elections be partisan?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 50-51, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Should school board elections be partisan? Jonathan E. Collins writes about the pros and cons of bringing political parties back into school board elections. While partisan elections can bring more voter participation and interest in school governance, they also run the risk of pushing aside real education issues for culture war distractions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304833?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>UNDER THE LAW: The (mis)education of Indigenous students</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 52-53, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Indigenous students in the U.S. — including American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian children — have faced a history of serious educational mistreatment. Today, the abusive boarding school program has ended, but Indigenous children still experience formidable challenges. Robert Kim describes laws related to schools funded by the Bureau of Indian Education, studies showing how the federal government has fallen short of its responsibilities, and a recent case attempting to hold the government accountable.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304834?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BACKTALK: Finding the sweet spot between curriculum fidelity and teacher agency</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 54-55, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Two common perspectives on the implementation of curriculum and instructional strategies often appear to be at odds. On one side are those who call for fidelity to designers’ plans. On the other side are those who call for the empowerment of teachers to meet individual student needs, regardless of the pace required by curriculum guides. Ronald S. Thomas explains how teachers can use data to find a sweet spot between these approaches.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304835?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CAREER CONFIDENTIAL: How do we help students overcome the &#39;I can&#39;ts&#39;?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 56-57, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;In Career Confidential, Starr Sackstein offers professional advice for educators. In this edition, an instructional coach wants to help an art teacher whose students think they’re no good at art.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304836?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>STUDENTS SPEAK UP: What makes math matter for students?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Educators Rising students share why math matters to them and describe some of the most engaging math lessons they’ve experienced.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304837?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>POLL POINTS: Public engagement in public schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 64-64, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;According to the 2024 PDK Poll, 46% of Americans report engaging with their local schools in the past year in at least one of four ways: attending a school event, donating money or supplies, attending a PTA meeting, or attending a school board meeting.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304839?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>FIRST PERSON: The person who taught me the most about teaching just graduated from high school</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 48-48, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Author Steven Goldman reflects on the lessons he learned from his son Theo during their car rides to and from school. Theo, who has mild dyslexia, talked about what school was like from his point of view. His perspectives helped Goldman become a better teacher.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304831?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK CONNECTION: Strategic planning and the future of PDK membership</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-63, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;In this month’s PDK Connection, CEO James F. Lane announces the association’s new vision (to eliminate the teacher shortage by reimagining educator pathways) and new mission (to inspire and grow current and rising educators to become community leaders and advocates for high quality education). Lane also shares information about a new member benefit and a new Kappan publication schedule. PDK members now have access to the Teaching Channel video library, while print editions of Kappan will be delivered to members four times a year (March, May, September, and December).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304838?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Holocaust education mandates work?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 42-47, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;In the context of both rising antisemitism in the U.S. and the increasing popularity of states mandating the teaching of the Holocaust in K-12 schools, William Smith asks, are such legislative mandates effective? Can states achieve ambitious goals like preventing future genocides and reducing antisemitism by requiring that students learn about the Holocaust? He reviews the limited research on Holocaust education mandates, and Holocaust education generally, with analysis suggesting that such curriculum mandates may not be having the desired effects on student learning. He poses theories about the factors limiting the effectiveness of these mandates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304830?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>THE EDITOR’S NOTE: Math, mindset, and identity</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Kappan editor-in-chief Teresa Preston reflects on common perceptions about math, developing a math identity, and the math education students need, as discussed in the December 2024/January 2025 issue of Kappan.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304821?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BROWSING: Further thoughts on this month’s theme</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 5-6, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Additional resources and discussion questions related to the December 2024/January 2025 Kappan theme, “The Math Education Students Need.”
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304822?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BOOKSHELF: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 7-7, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;In this regular column, Kappan authors recommend books that have influenced their thinking about education. In this issue, Paula M. Jakopovic recommends Troublemakers: Lessons in Freedom from Young Children at School by Carla Shalaby. William L. Smith recommends Threshold Concepts within the Disciplines, edited by Ray Land, Jan Meyer, and Jan Smith.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304823?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond the math wars: Focus on teachers to improve instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 8-13, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;The field of mathematics education has engaged in perennial debate about whether transmission-oriented or constructivist approaches to teaching will best help students learn. Yet, both fluency, learned through step-by-step procedural instruction, and the mathematical flexibility that comes from constructivist methods play an important role in mathematical achievement. Rachel S. McClam and Rebecca A. Cruz explain that the math wars debate acts as a straw man, with each side misrepresenting the other and detracting from what students really need — but often lack — to be successful in math: teachers who understand how both approaches work together to support students to become confident and knowledgeable mathematicians.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304824?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Math narratives and autobiographies</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 20-24, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Elementary preservice teachers enter teacher preparation programs with preformed conceptions of their abilities as mathematics learners that directly influence their sense of self as mathematics teachers. Often, they have had experiences that leave them feeling anxious about their capability to be effective mathematics teachers, which negatively impacts student outcomes. Math autobiographies offer teacher educators a window into the historical factors that influence preservice teachers’ math identity development and help them reflect on how these experiences have shaped them. Providing counterpoint experiences in mathematics pedagogical coursework can help preservice teachers overcome past influences and foster positive identities as future mathematics teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304826?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The myth(s) of a ‘balanced’ approach</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 14-19, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;How we should teach mathematics has long been debated by advocates of different instructional approaches. These debates can lead to tensions that are difficult to navigate for those who are new to (or even veterans of) the profession. Educators often propose a “balance” of different approaches as a solution. Charles Munter considers whether such a balance is actually possible — and also considers whether some other questions may be more urgent.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304825?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building thinking classrooms in mathematics: A conversation with Peter Liljedahl</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 32-35, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Peter Liljedahl, a professor of education at Simon Fraser University in British Columbia, studied math classrooms and students for 15 years. His book, Building Thinking Classrooms in Mathematics, Grades K-12: 14 Teaching Practices for Enhancing Learning, is the result of that research. He found that by disrupting the norms of the classroom – having students work in small, randomized groups at vertical whiteboards or other erasable surface – students are more engaged and more likely to think, not simply mimic back what the teacher is saying.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304828?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Everyone is a math person</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 26-30, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Early intervention and identity-building can promote the idea among students that everyone is a math person. Natalie Parker-Holliman and Tenisha Marcel-Herbert share practical tools and strategies that schools and teachers can use to build students’ confidence and strengthen their mathematical foundation. They highlight the significance of culture and diversity in mathematics education and the impact of affirming messages on students’ mathematical identity, ultimately fostering a culture of belonging and success in mathematics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304827?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Addressing student behavior to meet everyone’s needs</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 36-41, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Problem behavior disrupts classrooms across the United States, impacting student learning. Despite the adverse consequences, teachers often exclude disruptive students from school as a punitive and default response to problem behavior. Alternatives to exclusion are becoming increasingly popular in many school districts to improve behavior and keep students in the classroom. But these alternatives tend to group students without identifying and addressing their individualized needs. Nasaskyia R. Hicks reviews the existing literature on punitive school discipline, considers the benefits of alternative discipline, and strengthens the underexplored gaps in research by conceptualizing an approach teachers can use.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304829?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
