<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing student teachers’ critical awareness of information and communications technology in primary teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 08:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2407540?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Opening the Gateway to Oral Participation: Exploring Facilitative Contextual Factors in the Association Between Student Shyness and Hand Raising</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This field study examined factors that might influence hand raising in students with high levels of shyness. Data were assessed using student self-reports of shyness and social relatedness factors (student-teacher relationship and peer relationship), observations of instructional factors (wait time, warm calling, class size, and school subject), and behavioral measures of hand raising among 204 middle school students during a school week. Multilevel analyses show that student-teacher relationship and warm calling facilitate hand raising of highly shy students, but also that they less likely raise their hands the better their peer relationship. Thus, the results suggest that both social relatedness and instructional factors can promote hand raising in highly shy students, opening the gateway to their oral participation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241278585?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Online Education Working?</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examines the impact of instruction modality on student learning outcomes, with a focus on disparities observed pre- and post-pandemic. Using administrative data from a public university spanning seven pre-pandemic and five post-pandemic semesters, the analysis controls for endogenous sorting using fixed effects. The findings suggest that face-to-face (FtF) instruction results in better student performance, such as higher grades and a lower withdrawal rate. Additionally, students with greater exposure to FtF instruction are less likely to repeat courses, more likely to graduate on time, and achieve higher Grade Point Averages (GPA). The study also shows that the FtF advantage has been decreasing over time, and the differences are smaller post-pandemic. The results are consistent across student and instructor characteristics, except for Honors and graduate students, where the FtF advantage is either smaller or statistically insignificant.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 06:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241274802?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introduction to the JEBS Special Section on Artificial Intelligence in Educational Statistics</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/49/5&quot;&gt;Volume 49, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 691-693, October 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241276424?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Numerically Leveled Performance Assessment Framework (NLPAF): A Literature-Based Evaluation of Acceptability</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 01:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2405404?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Weaving together the threads of Indigenous knowledge and mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10272-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book review: Charting a career and its influence. Jinfa Cai, Gabriel J. Stylianides, and Patricia Ann Kenney (Eds.) (2023) Research studies on learning and teaching of mathematics: dedicated to Edward A. Silver</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10316-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reifying actions into artifacts: process–object duality from an embodied perspective on mathematics learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Grasping mathematical objects as related to processes is often considered critical for mathematics understanding. Yet, the ontology of mathematical objects remains under debate. In this paper, we theoretically oppose &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;internalist approaches&lt;/em&gt; that claim mental entities as the endpoints of process–object transitions and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;externalist approaches&lt;/em&gt; that stress mathematical artifacts—such as physical manipulatives and formulas—as constituting mathematical objects. We search for a view on process–object duality that overcomes the dualism of mind and body. One such approach is commognition that describes mathematical objects as discursive entities. This paper expands the nature of mathematical objects beyond discourse and highlights the role of learners’ interaction with the environment by adopting ecological onto-epistemology. We develop a functional dynamic systems perspective on process–object duality in mathematics learning emphasizing embodied actions and the re-invention of artifacts’ affordances. As a main result, we reconsider process﻿–object duality as a reification of repetitive actions into a cultural artifact that consists of two steps: (1) forming a new sensory-motor coordination that brings new perception to the fore and (2) crystallizing a new artifact in a mathematical environment that captures this new perception. An empirical example from research on embodied action-based design for trigonometry illustrates our theoretical ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus abstract-section outputmedium-online id-a-sec1&quot;&gt;
                      &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Graphical abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                      &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus figure id-figa float-no category-standard&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus media-object id-m-o1&quot;&gt;
                          &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;static-content.springer.com/image/MediaObjects/10649_2024_10310_Figa_HTML.jpg&quot; class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;/&gt;
                        &lt;/span&gt;
                      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/span&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10310-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching practices that support revising definition drafts to adhere to mathematical norms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Definitions play an integral role in mathematics and mathematics classes. Yet, expectations for definitions and how they are intended to operate, i.e., mathematical norms for definitions, can remain hidden from students and conflict with other discursive norms, explaining differences in mathematicians’ and students’ understandings of the nature of definitions. We examined how six inquiry-oriented Introduction to Proof instructors supported their students in revising their definition drafts to adhere to mathematical norms. We identified four procedures that effectively supported students’ drafts in adhering to various mathematical norms, particularly to those that worked to increase clarity. We discuss how the instructors’ teaching practices provided different opportunities for students to engage with mathematical norms for definitions, general mathematical norms, and mathematical content.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10331-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Development of high school students’ conceptions of sampling distribution in the context of learning significance tests with technology</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Sampling distributions are fundamental for statistical inference, yet their abstract nature poses challenges for students. This research investigates the development of high school students’ conceptions of sampling distribution through informal significance tests with the aid of digital technology. The study focuses on how technological tools contribute to forming these conceptions, guided by an emerging theory that describes this process. A workshop for high school students was organized, involving 36 participants working in pairs across four sessions, each with access to a computer. These sessions involved problem-solving activities, with the teacher introducing key concepts in the initial three sessions. The analysis, employing grounded theory, aimed to characterize the nature of students’ conceptions of sampling distribution as evident in their responses. The findings reveal a transition from empirical to informal conceptions of sampling distribution among students, facilitated by computational mediation. This transition is marked by an abstraction process that includes mathematization, processing, uncertainty/randomness, and conditional reasoning. The study underscores the role of digital simulations in teaching statistical concepts, facilitating students’ conceptual shift critical for grasping statistical inference.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10330-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The sensory politics of mathematics: aestheticizing multiplication</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research has highlighted the important role that the senses play in mathematics thinking and learning, particularly in the area of visualisation, but also in relation to physical movement. Recent scholarship suggests that sensory experiences are not limited to the five cardinal senses but involve a range of other specific senses as well as combinations of senses. The aim of this article is to explore how this expanded understanding of the senses matters to mathematics education research. We frame our argument in terms of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;aestheticizing mathematics&lt;/em&gt; education research, focusing not only on mathematics knowing, but also on implications for investigating the mathematical sensorium; for the latter, we propose the use of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;re-enactments&lt;/em&gt; as powerful research methods. To empirically elaborate on this argument, we illustrate the use of this method to investigate how senses matter in developing multiplicative thinking around/with multitouch technology.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10326-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Aligning school mathematics with a manufactured crisis: re-rendering neoliberal and neoconservative discourses as commonsensical in a rural place</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;School reform efforts are situated within social and political contexts and, as such, are susceptible to the commonsense discourses circulating through, and shaping, society. Two discourses prevalent in US education reform are those perpetuating the ideologies of neoliberalism and neoconservatism. These ideologies are inherently contradictory—with the former promoting a small state and the latter a strong state—but converge to promote their agendas, shaping school reform efforts. &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; this occurs is not always clear, especially in rural contexts, where there has been limited attention to ideological discourses’ relation to schooling. In this analysis, we describe how dominant, yet contradictory, discourses of neoliberalism and neoconservatism are resolved in a rural context. We find that the leaders of one rural, public school district identified fifth-grade number sense as a problem of practice needing improvement—framing the cause of their problem as misalignment and the solution as consistency within and across grade levels. In doing so, district leaders’ conversations were limited to those of standardization (e.g., state-mandated mathematics standards, approaches to timed-fact tests, and curriculum between grade levels). Alignment as a frame excluded conversations related to deeper considerations, such as students’ experiences in mathematics or issues of equity. We find that dominant discourses constrain the ways district leaders frame their mathematics-related problem and work through the frame (in this case, one of alignment) to resolve inherent contradictions and advance their agendas. We suggest that these discourses serve to distract from potentially more pressing issues in education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10340-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing the quality of conceptual knowledge through dynamic constructions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this contribution, we address the gap that has appeared in mathematics education research and practice with the emergence of dynamic geometry environments and build on the opportunities these environments offer to school geometry. In our qualitative empirical study, we investigate how to elaborate on the general model of conceptual knowledge to make it applicable to dynamic geometry tasks, specifically to tasks including dynamic geometric constructions. We present a design of dynamic constructions of quadrilaterals that comply with Euclidean constructions, derive an assessment instrument based on them, and study what information the instrument can provide about the quality of students’ conceptual knowledge. We present the results in the form of an assessment framework consisting of an example of the assessment instrument and an ordered system of qualitative categories serving as an assessment codebook for interpreting students’ responses in terms of the quality of conceptual knowledge. To clarify the relations between the assessment framework and the general model of conceptual knowledge, we establish a system of subdimensions of conceptual knowledge that indicates how conceptual knowledge can be understood in the context of dynamic geometric constructions and identifies the conceptual knowledge needed to achieve individual categories of the assessment framework.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10349-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I’ll just try to mimic that”: an exploration of students’ analogical structure creation in abstract algebra</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Despite the prominence of analogies in mathematics, little attention has been given to exploring students’ processes of analogical reasoning, and even less research exists on revealing how students might be empowered to independently and productively reason by analogy to establish new (to them) mathematics. I argue that the lack of a cohesive framework for interpreting students’ approaches to analogical reasoning in mathematics contributes to this issue. To address this, I introduce the Analogical Reasoning in Mathematics (ARM) framework. Constructed from an analysis of interviews with four abstract algebra students, ARM identifies several analogical activities that serve to analyze students’ analogical reasoning with a finer grain size than was previously possible with existing frameworks. Using this framework, I present an analysis of the students’ constructions of a ring-theoretic analogy to subgroup, thus revealing that even constructing simple analogies can elicit diverse pathways of analogical reasoning across students. Implications for further research related to analogies and analogical reasoning in mathematics education are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10345-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Eye movements in conceptual and non-conceptual thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;How to influence and assess whether students engage in conceptual thinking are longstanding methodological problems in mathematics education. Recently, eye-tracking technology has fueled a discussion on whether eye movement analysis can support valid inferences about mathematical thinking. This study investigates whether eye movement analysis can distinguish between conceptual and non-conceptual thinking in a geometric classification task where both modes of thinking lead to identical responses. Participants were asked to classify geometric shapes while we tracked their eye movements and to report their thinking verbally. Our findings indicate that self-reported conceptual thinking is characterised by fewer eye movements between task shapes and response shapes, and that self-reported non-conceptual thinking involves comparing the shapes’ similarity directly. A logistic regression model correctly classified the self-reported ways of thinking in 80.3% of the cases. We conclude that eye-tracking can contribute to making inferences about mathematical thought processes and facilitate research on how to engage students in conceptual thinking and development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10358-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Experienced teachers talking about their mathematics teaching with linguistically disadvantaged learners</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Learners of mathematics who are linguistically disadvantaged for a variety of reasons, including impoverished socioeconomic status, continue to be educationally disadvantaged and at considerable risk of school failure and early dropout. This is the case in many parts of the world. While much has been researched on linguistically disadvantaged learners in the fields of sociology and general pedagogy, little is known about the classroom teaching of mathematical content in language-responsive ways for all learners in school. Experienced mathematics teachers draw on a wealth of knowledge of content teaching in language-responsive ways developed through their practices working with linguistically disadvantaged learners in their classrooms. In this paper we report on interviews with some of these experienced mathematics teachers from seven educational contexts focusing on teaching probability in language-responsive ways. We focus on what we can learn from these teachers that could inform our practice as mathematics teacher educators and our research. We identify three challenges and three practices that add nuance and depth to theoretical research findings and recommendations on language in mathematics teaching, which can potentially develop these findings in more practical and accurate ways.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09628-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Centering on power relations in collaboration among mathematics teacher educator-researchers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics education research tends to center on what Mathematics Teacher Educators-Researchers (MTERs) work on or the people (teachers and students) they work with. Rarely, research in mathematics education focuses on MTERs working with one another. This article decenters from these traditional foci and instead examines a heterogeneous group of MTERs describing their research collaborations for professional development efforts on social justice issues in mathematics education. The MTERs’ paired conversations focused on their retrospective stories of their collaborations were analyzed using an Anzaldúan framework to name the different spaces of collaboration that MTERs identified. Results provide insight into how MTERs’ identified binarized spaces linked to their identities and compounded by issues of power. Nevertheless, MTERs also identified spaces where boundaries were blurred promoting a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;nos/otras&lt;/em&gt; space of collaboration. We discuss how collaboration reaches beyond doing the same research work and sharing talent but also understanding the work of one another.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09634-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing the role of being an advocate in mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics teacher education is often described in terms of the mathematical content and pedagogy that teachers need. However, recent calls for equity in mathematics education demand a broadening of this view. In this article, we articulate a theoretical description of what the role of being an advocate in language-diverse classrooms could involve and some of the practical challenges that mathematics teacher educators may have when introducing it, using empirical examples from our teacher education courses for teachers of Grades 1–7 in Norway. In the theoretical description of the role of being an advocate into mathematics teacher education, we distinguish between in-class advocacy and advocacy beyond the classroom and what these different kinds of advocacy might entail in language-diverse classrooms. The practical issues that we identified in raising different aspects of the role indicate the need for further research into how to raise preservice teachers’ awareness about the role of being an advocate, in and outside of the classroom, in different cultural settings and how this knowledge could be used in teacher education to challenge preservice teachers’ language ideologies and raise non-trivial issues.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09629-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Political Conocimiento in Teaching Mathematics: mathematics teacher candidates enacting their ethical identities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The sanctioned language around “mathematics teacher knowledge” in the US centers pedagogy, content (mathematical knowledge), and students. Yet, this teacher learning approach often promotes (explicitly or implicitly) teaching and learning of mathematics that operationalizes mathematics as rigid, as a gatekeeper, and only useful for global competition in STEM-related fields. These tacit capitalist goals result in teachers being expected to convey “clear and useful” mathematical information to students, not question why mathematics is being taught, who benefits, and/or how to intervene if the learning environment is harmful for students who are Black, Indigenous, students of Color, multilingual, dis/abled, queer, nonbinary, and/or of immigrant backgrounds. In this article, we build upon a form of relational knowing that intertwines mathematics, pedagogies, students, and politics called Political Conocimiento in Teaching Mathematics. Focusing on political knowledge brings the margins to the center by recognizing political issues cannot be separated from other dimensions or added on, as if politics are not already present in mathematics teaching and learning. As three women of Color, we present empirical results from three teacher education programs in the USA with teacher candidates (n = 55) who range in intersectional identities. Using scenario-based activities that support their development of political knowledge, we apply the lens of “The Mirror Test” to highlight how teacher candidates’ intersectional identities influenced the ethical identities they enacted. Some candidates focused more on “accountability” while others focused on “performativity.” We offer implications for future research on ethical identities in mathematics education with teachers and teacher candidates of various intersectional identities.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09627-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Political conocimiento in teaching mathematics: mathematics teacher candidates enacting their ethical identities</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09646-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Decentring research on mathematics teacher education: Why does it matter?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09655-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publishing mathematics education research in English: amplifying voices from the field</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper we investigate the issue of representation within the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Journal of Mathematics Teacher Education&lt;/em&gt; (JMTE) and the broader academic publishing landscape, particularly focusing on the underrepresentation of authors from various world regions. A questionnaire, distributed globally, aimed to amplify the voices of the underrepresented, exploring the constraints and affordances of publishing in English-medium mathematics education research journals. The question that guided our investigation was: What do voices from the mathematics education community raise in their responses to questions about publishing in English-medium research journals like JMTE? We used qualitative methods to review the responses and identify common themes. The findings revealed significant barriers and challenges related to language, research location, and institutional support, highlighting the complexities of navigating the global academic community and the academic publishing culture. We propose actionable suggestions to foster a more equitable, diverse, and inclusive publishing environment.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09659-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Tale of Two Exams</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics is a rich and beautiful playground of ideas, the apex of human creativity and ingenuity, applicable to all the world around us: humankind’s best effort at understanding and describing the universe. Mathematics examinations aren’t this. They’re uninspiring and trauma-inducing, with an emphasis on routine calculations and easy-to-grade problems. Why the disconnect? This article is an account of two instructors in dialogue, negotiating the tension between their implicit educational values and desired outcomes for their students, and the pragmatics of administering and grading a final examination. Both wish the best for their students, but are mindful of the many, many constraints imposed by institutionalized education. Unlike the questions on the exams they eventually offer, there is no correct answer to the question: what is an ideal examination in postsecondary mathematics?&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00333-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Enhancing Professionalism</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 117&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 10&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 694-700
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/117/10/article-p694.xml</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
