<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>World Bank Influence on Policy Formation in Education: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The World Bank has been called the most influential organization in education reform globally. Not only is it the single largest funder of education for international development, but it also produces knowledge, circulates discourse, and structures policymaking processes in ways that extend its influence far beyond its primary role as a bank. However, while much literature has been produced about the World Bank, the field of education lacks a systematic discussion of what has been reported about how the World Bank influences policy formation at the country level. Through the conduct of a theoretically informed systematic literature review of 70 publications, this article clarifies and provides examples for the numerous ways that the World Bank influences policy formation. In all, the article documents 11 pathways through which the World Bank influences policymaking. The article concludes by suggesting areas where research on the World Bank can be improved, namely, through more explicit attention to the theoretical and methodological approaches employed. The goal of this review is to encourage scholars to be more specific in their conceptualizations and discussions of World Bank influence, to go beyond general claims of policy imposition or agenda shaping.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-16-2023 06:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231194725?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interpolation and extrapolation in Year 5 STEM activities: exploring data about viscosity without advanced statistics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Incorporating an evidence-based approach in STEM education using data collection and analysis strategies when learning about science concepts enhances primary students’ discipline knowledge and cognitive development. This paper reports on learning activities that use the nature of viscosity and the power of informal statistical inference to build students’ conceptual understanding of interpolation and extrapolation without imposing on them the demands of understanding the nonlinear mathematics used to explore the concepts at the tertiary level. An exploratory research strategy was adopted to investigate the way in which Year 5 students created and analysed graphical representations from data collected when performing viscosity experiments. The data representations produced by the students and their subsequent predictions were analysed using the Structure of Observed Learning Outcomes (SOLO) model as adapted specifically for graphical representations. The results illustrate that when provided with appropriate technological tools to scaffold student learning, in this case &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;TinkerPlots&lt;/em&gt;™, development of students’ appreciation of interpolation and extrapolation within meaningful data contexts across the STEM curriculum does not have to wait until the tertiary level.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-16-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00473-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructor perspectives on quantitative reasoning for critical citizenship</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;A tertiary course in Quantitative Reasoning (QR) has the potential to develop key practical and intellectual skills for citizenship, such as critical thinking, problem solving, quantitative literacy, and oral and written communication. In this article, we present research conducted on four instructors of such a QR course for students enrolled in a wide variety of nonscience degree programs at a university in the United States. The course used a student-inquiry approach to proportional reasoning, probability, statistical reasoning, and mathematical modeling. The findings are framed by a 5 C model of QR, which entails &lt;strong class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ritical thinking to link real-world &lt;strong class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ontexts to mathematical &lt;strong class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;oncepts supported by student &lt;strong class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ollaboration and QR &lt;strong class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ompetencies. The research addressed the questions of how university instructors support student development of the skills needed for critical citizenship and how this support relates to the 5 C model. We found that three of the four instructors viewed critical thinking as a central goal of the QR course and as supporting citizenship education. All four engaged students in tasks designed to develop a combination of skills associated citizenship, including critical thinking, self-questioning, collaboration, and communication. The discussion addresses such issues as the course’s merits and challenges, student engagement, the relative importance of the five Cs, the importance of instructional autonomy, and recommendations for related professional development and future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-15-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01520-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rest in Peace, Journal of the Saskatchewan Mathematics Teachers’ Society</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Armed with half a decade of experience as editor of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;vinculum&lt;/em&gt;, 4 years of writing the regular column “Math Ed Matters by MatthewMaddux” for &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The Variable&lt;/em&gt;, and as lead editor of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Selected Writings from the Journal of the Saskatchewan Mathematics Teachers’ Society&lt;/em&gt;, I can safely say that the reports of the death of the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Journal of the Saskatchewan Mathematics Teachers’ Society&lt;/em&gt; (SMTS) have been greatly exaggerated — until now. I mean, sure, with all due respect, and as a member of the executive of the SMTS myself, the journal kind of carries on as &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;the subscript&lt;/em&gt;, which is a series of links compiled by the SMTS executive. Looked at from an old-man-yells-at-cloud perspective, emailing a few links out is a far cry from the mountain of material found printed in the many, many pages of the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Journal of the SMTS&lt;/em&gt;, differently named as &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The Mathematics Newsletter&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The SMTS Newsletter&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;SMTS Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Journal of the SMTS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;vinculum&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The Variable&lt;/em&gt; over the past 60 years. I should know, after all, I led an extensive excavation of math teacher journal materials here in Western Canada. This article, then, is a quasi-autopsy of the journal. Rest in Peace, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Journal of the SMTS&lt;/em&gt;. You deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-15-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00286-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mapping the Indigenous Postcolonial Possibilities of Teacher Preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, a team of teacher educators collectively think through the many possibilities of how concepts such as decolonization, abolition, and fugitivity intersect with and are taken up by teacher education programs. To do so, we undertook a critical interpretive synthesis of scholarly literature spanning 2000 to 2020 to locate, examine, and organize existing examples of teacher education programs that work to transgress hegemonic colonial models of education. We revisit de Oliveira Andreotti et al.’s social cartography as a framework for comparing the theoretical foundations and social implications of each teacher education program.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2023 07:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231199361?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Research on gender and mathematics: exploring new and future directions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This narrative review of current research on gender and mathematics covers the years 2020 to 2022. The number of exemplary publications within these 3 years and the diversity of topics, theoretical frameworks, subjects, and authors are indications of gender and mathematics remaining a robust and evolving area of study. Of particular interest are studies of lived experiences of students in secondary school and university programs, many of which featured continuing and troubling discriminatory incidents. In addition, the focus in several studies on the intersectionality of gender with race and other identity features is a commendable trend that should be continued. Similar to the transition from sex differences to gender differences that emerged in the 1990s and 2000s, in the papers examined, some authors have reconceptualized gender as a fluid, non-binary construct, although most gender data are reported in binary ways. Gender remains a focus of research in mathematics education because of persistent inequities in achievement, attitudes, representation, and lived experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01510-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Weaving together the threads of Indigenous knowledge and mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As in many countries, for decades in Aotearoa (New Zealand), we have heard the story of the Pacific and Māori achievement gap in mathematics. This has become a widely accepted part of beliefs constructed across multiple communities about students and schools and who can do and learn mathematics successfully. A common response by policy makers and educators alike is to fix the problem of those deemed academically bleak by putting in place a range of interventions. In this article, we challenge the positioning of Pacific students as a problem to be fixed and instead focus on how we can address the practices inherent in historical forms of institutionalised racism related to colonisation. We use an Indigenous research model—Tivaevae—to develop an exemplary case study of the teachers and students from one low socio-economic urban school as they were involved in conscientisation and the reconstitution of educational practices to privilege indigenous knowledge systems. The findings highlight one model of how teachers and students can change institutionalised Western world practices in the mathematics classroom. We argue that the shift to honouring indigenous knowledge systems and a strength-based approach provided opportunities for Pacific students to learn mathematics in ways that supported them to build strong mathematical dispositions, and rather than being assimilated, retain their cultural identity.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10256-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“But once I did it, it was incredible”: practitioner action researchers’ experiences of transcription and using transcripts</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2023 12:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2257233?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using a contemplative practice intervention in teacher education courses to neutralize implicit racial bias: a feasibility study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2023 11:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2252353?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Competency Based Education Pilot in Illinois: Preliminary Findings</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this study we employed regression analysis and between-group matched pair design to analyze whether participation in a competency-based education pilot was associated with improved high school completion and postsecondary entry. Data were obtained for high schools participating in a CBE pilot program in Illinois. Results of the matched pair design showed that CBE participation was significantly associated with higher rates of high school graduation for seniors across all groups with differences significant overall (97.2% for CBE vs. 93.1% for non-CBE), for White students (97.2% vs. 92.7%), and for students eligible for Free and Reduced Lunch (96.3% vs. 90.3%). Graduation rate for seniors was also higher for African American students and for Hispanic-Latinx students, but the differences were not statistically significant. In the matched pair design, CBE participation was not significantly associated with entry into college within 12 months of high school.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2023 06:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231198819?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptualizing State Re-Engagement With Public Higher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Three trends have characterized state policymaking for higher education in the 21st century: divestment, accountability, and race neutrality. These policy agendas are often justified as an attempt to optimize system efficiency and performance by making institutional actors (agents) responsive to the demands of state officials (principals). In this manuscript, we present quantitative evidence that these three policy initiatives have not achieved their stated purpose. We use contemporary social theory to explain why this is the case. Finally, we call for deeper re-engagement of states and their higher education systems in place of transactional and technocratic models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2023 06:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231198815?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Stubborn Unresponsiveness of Youth Voter Turnout to Civic Education: Quasi-Experimental Evidence From State-Mandated Civics Tests</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Youth voter turnout remains stubbornly low and unresponsive to civic education. Rigorous evaluations of the effects of adopting civics tests for high school graduation by some states on youth voter turnout remain limited. We estimate the impact of a recent, state-mandated civics test policy—the Civics Education Initiative (CEI)—on youth voter turnout by exploiting spatial and temporal variation in the adoption of CEI across states. Using nationally representative data from the 1996 to 2020 Current Population Survey and a difference-in-differences analysis, we find that CEI does not significantly affect youth voter turnout. Our null results, largely insensitive to a variety of alternative specifications and robustness checks, provide evidence regarding the lack of efficacy of civics test policies when it comes to youth voter participation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2023 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231195887?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How do school-related mathematical problems become relevant for prospective teachers in mathematics courses at university? A qualitative interview study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2023 08:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2243261?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“When We Come to Your Class … We Feel Not Like We&#39;re in Prison”: Resisting Prison-School’s Dehumanizing and (De)Socializing Mechanisms Through Abolitionist Praxis</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Education research increasingly conceptualizes how social interactions and contexts of public schools replicate practices found in prisons. Yet prison-schooling is often left out of education research. Concurrently, prison-schooling is where we educate a disproportionate amount of multiply marginalized youth, specifically disabled Girls of Color. The lack of attention to prison-schools has limited how teaching in youth carceral facilities can be examined for its challenges and supports of disabled Girls of Color. Centering the girls’ words from class observations, field notes, and interviews, this study describes and intervenes in dehumanizing and (de)socializing mechanisms in prison-school education. We explore attempts and impacts of countering prison-school education through a sociocritical literacy course infused with an abolitionist praxis. We end with discussion on the limits of countering prison-school through courses alone, suggesting abolition across multiple scales instead.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2023 07:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231198236?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Does ESL Mean to Her? An Analysis of Women of Color Recounting Their Attempts to Exit EL Instructional Services</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;A portion of EL-identified youth want to exit the EL instructional services to which they are legally entitled. Moreover, institutionalized adultism within EL policy does not provide youths a role in decision-making about these services. As a result, little is known about how individuals who attempt unsanctioned exits conceptualize EL instructional services. This study uses an intersectional anti-adultism conceptual lens to analyze the retrospective interviews of 35 women of color who attempted to exit EL instructional services during their K–12 schooling. The findings highlight three dominant themes in participants’ conceptualizations of EL instructional services: they were academically limiting, socially isolating, and that placement in these services was a product of racism. Moreover, this detailed analysis evidenced how schooling transitions impacted participants’ conceptualization of EL instructional services. These findings have implications for how research, policy, and practice can center EL-identified youths’ decision-making and disrupt their experiences of marginalization.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2023 06:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231195878?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>16th Annual AERA Brown Lecture in Education Research “A Shade Less Offensive”: School Integration as Radical Inclusion in the Pursuit of Educational Equity</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The historical record reveals that in the final opinion of the landmark school segregation case Cooper v. Aaron, the U.S. Supreme Court justices intentionally used the term “desegregation” rather than “integration” to soften the ire of those opposed to the Brown v. Board of Education decision. The justices believed that Southern resisters to integrations would find the former term “a shade less offensive” than the latter. In this lecture, education scholar and sociologist Prudence Carter reverses that logic and discusses why educational practices of “radical inclusion” are “a shade less offensive” today than mere desegregation in light of persistent educational disparities by race, ethnicity, and class. Carter draws on her original research and other social science evidence to show why societies marred by social and economic divides continue to struggle with the realization of integration in schools and communities. In her commentary on multiple dimensions of educational inequality, she highlights policies and evidence-based practices that have the potential to bring us closer to equity in schools and society.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-11-2023 07:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231187319?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Parents don’t know they have the option to say no”: the experiences of Caribbean and Latin American parents navigating special education in Ontario</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-11-2023 02:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2255837?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Types of mathematical tasks in lower secondary classrooms in Germany</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Tasks play an important role in mathematics education, as they provide opportunities for students to develop their competencies and to cognitively engage with the mathematical content. The potential for cognitive activation as a central feature of a mathematical task has been considered in numerous studies, mostly as a didactical analysis by means of existing classification systems. In this study, which has been carried out in the frame of the TEDS research program, a different approach is taken by which we aim to identify the cognitive demand level of tasks used in ordinary mathematics lessons. Thus, the correlation between general mathematical competencies and the cognitive mathematical activities required to solve the task was analyzed and common properties of groupings of tasks were empirically extracted. In detail, 2490 tasks from mathematics lessons in Germany were analyzed by means of a rational task analysis with regard to their potential for fostering general mathematical competencies, namely modelling, problem solving, reasoning and argumentation, use of representations, use of symbols and operations, and communication. Latent class analysis revealed six classes of mathematical tasks with varying potential for the different competencies. In accordance with previous studies on mathematical tasks in Germany, the biggest class focused solely on the use of symbols and operations, while other classes showed different foci. Post hoc analyses revealed that the classes of tasks differ with regard to the level of cognitive activity they require. The results of the study highlight that the potential for cognitive activation of the tasks used in the classrooms of this more recent study has not improved in the last decades, despite many reform activities in German mathematics education, and that many mathematical tasks used are still more or less calculation oriented.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-11-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10254-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building a Logic Model to Foster Engagement and Learning Using the Case of a Province-Wide Multispecies Antimicrobial Use Monitoring System</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Successfully designing and implementing a program is complex; it requires a reflexive balance between the available resources and the priorities of various stakeholders, both of which change over time. Logic models are theory-based evaluation approaches used to identify and address key challenges of a program. This article describes the process of building a logic model on advanced theories in complexity studies. The models aim to support a province-wide multispecies monitoring system of antimicrobial use (AMU), designed in collaboration with the animal health sector in Quebec (Canada). Based on a rigorous theoretical foundation, the logic model is built in three steps: (1) mapping, a narrative review of literature on similar programs in other jurisdictions; (2) framing, iterative consultations with project members to elaborate the logic model; (3) shaping, hypotheses based on the logic model. The model emerges from the reflexive balancing of current scientific knowledge and empirical insights to gather relevant information about stakeholders from interdisciplinary experts that led a 3-year consensus-building process within the community. Recognizing the challenge of unpacking theories for practical use, we illustrate how the process of an “open” logic model building could enable governance coordination in complex processes. Logic models are useful for evaluating public, private, and academic partnerships in One Health programs that characterize an adaptive governance process.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-09-2023 10:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231198706?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stories of devoted university students: the mathematical experience as a form of ascesis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Drawing on autobiographical essays written by master’s students in mathematics preparing to become teachers, we investigate what mathematical identity these students articulate and how. By means of a discursive thematic analysis centered on the notion of ascesis, we show that the participants’ identity revolves around a characterization of mathematics as a challenging, useful, and comforting activity or knowledge, which is however regarded negatively by others. Indeed, mathematics is described as a uniquely challenging activity which requires an increasingly demanding self-discipline. Moreover, mathematics is depicted as a variously useful form of knowledge which is additionally capable to offer comfort to those who engage with it. However, the participants often remark that other people regard mathematics negatively, a fact explained by stressing others’ inability or unwillingness to understand or appreciate mathematics’ inherent positive features. This sets the boundary of an ideal club of math enthusiasts whose elitist membership is regulated in terms of acceptance or refusal of its constitutive values. Belonging to the club as well as proselytizing in order to recruit new members appears to be central to the participants’ mathematical identity.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-09-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10259-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacherly response-ability: ethical relationality as protest against mathematical violence</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;What do ethical relations look like in the context of the many injustices that pervade mathematics education? In this paper, I argue, first, that violence is the relation that characterizes much of contemporary mathematics education and, second, that understanding ethical relations requires considering mathematics as an equal actor in creating possible relations rather than simply treating it as a context for human relations. I examine how literature in care theory, emancipatory pedagogies, and mathematics education have framed ethical relationality and suggest that the feminist new materialist conceptualization of response-ability offers several contributions for rethinking agency, justice, and praxis for mathematics teachers concerned with addressing mathematical violence.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-08-2023 22:10</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10230-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preschool children’s conceptions of the meanings and use of written numerals in everyday life: a phenomenographic study of the nature and structure of qualitative variation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Supporting children’s understanding of the everyday, cultural use of written numerals is highly significant, as it is this understanding that gives meaning to classroom conversations on the purposes of written numbers. This paper presents findings from a phenomenographic study of the qualitatively different ways in which 3–5-year-old children interpret the meanings and use of numerals in everyday contexts. The study involved a volunteer sample of 37 preschool children. With their family’s support, children played a Number Spotting game, taking photographs of numerals in their environments. These photographs were supplemented with other photographs selected by the researchers and used in individual photo-elicitation interviews with children. We collected data on children’s interpretations of a range of examples of numerals used to denote quantity, order and measurement, and numerals used as labels/identifiers. The findings document qualitatively different categories that capture the range of children’s expressed conceptions as well as the critical aspects of variation that underpin &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; qualitatively different categories of conceptions differ or relate to each other. The study provides original insights into the nature and structure of children’s awareness of the cultural uses of written numerals. The findings can support early mathematics teaching to make meaningful connections between the knowledge that children develop outside of school and the new knowledge about written numbers that they develop in formal education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-08-2023 22:10</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10232-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understandings of race and racism in globalizing higher education: when east Asian international student perspectives resonate with color-blindness</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-08-2023 03:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2257138?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Your title is no exception: the racial constraints of African-American Chief Diversity Officers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-08-2023 03:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2255828?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
