<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating the impact of racial microaggressions on Black, racialized, and Indigenous students: a narrative synthesis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-25-2024 12:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2447118?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From teacher surplus to teacher shortage and its effects on teacher education: the Portuguese case</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-25-2024 06:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2443668?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Validating Classrooms: Teaching Strategies to Advance Equity in Developmental Education</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research on developmental education reform has given surprisingly limited attention to what happens inside the classroom between faculty and students. Our qualitative study used interview data from 20 faculty and 20 students in corequisite math and English courses at one of the nation’s largest and most racially diverse community college systems. Specifically, we used validation theory to examine faculty teaching strategies and support structures that may increase academic success among corequisite students. Our findings demonstrate that the most effective faculty, who often had course pass rates 20% above the institutional average, created validating learning environments that addressed students’ academic and interpersonal needs. We provide recommendations for expanding the use of validating teaching and learning practices in corequisite-developmental education courses to ensure more equitable student outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 12:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241309575?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Finessing the system: navigating and negotiating the model minority identity as South Asian American youth</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 10:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2446210?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Updates</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 788-789, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297954?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcements</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 788-789, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297955?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On synthetic difference-in-differences and related estimation methods in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 557-598, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we describe a computational implementation of the synthetic difference-in-differences (SDID) estimator of Arkhangelsky et al. (2021, American Economic Review 111: 4088-4118) for Stata. SDID can be used in many circumstances where treatment effects on some particular policy or event are desired and repeated observations on treated and untreated units are available over time. We lay out the theory underlying SDID both when there is a single treatment adoption date and when adoption is staggered over time, and we discuss estimation and inference in each of these cases. We introduce the sdid command, which implements these methods in Stata, and provide several examples of use, discussing estimation, inference, and visualization of results. Along with SDID, the sdid command allows for the implementation of standard synthetic control and difference-in-differences methods in an identical framework, permitting estimation, inference, and the generation of graphical output in a computationally efficient way.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297914?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>require: Package dependencies for reproducible research</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 599-613, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The ability to conduct reproducible research in Stata is often limited by the lack of version control for community-contributed packages. In this article, we introduce the require command, a tool designed to ensure package dependencies are compatible across users and computer systems. Given a list of packages, require verifies that each package is installed, checks for a minimum or exact version or package release date, and optionally installs the package if prompted by the researcher.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297915?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estimating treatment effects when program participation is misreported</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 614-629, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Instrumental variables are commonly used to estimate treatment effects in cases of imperfect compliance. However, if participation in the program is misreported, standard techniques can yield severely biased results. We present a new command, ivreg2m, that implements the mismeasured robust local average treatment-effect estimator developed by Calvi, Lewbel, and Tommasi (2022, Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 40: 1701–1717) and Tommasi and Zhang (2024b, Journal of Applied Econometrics, doi.org/10.1002/jae.3079), to estimate the heterogeneous treatment effect of a program in the presence of treatment noncompliance and misreporting. The ivreg2m command can be used as the preferred strategy in cases of exogenous (nondifferential) misclassification.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297916?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Outlier detection for inequality and poverty analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 630-665, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Extreme values are common in survey data and represent a recurring threat to the reliability of both poverty and inequality estimates. The adoption of a consistent criterion for outlier detection is useful in many practical applications, particularly when international and intertemporal comparisons are involved. In this article, we discuss a simple univariate detection procedure to flag outliers. We present outdetect, a command that implements the procedure and provides useful diagnostic tools. The output of outdetect compares statistics obtained before and after the exclusion of outliers, with a focus on inequality and poverty measures. Finally, we carry out an extensive sensitivity exercise where the same outlier detection method is applied consistently to per capita expenditure across more than 30 household budget surveys. The results are clear and provide a sense of the influence of extreme values on poverty and inequality estimates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297918?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 158: The devil is in the delta</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 777-783, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297950?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Erratum: Power and sample-size calculations for trials that compare slopes over time: Introducing the slopepower command</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 784-787, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297951?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Distinguishing differences in construct from differences in response style: gsem for item response theory models with anchoring vignettes</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 666-686, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Item response theory models allow estimation of participant and group-mean trait scores from responses to a set of items, but estimates can be biased when participants vary in their response style. We illustrate models fit in gsem that can account for such response style differences by comparing self-report with their ratings of anchoring vignettes—descriptions of other individuals displaying different levels of the trait. Simulation results from standard item response theory, mean bias, random bias, and free-threshold models are illustrated. We show that unbiased estimates can be recovered when the vignettes rated depend on the participants’ own self-rating or are even rated by a different sample, substantially broadening their scope of application.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297920?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>gtsheckman: Generalized two-step Heckman estimator</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 687-710, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I introduce the gtsheckman command, which estimates a generalized two-step Heckman sample-selection estimator adjusted for heteroskedasticity. This estimator has been previously proposed in Carlson and Joshi (2024, Journal of Applied Econometrics 39: 237-255), where the presence of heteroskedasticity was motivated by a panel-data setting with random coefficients. The gtsheckman command offers several advantages over the heckman, twostep command, including robust inference, a more general control function specification, and the incorporation of heteroskedasticity. I discuss syntax and the underlying methodology and provide examples showing how the gtsheckman command can be used in a variety of settings
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297921?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cluster-weighted models using Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 711-745, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The cluster-weighted model (CWM) is a member of the family of mixtures of regression models and is also known as a mixture of regressions with random covariates. CWMs refer to the framework of model-based clustering and naturally apply when the research interest requires modeling the relationship between a response variable and a set of covariates using a regression-based approach such as a generalized linear model with the sample being suspected of comprising heterogeneous latent classes. A command for fitting these models is not yet available in Stata, so the aim of this article is to introduce the package cwmglm, which fits CWMs based on the most common generalized linear models with random covariates. Moreover, cwmglm allows the estimation of parsimonious models of Gaussian distributions, with the parameterization of the variance–covariance matrix based on the eigenvalue decomposition. These features are completely new for Stata users. The cwmglm package features goodness-of-fit, bootstrapping, and model-selection tools. We illustrate the use of cwmglm with real and simulated datasets.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297922?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Calculating the Women’s Empowerment in Agriculture Index (WEAI) using Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 746-765, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The Women’s Empowerment in Agriculture Index (WEAI) is a standardized, survey-based tool that has been widely used to track gender equality and measure empowerment, agency, and women’s inclusion in the agricultural sector (Alkire et al., 2013, World Development 52: 71–91). Since the WEAI’s release in 2012, an abbreviated version of the WEAI (A-WEAI) and a project-level version of the WEAI (pro-WEAI) have been developed (Malapit et al., 2017, The abbreviated Women’s Empowerment in Agriculture Index [A-WEAI]; Malapit et al., 2019, Development of the project-level Women’s Empowerment in Agriculture Index [pro-WEAI]). In this article, we review the shared methodology that underlies all members of the WEAI family of indices and introduce a command, weai, that can be used for index calculation. We describe the command and its options and provide empirical examples using publicly available data from the Gender, Agriculture, and Assets Project, Phase 2.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297923?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Speaking Stata: Getting by without the by() option: Some graphics for unequal groups</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 766-776, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The by() option of the graph command is often used to show groups or subsets of some data in separate panels or facets of a graphical display. If groups are unequal in size, the result may seem awkward or inefficient in use of space. Devices to allow such groups to be shown directly without using a by() option are explained and exemplified for graph dot and its siblings and for graph twoway.New variables to show rank within groups and (if needed) separation of groups are easily constructed. Group summaries such as medians may easily be added. Graph types shown are dot charts, quantile plots, and displays using spikes to show differences between variables. Data examples are for ocean salinity and changes in weight of anorexic girls.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297949?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Stata Journal Editors’ Prize 2024: Ian R. White</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/24/4&quot;&gt;Volume 24, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 553-556, December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X241297909?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Self-Efficacy, Instructional Practice, and Student Outcomes: Evidence from the TALIS Video Study</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this paper we use novel data to test the direct and indirect paths between teacher self-efficacy and student outcomes. This includes how teacher self-efficacy is linked to student, teacher, and expert rater views of lesson quality. Our results illustrate how the link between teacher self-efficacy and instructional quality is sensitive to how lesson quality is measured, with large effects when based on teacher reported outcomes but no association when based on the ratings of expert observers. Virtually no relationship is found between teacher self-efficacy and student outcomes. We thus conclude that while there is probably some positive association between teacher self-efficacy and the quality of their instruction, the strength of this relationship is relatively weak.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 06:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241300265?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Political dismissal vs. political alignment: fostering supportive school environments for Black teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 01:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2446208?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effect of Concrete and Virtual Manipulative Blended Instruction on Mathematical Achievement for Elementary School Students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics has been crucial to learning and extending the frontiers of knowledge in all academic areas. At the elementary level, several teaching approaches have been implemented to improve students’ mathematical achievement. However, compared to traditional teaching exposition techniques, the teaching with the use of math manipulatives has been found useful to enhance mathematical achievement. The current quasi-experimental study was carried out with Pakistani students, and aimed to explore the blended effect of concrete and virtual manipulatives on fifth-graders’ mathematical achievement. Different mathematical concepts such as whole number, decimals and percentages, fraction, unitary method, perimeter, area, and geometry from a grade 5 textbook were targeted for the intervention period. Following randomization, one section from a public school was chosen as a control group and the other section classified as an experimental group. The mathematical achievement of fifth graders was measured through mathematics achievement test (MAT), developed, and piloted for this particular study, in a pre–posttest design. The data were analysed using one-way ANCOVA and mixed between-within ANOVA test to examine the significant differences, if any exist, in pretest/posttest scores between and within the groups over the period of intervention. The results revealed blended use of concrete and virtual manipulatives significantly enhances students’ mathematical achievement as compared to the results achieved from traditional instruction. This study offers information for teachers and students to incorporate concrete and virtual manipulatives simultaneously in mathematics lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00336-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A personal reflection on the importance of participatory action research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-23-2024 06:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2444098?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Time to Take a Chance: The Promise of Royston-Parmar Proportional Hazard Models for Understanding Caseload Transitions</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this letter to the editor, we compare six different event history models to estimate which eligible families participated in a subsidized rental housing program and when. Answering these questions can inform efforts to improve program marketing and outreach, staffing and budgeting, triage, bias identification, as well as benchmarking and evaluation. One of six specifications clearly outperforms the others and understanding how will inform similar research pursuits. Although decision-relevant participation patterns are available in state administrative records, deciphering them is difficult for several well-known reasons. Participants enter and exit the eligible risk pool at different times, for different reasons, and at different rates. To answer our questions of when and whom, we restructure the data from calendar to relative months and then employ event history models designed to accurately estimate a complete hypothetical risk trajectory from observed spells of varying lengths, many of which ended before families took up the rental subsidy, (i.e., censored observation spells). We find that eligible parents most likely to take up the subsidy live in high-rent counties, have relatively strong recent work history, short prior adult lifetime TANF receipt, and medium-size families. Program take-up fell substantially during the COVID-19 pandemic. Contrasting the application of six parallel specifications, we find that a Royston-Parmar proportional hazard model achieves an exceptional balance between the descriptive accuracy of discrete time approaches and the elegance of Cox regression.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-23-2024 02:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241305869?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Opportunity to learn flexible and adaptive strategy use in current and past Dutch mathematics textbooks</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-23-2024 01:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2435827?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
