<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promises and Limitations in District Digital Capacity for Education During COVID-19</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The roles of technology and education were at the forefront throughout the COVID-19 pandemic. This mixed-methods study examines the role of the three levels of the digital divide (i.e., access, capability, and outcomes) during the COVID-19 pandemic in Kentucky. We create and analyze a new multifaceted measure of district-level digital capacity to examine the role of prior investments in technological infrastructure and the relationship with student scores in reading, math, and the ACT exam. Increased investment in digital preparedness leading up to the pandemic was protective against decreases in test scores. However, nonmetropolitan and Appalachian areas did not experience the same benefits from their digital capacity investments compared with their metropolitan counterparts. Using interview data from the summer of 2021 with 16 educators predominantly from Appalachian school districts, we discuss why these efforts to bridge the digital divide were hindered by larger, systematic challenges faced by their students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2024 10:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241303875?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Let’s CHAT About Artificial Intelligence for Students With Disabilities: A Systematic Literature Review and Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Researchers have explored artificial intelligence (AI) applications across educational contexts; however, there is a lack of meta-analysis focused on students with disabilities (SWDs). This study examined the overall effect of AI-based interventions on SWDs’ learning outcomes in 29 (quasi-)experimental studies conducted globally. We used cultural historical activity theory (CHAT) to explore how the effect was moderated by factors, including participant-, AI-, AI-SWD interaction-, intervention-, and methodology-related characteristics. Results indicated a medium effect (Hedge’s g = 0.588) of interventions operating through robots, computer software, and intelligent VR systems. There were no statistically significant moderators. Regardless, this study contributes to a holistic understanding of historical dimensions of AI applications for SWDs and offers critical theoretical implications for future investigations. We call for more rigorous research to explore AI that not only ensures accessibility but also promotes opportunities for SWDs to take an agentic role in participating in and contributing to AI-mediated learning activities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2024 11:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241293424?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making the Data Visible: A Systematic Review of Systems-Level Data Dashboards for Leadership and Policy in Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Systems-level data dashboards, those that provide education data aggregated to or used by leaders from school to state to federal levels, have become increasingly prevalent in the field of education both in the United States and in many education systems worldwide. This study provides a systematic review of the literature on systems-level data dashboards in K–12 schooling. The review demonstrates that research on systems-level dashboards lags that of student and teacher-focused learning analytics dashboards; that academic achievement remains the primary focus of dashboards, but contextual and non-test-score outcomes are now included in many dashboards and that use of dashboards by educators and the public is lower than desired but may be improved through alternative dissemination methods. It also demonstrates that research on the impacts of dashboards is particularly limited, a concern given the potential for unintended negative consequences. The article discusses the need to further incorporate systems-level dashboards into the organizational structures of education systems in order to enhance their utility for improving outcomes. The findings provide insights for stakeholders designing and using dashboards and hold the potential to improve dashboard use and student outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2024 11:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241288249?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Co-creating with teachers during participatory action research: Teachers’ perceptions, researchers’ dilemmas, and some possible strategies to enhance communication in the field</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The study explores teachers’ perception of the level of involvement of academic researchers in participatory action research and outlines some possible strategies to enhance communication during the process of co-creation. Data were collected within a pilot action that involved 159 pupils and 16 teachers in a preschool and a primary school in Italy. Throughout the research process, researchers tended to limit their direct interventions in the planning and implementation of the activities in order to avoid surreptitiously shaping the activities from their epistemically authoritative position. This choice was effective in promoting teachers’ and children’s ideas and resulted in a set of activities that positively impacted everyday school life. However, the analysis of the post-hoc interviews illustrates that several teachers evaluated this posture negatively. It is argued that these negative evaluations point to a dilemma that researchers inevitably face when adopting a methodological framework based on co-creation. On the basis of this critical appraisal of teachers’ perceptions, the article outlines some implications for researchers’ professional practice and some possible strategies to improve communication in the field.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2024 09:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241306023?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>In-service teachers’ developing conceptualisations of inquiry in mathematics during a professional development course</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2024 08:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2430256?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Homework completion and academic achievement: A multilevel study in high school settings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2024 06:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2431680?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Best-Evidence Synthesis and Meta-analysis on Effective Reading Programs in Spanish</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This systematic review and meta-analysis examined the effectiveness of Spanish reading programs in grades K–6. The research designs included were experimental and quasi-experimental. Effect sizes were analyzed using a multivariate meta-regression model with robust variance estimation. To assess the degree of heterogeneity in the effect sizes, a 95% prediction interval was calculated. A total of 11 studies and 51 effect sizes met the inclusion criteria. The full meta-regression model controlling for grade level and outcome type showed a large positive effect across all studies (effect size = 0.49, p &amp;lt; 0.05), with a large, positive effect on reading outcomes, and significant impacts on phonological awareness, phonics, fluency, and reading comprehension in K–2. Results suggest that effective instructional programs for K–6 Spanish reading exist. However, there is a need for more rigorous research on reading instructional programs for Spanish-speaking children.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2024 11:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241297668?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The mathematical neighborhoods of school mathematics and teachers’ horizon knowledge</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2024 05:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2434986?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What does it mean to be(come) a professional bilingual education teacher?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2024 01:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2436430?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ and kindergartners’ perceptions of children’s participation in interactive book reading</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2024 10:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2436879?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Liberatory Race-Conscious Mentorship Practices: Collaborating for Change</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2024 08:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2430767?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Difficult Topics Bubble Up: How K-12 Teachers Understand Unplanned Difficult-Topics Moments</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2024 08:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2430771?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educator Experiences During a Collaborative STEAM Program</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2024 08:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2430768?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teacher educators’ discussion practice</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Descriptions of expertise have focused on knowledge and characteristics of mathematics teacher educator (MTE) practice. To contribute to discussion of MTE expertise we share findings from a study of MTE discussion practice with prospective teachers (PTs) concerning pedagogy of teaching mathematics. Research on MTE discussion practices have shown there are key differences between discussions of mathematics and mathematics teaching in professional development, making clear MTEs’ discussion practices in mathematics methods courses focused on mathematics and mathematics teaching must differ. In this paper we focus on MTEs&#39; discussion practice in initial teacher education settings, building from empirical findings that include descriptions of MTEs&#39; discussion practice focused on mathematics teaching. Specifically, we address the question: What is our mathematics teacher educators’ pedagogy of discussion practice? Using self-study methodology and data from two primary sources: (1) transcripts of 8 critical friend conversations, and (2) evidentiary maps created using course artifacts, we use vignettes to describe three characteristics: anticipating preservice teachers’ thinking, layering instructional activities, and preservice teachers’ move toward independence in teaching practice. Findings from this study and mathematics education literature are used to support the claim that MTEs use anticipating, layering, and handover to independence as a system to promote PTs’ discussion of mathematics teaching in methods courses. Findings are used to draw conclusions about MTE expertise of discussion practice and the importance of selfbased methodologies in research on MTE expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09666-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An appropriate problem – considerations behind pre-service mathematics teachers’ problem posing in combinatorics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2024 06:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2435616?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking the gender equality paradox: narratives about mathematics and gender among teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2024 06:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2435016?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging Home Reading to Strengthen Literacy Development: Applying Principal Stratification to Explore Efficacy Trial Effects</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 07:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2430583?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing Teachers’ Disciplinary Knowledge for High School STEM Integration: A Review of a Decade of Educational Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Increasing calls for greater STEM-integrated experiences in K–12 education have spawned numerous studies on teacher beliefs, educational goals, and practices for teaching and learning. However, how the field proposes to support the development of teachers’ STEM-integrated disciplinary knowledge appears to be underresearched. In this systematic review, we analyzed 110 articles to determine (a) in what ways has the literature focused on teacher learning, (b) to what extent the literature addressed the development of teachers’ STEM-integrated disciplinary knowledge, and (c) to what extent the literature identified mechanisms for developing teachers’ STEM-integrated disciplinary knowledge. Results reveal needs that include, among others, more studies focused on developing teacher disciplinary knowledge; studies that differentiate teacher needs at different grade levels; studies that differentiate mechanisms aimed at developing teachers’ pedagogical knowledge, pedagogical content knowledge, and disciplinary knowledge; and studies that explicitly examine the mechanisms being used to support the development of teachers’ STEM-integrated disciplinary knowledge.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241289566?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The practicum in initial teacher education – enduring challenges, evolving practices and future research directions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/47/5&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2024&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2428031?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>POLICY SOLUTIONS: Should school board elections be partisan?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 50-51, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Should school board elections be partisan? Jonathan E. Collins writes about the pros and cons of bringing political parties back into school board elections. While partisan elections can bring more voter participation and interest in school governance, they also run the risk of pushing aside real education issues for culture war distractions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304833?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>UNDER THE LAW: The (mis)education of Indigenous students</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 52-53, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Indigenous students in the U.S. — including American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian children — have faced a history of serious educational mistreatment. Today, the abusive boarding school program has ended, but Indigenous children still experience formidable challenges. Robert Kim describes laws related to schools funded by the Bureau of Indian Education, studies showing how the federal government has fallen short of its responsibilities, and a recent case attempting to hold the government accountable.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304834?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BACKTALK: Finding the sweet spot between curriculum fidelity and teacher agency</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 54-55, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Two common perspectives on the implementation of curriculum and instructional strategies often appear to be at odds. On one side are those who call for fidelity to designers’ plans. On the other side are those who call for the empowerment of teachers to meet individual student needs, regardless of the pace required by curriculum guides. Ronald S. Thomas explains how teachers can use data to find a sweet spot between these approaches.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304835?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CAREER CONFIDENTIAL: How do we help students overcome the &#39;I can&#39;ts&#39;?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 56-57, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;In Career Confidential, Starr Sackstein offers professional advice for educators. In this edition, an instructional coach wants to help an art teacher whose students think they’re no good at art.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304836?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>STUDENTS SPEAK UP: What makes math matter for students?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/106/4&quot;&gt;Volume 106, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, December 2024/January 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Educators Rising students share why math matters to them and describe some of the most engaging math lessons they’ve experienced.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217241304837?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
