<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Empowering Expecting Women to Obtain High-Quality Healthcare in Pakistan: An Evaluation of Khyber Pakhtunkhwa’s Conditional Cash Transfer Program</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Maternal mortality, largely stemming from complications during pregnancy and childbirth, impacts poor expecting women with limited healthcare access in rural Pakistan. Conditional Cash Transfers (CCTs), commonly implemented in developing nations, are designed to improve the well-being of vulnerable populations by focusing on health and education. A CCT initiative named Chief Minister’s Special Initiative for Mother and Child Health (CM-SIMCH) was launched in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa (KP), one of the less-developed provinces of Pakistan, to empower expecting women to access quality healthcare. This study investigates the factors influencing CM-SIMCH program participation and assesses its impact on the health of expecting women by analyzing health-seeking hospital visits in KP, Pakistan. The study utilizes the Propensity Score Matching (PSM) technique to analyze cross-sectional data obtained from 303 expecting women residing in the Nowshera district of KP. The PSM allows for a balanced comparison of participants who received the CM-SIMCH transfers with those who did not, assessing its impact on maternal healthcare access and outcomes. Empirical results show that factors such as education and family system positively influence the participation of expecting women in the CM-SIMCH program, whereas travel costs exert a negative effect. The intervention leads to a notable increase in hospital visits among these women, contributing to improved health outcomes in KP. This underscores the program’s potential effectiveness in addressing maternal healthcare challenges and enhancing healthcare access for vulnerable women in less-developed areas. Therefore, empirical evidence supports the CM-SIMCH program’s potential to promote maternal health and improve healthcare access in KP. The study recommends government intervention in health sector as a strategic imperative to empower women and enhance infant health.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-26-2024 07:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241246826?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Algebraic Representations of a Splitting Task: Implications of Numerical Reasoning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-25-2024 07:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2343639?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Radian π: Concept images evoked by quantitative representations of radian angle measure</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-25-2024 04:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2338893?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I’ll do it Later”: Multilevel antecedents of homework procrastination</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-25-2024 02:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2341675?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Campus caring from the lens of preservice teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-24-2024 11:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2345600?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>HBCUs, #BlackLivesMatter, and the Global Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-24-2024 01:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2343242?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Use and Effectiveness of Academic Supports After Developmental Education Reform in California’s Community Colleges</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;AB705 is a landmark higher education policy that has changed approaches to developmental/remedial education in the California Community College system. We study one district that implemented reforms by placing most students in transfer-level math/English courses and encouraging enrollment in support courses based on multiple measures of academic preparation (e.g., grade point average [GPA]). We use regression discontinuity designs to examine the impact of these new placement recommendations, finding some benefits to English support course recommendations for low GPA students and increased math support course enrollment. We use matching methods to explore the relationship between support course enrollment and subsequent outcomes; finding enrollment in concurrent math and English support courses was associated with increased likelihood of completing transfer-level math and English.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-22-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241242108?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bildung in the digital age: Exploring Bildung through digital media in education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-22-2024 06:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2343497?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/46/2&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Summer 2024, Page 95-96&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-22-2024 01:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2333677?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using the proof assistant Lean in undergraduate mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper we develop a case for introducing a new teaching tool to undergraduate mathematics. Lean is an interactive theorem prover that instantly checks the correctness of every step and provides immediate feedback. Teaching with Lean might present a challenge, in that students must write their proofs in a formal way using a specific syntax. Accordingly, this paper addresses the issue of formalism from both a theoretical and a practical point of view. First, we examine the nature of proof, referring to historical and contemporary debates on formalization, and then show that in mathematical practice there is a growing rapprochement between strictly formal proof and proofs-in-practice. Next, we look at selections from the mathematics education literature that discuss how and when students advance through higher levels of mathematical maturity to reach a point at which they can cope with the demands of rigorous formalism. To probe the integration of Lean into teaching from an empirical point of view, we conducted an exploratory study that investigated how three undergraduate students approached the proof of double negation with Lean. The findings suggest that the rigorous nature of Lean is not an obstacle for students and does not stifle students’ creativity in writing proofs. On the contrary, proving with Lean offers a great deal of flexibility, allowing students to follow different paths to creating a valid proof.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01577-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Socio-ecological gestures of mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this theoretical article, we argue that the imminent collapse of earth systems that sustain life forms calls for mathematics education as a field to reflect on and re-evaluate its priorities and thus practices. We consider both what ecological collapse means for mathematics education and whether mathematics education might offer meaningful gestures in response. We explore how the relationship between the social and the ecological is conceptualised in mathematics education (and other relevant) research and what this implies for mathematics education. We read, in this scholarship, a growing focus on the ecological and conceptualisations of socio-ecological relations between existing entities that are dialectical, or mutually dependent. More rarely, are they seen as entangled and monist, and it is in this thought that we locate our contribution of multi-layered gestures of mathematics education. We describe these, in terms of three broad practices: listening for socio-ecological entanglement; attending to the scales of socio-ecological entanglements; and living entanglement as mathematics educators. We exemplify these gestures through examples of curriculum innovation. This article, a socio-ecological gesture in itself, is written in the spirit of opening a conversation into which we invite others.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-20-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10318-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Revisiting an historic tool of participatory action research: Consciousness-raising as a methodology for transformative change</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Freirean consciousness-raising methodology is an historical, emancipatory tool useful in transforming modern socio-political oppressions in the current War on Women as it can simultaneously raise critical consciousness and ignite social action. Unfortunately, there are no systemic guidelines on conducting consciousness-raising as a research method. Therefore, the purpose of this critical literature review is to examine how consciousness-raising has been used as a research methodology and evaluate its associated tools and procedures. The review (n = 12 studies) revealed ten decision-making processes: assumptions and aims, group composition, governance, environment, rules, session structure, activities, collective data collection and analysis, evaluation, and transition planning. I use an exemplar study of diverse girls exploring how city planning contributed to their experiences of neighborhood violence to integrate experiential knowledge into the literature review findings. The article concludes with a discussion on the implications, limitations, and future directions of the consciousness-raising methodology.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 10:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241248569?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring teacher educators’ challenges in the context of digital transformation and their self-reported TPACK: a mixed methods study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 04:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2340689?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Self-Care is Not Enough: Effects of Self-Care Self-Monitoring Intervention on Teacher Candidates’ Resilience and Self-Efficacy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 02:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2342906?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Effects of a Social-Emotional Learning Intervention in Brazilian Primary Schools: Findings from Year Two of Implementation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 01:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2322609?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Forced to Redshirt: Quasi-Experimental Impacts of Delayed Kindergarten Entry</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 01:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2333733?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical naming and explaining in teaching talk: Noticing work with two groups of mathematics teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research shows the salient place of mathematical teaching talk, including the mathematical-linguistic practices of naming and explaining, in the enactment of students’ mathematical talk and learning with understanding in the classroom. Our study was developed to examine the noticing of two groups of secondary-school mathematics teachers in one-day workshops with tasks about these practices. The two workshops were mathematically content-specific, with teaching and learning accounts and prompts aimed at guiding focused attention to naming and explaining in the teaching of linear equations and probability. Thematic text analyses led to identify three foci of the two groups’ noticing: (i) missing practices of mathematical naming in own teaching talk; (ii) relative impact of mathematical explaining in teaching talk; and (iii) tensions around mathematical naming and explaining in teaching talk. Our results show that the social construction of teacher noticing is a feature of noticing development that can be documented in the context of one-day workshops. Whereas time for individual thinking and responses to the tasks created a context of support for noticing development, participation in the group discussions allowed the teachers to notice nuances of mathematical naming and explaining in teaching talk unaddressed in the task prompts. The group discussions thus amplified and opened up the opportunities to develop some focused noticing on the content of the workshops, specifically in connection with the teachers’ own teaching practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01576-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics education researchers’ practices in interdisciplinary collaborations: Embracing different ways of knowing</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics education researchers (MERs) use practices unique to the mathematics education discipline to conduct their work. MERs’ practices, i.e., ways of being, interacting, and operating, define the field of mathematics education, are initially learned in doctoral preparation programs, and are encouraged and sanctioned by conferences and publications. Disciplinary practices facilitate MERs’ interactions within mathematics education. When working in interdisciplinary groups, differences in disciplinary ways of being, interacting, and operating can create challenges with completing research and other work. Since MERs’ engagement in interdisciplinary collaborations is encouraged and can result in products contributing to the evolution of the mathematics education discipline, it is important to explore what practices MERs use in interdisciplinary collaborations. We interviewed four MERs who led international interdisciplinary collaborations and used qualitative content analysis to create descriptions of practices described by MERs in their collaborations. Five practices were common between the MERs in interdisciplinary collaborations. MERs conducted interdisciplinary work by using practices that allowed them to situate themselves and others in the group (i.e., being practices), develop ideas (i.e., interacting practices), work towards common goals, and use structures to get the work done (i.e., operating practices). We argue that MERs developed new practices to position themselves and others, interact with practitioners from other disciplines, and get interdisciplinary work done. This study contributes to the evolution of the mathematics education discipline by offering five practices that can orient MERs to conducting interdisciplinary work and discussing how MERs experience interdisciplinary collaborations beyond providing mathematics education expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00489-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Multiply by 37 (or Divide by 0.027): A Surprisingly Accurate Rule of Thumb for Converting Effect Sizes From Standard Deviations to Percentile Points</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Educational researchers often report effect sizes in standard deviation units (SD), but SD effects are hard to interpret. Effects are easier to interpret in percentile points, but converting SDs to percentile points involves a calculation that is not transparent to educational stakeholders. We show that if the outcome variable is normally distributed, we can approximate the percentile-point effect simply by multiplying the SD effect by 37 (or, equivalently, dividing the SD effect by 0.027). For students in the middle three-fifths of a normal distribution, this rule of thumb is always accurate to within 1.6 percentile points for effect sizes of up to 0.8 SD. Two examples show that the rule can be just as accurate for empirical effects from real studies. Applying the rule to empirical benchmarks, we find that the least effective third of educational interventions raise scores by 0 to 2 percentile points; the middle third raise scores by 2 to 7 percentile points; and the most effective third raise scores by more than 7 percentile points.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-18-2024 12:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241239677?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessment of phonological awareness: Effects of emotional words on preschoolers’ skills</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-18-2024 11:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2341652?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Care for the learning of mathematics – put to the test</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-18-2024 04:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2339802?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ecological perspectives in early language education: Parent, teacher, peer and child agency in interaction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-18-2024 03:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2335791?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to (mis)align participatory approaches with the everyday life? Construction of an improved cookstove in India</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Improved cookstoves aimed at reducing exposure to indoor air pollution have had a lasting presence in development and health discussions. Through this article we contribute to current debates in the field by reflecting on our experiences during a cookstove participatory project in two ‘non-notified’ communities, or ‘slums,’ in Bangalore, India. We interrogate the alignment between some of the central tenets and methods of participation and the lived experiences of participating communities. The current predominant recommendations focus on developing and implementing cookstoves tailored for user needs. Yet, the project implementation entered a space of uncertainty where the priorities and needs of participants were diverse and changing. While urban infrastructures related to housing and work security, drainage systems, access to health care, and aspects of governance, citizenship and rights, may seem to fall outside the scope of ICS projects, our experiences show how inescapably they shape participatory processes and technologies. We highlight the need to take a closer look at how we can include these broader and changing priorities and needs in our methodologies and reflect on how we can better respond and align them with the ways in which people live.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-17-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241234495?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pre-service teachers as learners of formative assessment in teaching practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-17-2024 10:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2338840?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
