<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Equipping Preservice Teachers for Data Use: A Study of Secondary Educator Preparation Programs in Virginia</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Because data-informed decision-making (DIDM) can help teachers meet diverse learners’ needs (van Geel et al., 2016), educator preparation programs (EPPs) must ensure that preservice teachers (PSTs) develop the data literacy skills needed for effective data use. However, little is known about the ways in which EPPs work towards building PSTs’ data literacy, despite licensure and accreditation requirements compelling EPPs to do so. In this study, we analyzed survey, document, and interview data from Virginia EPPs to determine what present practices for DIDM preparation are taking place across the state. Results point to a lack of uniformity among EPPs for how preparation is undertaken, and that PSTS seem to have limited coursework on data use. Additionally, there appears to be minimal collaboration between EPPs and clinical partners, such that PSTs infrequently have opportunities to engage in DIDM during field experiences.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-20-2024 03:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241286798?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Curriculum Punishment in Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Milner advances curriculum punishment as a tool to describe how students may be harmed with policy and practice moves in education. Curriculum punishment pushes students and curriculum apart—where practices do not connect with and align with rich and robust diversity among young people, families, and communities. Although curriculum practices should honor, reflect, speak from the point of view of, deepen knowledge about, nuance myopic and mundane notions of, and enhance student identity, motivation, interests, and needs, curriculum punishment does the opposite by presenting one-dimensional, under-substantiated, and untruthful narratives and themes of individuals, communities, and nation-states. Tenets that explicate practices that Milner describes through curriculum punishment are (a) Avoiding, (b) Scripting, (c) Narrowing, (d) Distorting, and (e) Banning. Although some of these practices are beyond the control of teachers, teachers are encouraged to Study, Collaborate with others about, Reflect on, Advocate against, and Transform (SCRAT) Curriculum Punishment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-20-2024 03:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241286066?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sociodemographic Differences in Kindergarten Children’s Summer Enrichment: Trends Over Time Using National Data</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;During summer, children’s activities are dependent on their families’ and communities’ resources, raising concerns about inequalities in access to summer enrichment experiences. In this research brief, we use nationally representative data from the 1999 and 2011 ECLS-K cohorts to examine trends in kindergarten children’s summer enrichment activities over time by socioeconomic status and race. Although we find that persistent inequalities characterize many of these experiences, there were some promising trends, including small shifts upward in summer home academic activities. We discuss implications and future research directions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-19-2024 06:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241286524?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>David Orme Tall (1941-2024)</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-19-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00258-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Enabling and constraining ‘vulnerability ready’ teachers in mentee–mentor relations</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2024 11:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2413502?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>There’s No Way for This to End Well: Lesson Planning, Neoliberalism, and Whiteness</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The author relies on practices of storytelling to consider how an unexamined and evaluative preoccupation with lesson planning in education supports neoliberalism, affirms whiteness, and limits democratic curriculum and pedagogy. The author theorizes ways that striving toward a nonevaluative stance in education can be used to resist complying with neoliberalism and whiteness in education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2024 10:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241289932?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring beliefs among Chinese preschool teachers and their associations with perceived practices and process quality</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2024 10:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2414907?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effect of Science Teachers’ Pedagogical Content Knowledge on Student Achievement: Evidence From Both Text- and Video-Based Pedagogical Content Knowledge Tests</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article provides robust empirical evidence for the association between science teachers’ pedagogical content knowledge (PCK) and student achievement. Unlike previous studies, we employed two approaches (text-based vs. video-based tests) to assess if, and to what extent, teachers’ PCK assessed by these two approaches are related to student achievement. An analysis utilizing two-level hierarchical linear modeling revealed that PCK assessed by both types of tests reveals a significant and positive association with student achievement. Teachers’ PCK assessed by the video-based test better predicted student achievement than teachers’ PCK assessed by the text-based test. Based on this result, we discuss implications for research on teacher knowledge and policy implications for teacher education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2024 10:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241278627?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do the Effects Persist? An Examination of Long-Term Effects After Students Leave Turnaround Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Whole-school reforms have received widespread attention, but a critical limitation of the current literature is the lack of evidence around whether these extensive and costly interventions improve students’ long-term outcomes after they leave reform schools. Leveraging Tennessee’s statewide turnaround reforms, we use difference-in-differences models to estimate the effect of attending a turnaround middle school on student outcomes in high school, including test scores, attendance, chronic absenteeism, disciplinary actions, drop out, and high school graduation. We find little evidence to support improved long-run student outcomes—mostly null effects that are nearly zero in magnitude. Our results contribute to a broad call for educational researchers to examine whether school reforms meaningfully affect student outcomes beyond short-term improvements in test scores.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2024 10:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241284026?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Domestic Study Away in Higher Education: A Systematic Literature Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The recent COVID-19 pandemic and an emphasis on improving access to international education experiences have spurred researchers and practitioners to consider global experiences without international travel. Domestic study away programs can broaden access to intercultural learning for postsecondary students. This systematic literature review, the first known attempt to review the literature on study away, explores how researchers and professionals have previously discussed these opportunities. We draw from 59 publications to understand how study away is defined; conceptual, theoretical, and methodological approaches to investigating study away; common programmatic features; and learning outcomes. We find that study away is often ill-defined, and many empirical publications do not utilize theoretical or conceptual frameworks in their exploration. Learning outcomes attributed to study away were most commonly either psychosocial or related to attitudes and values. Based on our findings, we provide recommendations for researchers and practitioners and highlight directions for future work.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2024 10:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241279296?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reforming School Choice Systems to Reduce Segregation in Schools: A Comparative Political Economy Study of Education Reform in Belgium, Chile, and the Netherlands</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2024 06:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2407252?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Missing the Forest for the Trees: Toward a Networked Racial Analysis of White Parents in Education Policy and Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Education policy research on White parent opportunity hoarding overlooks whiteness studies and focuses on individual-level behaviors. In this article, we advance a racial network analysis of White parent collectives to better understand how White parents reinforce racial hierarchies in schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-16-2024 12:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241290791?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Call for Research on the Role of Legal Counsel in Promoting (In)Equitable Educational Policies in a Hostile, Anti-DEI Sociopolitical Climate</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The current climate reflects not only a hostile politicization of diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) work but also an institutionalization of anti-DEI sentiments through legislation and litigation, leaving educational institutions to operate within a hyper-legalistic environment. Although there are a large number of education attorneys who interface regularly with educational institutions, the field of education knows very little about contemporary models of collaboration between attorneys for educational institutions and the values that inform these collaborations. In this article, we aim to illustrate the significant role of attorneys for P–20 educational institutions, the need for more research to help us better understand existing strengths and limitations, and ways to harness this role in meaningful ways to further DEI commitments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-16-2024 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241289402?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of an Infant/Toddler Intervention at 1-Year Follow-Up: Sustained Impacts to Preschool Entry</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We Learn Together is a 20-week, low-cost infant/toddler school-readiness intervention developed to provide instructional content and supportive tools for teachers to be more explicit and intentional in interactions with children to support early development. Short-term effects were established in a previously published real-world effectiveness randomized controlled trial. In the present quasi-experimental study, we examined the extent to which the effects remained approximately 1 year after the intervention. Because the original control group eventually also got the intervention, we compared mandatory municipal language assessment outcomes of 2,327 children in the treatment group to matched nontreatment children. The intervention effect was maintained at similar magnitudes at the 1-year follow-up for oral language skills (effect sizes = 0.09–0.14), and spillover effects were found for rhyming skills (effect size = 0.12).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-16-2024 12:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241282419?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating the use of a mobile portfolio app to develop pre-service teachers’ reflective abilities and orientations to learning to teach</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-16-2024 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2414912?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Bad Commute: Travel Time to Work Predicts Teacher Turnover and Other Workplace Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research suggests that longer commute times may increase employee turnover probabilities by increasing stress and reducing job attachment and embeddedness. Using administrative data from a midsized urban school district, we test whether teachers with longer commute times are more likely to transfer schools or exit the district. Both descriptively and in regression results employing multiple fixed effects, we find that teachers with longer commutes are more likely to transfer schools within the district. Regression results show that each 5-minute increase in one-way commute time predicts an increase in transfer probability of 0.8 to 1.0 percentage points over most of the commute time distribution. We also find evidence that teachers with the longest commutes (i.e., 40+ minutes each way) have higher district exit probabilities. Moreover, teachers with longer commute times are absent from work more frequently and receive lower observation ratings. We discuss potential implications for local human resources policy and practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-15-2024 06:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241287792?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effectiveness of a Social-Emotional Learning Program for Both Teachers and Students</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;This study investigated the effects of the Leader in Me (LiM), a social-emotional learning program implemented in thousands of schools. A mixed-method design included (1) a collective case study in four diverse, high-implementing elementary schools and (2) a post hoc quasi-experiment using propensity score 1:3 matching of 117 LiM and 348 non-LiM schools to compare achievement and discipline incident rates. The case study indicated that participants perceived LiM as improving social-emotional competencies for both teachers and students. Teachers reported being more prosocial, feeling more camaraderie, using more effective discipline, developing better teacher-student relationships, and enjoying teaching more. Students were more prosocial, confident and motivated, and had fewer problem behaviors. School climate improved. Results replicated across four diverse schools. The quasi-experiment supported results of the collective case study. Schools implementing LiM had higher mathematics and ELA, but not science, scores on state proficiency exams and fewer discipline incidents.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-15-2024 06:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241281284?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Children’s views on why environmental protection is important: Are nature-based schools enough?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-15-2024 05:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2413117?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Alignment of P–3 Math Instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Preschool through third grade (P–3) alignment is regularly named as a key aspect of early childhood education and the transition to formal schooling. However, little is known about P–3 alignment in practice. Using data from 265 observations of math instruction in preschool, kindergarten, first-, and third-grade classrooms in New York City public schools, we explore P–3 instructional alignment as it would be experienced sequentially, over time and across grades, by students. We examine the continuity of developmentally appropriate instructional environments and high-quality pedagogical practices, as well as the progression of P–3 mathematics content coverage. We find notable discontinuities in instructional environments and some pedagogical practices, particularly across preschool and kindergarten. We also find both progression and repetition in math content coverage. Results suggest that, on some dimensions, kindergarten may be poorly aligned with both preschool and the early elementary grades.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-15-2024 01:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241281483?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Cosmopolitan Approach to Preparing Preservice Teachers for a Diverse World</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article considers the future of teacher education through researching the impact of encouraging cosmopolitan perspectives in an undergraduate children’s literature course for preservice teachers. The research question focuses on how preservice teachers respond to reading and dialoguing through a cosmopolitan lens. Reading literature through a cosmopolitan lens entails a reflexive consideration of personal convictions and a reflective openness to learning from the perspectives of others. The results of this study provide insights into how preservice teachers understood a cosmopolitan response. The results also highlight the need for further critical inquiry into how to invite greater reflexive consciousness and reflective openness to other perspectives in preparing teachers for a diverse society.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2024 12:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241292640?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racialized Decoupling and Race-Neutral School Integration Policies From the Implementers’ Perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Today’s school integration policies in the United States are often “race neutral.” Scholarship on these race-neutral school integration policies finds they do not change the racial and ethnic composition of schools or do so under very specific conditions. Yet, we know relatively little about the mechanisms explaining these outcomes. Building on 2 years of qualitative data collection in two public elementary schools in a New York City implementing a voluntary, race-neutral integration policy, I find school leaders experience a racialized decoupling of their commitment to racial equity from the policy’s race-neutral design, its choice-based design, and the implementation context. I show how school leaders navigated this decoupling and how it led to racialized outcomes. I contribute to our understanding of the mechanisms shaping the outcomes of race-neutral policies, a point of growing importance given recent Supreme Court decisions on higher education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2024 10:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241288499?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Neoliberalism and the Complexities of Conceptualizing Community School Policy for Racial Equity</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Full-service community schools are increasingly adopted as educational policy nationwide to transform educational institutions into community hubs, addressing racial and social disparities and countering deficit narratives related to marginalized youth and families. As the movement toward community schooling as an educational policy gains momentum, more research is needed to understand the complex process of conceptualizing such an initiative for racial equity. Spanning from the early planning stages to 3 years into the implementation of community schooling, this paper uncovers the tensions that emerge as school and district leaderships’ interpretation of the purpose of community schooling and root cause of racial inequity unveil conflicting conceptualizations of the community school initiative: community schooling rooted in neoliberal ideals of efficiency, coordination, and service choice, on one hand, and those rooted in more transformative approach with systemic reflection and change in classrooms, schools, and other institutions on the other.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2024 10:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241278294?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Towards embedded academic language development in a teacher education programme</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2024 06:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2414914?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Trends in Special Education Identification During the COVID-19 Pandemic: Evidence From Michigan</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We use data from Michigan and an interrupted time series strategy to show how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted special education identifications and discontinuations. We find a substantial decrease in K–5 identifications and discontinuations during the 2019 to 2020 and 2020 to 2021 school years. Identifications fell by 19% and 12% in the first two pandemic years, with smaller but still significant reductions in discontinuations. Districts with remote schooling and Black, Asian, and economically disadvantaged students saw larger decreases in identifications. By 2021 to 2022 rates returned to trend and continued to grow in 2022 to 2023, albeit at a similar rate to pre-pandemic. This suggests some “catch-up” accounting for delayed or missed identifications but likely not enough at this point to overcome the pandemic induced deficit.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2024 05:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241274799?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
