<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating the Complexity in Elementary Teachers’ Noticing of Children’s Mathematical Thinking in Written Work</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-09-2024 08:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2372977?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice Secondary Teachers’ Mathematical Knowledge for Teaching: Focus on Reflective Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 09:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2373653?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Intertwining of Children’s Interests and Micro-Practices at a Science Museum: Case Study of Three Children</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 06:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2374705?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cooperation in primary school children: The role of cardiac vagal tone and cognitive control</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 04:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2366347?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transforming teaching through cooperative inquiry: meaningful research for university teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 01:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2374745?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Learner-Centered Teaching and Learning Goes Online: Zooming into Linear Algebra Tutorials During the Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic shifted higher education online, drawing attention to synchronous learning and instruction on digital communication platforms. Learner-centered teaching practices in the tertiary level, such as mathematical discussions, have been shown to benefit student learning. The interactions involved in online synchronous mathematical discussions have been studied less. Most research taps into these aspects drawing on students’ academic outcomes and reflective interviews. This study explores instructional practices as they unfold online, with a focus on student-instructor and student-student interactions. We zoom-in to online synchronous teaching and learning processes on a popular communication platform by analyzing Linear Algebra tutorials in the first pandemic year. Using the commognitive framework, we characterize instructional interactions with the construct of a learning-teaching agreement. The analysis resulted in three interactional patterns, where in all cases, the tutorial transformed at some point to the one dominated by the instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00244-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analyzing Teacher-Designed Tasks Through the Lens of Procedural and Conceptual Knowledge</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Literature suggests that “current characterizations of the terms procedural knowledge and conceptual knowledge are limiting and are, in fact, impediments to careful investigation of these constructs” (Star, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r31&quot;&gt;2005&lt;/span&gt;, p. 405). We examined secondary mathematics teachers’ understanding of procedural and conceptual knowledge at superficial and deep levels through the design of mathematical tasks. For this purpose, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;=55 secondary mathematics teachers were asked to design a procedural and a conceptual task on a given topic and explain why they think the task they designed is a procedural and/or conceptual task. The study results showed that 78% of teachers were able to design and correctly explain procedural tasks. However, only 5.5% of teachers were able to design conceptual tasks correctly. Teachers’ narratives were examined to categorize emerging characteristics of procedural and conceptual tasks as well as to address teachers’ (mis)conceptions about procedural and conceptual knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00319-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning models and achievements of the most gifted students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2024 08:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2364690?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Heading for new shores? Longitudinal participation patterns in teacher professional development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2024 07:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2370891?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: How can university mathematics overcome Klein&#39;s second discontinuity? Specific course design</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01611-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Task potential in relation to teaching quality and teacher competence in secondary mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The potential of tasks to foster mathematical learning and understanding is an important aspect of instruction and their implementation in teaching is thus often viewed to be positively related to the quality of instruction. Both the selection of tasks as well as their implementation in the classroom depend on many factors, with teachers’ knowledge and skills as one of the most important ones. The present study aims to analyze the relations between different aspects of task potential, the quality of instruction, and teachers’ competence in order to investigate whether task potential can be seen as an indicator for teaching quality, for teacher competence, or as an independent construct in models of educational effectiveness. To this end, we draw on data from the TEDS-Validate study, namely tests of mathematics teachers’ competence (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 31) observations in their classrooms (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 60), and an in-depth analysis of all tasks used in the respective lessons (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 2490). Multiple regression analysis suggests that while some facets of task potential are related to either teaching quality or teacher competence, the potential of tasks emerges as an independent construct with some characteristics predicting the teaching quality of the respective lessons. Implications of these results for the role of tasks in educational effectiveness research are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01596-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Epistemological justification</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Epistemological justification&lt;/em&gt; is a way of thinking that manifests itself through perturbation-resolution cycles revolving around the question &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;why and how was a piece of mathematical knowledge conceived&lt;/em&gt;? The paper offers a conceptual framework for constituent elements of epistemological justification. The framework provides: (a) a theoretical basis for epistemological justification, (b) criteria for its occurrence, and (c) analysis of its relation to &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;mathematical explanation&lt;/em&gt;. The criteria are illustrated by a series of learning-teaching events taken from teaching experiments aimed at investigating the learning and teaching in linear algebra. The contribution of the proposed framework is three-fold: (a) it addresses a critical aspect of proof understanding not explicitly addressed in the literature; (b) it goes beyond the traditional treatment of mathematical understanding and production into questions about learners’ conceptualization of the origins of mathematical knowledge; and (c) it theorizes instructional approaches that can advance this conceptualization among students.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01603-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Towards an advanced mathematical language task for the early primary school years: preliminary results on reliability and validity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical language (or the content-specific words in mathematics) has repeatedly shown to be related to mathematical abilities in preschool and in the early grades of primary education. Research in this field has predominantly focused on young children’s quantitative and spatial language. At the same time, recent research has discovered that children in the early years of primary education already possess advanced mathematical skills such as reasoning about patterns, proportions and probabilities. In this study we developed an advanced mathematical language task to measure children’s understanding of mathematical language proper of the domains of patterning, proportionality, and probability, specifically aimed at first, second, and third graders (ages 5 -8). To develop a valid test instrument, our task was substantiated by a review of relevant literature and previously conducted studies. Further, the task was optimized based on the feedback received from expert professionals and a pilot study with 36 children. After administering the advanced mathematical language task to 236 first, second, and third graders, the results suggest that the task provides reliable scores in these grades. The internal consistency is excellent (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;α&lt;/em&gt; = .993). In addition, the test–retest reliability was checked in 49 children (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; = .704; &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; .001), and shows that the test also produces stable results over time.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10342-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Political conocimiento in teaching mathematics: mathematics teacher candidates enacting their ethical identities</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09646-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Units Coordination in Preservice Elementary Teachers&#39; Mathematical Knowledge for Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2024 11:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2370178?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher education for mathematical modelling: exploring the experiences of secondary school teachers in two courses</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper focuses on in-service teacher education as a crucial agent in driving educational paradigm shifts for the teaching and learning of mathematical modelling. Our paper presents empirical research based on two case studies, examining training courses for in-service secondary school mathematics teachers. The first course integrates different modelling approaches, while the second one is based on the anthropological theory of the didactic and uses the proposal of the study and research paths for teacher education. Both experiences conclude with teachers working on the design of modelling tasks to be implemented in secondary schools. Both courses are analysed through the lenses of how teachers progress on the collective identification of conditions and constraints for modelling, when teachers deal with the design of modelling tasks and analyse their implementations. First, the results show the kind of modelling tasks teachers design and the level of disciplinary specificity at which they plan modelling to be implemented. Second, we analyse how teachers address the “ecological analysis”, that is, the identification of conditions and constraints that facilitate or hinder the integration of modelling in secondary school classrooms after their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01609-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beginning mathematics teachers’ values and beliefs about pedagogy during a time of policy flux</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study interrogates how beginning secondary mathematics teachers align their beliefs with their practice when they justify their pedagogical choices in the context of recent English mathematics education policy which is strongly influenced by approaches to mathematics teaching in Shanghai and Singapore currently referred to as ‘mastery’ approaches. It seeks to understand beginning teachers’ perceptions and understandings of these approaches and the extent to which they recognise aspects of ‘mastery’ in practice. In setting the context, pre-service teachers’ beliefs were surveyed and found to be congruent with constructivist approaches to learning. We then draw on qualitative data from semi-structured interviews secondary mathematics teachers in their first year post-qualification. The interviews were designed to interrogate and capture understanding of the features of mastery within their own classrooms. By using vignettes to capture participants’ beliefs, our aim was to present a ‘more nuanced understanding of the phenomena’ (Skilling and Stylianides in Int J Res Method Educ 43(5):541–556, 2019, 10.1080/1743727x.2019.1704243). The analytical framework developed draws on Guskey’s (In: Wright J (ed) International encyclopedia of the social &amp;amp; behavioural sciences, 2015, vol 14, 2nd edn, Elsevier, pp 752–759) interpretation of Bloom’s theory of mastery learning together with features of mastery learning in mathematics articulated by Drury (How to teach mathematics for mastery, 2018, Oxford University Press) and Boylan et al. (Edu Sci 8(4):202, 2018, 10.3390/educsci8040202). This posed a research design challenge given the variation in interpretation of mastery learning as it is understood in practice. The data exposes differences in the interpretation of mastery approaches in the settings where they learn to teach, as well as the tensions that arise between beginning teachers’ beliefs, practice, professional knowledge and agency in their developing classroom roles.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09647-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School gardens as sites for community, empowerment, and justice: a participatory action research study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 12:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2374746?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting students’ participation in collective argumentation: Use of displays in a secondary mathematics classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 04:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2371515?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Development of prospective elementary teachers’ knowledge to teach early algebra through case discussions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigated the development of prospective elementary teachers (PETs)’ subject matter and pedagogical content knowledge for teaching early algebra through participation in case discussions. PETs attended five weeks of intervention as part of a method course, which included case discussions. During the intervention, the participants were presented with big ideas of equivalence and equations, generalized arithmetic, and functional thinking as the content of early algebra through text-based classroom cases. Data were collected through one-hour individual interviews before and after the early algebra lessons. The analysis of the pre-interviews indicated that prospective elementary teachers may not be ready to foster algebraic thinking in elementary grades in terms of the required knowledge for teaching. We found that PETs needed more development of required subject matter knowledge to guide algebraic thinking in elementary grades, such as the relational meaning of the equal sign, generalizing, representing, or justifying arithmetic or functional relationships, and reasoning with them. Likewise, PETs were found to lack in pedagogical content knowledge related to students’ conceptions and misconceptions and effective teaching strategies to promote early algebraic thinking. However, we found that specifically designed method courses could help develop PETs’ knowledge of teaching early algebra. Following early algebra lessons centered around case discussions, PETs showed progress in multiple aspects of knowledge across all big ideas, though their improvement in generalized arithmetic was somewhat less pronounced. This progress was observed in their subject matter and pedagogical content knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09642-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A proposal for the study of mathematics teachers’ beliefs through the analysis of their practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In recent years, research on mathematics teachers’ beliefs has increasingly shifted its focus toward understanding their connection with instructional practices. This article introduces a model designed to explore mathematics teachers’ beliefs through a comprehensive analysis of their practices. The contributions of models that study the relationship between beliefs and practices of teachers, such as those from Schoenfeld (Journal of Mathematical Behavior, 18(3), 243–261, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r27&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/span&gt;) and Cobb and Yackel (Educational Psychologist, 31(3), 175–190, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r5&quot;&gt;1996&lt;/span&gt;), were reviewed and considered. Additionally, it includes methodological considerations from Leatham and Speer for studying beliefs. These approaches are integrated by utilizing the notions of practice, types of didactic-mathematical practices and norms, derived from the onto-semiotic approach, as the central organizing axis. Furthermore, we demonstrate the application of these stages of analysis for exploring teachers’ beliefs by analyzing the beliefs of a prospective mathematics teacher. The findings enable us to identify the beliefs held by this prospective teacher regarding the use of introductory activities characterized by a high motivational level but a low mathematical level. Additionally, these results provide insights into potential avenues for developing training programs aimed at instigating a shift in these beliefs, thereby fostering an enhancement in teaching practices. These outcomes show the feasibility of the analytical model proposed in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-02-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00496-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building mathematical micro-identities through supporting productive struggle</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 11:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2372711?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Way to Consider Balance Among JRME Publications: Descriptive, Transformative, and Reflective Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Journal for Research in Mathematics Education&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 55&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 4&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 156-162
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/jrme/55/4/article-p156.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Looking Inside the Black Box: Measuring Implementation and Detecting Group-Level Impact of Cognitively Guided Instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Journal for Research in Mathematics Education&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 55&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 4&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 163-181
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/jrme/55/4/article-p163.xml</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
