<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>“You can’t just check the box”: the mathematics of ethnoracial contortions at a California high school</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article brings critical and postcolonial theories together with extended ethnographic research in a predominantly Latinx high school in California’s “South Bay” to theorize the co-production and co-naturalization of mathematical and racial essentialization. Analysis of vignettes and interview excerpts illuminates both student uptake and resistance to homogenizing narratives of mathematics and racial personhood. Student voices from Sierra High School both evidenced the existence, stakes, and personal consequences of narrowly bounded, taken for granted, conceptions of mathematics and racial personhood and challenged these homogenizing categories. This paper contributes theory illuminating the co-construction of mathematical and racial essentialization along with examples of local critique and resistance from youth and their adult allies at one high school in the USA. Implications suggest that decolonial work in mathematics education must jointly address the narrow and essentializing frames for race and racialization and for mathematics itself as co-producing and co-naturalizing each other. This study contributes insight into mechanisms that perpetuate and also resist or disrupt these processes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10258-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Statistics education research at the school level in Australia and New Zealand: A 30-year journey</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The introduction of statistical concepts into school curricula in Australia and New Zealand in the early 1990s initiated an ongoing research program into the learning and teaching of statistics and probability in both countries. This paper reviews the contribution of Australian and New Zealand researchers to building statistical literacy at school, alongside international developments. From recognising how students develop understanding of specific statistical and probabilistic concepts, through teacher knowledge and beliefs for teaching statistics, to intervention studies and targeted teaching, the field of statistics education has grown and changed. Statistics and probability are now well established as part of the mathematics curriculum. The importance of linking statistical literacy and statistical understanding across the curriculum, as well as in STEM, has also begun to receive attention as other subjects have recognised the importance of data in their fields. Following a comprehensive review of the field in Australia and New Zealand, this paper then considers emerging areas of interest, such as new approaches to data visualisation, and suggests future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00470-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Texting and tutoring: Short-term K-3 reading interventions during the pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 11:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2251432?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identifying Informative Predictor Variables With Random Forests</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Random forests are a nonparametric machine learning method, which is currently gaining popularity in the behavioral sciences. Despite random forests’ potential advantages over more conventional statistical methods, a remaining question is how reliably informative predictor variables can be identified by means of random forests. The present study aims at giving a comprehensible introduction to the topic of variable selection with random forests and providing an overview of the currently proposed selection methods. Using simulation studies, the variable selection methods are examined regarding their statistical properties, and comparisons between their performances and the performance of a conventional linear model are drawn. Advantages and disadvantages of the examined methods are discussed, and practical recommendations for the use of random forests for variable selection are given.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 10:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231193327?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“They Don&#39;t Feel Like This Is Their Place Anymore:” School Leaders’ Understanding of the Impacts of Gentrification on Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A number of urban U.S. cities that were traditionally Black and underinvested are now becoming enclaves to whites and upper-middle-class people. Consequently, a growing body of research on schools and gentrification is emerging. While most of this research has focused on the shifts that neighborhoods and schools undergo due to gentrification, we know less about how school leaders make meaning of these impacts. This study draws on interviews with 26 principals in two gentrifying cities to examine the impacts of gentrification on schools. We find that school leaders understand gentrification&#39;s impacts on schools materially, epistemically, and affectively, and at the same time, these shifts complicate the work of school leaders. This study concludes with implications for future research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 05:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231191704?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participatory and critical action research</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/31/4&quot;&gt;Volume 31, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, October 2023, Page 611-619&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 04:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2252212?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A National Study Exploring Factors Promoting Adolescent College Readiness in Math and Science (STEM-CR)</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Numerous national and state endeavors have advocated for approaches, funding, and programs focused on expanding the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) workforce of the nation and investing in education to cultivate a more diverse and impactful cohort of students who pursue STEM pathways. Educators, support personnel, and policymakers are in a position to engage in discussions about expanding STEM college readiness (STEM-CR) and participation. However, few are cognizant that STEM-CR is a progression that students strive for in developing skills, behaviors, and attitudes that spans over time. The current study established and validated a measurement model of student STEM-CR in mathematics and science utilizing the High School Longitudinal Study of 2009. The model was created based on a multidimensional and theoretical perspective of college readiness using a confirmatory factor analysis and modeling approach that accounted for measurement invariance. The sample (N = 16,044) comes from a racialized/ethnoracial and socioeconomically diverse high school population in the United States. The findings confirmed that STEM-CR involves four related yet distinct dimensions of Think, Know, Act, and Go. Results also demonstrated soundness of these STEM-CR dimensions by race and gender (key learning skills and techniques/Act). Academic self-efficacy was the strongest dimension of our STEM-CR model and strongly predicted academic achievement and college enrollment. Research and practice implications are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 01:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231193309?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Job satisfaction of mathematics teachers: an empirical investigation to quantify the contributions of teacher self-efficacy and teacher motivation to teach</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The shortage of mathematics teachers necessitates deliberate efforts to retain high-quality ones in many parts of the world. This puts teacher job satisfaction in the spotlight since satisfied teachers are likely to retain their jobs. Thus, the purpose of this study is twofold. The first is to quantify the influence of teacher self-efficacy and teacher motivation on teacher job satisfaction. The second is to investigate the patterns of changes in teacher job satisfaction across gender, age, and work experience. Using both descriptive and inferential statistics, we analysed the dataset of 1304 Norwegian mathematics teachers to address two research questions. The results showed that both teacher self-efficacy and social utility motivation have a significant influence on teacher job satisfaction with an additional mediating role of teacher self-efficacy. Contrary to our expectations, personal utility motivation has a negative influence on teacher job satisfaction. We found that women had significantly higher teacher job satisfaction than men. Also, we found a high-low–high pattern of changes in teacher job satisfaction in ascending order of teachers’ age and work experience. One practical implication of these findings is exposing an appropriate time (i.e. at a low stage of job satisfaction) for interventions targeted at teacher job satisfaction to be effective. We discussed other implications of these findings concerning which constructs, gender, and age groups of teachers to prioritise for interventions that would reinforce the job satisfaction of mathematics teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00475-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining Race in LatCrit: A Systematic Review of Latinx Critical Race Theory in Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This systematic review includes 125 peer-reviewed education-research articles that employ a LatCrit framework (from a search including articles published from 1995 to 2020). The author examines how the literature utilizes LatCrit and advances ideas about race, Latinxs, and Latinidad in education. The author presents significant patterns and divergences in the literature’s strengths, challenges, and tensions. Some strengths include detailing Latinxs’ experiences and valuing experiential knowledge. The author problematizes four research practices: (1) describing LatCrit with select tenets of CRT; (2) not defining race or other relevant concepts (language, culture, etc.); (3) claiming Latinxs are unique because of their multidimensionality; and (4) exceeding LatCrit’s scope by rationalizing the study’s use of LatCrit because its participants are Latinxs. The author argues that these complications lead to a paradox: even though LatCrit emerges from critical race theory and is described as for Latinxs, the literature largely undertheorizes race and lacks clarity about conceptualizing Latinxs as a racialized group. The author recommends four framing ideas that are particular to LatCrit and that help advance the specificity of Latinidad in education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 10:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231192685?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The effects of online enactive education on secondary school students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 10:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2251405?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Study of modeling questions in a first-year university mathematics online course</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The training of non-specialists, particularly engineers, in mathematics requires designing specific didactic proposals that make the importance of mathematics evident. One approach to creating such proposals consists in analyzing the mathematics used in authentic contexts of engineering research and then effectuating a didactic transposition to mathematics teaching. To this end, in this research, we use elements of the anthropological theory of the didactic and the methodology of didactic engineering. Initially, we analyze the blind source separation method, a case of inverse modeling widely used in numerous engineering contexts (e.g., telecommunications, acoustics, geophysics, biosignal analysis). More specifically, we examine the algorithm based on the &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(A\mathbf{x}=\mathbf{b}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; matrix model and its use in a signal processing context. Based on this analysis, we designed a didactic device that focuses the study on a simulated signal mixture of pure tones and implemented it in two first-year university mathematics courses in the virtual modality. This article reports the results of the students’ first approximation to mathematical modeling activity in a setting of authentic research in engineering using a blind source separation method.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10261-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Increase in self-efficacy in prospective teachers through theory-based lesson study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper explores the education of prospective teachers with regard to the Theory of Didactical Situations when they engage in lesson study. We particularly focus on studying how a lesson study process oriented towards the Theory of Didactical Situations contributes to increasing prospective teachers’ self-efficacy to plan and teach lessons based on such theory, reducing the gap between theory and practice. Prior to the study, we will discuss how the theoretical postulates assumed in lesson study affect crucial aspects of the process. The study is implemented with 47 prospective early childhood education teachers. We also consider another group of 47 prospective teachers that were engaged in practicum at the time the lesson study process took place. Using a quasi-experimental methodology based on a questionnaire developed ad hoc that captures the particularities of the didactic paradigm assumed, the results of our study show that both lesson study and practicum lead to a statistically significant increase in future teachers’ self-efficacy to plan and teach lessons in line with the paradigm assumed. However, size effect measures show that the increase observed in the lesson study group is significantly higher, which supports the benefits of lesson study in initial teacher education. We discuss what the features of lesson study are that could be related to this increase. Finally, we sketch new lines of research connected with the benefits of lesson study versus other teacher education experiences like practicum, as well as with links between self-efficacy and knowledge growth in lesson study.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09597-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics identity instrument development for fifth through twelfth grade students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Given the importance of mathematics identity for students continued participation and engagement with mathematics, it is important for educators and researchers to be able to explore students’ mathematics identity development. However, an instrument with validity evidence that can be used to explore mathematics identity efficiently and with groups of students is not currently available. This article draws on prior research to test and validate items for a mathematics identity instrument to be used with fifth through twelfth grade students. This study includes 1559 participants from two school districts in a midwestern state in the USA. Analysis includes assessing four components of validity including content validity, internal structure, relationship to other variables, and generalization. Findings provide evidence for the reliability and validity of the items in the mathematics identity scale, giving researchers and educators a way to explore this construct efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00474-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The First-Grade Outcomes of Pre-K Attendees: Examining Benefits as a Function of Skill Type, Environments, and Subgroups</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examined whether pre-K benefits persist through the end of first grade and the extent to which persistence differs based on outcome domains, subsequent classroom environments, and key subgroups of children. Data from 2,351 children living in a large and diverse county in Virginia revealed that the initial benefits of pre-K for academic and executive function persisted through the end of first grade but were 75% to 80% smaller than at kindergarten entry. Kindergarten and first-grade classroom environments did not sustain pre-K benefits. Although the initial benefits of pre-K were larger for dual language learners and children in poverty relative to English speakers and low-income children, there were no differential benefits by the end of first grade.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2023 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231195559?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I don’t like to ask for charity”: The possibilities of social inclusion among immigrant low-income Latina mothers via feminist action research</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This Feminist Action Research (FAR) examines the impact of economic and societal exclusion on low-income Latina mothers. The study, conducted in an urban community in the Northeast U.S., aimed to foster social inclusion among low-income Latina mothers via a financial intervention. Data were collected from 12 participants, and the intervention emphasized curriculum negotiation and critical thinking. Descriptions and roles of positionality are considered and contextualized. Findings exemplified economic and societal exclusion in the form of economic deprivation and experiences of discrimination, along with experiences of personal agency, solidarity, and social inclusion. Conclusions include a discussion on the potential of FAR within poverty research, along with practical implications in developing community change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 11:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231199846?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Errybody Sayin ‘No New Friends’?: The Proverbs of Rap and Why Young People Recite Them</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 06:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2240460?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional digital competence beliefs of student teachers, pre-service teachers and teachers: Validating an instrument based on the DigCompEdu framework</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 02:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2251663?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unfolding algebraic thinking from a cognitive perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Little is known about the cognitive effort associated with algebraic activity in the elementary and middle school grades. However, this investigation is significant for sensitizing teachers and researchers to the mental demands of algebra learning. In this paper, we focus on the relationship between algebraic thinking and domain-general cognitive abilities. The sample of the study comprised 591 students from grades 4 to 7. The students’ abilities in algebraic thinking were assessed through a test that involved three task categories: generalized arithmetic, functional thinking, and modelling languages. Test batteries were used to assess students’ domain-general cognitive abilities in terms of analogical, serial, spatial, and deductive reasoning. The results of structural equation modelling analysis indicated that (a) analogical reasoning predicts students’ abilities only in generalized arithmetic; (b) serial reasoning predicts students’ abilities only in generalized arithmetic; (c) spatial reasoning predicts students’ abilities in functional thinking and modelling languages; and (d) deductive reasoning predicts students’ abilities in all three categories. Differences between students across grades are also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10218-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning from English and Kuwaiti children’s transcoding errors: how might number names be temporarily adapted to assist learning of place value?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study identifies language specific errors made with transcoding tasks to inform possible future pedagogic decisions regarding the language used when teaching early number. We compared children aged 5–7 years from Kuwait and England. The spoken Arabic language of Kuwait gave the opportunity to compare not only languages where the tens and units digits are said in a different order, but also where the direction of writing is different. We asked 396 children from Kuwait and 256 children from England to write down 2-, and 3-digit numbers which were spoken to them. We found that the direction of the language did not affect the nature of errors made, but that other aspects of the two languages could account for some of the differences we found. As well as supporting previous studies regarding the significance of the order in which the tens and units are said, we found significance in the role the word &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; can play in marking the number of digits involved. We also noted that the way the numbers 20, 100 and 200 are said in Arabic can set up particular symbolic associations which could account for other differences we found. Having identified language-specific errors, we discuss possible pedagogic decisions to temporarily use more regular language for the number names in each of the languages and propose the order in which number names are taught might be different to their mathematical order of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10231-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Theorizing university mathematics teaching: the Teaching Triad within an Activity Theory perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we draw on our recent research to inspect again some of the theoretical perspectives we have been using to analyze data and to characterize teaching-learning in university settings. We focus particularly, within a sociocultural perspective on Activity Theory and the construct the “Teaching Triad,” seeking to embed the Triad within an Activity Theory perspective. To achieve this, we relate the Teaching Triad with aspects of the sociocultural setting both in and beyond direct interactions in face-to-face teaching. While this is mainly a theoretical paper, an example is taken from observations of teaching in university lectures in a Greek university to show how these theoretical perspectives have provided insights to the institutional and cultural complexities involved and in what ways the Triad construct has evolved.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10244-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effect of algebraic language and problem text wording on problem model accuracy when solving age word problems</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The use of the algebraic method for solving word problems is a challenging topic for secondary school students. Students’ difficulties are usually associated with extracting the problem’s network of relationships between quantities and with formalizing these relationships into algebraic language in a problem model. Both sources can coexist and interact; thus, it is usually not possible to determine which source of difficulty is more relevant. In addition, there are specific errors, such as the error by multiple referents for the unknown, which are directly linked to the wording of the problem text, and in which the same two sources of error coexist. In this work, we present the results of an experiment conducted with 255 secondary school students assessing the effect of two common difficulties on the accuracy of problem models and on the rate of multiple referents for the unknown. The first difficulty is the use of algebraic language in the construction of the problem model; the second is the use of the same expression to designate different quantities within the problem text. We used a 2 × 2 between-between design, with one factor related to the symbolic language (algebraic or arithmetic) in which the problem model is constructed, and the other factor related to the actual language features of the text problem. Our results indicate that overall, the main source of difficulty for students is the use of algebraic language to formalize a problem model, representing a large effect size.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10236-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collaboration between Mathematicians and Mathematics Educators: dialogical inquiry as a methodological tool in Mathematics Education research</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Collaboration between Mathematicians and Mathematics Educators is crucial in advancing knowledge on the teaching and learning of Mathematics, particularly in advanced Mathematics pedagogy. However, there is a need for the type of collaborations where Mathematicians and Mathematics Educators can find common ground, and the synergy of their expertise results in new, hybrid meanings and understandings that can benefit practice. This paper aims to help researchers from these communities come together by presenting a novel methodology for collaborative inquiry and qualitative data analysis—&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dialogical inquiry&lt;/em&gt;—based on Mikhail Bakhtin’s theory of dialogism. In this framework, “truth” is conceived as never finalised but always coevolving through dialogue that involves participants with different “voices” and “languages”. We describe the three principles that underpin &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dialogical inquiry&lt;/em&gt;: motivation, power balance and a process for solving disagreements. These three principles interact together to create a space where critically productive dialogue allows for meanings to coevolve and new, hybrid understandings to emerge. We illustrate our operationalisation of these principles (i.e., the methods of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;dialogical inquiry&lt;/em&gt;) in two areas: understanding solutions to linear ordinary differential equations and making meaning of the Bakhtinian concept of superaddressee. We reflect on our use of this methodology in Mathematics Education research and invite the readers to create their own dialogic spaces of collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10245-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: From planning to publishing: navigating the researcher’s journey. James Hiebert, Jinfa Cai, Stephen Hwang, Anne K Morris, Charles Hohensee (2023) Doing Research: A New Researcher’s Guide</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10248-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Combined use of the extended theory of connections and the onto-semiotic approach to analyze mathematical connections by relating the graphs of f and f’</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The literature reports that students have difficulties connecting different meanings, multiple representations of the derivative, and performing reversibility processes between representations of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt;. The research goal is to analyze the mathematical connections that university students establish when solving tasks that involve the graphs of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt; when the two functions do not have associated symbolic expressions. Seven students from the first year of undergraduate studies in mathematics from a university in southern Mexico participated. For data collection, two tasks involving the graphical context of the derivative were applied. An analysis of the mathematical activity was carried out by the participants with the analysis model proposed by the onto-semiotic approach, and thematic analysis with types of mathematical connections from the extended theory of connections was carried out to infer the connections made in that mathematical activity, which allowed us to consider the reversibility connection between the graphs of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt; as the encapsulation of a portion of the mathematical activity. Four students establish the reversibility relationship between the graph of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and the graph of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt;. It has been concluded that some students can establish the reversibility connection between the graphs of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt;, but the complexity of the mathematical activity that encapsulates the connection explains (by showing everything that the student must do) why some students are not able to establish it.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10246-9</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
