<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Content Analysis of Tasks Involving Two-Dimensional Cartesian Graphs in Grade 6–8 U. S. Textbooks</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-08-2023 12:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2241773?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The (In)Consistency of Teacher Survey Responses About Teacher Evaluation Implementation: Implications for Principal Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Principals can affect several consequential schooling processes and outcomes. However, their effectiveness varies substantially and is distributed across schools inequitably, underscoring the importance of effective principal professional development (PPD), which begins by using needs assessments to inform PPD content. A researcher-practitioner partnership assessed principal needs via monthly teacher surveys about specific teacher evaluation skills. While internal consistencies were high, test-rest reliabilities were low, implying that reports regarding the quality of specific principal practices may fluctuate substantially over short periods, potentially hampering the design of effective PPD.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2023 12:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231189273?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educator Attrition and Mobility During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Using 7 years of administrative data from North Carolina public schools (NCPS), we track changes in teacher and principal attrition and mobility during the COVID-19 pandemic and assess how attrition is related to characteristics of educators and schools. We find that educator attrition and mobility increased sharply between Fall 2020 and Fall 2022. Data from the pandemic period indicate that educators of color and more effective educators have experienced larger increases in attrition than their White and less effective peers. Gaps in teacher attrition have narrowed between schools educating many versus few historically marginalized students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2023 12:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231187890?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fostering, Tailoring, Negotiating: The Complexities of Collaborative Coaching in Schools Under Pressure to Improve</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Recent research has examined the influential role coaches may play in supporting teachers’ collective capacity building for instructional improvement. While emerging research is promising, much remains to be learned about collaborative approaches to coaching, particularly in schools with the greatest opportunity gaps. We draw on extensive longitudinal qualitative data to explore a collaborative approach to coaching in urban middle schools under pressure to improve math outcomes. Findings reveal key coaching strategies to promote teacher team capacity building, including fostering student-centered discussion and collaborative relationships, tailoring capacity-building opportunities to provide access for all teachers, and negotiating across teachers and leaders to support improvement efforts. This work was complicated by conflicting expectations between leaders and teachers as well as challenges with addressing teachers’ misconceptions about math content in group settings. These findings reflect the need for ongoing capacity building that supports coaches as they attend to group dynamics and accountability pressures.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2023 12:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231187372?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tale of the tape: psychometric investigation of two popular teacher self-efficacy scales</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2023 12:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2239714?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Randomized Controlled Trial Aversion among Public Sector Leadership: A Survey Experiment</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Background: While randomized controlled trials (RCTs) are typically considered the gold standard of program evaluation, they are infrequently chosen by public sector leaders, defined as government and nonprofit decision-makers, when an impact evaluation is required. Objectives: This study provides descriptive evidence on RCT aversion among public sector leaders and attempts to understand what factors affect their likelihood of choosing RCTs for impact evaluations. Research Design: The authors ask if public sector leaders follow similar preference patterns found among non-public sector leaders when choosing either an RCT or a quasi-experimental design and use a survey experiment to determine which factors affect the RCT choice. Subjects: The study sample includes 2050 public sector leaders and a comparison group of 2060 respondents who do not lead public sector organizations. Measures: The primary outcome measure is selecting an RCT as the preferred evaluation option. Results: When asked to make a decision about an impact evaluation, the majority of people do not choose an RCT. While also averse to RCTs, public sector leaders are about 13% more likely to prefer a RCT to a quasi-experimental evaluation compared to the general population. Public sector leaders are less likely to use RCTs for evaluations of more intense interventions, potentially because they are perceived to be superior to the options available for the control group. Conclusion: Funders should be aware that when given a choice, public sector leaders prefer other options to RCTs. Greater awareness of the benefits of RCTs could increase their use in the public sector.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2023 09:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231193483?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>DINA-BAG: A Bagging Algorithm for DINA Model Parameter Estimation in Small Samples</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Cognitive diagnosis models (CDMs) are the assessment tools that provide valuable formative feedback about skill mastery at both the individual and population level. Recent work has explored the performance of CDMs with small sample sizes but has focused solely on the estimates of individual profiles. The current research focuses on obtaining accurate estimates of skill mastery at the population level. We introduce a novel algorithm (bagging algorithm for deterministic inputs noisy “and” gate) that is inspired by ensemble learning methods in the machine learning literature and produces more stable and accurate estimates of the population skill mastery profile distribution for small sample sizes. Using both simulated data and real data from the Examination for the Certificate of Proficiency in English, we demonstrate that the proposed method outperforms other methods on several metrics in a wide variety of scenarios.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2023 07:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231188442?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using simulation-based learning to inform preservice teachers’ professional development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2023 07:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2240716?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Walking a Tightrope: Navigating Principal-Agent Dilemmas in Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although research alliances (RAs) have long been seen as mutualistic and reciprocal, RAs face numerous obstacles navigating stakeholders’ differing goals, incentives, and information. This longitudinal, comparative case study of two RAs uses principal-agent theory to analyze these interdependent challenges and their relationship to RA strategy and design. Findings suggest that while some RAs may be better designed to balance the competing interests of various stakeholders, increasingly contested definitions of RA effectiveness among those stakeholders have muddled RA identities. As a result, RA researchers are now often held to expectations that their organizations were not originally designed to meet. We argue that this has implications for how RAs are funded, designed, and, ultimately, evaluated.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231188366?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Constructive developmental interiority: Deliberately transformative action research</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper focuses on the process and theory of action-research for transformation (ART) targeting individual transformation as a required means for global change. Addressing the lack of a practical framework to organize and report transformation, we conceptualise, identify and demonstrate an approach by linking ART with Interiority and Constructive Development Theory. Interiority focuses on the individual’s sense-making as it relates to the sensed world and provides direction for data to be collected. Crucially, the individual’s capacity for sense-making impacts how data are identified, experienced, interpreted and evaluated. It is shifts in this capacity that constitute fundamental transformation required to better handle complexity and ambiguity - intrinsic to ART. We propose Constructive Developmental Interiority (CDI) that provides a lens to recognise, analyse and frame constructive developmental shifts. Two case studies are presented in which researchers engaged in applying CDI for transformation. Both cases highlight, through first-person action-research and reflexive collaboration, that although the will to address developmental transformational challenges was an espoused motivation, its misalignment with the capacities for transformative change is always a possibility. Applying CDI reveals the nature of the challenge (time, effort and support), how transitions were made, and the potential for transformational impact.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2023 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231191863?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“A little bit fun, a little bit frustrating:” utilizing photovoice to document university student responsibility during a global pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-06-2023 02:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2244536?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Interplay Between Fiscal Institutions and the Great Recession: Evidence From U.S. School Districts</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Recessions may disproportionally affect school districts, especially with established fiscal institutions and policies including balanced budget requirements, tax and expenditure limitations, and school finance reforms. Analyzing the Great Recession and school districts in the United States between 2003 and 2016, we estimated difference-in-differences models leveraging variation in state recession severity to evaluate revenue and expenditure impacts as well as to measure differential recession effects for districts exposed to and not exposed to fiscal institutions and policies. Although revenues and expenditures increased relative to pre-recession levels in all districts, increases were much larger in school districts with less severe than more severe recessions. Balanced budget requirements exacerbated recession effects for low-income districts, and local tax and expenditure limitations intensified recession effects for high-income districts. School finance reforms worsened recession effects for all districts. Our findings can aid districts in understanding potential recessionary impacts, given their prior established fiscal policies and institutions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-05-2023 06:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231189176?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Mathematics Teacher in the Digital Era: International Research on Professional Learning and Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-05-2023 02:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2243250?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of Co-Teaching and Related Collaborative Models of Instruction on Student Achievement: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Co-teaching and related collaborative models of instruction are widely used in primary and secondary schools in many school systems. This systematic review and meta-analysis investigated the effects of such models on students’ academic achievement and how these effects are moderated by factors of theoretical and practical relevance. Although previous research and reviews have asserted that the evidence base is scarce, we found 128 treatment and control group studies from 1984 to 2020. We excluded 52 studies due to critical risk of bias via Cochrane’s risk of bias assessment tools and conducted a meta-analysis of 76 studies. This yielded 280 short-term effect sizes, of which 82% were pretest-adjusted. We found a moderate, positive, and statistically significant mean effect of [math] = .11, 95% confidence interval [.035, .184] of collaborative instruction compared to single-taught controls, using the correlated-hierarchical effects (CHE-RVE) model. From moderator analyses, we found that collaborative instruction yields effects of mostly the same size, whether the interventions involved trained teachers or assistants with no teaching qualifications. This implies a potential for the expansion of such interventions at lower costs than otherwise expected. Moreover, factors that are highlighted in the co-teaching literature as preconditions for the effectiveness of collaborative instruction did not explain variations in effect sizes. Finally, we found no clear evidence for publication bias or small study effects. Notably, a large number of the studies that we drew upon were nonrandomized studies; and therefore, more rigorous experimental research is needed, especially on relevant co-teaching interventions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231186588?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Public Debt in the Spanish Municipalities: Drivers and Policy Proposals</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic has exacerbated the local debt in Spanish municipalities with negative consequences on the macroeconomic financial stability at national and eurozone level. The main objective is to identify the causes of public debt per capita in four groups of Spanish municipalities according to size. It is based on a quantitative analysis based on correlational and causal-comparative approaches. It consists in the construction of panel quantile regressions (MMQ) and mean group (ME) estimators to explain public debt per capita in Spanish municipalities. Moreover, the Juodis test for causality analysis in panel data is applied. The research is constructed around various types of potential determinants related to economic factors (GDP per capita and unemployment rate), demographic factors (population under 15 and population over 65), and political factors (political party, ideology, and political strength). The results based on MMQR for the period 2011–2020 indicate common factors that reduce local debt (short-run economic growth), but also differences between clusters in what concerns factors that increase or decrease the debt. The Juodis et al. (2021) test shows that growth and unemployment are factors that influence the level of public debt in all groups of municipalities except one (5001–20,000 inhabitants) where political party affects debt. These empirical findings support policy proposals to reduce the local debt in Spanish municipalities. The main initiatives to reduce debt should be based on the promotion of economic growth and creation of new jobs, especially for young people.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 09:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231193465?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The significance of children’s olfactory experiences in a Norwegian kindergarten: an olfactory researcher-practitioner collaboration</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 09:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2240391?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>MeToo Moments: Teacher Candidates’ Disclosures of Sexual Violence</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 07:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2242324?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engaging Preservice Teachers with Equity-Related Cases to Make Visible the Inequities in Mathematics Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 07:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2242312?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How well does teacher education prepare for teaching with technology? A TPACK-based investigation at a university of education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 01:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2243645?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching and learning of probability</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we develop a personal synthesis of the most outstanding research on the teaching and learning of probability in the past years. We conducted a systematic search to examine publications on this topic in mathematics education, statistics education, education, and psychology journals. This exploration was complemented by additional studies published in conference proceedings or books. We classified these papers to highlight the main recent research tendencies in the field, according to the theme studied and considering the research objectives. Epistemological analyses suggest that informal inference based on simulation diminishes the topic abstraction but reduces probability to its frequentist view. Topics receiving particular attention include children’s probabilistic knowledge, the effect of visualizations on solving conditional probability problems, teachers’ education and probability modelling. In the final section, we recommend relevant points in which more investigation is needed to complete our knowledge about teaching and learning. In particular, we miss research on teachers’ mathematical knowledge of many probability concepts and on their didactic knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01511-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Teach Your Classmates About the Behavior of Water with School-Level Science Models”: An Experience in Initial Preschool Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Prospective preschool teachers (PPTs) need to have learning experiences with the practice of scientific modelling to be able to design appropriate lessons as teachers. In the literature on research in science education, scarce experiences of PPTs in scientific modelling can be found. This study aims to fill the knowledge gap about PPTs’ representations of water and its states by means of models. To this end, an analysis is made of the models designed by PPTs and the difficulties they found in such a design process. The participants were 47 PPTs, working in groups of 2 or 3, forming 19 groups in total. The data source for analysis was the report written by each group. The oral presentation of these reports in class also served to clarify any doubts about the models elaborated by the PPTs. The models were analysed and categorized using qualitative content analysis methods, by combining inter- and intra-rater evaluation strategies. The results reveal that PPTs in general used a variety of resources to make models about the water molecule. Nonetheless, they found it harder to model the differences between the three aggregation states of water from a molecular perspective. The PPTs also acknowledged having had difficulties, such as when choosing and handling the materials they used to create the models or when thinking how to adapt them for the explanations to their peers. It is concluded with a discussion and implications of this study towards the PPTs’ training in scientific modelling and its didactics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-04-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00283-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The battle for curriculum: arrested semantics and reconciling racism with Critical Race Theory and Ethnic Studies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 12:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2239726?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Placing Equity Front and Center” for Teacher Education in a Time of Crisis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/74/4&quot;&gt;Volume 74, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 293-298, September/October 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 08:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231189792?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Segregating Gotham’s Youngest: Racial/Ethnic Sorting and the Choice Architecture of New York City’s Pre-K for All</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;New York City’s Pre-K for All (PKA) is the nation’s largest universal early childhood initiative, serving over 64,000 four-year-olds annually. Stemming from the program’s choice architecture as well as the city’s stark residential segregation, PKA programs are extremely segregated by child race/ethnicity. Our current study explores the complex forces that influence this segregation, including the interplay between family choices, seat availability, site-level enrollment priorities, and the PKA algorithm that weighs these and other considerations. We find that a majority of PKA segregation lies within local communities, and that areas with increased options and greater racial/ethnic diversity exhibit the most extreme segregation. We also conduct a simulation that leverages family PKA choices to maximize site-level racial/ethnic diversity and reduce between-site segregation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-03-2023 08:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231190071?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
