<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Anticipating the Side Effects of Educational Reform Using System Dynamics Modeling</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1-27, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;There have been countless efforts to improve academic achievement in public schools across the United States, especially in urban school districts. Few efforts, however, use rigorous analytic modeling tools to anticipate and prevent the potential side effects of change. This chapter proposes the application of system dynamics on educational reform efforts by offering a conceptual model, literature review, and research agenda to identify and mitigate the potential side effects of reform. The model is based on interviews and workshops with public school leaders, teachers, and parents in a midsized midwestern urban city. We identify a “capability trap” that may lead to policy resistance with educational reforms. Limitations to this approach are noted, and future areas of research are identified.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241260012?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interrogating Side Effects in Critical and Quantitative Research in Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 191-219, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Quantitative education research is often perceived to be “objective” or “neutral.” However, quantitative research has been and continues to be used to perpetuate inequities; these inequities arise as both intended effects and unintended side effects of traditional quantitative research. In this review of the literature, we synthesize how quantitative researchers have attempted to use critical paradigms to address questions of equity in education research published over the past 15 years. We identify and describe three main tensions that critical and quantitative researchers navigated: (a) creating and analyzing social group categories, (b) trying to describe commonalities within group experiences without erasing heterogeneity of experience within the group, and (c) determining what is a “significant” result when conducting critical and quantitative research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241255093?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Side Effects of Universal School-Based Mental Health Supports: An Integrative Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 28-57, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;A challenge with universal school-based mental health supports is the limited understanding of potential unintended or unanticipated outcomes. In this review, we examined 47 academic and gray literature sources to address the question, “What are the side effects of universal school-based mental health supports?” We discuss how universal supports can positively impact student mental health, enhance school staff’s knowledge and attitudes in addressing mental health topics, and contribute to an improved school climate. However, universal supports can also lead to school staff feeling the strain of resource and time pressures from integrating mental health programming into demanding schedules, voicing frustrations about or exhibiting resistance to mental health supports, and encountering varied, unpredictable outcomes for different student populations across system contexts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241256628?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Governance Through Performance-Based Accountability: A Comparative Analysis of Its Side Effects Across Different Regulatory Regimes</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 248-286, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Performance-based accountability (PBA) has gained popularity worldwide due to its promise to strengthen the effectiveness and equity of educational systems. Nonetheless, its implementation does not always generate the expected reactions within schools. Through a configurative review, we systematically reviewed 133 empirical studies focusing on PBA side effects. We provide novel insights into the literature on PBA side effects, generating a better understanding of how and under what circumstances they are more likely to occur and through which mechanisms. In contrast to existing reviews, our research includes country contexts where accountability designs are predominantly low-stakes and challenges dichotomous ways of thinking about PBA systems. It uncovers side effects across diverse accountability frameworks and investigates differences and similarities in the mechanisms driving them.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241270672?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advancing Equity and Access: Addressing the Side Effects of Broadening Participation in Computer Science K–12 Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 121-153, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Over the past 20 years, there has been a concentrated effort on expanding K–12 pathways, experiences, and access in computer science education (CSEd). Computer science (CS) is a multifaceted discipline within education, and the current emphasis in education policy has focused on how to expand access for K–12 students in CSEd that will lead to increased innovation and bring new participants into the United States labor economy. Industry partners have advocated for policies and incentives to increase pathways to CS opportunities. This chapter interrogates the side effects of CSEd and offers a framework for considering how side effects impact CS teaching and learning. We highlight the barriers that exist within CS and CSEd and how broadening participation in computing efforts could address longstanding equity and disparity issues.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241286475?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects and Side Effects: What Is Missing in Education Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page vii-xxviii, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241282571?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Side Effects of School Turnaround? A Systematic Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-88, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this systematic review, we examine research from 2009 to 2022 to identify and classify the unintended effects of turnaround in the United States. We develop a conceptual framework classifying three types of side effects—spillover effects, systemic side effects, and internal side effects—and differentiate these side effects from unintended negative intervention effects. We identify four broad categories of side effects within this framework based on the population they impact: communities, school systems, educators, and students. We find that the most prevalent side effects are related to educator experiences, staffing, community reaction, education governance, and the proliferation of external actors. We conclude by calling for future research to explicitly examine common side effects alongside the intended effects of turnaround.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241248151?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Review of Posthumanist Education Research: Expanded Conceptions of Research Possibility and Responsibility</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 220-247, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The influence of posthumanist philosophies—broadly defined to include theories such as Baradian new materialism, Deleuzian assemblage theory, Wynterian counterhumanism, Afro-futurism studies, Indigenous studies theories of nonhuman agency, and others—on education research has been increasing at an exponential rate. This chapter provides a review of this literature organized around the theme of ethical and political responsibility. It compares four genres of posthumanist inquiry: assemblage studies, cartographic studies, diffractive studies, and place-based research. It locates these genres on a continuum from descriptive to enactive forms of inquiry. The review concludes with an examination of three different conceptions of futurity that inform posthumanist reconceptualizations of research responsibility, suggesting research is most powerful when all three are attended to in research designs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241265332?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessment of Adverse Events, Side Effects, and Social Validity in Evidence-Based Behavioral Interventions for Autistic Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 154-190, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Research has demonstrated positive impacts of behavioral interventions on various educational outcomes for autistic youth, and implementation of these interventions in education settings has been widely advocated. However, recent studies have identified methodological shortcomings in the behavioral intervention evidence base, including lack of reporting on side effects and social validity. This review including 98 studies identified as evidence-based practices by the National Clearinghouse on Autism Evidence and Practice further highlights the lack of evaluation of side effects and social validity in behavioral intervention research. Suggestions are given regarding assessment of side effects, embedding social validity into intervention, and practical takeaways for educators. Future research and practice should prioritize addressing potential side effects and advancing ethical implementation of evidence-based behavioral interventions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241281268?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Double-Edged Sword of Role Models: A Systematic Narrative Review of the Unintended Effects of Role Model Interventions on Support for the Status Quo</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Research in Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rrea/48/1&quot;&gt;Volume 48, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 89-120, March 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Role model interventions are often designed to foster students’ pursuit of careers in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM). We hypothesize that role model interventions might also unintentionally shape students’ beliefs concerning the broader social system—their ideologies—leading them to view the (inequitable) status quo in STEM as natural and acceptable. A systematic narrative review (35 articles, 42 studies) indicated that the ideological effects of role model interventions were rarely considered in the literature. Although limited, the few relevant findings revealed both desirable and undesirable side effects of role model interventions on students’ ideologies. This review demonstrates that role models can be a double-edged sword and serves as a call to evaluate role model interventions on criteria beyond motivation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0091732X241261310?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveling Up: An Academic Acceleration Policy to Increase Equity in Advanced High School Course Taking</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Taking advanced courses in high school predicts many positive outcomes, yet low-income students and students who identify as Black and Hispanic are underrepresented. Policies such as “algebra for all” that accelerate middle school students into advanced courses are well-studied, but little is known about newer academic acceleration policies that target older students. Between 2014–2015 and 2016–2017, 72 districts in Washington implemented Academic Acceleration policies, which identified proficient 11th- and 12th-grade students for automatic acceleration into AP, IB, and other dual credit courses. We used difference-in-differences models to examine changes in advanced course enrollments, GPAs, and high school graduation between districts that began implementing the policy at different times. We found advanced course enrollment increased and became more equitable postpolicy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2024 03:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241282793?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Appreciation</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/75/5&quot;&gt;Volume 75, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 543-544, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2024 11:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241290916?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading Teacher Education: Navigating the Tension Between Past and the Future</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/75/5&quot;&gt;Volume 75, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 473-475, November 2024. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2024 11:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241284086?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Draw Yourself Doing Mathematics: Creating a Prompt and Rubric to Probe Student Mental Images of Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-25-2024 12:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2417596?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A National Analysis of P–12 Equity Director Role Establishment</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;District “equity director” (ED) roles have grown rapidly over the past decade. Drawing on interviews and surveys with over 70 EDs across nearly 30 states, this study documents dramatic ED role growth from 2018 to 2022 specifically and examines why, according to EDs, such roles were established locally. Findings, drawing on scholarship on social activism, demonstrate how insider influence from district educators and leaders; intermediate pressure from community coalitions, parents, and students; and external coercion from state and federal education departments and civil rights agencies spurred ED role establishment. Challenges to ED efficacy are discussed, including ED role establishment as “checkbox” work and politicized attacks on district diversity, equity, and inclusion work.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-25-2024 09:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241269131?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Blackademics as prophetic witnesses and the continuing struggle for racial justice in higher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-25-2024 05:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2419137?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparative Educational Pluralism: A Framework for Comparative Policy Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-24-2024 06:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2407244?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Principals’ Instructional Leadership and Support Needs in Prekindergarten and Kindergarten: A Case Study in Texas</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In states that fund public prekindergarten and kindergarten in elementary schools, principals are central to ensuring these programs support children’s learning and development. Yet few studies explore how principals position these programs within their instructional leadership and what they perceive should be done by district leaders to support their efforts to lead these programs. This case study investigated these issues with a sample of elementary school principals (N = 14) working in Texas. Using a modified conceptual lens that categorizes four essential dimensions of instructional leadership for prekindergarten and kindergarten, we found that principals possessed insight into many of these leadership practices but often did not enact these visions due to the academic performance pressures of the upper grades. Furthermore, principals wanted additional support from their district and state administrators to lead their prekindergarten and kindergarten programs better. Such findings illuminate several opportunities to strengthen principals’ instructional leadership of prekindergarten and kindergarten.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-24-2024 05:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241288834?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Livonia is just all racism”: locating black families’ racial and spatial experiences, school choices, and educational agency in metropolitan Detroit</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2024 06:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2419131?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice Teachers’ Reflecting on Reflections of Critical Incidents: Effects on Professional Development and Identity Construction</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This interpretive phenomenological study reports the effects of reflecting on reflections concerning Critical Incidents (CIs) on the pre-service teachers’ (PSTs) professional development and conceptualization of their identity as TESOL (Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages) teachers. The study involved nine PSTs who were specializing in TESOL and doing their teaching practicum. The main instrument of the study was reflective writing, which required the PSTs to report CIs, write reflections, and share these for receiving peers’ reflections to further reflect on self-reflection and reflection of peers. The process enabled the participants to pursue professional development and conceive identity as TESOL teachers. This seemingly engaging, thought-provoking and meaningful reflective practice can be additive to the existing reflective practices, which have been questioned and debated in the literature. In pursuit of professional development and teacher identity, PSTs can be assigned to reflect on reflections with diverse elements of focus alongside CIs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2024 05:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241286088?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developed in conversation: a duoethnographic evaluation of a participatory action research project</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2024 05:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2418488?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing the Role of Attitudes on the Enactment of Academic and Non-Academic Education Performance Indicators</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Chile has followed the international trend of implementing a standards-based reform, with the particularity of encompassing both academic and non-academic outcomes. Drawing on interview data from four school cases in Santiago, Chile, this study examines the role of attitudes in reform enactment, analyzing whether and how school actors’ attitudes toward academic and non-academic performance indicators influence practice change. Alignment between attitudes toward academic standards and practice change is often disrupted by subjective norms, whereas attitudes toward non-academic indicators consistently drive behavior. This research sheds light on the complex interplay between attitudes and policy enactment, offering valuable insights.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2024 04:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241288505?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Career Academies Work as a School Turnaround Strategy?</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Under the Every Student Succeeds Act, college and career readiness became the central focus of education policy in the United States. Career academies (CAs) are a popular way to support students in their postsecondary transitions, but little causal evidence exists about whether this model of schooling is effective in promoting learning and transition outcomes. We capitalize on the adoption of the CA model in a large school district that was under the threat of school turnaround and employ a generalized difference-in-differences approach to test whether adopting this model improved student outcomes. We find suggestive evidence that CA adoption improved graduation rates and that these effects were most likely concentrated among schools that had the lowest graduation rates at baseline.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2024 04:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241289152?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical reasoning in elementary grade classrooms in India: what is there and what is missing?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The paper presents an analysis of elementary grade mathematics teaching in India focusing on mathematical reasoning. Mathematical reasoning is an important tool to make sense of mathematical ideas, which in turn makes mathematics more accessible to learners and promotes social equality. The paper analyzes 112 lessons from Grades 1 to 8 by 21 teachers in 5 schools in a big city in India. Synthesizing the literature, the paper identifies three main functions of mathematical reasoning (reasoning for sense-making, reasoning for inquiry, reasoning for justification) and concomitant reasoning actions. Working from these three functions of reasoning, a scheme that was suitable for categorizing the reasoning observed in the highly teacher-led instruction was developed and applied to identify the nature and prevalence of reasoning across grade levels and topics. No “reasoning for inquiry” was found in the analyzed lessons. Explanatory Reasoning, a limited form of “reasoning for sense-making” with little student input, was observed, usually in extremely short episodes, in about a quarter of lessons. Modelled Reasoning, a limited form of “reasoning for justification” where step-by-step deductive problem solutions were demonstrated, was more common, dominating lessons in some topics, especially in higher grades. In most lessons, the teacher stated rules and procedures without reason; sometimes providing non-mathematical justifications for procedures in lower grades (e.g., the need to follow arrows or use a mnemonic). The observed rarity of Explanatory Reasoning highlights an urgent need for teacher education programs in India to enhance the sense-making mathematical experiences offered to teachers so that they can, in turn, promote sense-making in their students.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10362-0</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
