<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bridging culture and science: Culturo-Techno-Contextual Approach in culturally relevant biology pedagogy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-20-2025 06:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2446898?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Classroom data science: data and dataing for making sense of multivariate plant growth</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;What is considered data and how it is communicated publicly is rapidly changing. Participation in society involves multiple opportunities to engage with complex statistical concepts in media, in personal health, and regarding climate change. Children also are engaging with evolving data types in social media interactions and in educational contexts where they &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; the data. Yet little time is spent in classrooms supporting children to explore and make their own data decisions about various data types. This study investigates the role that fourth graders’ use of graphing conventions played in supporting their conceptual development of: non-traditional data and data&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;ing&lt;/em&gt; during one lesson. The author hopes to contribute a new perspective in conceptualising data&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;ing&lt;/em&gt; as enculturating statistical practices around data that involves multiple features, to communicate key information, involving tools for engaging with statistics to communicate a story. In this case study, a video clip presented an entrance point in exploring multivariate data (multiple variables). Video observation and student graphs revealed insights into children’s data and data&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;ing&lt;/em&gt; experiences and processes involved with multivariate data, supported by a classroom culture that valued statistical processes as a creative and meaningful, story-telling endeavour. When students were tasked with representing plant growth using a graph, displays included a wide range of variables such as patterns of leaf growth and qualitative stages of plant growth. Engaging with multivariate data in exploratory ways supported students in this study to play with graphing conventions, establishing local mathematical practices involving non-traditional data.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01655-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Structured mathematical modelling in an authentic scientific-engineering context</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study suggests the framing of structured mathematical modelling (MM) in an authentic scientific-engineering context. Taking a task design view, structure is maintained through inherent scaffolding for the dual purpose of preserving the authenticity of the extra-mathematical context and making the adaptations required to allow incorporation of the task into the duration of a regular lesson and within the full capacity of the curriculum. Participants were 23 secondary school novice mathematics teachers and two experts who possess extensive experience in MM task design. Research tools included a reflective diary filled in by the novice teachers throughout the design process, and a task design evaluation form that was filled in by the two expert designers. Both tools aimed at identifying MM task characteristics and the alignment of the designed structured MM tasks with the MM cycle phases. Findings show the presence of all the unique characteristics that underly a quality designed MM task, with relatively low presence of openness and high presence of accessibility and authenticity from the novice teachers’ point of view. The alignment with the MM cycle was further manifest in the designed tasks, with the validation phase as being less evident compared to the other MM phases. Theoretical and practical contributions are discussed in the paper, indicating the sequentially-oriented process by which the structured MM tasks scaffold students through the MM cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01654-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Quasi-Poisson Item Response Theory Model for Heterogeneous Dispersion in Count Data</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Item-level count data frequently arise in cognitive, educational, and psychological assessments. Correctly handling different dispersion levels in count data is crucial for accurate statistical inference. This research proposes a Quasi-Poisson item response theory model that accommodates overdispersion, underdispersion, and equidispersion in count data, aiming to explicitly model the connection between the mean and variance parameters, providing a method that is both computationally efficient and statistically robust. This semiparametric model specifies the first two conditional moments for the count variables and derives marginal moments to estimate model parameters. Simulation studies demonstrate the Quasi-Poisson model’s efficacy in parameter recovery across different dispersion scenarios and its negligible computation time. Empirical data analysis further underscores the model’s superior fit and computational efficiency in a real-world setting.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2025 07:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241305786?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racial, Linguistic, and Economic Diversity Across Schools with Two-Way Dual Language Immersion Programs: Evidence from the Los Angeles Unified School District</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Two-way dual-language immersion (TWDL) programs aim to combine English speakers and speakers of a partner language in the same classroom to receive content instruction in both languages. Stated goals include bilingualism and biliteracy, high academic achievement, and sociocultural competence. In school districts aiming to reduce segregation, TWDL programs also can integrate students from diverse linguistic, racial, and economic backgrounds, although mounting evidence shows that equitable integration does not always happen. Using school-level enrollments and district data on TWDL program growth from 2000 to 2021, this paper describes enrollment and segregation patterns across the Los Angeles Unified School District elementary schools with TWDL programs. We find that elementary schools with TWDL programs are enrolling increasing numbers of racially, linguistically, and economically marginalized students and are generally more diverse than schools without TWDL programs, although there appear to be limits on the potential of TWDL programs to foster diversity, especially in a segregated urban context.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2025 06:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241310428?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reconstructing professional identity through collaboration in pluralistic approaches</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2025 02:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2025.2454638?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Black Children’s Refusal in a “Hege-Mindful” World</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;This case study examines the connections between mindfulness activities and related benefits, including wellness, as 13 Black fifth graders embarked on an 8-week mindfulness program in their public-school classroom. The children responded well to the program and exhibited some wellness outcomes associated with mindfulness. However, hegemonic school and classroom practices emphasizing adult control and minimal child agency prevented the children from practicing new mindfulness skills or sustaining feelings of wellness, mattering, and harmony throughout the school day. We found that classroom mindfulness efforts, when not supported by all classroom teachers and administrators, necessarily limit Black children’s ability to develop a sense of self-awareness and self-efficacy and can in fact reinforce feelings of self-blame. Our findings suggest that mindfulness programs can have a positive impact for Black children when paired with antiracist practices, allowing space for the children to practice refusal and prioritize their right to matter.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2025 06:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241311237?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pre-service mathematics teachers’ experiences and insights into the benefits and challenges of using explanatory videos in flipped modelling education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Explanatory videos play an important role in the flipped classroom (FC) approach, which has become highly important especially since the COVID-19 crisis. In this qualitative study, we explore the potential of using explanatory videos (EVs) in mathematical modelling education as important component of FC and assess its merits and deficiencies. We focus on the perspectives and experiences of 44 preservice mathematics teachers (PSTs) attending a German university in their master phase. Considering EVs in an interactive FC context, we employed a multifaceted approach to data collection that included interviews, online surveys with open-ended questions, EVs generated by the PSTs, and written documents resulting from collaborative group activities. The findings show that the EVs used in FCs in modelling can enhance understanding and simplifying modelling content and real-world situations. Moreover, PSTs report that using EVs in flipped modelling seminars can offer personalized learning, optimize teaching hours, decrease anxiety, and increase learners’ attention. PSTs also improved their skills in developing EVs on modelling and evaluating their quality in terms of structure, content, and focus. The experienced challenges include time-consuming content development, workload, technical hurdles, and feasibility of FC implementations. Although these challenges are important, they are not content-specific issues, and we conclude that the notable benefits of using EVs in FCs have the potential to promote technology-enhanced modelling education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01650-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identifying and describing generic, specific, and catalytic enablers of mathematical modelling</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this article, we report on an Australian study in which generic, specific, and catalytic enablers of mathematical modelling are identified and described. The study adopted a design-based research approach involving six secondary teachers, and their intact classes, over three years. Data was generated from 60 pre/post-teacher and student (Years 9–11) interviews, which was subject to reductive thematic analysis, consistent with the principles of inductive category formation&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; This analysis led to the development of a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Typology for Instructional Enablers of Mathematical Modelling&lt;/em&gt; which identifies and describes both enablers and un-enablers of modelling activity. These are related to external/internal/personal learning goals, classroom expectations and ways of working, management of the learning process, and instructional anticipation. Enablers/un-enablers are further categorised into generic, specific, and catalytic dimensions. Implications for both practice and future research are discussed, including the nature of catalytic enablers and the connections between enablers and specific aspects of the modelling process.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01653-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collaborating with mathematicians to use active learning in university mathematics courses: the importance of attending to mathematicians’ obligations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we discuss our experience in collaborating with mathematicians to increase their use of active learning pedagogy in a proof-based linear algebra course. The mathematicians we worked with valued using active learning pedagogy to increase student engagement but were reluctant to use active learning pedagogy due to time constraints. Our mathematicians perceived obligations in their teaching that increased the time it would take to implement some of the active learning pedagogy that we suggested, leading them to view this pedagogy as inviable. By attending to mathematicians’ obligations, we were able to design active learning strategies that met the interests and needs of the mathematics educators and mathematicians collaborating on this project.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10381-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Longitudinal Analysis of a Mathematics Education Publication</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This research examines a 58-year, 202 sequential issues, longitudinal published record of the Ontario Mathematics Gazette. The publication is oriented to K–12 teachers of mathematics in Ontario. A total of 3609 units of analysis were identified that led to 447 unique index categories. A chi-squared goodness of fit test found, within the limits of the test, that these categories arise continuously, independently, and at a steady rate. The frequency of occurrence in both absolute and relative terms showed a few trends, such as the shift of curriculum development away from teachers and toward research findings. A key finding was the absence of significant biases or short-term trends within the publication’s history. This speaks to the association being an independent voice, but the breadth of topics indicates it is an important support for teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00344-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Overlooked Explanation for Increasing Suicidality: LGBQ Stressors Felt by More Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Recent data show rising suicidality among high school girls. We posit this increase may be related to an overlooked factor: more girls identifying as LGBQ. Using four cohorts of national Youth Risk Behavior Survey data (N = 22,562 females, N = 22,130 males), we found that LGBQ identification among females rose from 15% in 2015 to 34% in 2021. LGBQ females consistently reported higher suicidality, although rates remained stable within both LGBQ and heterosexual groups. The rise in females’ suicidality may stem from social pressures faced by LGBQ youth. Male suicidality and LGBQ identification showed smaller changes. More support for LGBQ students is essential to address this trend.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2025 08:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241305329?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Middle School Math: Cool Problems to Get Students Thinking and Connecting</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This book is designed to enhance students’ learning experience in mathematics. It provides valuable resources for developing engaging mathematics learning in junior high school, focusing on students’ conceptual understanding and connections between concepts. The book’s approach, which includes various contextual problems and strategies such as Know, Want to know, Conditions (KWC); representation; analytical thinking; and reading integration, is discussed in this summary. The seven main chapters are highlighted, along with their concepts, example problems, and the implications of various approaches. Educators can feel reassured that their efforts will be rewarding in developing meaningful mathematics learning for their students.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00339-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 11:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2025.2453306?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educators’ interventions in gendered harassment: the importance of school culture</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 10:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2024.2442935?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hands-on Consensus Building: Leveraging Deep Learning Models to Unveil Hand Gestures in Consensus-Building Discourses</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2448797?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promoting mathematical competence development through programming activities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The reasons for teaching programming in school are indeed manifold. Programming can for example be utilized as a vehicle for understanding and learning particular mathematical subject matter, or as a tool for solving mathematical problems. In this paper, however, we propose to utilize programming as a vehicle for developing mathematical competencies such as problem-solving, exploration, modeling, reasoning, representation, generalization, and abstraction. We perform a design study utilizing a systematic, iterative development process for designing teaching sessions, focusing on one mathematical competence at a time. We apply the proposed methodology on a set of teaching sessions that are developed, implemented, and tested in a range of classroom settings. Based on this development process, we conclude that programming can be used to develop mathematical competencies. Furthermore, we identify a set of teacher practices that can be used to facilitate mathematical competence development in programming activities.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10380-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Works for Whom: Exploring the Students, Settings, and Outcomes in What Works Clearinghouse Study Data</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-14-2025 04:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2427762?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Empirical Benchmarks for Effect Size Interpretation and Study Planning with Social and Behavioral Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-14-2025 04:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2427767?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Addressing teacher shortages in an international context: implications for the quality and status of teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 12:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2025.2447968?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rera/95/1&quot;&gt;Volume 95, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 154-170, February 2025. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 10:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241308357?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supervising, Coaching, and Preparing Dual Language Bilingual Education Teachers: A Collaborative Autoethnography</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Feedback and preservice teachers’ (PSTs’) clinical practice/field experiences are vital for their learning. Understanding influences on field supervisors’ feedback is critical, especially for preparing dual language bilingual education (DLBE) teachers because it requires specialized knowledge—yet systematic guidelines and programs for DLBE teacher preparation are lacking. We conducted a collaborative autoethnography to determine how our identities and experiences with language and DLBE related to our feedback and supervision of DLBE PSTs. We analyzed and discussed the narratives we wrote about our experiences and the feedback we provided while supervising 13 Spanish–English bilingual PSTs in elementary DLBE classrooms. Our identities and experiences, which were influenced by families, education, language histories, geography, and sociopolitical contexts, influenced our feedback. Considering identities and experiences illuminates what is (sometimes unconsciously) prioritized and ignored in feedback. Engaging in deep reflection is important for continued support of supervisors and PSTs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 10:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241312351?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Democracy on the Sidelines: The Erosion and Potential of Youth Sports as Democratic Education</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;In this philosophical paper, we argue that youth sports, both in and out of schools, are a largely unrealized space for democratic/civic education. Where youth sports leagues used to be low cost, local, and inclusive, much has changed over the last several decades. We are now in the neoliberal era of exclusive, privatized, and professionalized youth sports. Drawing on Dewey’s robust conception of democracy and Talisse’s concerns about partisan polarization, we argue that youth sports should be spaces to develop democratic habits, dispositions, and values. We explore the benefits of youth sports as well as current challenges, including excessive costs and pressure, disrupted families, and hyperindividualism. We end by offering suggestions for reforming youth sports to recenter their educational and democratic potential and value, including supporting loosely structured play, modeling democratic behavior, teaching democratic habits directly, and learning from more progressive national sports models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 09:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241311810?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inscribing proportional relationships using partitioning, co-occurrence, and same extent</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2025 08:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2025.2450408?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
