<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacherly response-ability: ethical relationality as protest against mathematical violence</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;What do ethical relations look like in the context of the many injustices that pervade mathematics education? In this paper, I argue, first, that violence is the relation that characterizes much of contemporary mathematics education and, second, that understanding ethical relations requires considering mathematics as an equal actor in creating possible relations rather than simply treating it as a context for human relations. I examine how literature in care theory, emancipatory pedagogies, and mathematics education have framed ethical relationality and suggest that the feminist new materialist conceptualization of response-ability offers several contributions for rethinking agency, justice, and praxis for mathematics teachers concerned with addressing mathematical violence.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-08-2023 22:10</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10230-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preschool children’s conceptions of the meanings and use of written numerals in everyday life: a phenomenographic study of the nature and structure of qualitative variation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Supporting children’s understanding of the everyday, cultural use of written numerals is highly significant, as it is this understanding that gives meaning to classroom conversations on the purposes of written numbers. This paper presents findings from a phenomenographic study of the qualitatively different ways in which 3–5-year-old children interpret the meanings and use of numerals in everyday contexts. The study involved a volunteer sample of 37 preschool children. With their family’s support, children played a Number Spotting game, taking photographs of numerals in their environments. These photographs were supplemented with other photographs selected by the researchers and used in individual photo-elicitation interviews with children. We collected data on children’s interpretations of a range of examples of numerals used to denote quantity, order and measurement, and numerals used as labels/identifiers. The findings document qualitatively different categories that capture the range of children’s expressed conceptions as well as the critical aspects of variation that underpin &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; qualitatively different categories of conceptions differ or relate to each other. The study provides original insights into the nature and structure of children’s awareness of the cultural uses of written numerals. The findings can support early mathematics teaching to make meaningful connections between the knowledge that children develop outside of school and the new knowledge about written numbers that they develop in formal education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-08-2023 22:10</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10232-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>High School Enrolment Choices—Understanding the STEM Gender Gap</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students’ high school decisions will always impact efforts to achieve gender parity in Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM) at the university level and beyond. Without a comprehensive understanding of gendered disparities in high school course selection, it will be impossible to close completely the gender gap in many STEM disciplines. This study examines 11 years of detailed administrative data to determine gendered enrolment trends in university-stream secondary school STEM courses. Male and female enrolments for all publicly funded secondary schools across the province of Ontario (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 844) were tracked from the 2007/2008 academic year to 2017/2018. The data reveal a clear trend of growing enrolment in STEM disciplines, with the increase in female students continuing their STEM education significantly outpacing males in almost all courses. However, these results also demonstrate the significant disparities that persist across STEM disciplines. The existing gender gap in physics remains large—in 2018, the median grade 12 Physics class was only &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(36.5\pm 0.05\%\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; female—with virtually no progress having been made to close this gap. By tracking individual student cohorts, we also demonstrate a newly discovered result showing the continuation rate of male students in biology stream courses has experienced a precipitous drop-off. The proportion of male students continuing from grade 10 Science to grade 12 Biology 2 years later has seen an average yearly decline of &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(-0.44\pm 0.08\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; percentage points, potentially foreshadowing the emergence of another significant gender gap in STEM. We suggest that researchers and educators cease treating STEM as a monolith when addressing gender disparities, as doing so obscures significant differences between disciplines. Future efforts, particularly those aimed to support women in STEM, must instead adopt a more targeted approach to ensure that they solve existing problems without creating new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-08-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00285-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Factors That Influence the Intention of Smallholder Rice Farmers to Adopt Cleaner Production Practices: An Empirical Study of Precision Agriculture Adoption</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Sustainable agriculture is crucial for achieving SDG2 and building a resilient climate-food system. This study provides a nuanced understanding of factors that influence the adoption of precision agriculture technology by Vietnamese smallholder rice farmers as a sustainable agricultural solution. The study’s objectives are: (1) to provide a nuanced understanding of factors that influence adoption of precision agriculture technology by Vietnamese smallholder rice farmers; and (2) to identify factors associated with agricultural practice in Vietnam that may impact the adoption of precision agriculture technology. The study conducted 35 semi-structured interviews with smallholder rice farmers and agriculture experts. Data were analyzed using iterative thematic analysis. The Unified Theory of Acceptance and Use of Technology (UTAUT) model was used for empirical analysis. The UTAUT constructs of Performance expectancy, Effort expectancy, Government support, and Social influence were found to be determinants of adoption. Trialability and Observability impact Effort expectancy and Performance expectancy. We also discovered that the performance of agricultural cooperatives and support of lead firms play a crucial role in facilitating agricultural technology adoption by Vietnamese smallholder rice farmers. The results confirm the applicability of UTAUT in defining smallholders’ behavioural intention and predicting agricultural technology adoption. The study also provides constructive feedback on the UTAUT model by highlighting the effect of agricultural cooperatives’ performance as innovation intermediaries and of the support of lead firms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-07-2023 11:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231200775?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Child Education Rights Versus Parental Preferences: A Paradox Between United Nations Conventions and Alternative Schooling Methods</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Alternative schooling has been staunchly advocated for by groups disillusioned by government-sponsored public schooling that want to take personal control of their children’s education. There are concerns, however, about nontraditional schooling options that do not meet standards that apply to public schools. The United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child (CRC) specifies children’s fundamental educational rights. In the United States, this includes mastering basic English literacy and numerical abilities, as well as exposure to some scientific and historical knowledge needed to negotiate mainstream society. This paper focuses on how certain homeschooling and religious schooling practices run the risk of denying adolescents the right to the education necessary to work in the modern economy and achieve their potential. We argue that the United States should allow alternative schooling options but ensure that they conform to specific standards set by the state in order to meet the CRC goals.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-07-2023 09:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231198821?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Generic dimensions of teaching quality: the german framework of three Basic Dimensions</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01514-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The connections between citizenship education and mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The connections between citizenship education and mathematics education have been the focus of theoretical development and attention by educators interested in issues of justice, equity, power, criticality, and citizen engagement with societal issues, across schools, universities, and adult education levels. In this survey article, we contribute to new knowledge in the field by identifying and describing three interconnected &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;layers of influence&lt;/em&gt; on the praxis of teaching and learning: (1) perspectives from citizenship education and mathematics education (e.g., kinds of citizenship, critical thinking in mathematics education); (2) institutional factors (e.g., policy, curricula, implementation within education systems); and (3) emerging influences (e.g., changing skill demands, innovations from communities of practice). In exploring the connections between citizenship education and mathematics education, we go beyond extant theory development and point to influences such as global disruptions, societal changes, systemic structures at the national and local levels, messaging in the media, and the role of teachers and learners. The holistic analysis of these influences enables identification of tensions and dilemmas, and issues of identity, autonomy, adoption, and systemic change. Together these point to multiple implications for educators, policy makers, and researchers aiming to enable informed and engaged citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01521-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“You can’t just check the box”: the mathematics of ethnoracial contortions at a California high school</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article brings critical and postcolonial theories together with extended ethnographic research in a predominantly Latinx high school in California’s “South Bay” to theorize the co-production and co-naturalization of mathematical and racial essentialization. Analysis of vignettes and interview excerpts illuminates both student uptake and resistance to homogenizing narratives of mathematics and racial personhood. Student voices from Sierra High School both evidenced the existence, stakes, and personal consequences of narrowly bounded, taken for granted, conceptions of mathematics and racial personhood and challenged these homogenizing categories. This paper contributes theory illuminating the co-construction of mathematical and racial essentialization along with examples of local critique and resistance from youth and their adult allies at one high school in the USA. Implications suggest that decolonial work in mathematics education must jointly address the narrow and essentializing frames for race and racialization and for mathematics itself as co-producing and co-naturalizing each other. This study contributes insight into mechanisms that perpetuate and also resist or disrupt these processes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10258-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Statistics education research at the school level in Australia and New Zealand: A 30-year journey</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The introduction of statistical concepts into school curricula in Australia and New Zealand in the early 1990s initiated an ongoing research program into the learning and teaching of statistics and probability in both countries. This paper reviews the contribution of Australian and New Zealand researchers to building statistical literacy at school, alongside international developments. From recognising how students develop understanding of specific statistical and probabilistic concepts, through teacher knowledge and beliefs for teaching statistics, to intervention studies and targeted teaching, the field of statistics education has grown and changed. Statistics and probability are now well established as part of the mathematics curriculum. The importance of linking statistical literacy and statistical understanding across the curriculum, as well as in STEM, has also begun to receive attention as other subjects have recognised the importance of data in their fields. Following a comprehensive review of the field in Australia and New Zealand, this paper then considers emerging areas of interest, such as new approaches to data visualisation, and suggests future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00470-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Texting and tutoring: Short-term K-3 reading interventions during the pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 11:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2251432?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identifying Informative Predictor Variables With Random Forests</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Random forests are a nonparametric machine learning method, which is currently gaining popularity in the behavioral sciences. Despite random forests’ potential advantages over more conventional statistical methods, a remaining question is how reliably informative predictor variables can be identified by means of random forests. The present study aims at giving a comprehensible introduction to the topic of variable selection with random forests and providing an overview of the currently proposed selection methods. Using simulation studies, the variable selection methods are examined regarding their statistical properties, and comparisons between their performances and the performance of a conventional linear model are drawn. Advantages and disadvantages of the examined methods are discussed, and practical recommendations for the use of random forests for variable selection are given.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 10:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231193327?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“They Don&#39;t Feel Like This Is Their Place Anymore:” School Leaders’ Understanding of the Impacts of Gentrification on Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A number of urban U.S. cities that were traditionally Black and underinvested are now becoming enclaves to whites and upper-middle-class people. Consequently, a growing body of research on schools and gentrification is emerging. While most of this research has focused on the shifts that neighborhoods and schools undergo due to gentrification, we know less about how school leaders make meaning of these impacts. This study draws on interviews with 26 principals in two gentrifying cities to examine the impacts of gentrification on schools. We find that school leaders understand gentrification&#39;s impacts on schools materially, epistemically, and affectively, and at the same time, these shifts complicate the work of school leaders. This study concludes with implications for future research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 05:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231191704?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participatory and critical action research</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/31/4&quot;&gt;Volume 31, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, October 2023, Page 611-619&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 04:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2252212?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A National Study Exploring Factors Promoting Adolescent College Readiness in Math and Science (STEM-CR)</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Numerous national and state endeavors have advocated for approaches, funding, and programs focused on expanding the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) workforce of the nation and investing in education to cultivate a more diverse and impactful cohort of students who pursue STEM pathways. Educators, support personnel, and policymakers are in a position to engage in discussions about expanding STEM college readiness (STEM-CR) and participation. However, few are cognizant that STEM-CR is a progression that students strive for in developing skills, behaviors, and attitudes that spans over time. The current study established and validated a measurement model of student STEM-CR in mathematics and science utilizing the High School Longitudinal Study of 2009. The model was created based on a multidimensional and theoretical perspective of college readiness using a confirmatory factor analysis and modeling approach that accounted for measurement invariance. The sample (N = 16,044) comes from a racialized/ethnoracial and socioeconomically diverse high school population in the United States. The findings confirmed that STEM-CR involves four related yet distinct dimensions of Think, Know, Act, and Go. Results also demonstrated soundness of these STEM-CR dimensions by race and gender (key learning skills and techniques/Act). Academic self-efficacy was the strongest dimension of our STEM-CR model and strongly predicted academic achievement and college enrollment. Research and practice implications are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 01:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231193309?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Job satisfaction of mathematics teachers: an empirical investigation to quantify the contributions of teacher self-efficacy and teacher motivation to teach</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The shortage of mathematics teachers necessitates deliberate efforts to retain high-quality ones in many parts of the world. This puts teacher job satisfaction in the spotlight since satisfied teachers are likely to retain their jobs. Thus, the purpose of this study is twofold. The first is to quantify the influence of teacher self-efficacy and teacher motivation on teacher job satisfaction. The second is to investigate the patterns of changes in teacher job satisfaction across gender, age, and work experience. Using both descriptive and inferential statistics, we analysed the dataset of 1304 Norwegian mathematics teachers to address two research questions. The results showed that both teacher self-efficacy and social utility motivation have a significant influence on teacher job satisfaction with an additional mediating role of teacher self-efficacy. Contrary to our expectations, personal utility motivation has a negative influence on teacher job satisfaction. We found that women had significantly higher teacher job satisfaction than men. Also, we found a high-low–high pattern of changes in teacher job satisfaction in ascending order of teachers’ age and work experience. One practical implication of these findings is exposing an appropriate time (i.e. at a low stage of job satisfaction) for interventions targeted at teacher job satisfaction to be effective. We discussed other implications of these findings concerning which constructs, gender, and age groups of teachers to prioritise for interventions that would reinforce the job satisfaction of mathematics teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00475-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining Race in LatCrit: A Systematic Review of Latinx Critical Race Theory in Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This systematic review includes 125 peer-reviewed education-research articles that employ a LatCrit framework (from a search including articles published from 1995 to 2020). The author examines how the literature utilizes LatCrit and advances ideas about race, Latinxs, and Latinidad in education. The author presents significant patterns and divergences in the literature’s strengths, challenges, and tensions. Some strengths include detailing Latinxs’ experiences and valuing experiential knowledge. The author problematizes four research practices: (1) describing LatCrit with select tenets of CRT; (2) not defining race or other relevant concepts (language, culture, etc.); (3) claiming Latinxs are unique because of their multidimensionality; and (4) exceeding LatCrit’s scope by rationalizing the study’s use of LatCrit because its participants are Latinxs. The author argues that these complications lead to a paradox: even though LatCrit emerges from critical race theory and is described as for Latinxs, the literature largely undertheorizes race and lacks clarity about conceptualizing Latinxs as a racialized group. The author recommends four framing ideas that are particular to LatCrit and that help advance the specificity of Latinidad in education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 10:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231192685?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The effects of online enactive education on secondary school students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 10:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2251405?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Study of modeling questions in a first-year university mathematics online course</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The training of non-specialists, particularly engineers, in mathematics requires designing specific didactic proposals that make the importance of mathematics evident. One approach to creating such proposals consists in analyzing the mathematics used in authentic contexts of engineering research and then effectuating a didactic transposition to mathematics teaching. To this end, in this research, we use elements of the anthropological theory of the didactic and the methodology of didactic engineering. Initially, we analyze the blind source separation method, a case of inverse modeling widely used in numerous engineering contexts (e.g., telecommunications, acoustics, geophysics, biosignal analysis). More specifically, we examine the algorithm based on the &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(A\mathbf{x}=\mathbf{b}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; matrix model and its use in a signal processing context. Based on this analysis, we designed a didactic device that focuses the study on a simulated signal mixture of pure tones and implemented it in two first-year university mathematics courses in the virtual modality. This article reports the results of the students’ first approximation to mathematical modeling activity in a setting of authentic research in engineering using a blind source separation method.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10261-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Increase in self-efficacy in prospective teachers through theory-based lesson study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper explores the education of prospective teachers with regard to the Theory of Didactical Situations when they engage in lesson study. We particularly focus on studying how a lesson study process oriented towards the Theory of Didactical Situations contributes to increasing prospective teachers’ self-efficacy to plan and teach lessons based on such theory, reducing the gap between theory and practice. Prior to the study, we will discuss how the theoretical postulates assumed in lesson study affect crucial aspects of the process. The study is implemented with 47 prospective early childhood education teachers. We also consider another group of 47 prospective teachers that were engaged in practicum at the time the lesson study process took place. Using a quasi-experimental methodology based on a questionnaire developed ad hoc that captures the particularities of the didactic paradigm assumed, the results of our study show that both lesson study and practicum lead to a statistically significant increase in future teachers’ self-efficacy to plan and teach lessons in line with the paradigm assumed. However, size effect measures show that the increase observed in the lesson study group is significantly higher, which supports the benefits of lesson study in initial teacher education. We discuss what the features of lesson study are that could be related to this increase. Finally, we sketch new lines of research connected with the benefits of lesson study versus other teacher education experiences like practicum, as well as with links between self-efficacy and knowledge growth in lesson study.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09597-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics identity instrument development for fifth through twelfth grade students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Given the importance of mathematics identity for students continued participation and engagement with mathematics, it is important for educators and researchers to be able to explore students’ mathematics identity development. However, an instrument with validity evidence that can be used to explore mathematics identity efficiently and with groups of students is not currently available. This article draws on prior research to test and validate items for a mathematics identity instrument to be used with fifth through twelfth grade students. This study includes 1559 participants from two school districts in a midwestern state in the USA. Analysis includes assessing four components of validity including content validity, internal structure, relationship to other variables, and generalization. Findings provide evidence for the reliability and validity of the items in the mathematics identity scale, giving researchers and educators a way to explore this construct efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00474-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The First-Grade Outcomes of Pre-K Attendees: Examining Benefits as a Function of Skill Type, Environments, and Subgroups</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examined whether pre-K benefits persist through the end of first grade and the extent to which persistence differs based on outcome domains, subsequent classroom environments, and key subgroups of children. Data from 2,351 children living in a large and diverse county in Virginia revealed that the initial benefits of pre-K for academic and executive function persisted through the end of first grade but were 75% to 80% smaller than at kindergarten entry. Kindergarten and first-grade classroom environments did not sustain pre-K benefits. Although the initial benefits of pre-K were larger for dual language learners and children in poverty relative to English speakers and low-income children, there were no differential benefits by the end of first grade.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2023 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231195559?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I don’t like to ask for charity”: The possibilities of social inclusion among immigrant low-income Latina mothers via feminist action research</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This Feminist Action Research (FAR) examines the impact of economic and societal exclusion on low-income Latina mothers. The study, conducted in an urban community in the Northeast U.S., aimed to foster social inclusion among low-income Latina mothers via a financial intervention. Data were collected from 12 participants, and the intervention emphasized curriculum negotiation and critical thinking. Descriptions and roles of positionality are considered and contextualized. Findings exemplified economic and societal exclusion in the form of economic deprivation and experiences of discrimination, along with experiences of personal agency, solidarity, and social inclusion. Conclusions include a discussion on the potential of FAR within poverty research, along with practical implications in developing community change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 11:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231199846?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Errybody Sayin ‘No New Friends’?: The Proverbs of Rap and Why Young People Recite Them</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 06:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2240460?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional digital competence beliefs of student teachers, pre-service teachers and teachers: Validating an instrument based on the DigCompEdu framework</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2023 02:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2251663?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
