<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Use of Reparametrization and Constraints on Linear Models to Parse Qualitative and Quantitative Information for a Set of Predictors</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The following study shows how reparameterizations and constraints of the general linear model can serve to parse quantitative and qualitative aspects of predictors. We demonstrate three different approaches. The study uses data from the High School Longitudinal Study of 2009 on mathematics course-taking and achievement as an example. Results show that all mathematics courses are not equally predictive of math achievement. Thus, taking into account qualitative aspects of mathematics courses is useful. The study ends with a justification of quantifying qualitative aspects of predictors relative to a criterion with extensions to other linear models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2024 07:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231223769?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CRToP: toward a critical race theory of power in higher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2024 06:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306380?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the foundations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/32/1&quot;&gt;Volume 32, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, February 2024, Page 1-6&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2024 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2301257?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The underlying beliefs in Pirkko’s narrative about implementing collaborative learning in mathematics - ‘my job is to give individual instruction’</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2024 12:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2298359?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transferability of Lessons From Program Evaluations: Iron Laws, Hiding Hands and the Evidence Ecosystem</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Assessing the transferability of lessons from social research or evaluation continues to raise challenges. Efforts to identify transferable lessons can be based on two different forms of argumentation. The first draws upon statistics and causal inferences. The second involves constructing a reasoned case based on weighing up different data collected along the causal chain from designing to delivery. Both approaches benefit from designing research based upon existing evidence and ensuring that the descriptions of the programme, context, and intended beneficiaries are sufficiently rich. Identifying transferable lessons should not be thought of as a one-off event but involves contributing to the iterative and learning of a scientific community. To understand the circumstances under which findings can be confidently transferred, we need to understand: (1) How far and why outcomes of interest have multiple, interacting and fluctuating causes. (2) The program design and implementation capacity. (3) Prior knowledge and causal landscapes (and how far these are included in the theory of change). (4) New and relevant knowledge; what can we learn in our ‘disputatious community of truth seekers’.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2024 11:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241228332?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cluster Randomized Trials Designed to Support Generalizable Inferences</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;When planning a cluster randomized trial, evaluators often have access to an enumerated cohort representing the target population of clusters. Practicalities of conducting the trial, such as the need to oversample clusters with certain characteristics in order to improve trial economy or support inferences about subgroups of clusters, may preclude simple random sampling from the cohort into the trial, and thus interfere with the goal of producing generalizable inferences about the target population. We describe a nested trial design where the randomized clusters are embedded within a cohort of trial-eligible clusters from the target population and where clusters are selected for inclusion in the trial with known sampling probabilities that may depend on cluster characteristics (e.g., allowing clusters to be chosen to facilitate trial conduct or to examine hypotheses related to their characteristics). We develop and evaluate methods for analyzing data from this design to generalize causal inferences to the target population underlying the cohort. We present identification and estimation results for the expectation of the average potential outcome and for the average treatment effect, in the entire target population of clusters and in its non-randomized subset. In simulation studies, we show that all the estimators have low bias but markedly different precision. Cluster randomized trials where clusters are selected for inclusion with known sampling probabilities that depend on cluster characteristics, combined with efficient estimation methods, can precisely quantify treatment effects in the target population, while addressing objectives of trial conduct that require oversampling clusters on the basis of their characteristics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2024 05:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231169557?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating a Hypothetical Learning Trajectory for nets of rectangular prisms: A teaching experiment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2024 04:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2303505?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strategy flexibility in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this article we review the research on the flexible or adaptive use of solution strategies in school mathematics, with a focus on the most recent work in the field. After a short introduction, we provide an overview of the various ways in which strategy flexibility has been conceptualized and investigated in the research literature. Then we review the research that has looked at the relationship between strategy flexibility and task proficiency, followed by studies that analyzed the association of strategy flexibility and other learner variables, including learners’ age, general mathematical ability, prior knowledge, executive functions, gender, and affect. Studies addressing the socio-cultural and educational embeddedness of strategy flexibility are reviewed next, and, finally, we discuss the intervention studies that have tried to stimulate learners’ strategy flexibility by means of various instructional approaches. While this review reveals that strategy flexibility is increasingly recognized as an important and valuable construct in research and practice of mathematics education, and that recently substantial progress has been made in our understanding of this construct, there are many aspects of it that are still not well-understood and that need further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 23:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01491-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Dakota Cultural Intervention’s Influence on Native Students’ Sense of Belonging: A CBPR Case Study</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;This community-based participatory research case study demonstrates how Dakota Wicoḣaƞ utilized Indigenous and feminist epistemologies to create, implement, and evaluate a cultural intervention, the Mni Sota Makoce: Dakota Homelands Curriculum, to increase Native 6th- and 10th-grade social studies students’ peoplehood sense of belonging (Tachine et al., 2017). Findings demonstrate Native students liked the curriculum and reported an increase in support and a decrease in invalidation of their sense of belonging. While the curriculum provided a source of racial-ethnic socialization, some European American students criticized the curriculum, which likely negatively impacted 6th-grade students psychological sense of school membership (Goodenow, 1993). Results indicate Indigenous culture, epistemologies, and pedagogies should be infused throughout all curricula, teachers need to be prepared to effectively deal with racist and discriminatory behavior, and Indian education is important to Native students’ belonging. Implications and recommendations for funders, schools, researchers, teacher education programs, and Native communities are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 07:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231221793?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“No me dejaran ir porque they needed me here”: spatializing corrective representatives by critiquing latinx teacher role model discourse</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 01:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306413?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>(Re)presenting race: an analysis of special education textbooks for engagement with race and ethnicity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 01:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306409?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Structure sense in students’ quantity comparison and repeating pattern extension tasks: an eye-tracking study with first graders</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;There is growing evidence that the ability to perceive structure is essential for students’ mathematical development. Looking at students’ structure sense in basic numerical and patterning tasks seems promising for understanding how these tasks set the foundation for the development of later mathematical skills. Previous studies have shown how students use structure sense in enumeration tasks. However, little is known about students’ use of structure sense in other early mathematical tasks. The main aim of this study is to investigate the ways in which structure sense is manifested in first-grade students’ work across tasks, in quantity comparison and repeating pattern extension tasks. We investigated students’ strategies in quantity comparison and pattern extension tasks and how students employ structure sense. We conducted an eye-tracking study with 21 first-grade students, which provided novel insights into commonalities among strategies for these types of tasks. We found that for both tasks, quantity comparison and repeating pattern extension tasks, strategies can be distinguished into those employing structure sense and serial strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10290-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Seeing number relations when solving a three-digit subtraction task</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The decomposition of numbers when solving subtraction tasks is regarded as more powerful than counting-based strategies. Still, many students fail to solve subtraction tasks despite using decomposition. To shed light upon this issue, we take a variation theoretical perspective (Marton, 2015) seeing learning as a function of discerning critical aspects and their relations of the object of learning. In this paper, we focus on what number relations students see in a three-digit subtraction task, and how they see them. We analyzed interview data from 55 second-grade students who used decomposition strategies to solve 204 − 193 = . The variation theory of learning was used to analyze what number relations the students experienced and how they experienced them, aiming to explain why they made errors even though they used presumably powerful strategies in their problem-solving. The findings show that students who simultaneously experienced within-number relations and between-number relations when solving the task succeeded in solving it, whereas those who did not do this failed. These findings have importance for understanding what students need to discern in order to be able to solve subtraction tasks in a proficient way.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10287-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>There’s ‘learning in that struggle’: journey mindsets and agency in action research and culturally responsive education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2024 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2304807?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Predicted Academic Performance to Identify At-Risk Students in Public Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Measures of student disadvantage—or risk—are critical components of equity-focused education policies. However, the risk measures used in contemporary policies have significant limitations, and despite continued advances in data infrastructure and analytic capacity, there has been little innovation in these measures for decades. We develop a new measure of student risk for use in education policies, which we call Predicted Academic Performance (PAP). PAP is a flexible, data-rich indicator that identifies students at risk of poor academic outcomes. It blends concepts from emerging early warning systems with principles of incentive design to balance the competing priorities of accurate risk measurement and suitability for policy use. In proof-of-concept policy simulations using data from Missouri, we show PAP is more effective than common alternatives at identifying students who are at risk of poor academic outcomes and can be used to target resources toward these students—and students who belong to several other associated risk categories—more efficiently.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2024 05:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231212163?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emergent mathematical worlds from teacher knowing in whole-class discourse: using an enactivist lens on the teaching of exponential functions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reports findings related to the pursuit of describing a lived knowing for teaching mathematics. Specifically, we used an enactivist perspective to describe the knowing exhibited by three experienced high school teachers in their instructional actions while leading whole-class instruction on the topic of the equations of exponential functions. From classroom observations, we constructed maps of the emergent mathematical worlds of ideas and collective mathematical activity. Three major categories of ideas emerged in all three teachers’ classrooms relating to the recursive multiplicative nature of exponential functions, the role of the independent variable, and the definition of exponential. Findings of this study suggest attending to teacher knowing for mathematical whole-class instruction must include describing the role of the mathematical activity in the emergence of the ascribed mathematical ideas. When teachers facilitated the collective mathematical activity as the means by which the mathematical ideas and justifications emerge, the mathematical worlds were diverse and complex, and connections among ideas were more robust in their comprehensibility.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09610-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A model for problem creation: implications for teacher training</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The invention of problems is a fundamental competence that enhances the didactic-mathematical knowledge of mathematics teachers and therefore should be an objective in teacher training plans. In this paper, we revise different proposals for categorizing problem-creation activities and propose a theoretical model for problem posing that, based on the assumptions of the Onto-Semiotic Approach, considers both the elements that characterize a problem and a categorization of different types of problem-posing tasks. In addition, the model proposes a description of the mathematical processes that occur during the sequence of actions carried out when a new problem is created. The model is illustrated by its application to analyze the practices developed by pre-service teachers in three problem-posing tasks aimed at specific didactic-mathematical purposes (mobilizing certain mathematical knowledge or reasoning, contributing to achieving learning goals, or addressing students’ difficulties). We conclude discussing the potential of our model to analyze the mathematical processes involved in problem creation from the perspective of teacher education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00482-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Identifying Pre- and In-service Teachers’ Stances on Teaching Socioscientific Issues: A Systematic Review of Empirical Studies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;There is a prevalent consensus among science education scholars that teaching socioscientific issues (SSI) has notable importance for promoting functional scientific literacy and raising responsible citizens. However, teachers encounter numerous problems when teaching SSI, so they may not prefer to teach them. Today, we still do not know many specific particulars about how teachers’ own opinions, beliefs, or experiences influence the way in which they present controversies and which teacher’s role is best suited for teaching SSI. This paper aims to review the empirical studies that include teachers’ stances during teaching SSI and, if stated, their rationales about preferred stances. We employed the Web of Science and Education Resources Information Center (ERIC) databases and Google Scholar to find the relevant literature. Then, we independently screened the titles, abstracts, and full texts of the selected studies for eligibility. Based on the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) statement checklist, eighteen empirical studies were included in this review. Three main profiles of teachers’ positions while addressing SSI were identified: excluders, neutrals, and disclosers. Two subprofiles were identified for both neutrals and disclosers. Neutral teaching was found to be the most adopted and preferred teacher position for introducing SSI. It was followed by the avoidance of SSI teaching because the teachers viewed value-free education as important. Teachers’ own opinions, beliefs, epistemological orientations, concerns of indoctrination, and external factors were reported as the main underlying reasons for their preferred positions. Obviously, the studies conducted with in-service teachers yielded different reasoning patterns for their neutrality. We concluded that, given the pedagogical and epistemological challenges of teaching SSI, more research on teachers’ positions in addressing SSI in science classrooms is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00306-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strategies to Better Identify Student Homelessness Using Data in an Urban School District</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We tested 10 data-based strategies to better identify student homelessness in Camden City School District, which has a student body from minoritized backgrounds. We operationalized strategies through a research-practice partnership, following the federal homelessness definition. Data span 5 years (2014–15 through 2018–19), including integrated education, municipal, and health records. Nine strategies indicated significant unidentified student homelessness (min: 15; max: 5,008; p-values &amp;lt; .001). Consistent with homelessness, six strategies produced groups with lower attendance (p-values &amp;lt; .01) and seven with increased school mobility (p-values &amp;lt; .05). Homelessness was 34% greater in the most conservative interpretation, though counts could be as much as 454% greater. Student homelessness is more prevalent than recognized, data-based strategies can guide proactive outreach, and cross-system partnerships are warranted.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231215347?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond Prescriptive Reforms: An Examination of North Carolina’s Flexible School Restart Program</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although multiple studies have examined the impact of school turnaround, less is known about reforms under the Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA). To advance this literature, we examine North Carolina’s Restart (NCR) model. NCR aligns with ESSA by giving school leaders increased flexibility. Also, NCR differs from previous turnaround models by repackaging a traditionally sanction-based approach to instead motivate school leaders with increased autonomy. Using comparative interrupted time series models, we find positive NCR effects in math, but not in English Language Arts or on nontest-based student outcomes. Also, nearly a quarter of the positive NCR effect can be explained by decreased teacher and principal turnover. These results provide evidence to support current shifts toward reform models featuring local autonomy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231218735?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Resisting marginalization with culturally responsive mathematical modeling in elementary classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical modeling (MM) - a cyclical process that involves using mathematics to make-sense of and analyze relevant, real-world situations - has the potential to advance equity and challenge spaces of marginalization in the elementary mathematics classroom. When informed by culturally responsive teaching practices, MM creates opportunities to center the knowledge and experiences that students from diverse racial, cultural, and linguistic backgrounds bring to the classroom as valuable resources to support learning and inform action. It can disrupt power and status hierarchies in the classroom that contribute to structural and ideological marginalization. This paper describes ways teachers connected their teaching of MM with key components of a culturally responsive mathematics teaching framework. Analysis synthesizes data from an innovative, research-based professional development for elementary teachers to support teacher learning of equity-centered, culturally responsive MM instruction. Data sources include end of year teacher interviews, and professional development discussions from 19 teachers at four geographically, racially, and culturally diverse sites. Findings focus on how teachers connected their teaching of MM with key dimensions of culturally responsive mathematics teaching, and affordances and challenges related to resisting ideological and structural forms of marginalization.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01542-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional development for teaching mathematics with technology: a comparative study of facilitators’ beliefs and practices in China and Germany</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Facilitators, i.e., individuals who lead professional development (PD) programs, play a crucial role in providing high-quality PD to teachers, which is particularly relevant in the context of teaching mathematics with technology given the ubiquitous calls to exploit the potential of digital mathematical tools (DMT). However, quantitative research investigating facilitators’ beliefs and practices remains scarce, particularly research comparing countries. In this cross-national study conducted in China and Germany, we developed an online questionnaire and surveyed &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 340 facilitators to provide a comprehensive quantitative picture of facilitators’ beliefs and practices concerning PD for teaching mathematics with DMT. The results highlight various commonalities and differences between facilitators in China and Germany. We reveal significant differences concerning cooperation among facilitators, adaptation of PD materials, how facilitators professionalise themselves, and beliefs about when and how to use DMT. Furthermore, Chinese facilitators emphasise technical competence more strongly, while German facilitators focus more on developing teachers’ pedagogical content knowledge. A critical commonality was that facilitators’ self-efficacy concerning teaching with DMT and their self-efficacy for conducting PD for teaching mathematics with DMT was low. We discuss how the results can be linked to differences in the educational and cultural context and outline possible complements and enrichments for both countries’ educational systems.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10284-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career aspirations of the students preparing to work as teachers in Poland, Latvia and Ukraine</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-14-2024 03:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2301973?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“She didn’t mean it that way”: theorizing gendered Islamophobia in academia</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cree20/27/1&quot;&gt;Volume 27, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, January 2024, Page 39-54&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2024 07:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2268318?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
