<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ecological perspectives in early language education: Parent, teacher, peer and child agency in interaction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-18-2024 03:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2335791?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to (mis)align participatory approaches with the everyday life? Construction of an improved cookstove in India</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Improved cookstoves aimed at reducing exposure to indoor air pollution have had a lasting presence in development and health discussions. Through this article we contribute to current debates in the field by reflecting on our experiences during a cookstove participatory project in two ‘non-notified’ communities, or ‘slums,’ in Bangalore, India. We interrogate the alignment between some of the central tenets and methods of participation and the lived experiences of participating communities. The current predominant recommendations focus on developing and implementing cookstoves tailored for user needs. Yet, the project implementation entered a space of uncertainty where the priorities and needs of participants were diverse and changing. While urban infrastructures related to housing and work security, drainage systems, access to health care, and aspects of governance, citizenship and rights, may seem to fall outside the scope of ICS projects, our experiences show how inescapably they shape participatory processes and technologies. We highlight the need to take a closer look at how we can include these broader and changing priorities and needs in our methodologies and reflect on how we can better respond and align them with the ways in which people live.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-17-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241234495?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Problem With Perspective: Students’ and Teachers’ Reasoning About Credibility During Discussions of Online Sources</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-17-2024 08:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2340981?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working as facilitators and co-researchers: opportunities, tensions and complexities in educational participatory research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-17-2024 06:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2342824?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Early childhood pre-service teachers’ preparation for using technology with children: a systematic literature review</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-16-2024 09:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2341935?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Taproot, rhizome, disappointment, possibility: action research with(in) sociomaterial perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-16-2024 07:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2342724?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conditioning on the Pre-Test versus Gain Score Modelling: Revisiting the Controversy in a Multilevel Setting</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We consider estimating the effect of a treatment on a given outcome measured on subjects tested both before and after treatment assignment in observational studies. A vast literature compares the competing approaches of modelling the post-test score conditionally on the pre-test score versus modelling the difference, namely, the gain score. Our contribution lies in analyzing the merits and drawbacks of two approaches in a multilevel setting. This is relevant in many fields, such as education, where students are nested within schools. The multilevel structure raises peculiar issues related to contextual effects and the distinction between individual-level and cluster-level treatments. We compare the two approaches through a simulation study. For individual-level treatments, our findings align with existing literature. However, for cluster-level treatments, the scenario is more complex, as the cluster mean of the pre-test score plays a key role. Its reliability crucially depends on the cluster size, leading to potentially unsatisfactory estimators with small clusters.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-16-2024 06:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241246833?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impact of kinesthetic instructional strategies and manipulatives on fourth grader’s self-efficacy and self-confidence toward multiplication</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-16-2024 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2343036?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Awareness as an enactivist framework for the mathematical learning of teachers, mentors and institutions</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01569-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Navigating around marginalizing complexities: the case of mathematics teachers in the Philippines</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Marginalization, widely associated with poverty, inequality, and underdevelopment restricts access to resources, limits freedom of choice, inhibits the development of individual capabilities, and makes it challenging to escape from marginalized circumstances. We examine marginality in mathematics teaching and its complexities in the tightly centralized educational system in the Philippines by identifying the different situations that contribute to how mathematics teachers can be excluded from certain educational practices that would normally fall within their mandate as professional teachers. Adopting Gatzweiler and Baumüller’s (Marginality: Addressing the nexus of poverty, exclusion and ecology, Springer:27–40, 2014) framework, we interviewed 15 mathematics teachers from different geographical locations around the country. We identified and organized the drivers of marginality into biophysical and societal causal clusters that enable or constrain teachers to act as professionals. Biophysical causal clusters include mathematics curriculum and mathematics assessments among others while societal causal clusters include various directives, interpretations, and realities surrounding the biophysical causal clusters. Discussions about the complexities brought about by these clusters and how teachers act or respond as they navigate around them are highlighted. Recommendations for concrete de-marginalization actions are offered.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01571-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I’m a bit out of place here.”—Preservice teachers’ positioning in the figured world of university mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Preservice mathematics teachers are sometimes trained in programs so that they have both their own courses and joint courses with mathematics majors from the beginning of their studies. While this is thought to provide them with both deep mathematical knowledge and teaching-specific content right from the start, many of them report disaffection with and disengagement from mathematics during their very first semester. Current approaches often frame this from an individual’s perspective, investigating cognitive and affective individual differences among students. In contrast, we aim to understand this issue from a sociocultural perspective, examining underlying social processes. In this study, we thus explored preservice teachers’ experiences of the mathematics component of their training, using Holland and colleagues’ theory of figured worlds as a theoretical lens. Three group interviews with 14 preservice higher secondary teachers in a common mixed setting in Germany (one course specific to preservice teachers, one general mathematics course together with major students) were analyzed. Our findings displayed that the preservice teachers experienced two dichotomous figured worlds of mathematics and mathematics teaching. Our further analysis of their positioning between these worlds provided new insights to explain their disaffection, disengagement, and consequent learning behavior. We discuss practical implications, focusing on different teaching systems and interventions in teacher education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10315-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Latinx/a/o Senior Leaders in U.S Higher Education: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Latinx/a/o senior leaders remain underrepresented in the executive ranks, and more research is needed to adequately address equity gaps in higher education leadership. By employing a systematic literature review approach, we examined 57 pieces of scholarship that focused on the experiences of senior Latinx/a/o leaders in postsecondary education. This exploration was aimed at equipping higher education scholars and practitioners with the tools to understand how Latinx/a/o leaders navigate challenges and opportunities in higher education. We identified three major themes: 1) scholarship focusing on individual traits and important identity-based differences; 2) research describing the environmental and structural conditions that shape these leaders’ realities; and 3) literature describing these individuals’ leadership pathways. As an effort to make this body of work more accessible to researchers and decision-makers, we provided implications for research and practice to shape the field of Latinx/a/o leadership in higher education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-13-2024 04:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241242752?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring secondary school students’ geometrical figure apprehension: cognitive structure and levels of geometrical ability</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The present study examines secondary school students’ geometrical figure apprehension based on Duval’s theoretical framework regarding perceptual, operative, and discursive apprehension. The aim is to explore the cognitive structure of the geometrical figure apprehension dimensions (operative, discursive, and perceptual) in three grades of secondary school students. The tasks in the present study were completed by a sample of 881 students attending public secondary education in Cyprus. Confirmatory factor analysis indicated the stability of the structure of the model concerning secondary school students’ geometrical figure apprehension. However, differences were found in the interrelations among the three main aspects of the model in the examined grades (9, 10, and 11). Moreover, it was observed that students find it easier to solve tasks involving perceptual apprehension compared to discursive apprehension tasks, indicating a possible hierarchical structure of figure apprehension. The present study acts as a pilot study of the constructed instrument. Finally, the results are interpreted in relation to the type of geometrical paradigm in which students work at each hierarchical level.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10317-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Enhancing the enactment of assessment for learning principles during school placement: preservice teachers as practitioner researchers within a learning community</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-12-2024 12:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2340684?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Regularized Methods to Validate Q-Matrix in Cognitive Diagnostic Assessment</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;One of the central components of cognitive diagnostic assessment is the Q-matrix, which is an essential loading indicator matrix and is typically constructed by subject matter experts. Nonetheless, to a large extent, the construction of Q-matrix remains a subjective process and might lead to misspecifications. Many researchers have recognized the importance of estimating or validating the Q-matrix, but most of them focus on the conditions of relatively large sample sizes. This article aims to explore Q-matrix validation possibilities under small sample conditions and uses regularized methods to validate the Q-matrix based on the compensatory reparametrized unified model and generalized deterministic inputs, noisy “and” gate models. Simulation studies were conducted to evaluate the viability of the modified least absolute shrinkage and selection operator (Lasso) and modified smoothly clipped absolute deviation (SCAD) methods, comparing them with existing methods. Results show that the modified Lasso and the modified SCAD methods outperform the stepwise, Hull, and MLR-B methods in general, especially under the conditions of small sample sizes. While good recovery in all small sample size conditions is not guaranteed, the modified methods demonstrate advantages across various item quality conditions. Also, a real data set is analyzed to illustrate the application of the modified methods.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-12-2024 07:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241240084?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Testing the Way Forward: The Impact of Statewide ACT or SAT Testing on Postsecondary Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Twenty-nine states require or allow all 11th graders to take the ACT or SAT in school, for free, eliminating access to testing as a barrier to college entry. I examine whether this affects postsecondary outcomes using state-aggregated panel data and time-varying difference-in-differences methods. I find policy adoption led to 2% increases in selective 4-year enrollments by students from treated states. However, adoption had no effect on enrollments within adopting states’ selective institutions, in part because institutions enrolled fewer students from out-of-state after adoption. I also find null but directionally negative effects on the number of graduates from state institutions. Therefore, impacts are small but positive for students from adopting states, but null or negative for adopting states’ institutions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-12-2024 06:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241241260?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prospective secondary teachers’ noticing of students’ thinking about the limit concept: pathways of development</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research has shown that there is a need to examine prospective teachers’ development trajectories related to noticing expertise. An important content in the Spanish high school curriculum (16–18 years old) is the limit concept. Given the importance of this concept in the curriculum and the difficulties some prospective teachers have, developing their noticing of students’ mathematical thinking of this concept in teacher education programs is crucial to achieve high school student mathematics achievement. This study examines how prospective secondary school mathematics teachers (PTs) notice students’ mathematical thinking about the limit concept as they participated in a teaching module. PTs had to anticipate and interpret students’ mathematical understanding and make instructional decisions to support students’ conceptual progression using information about high school students’ understanding of the limit concept. We examined PTs changes related to how they anticipated, interpreted and made instructional decisions during the teaching module. We identified a change in how PTs conceived the understanding of the dynamic limit concept: from all-or-nothing dichotomy to progression; and a change in the instructional decisions they made: from decisions focused on changing the type of discontinuity to conceptual decisions. These changes allow us to characterise development noticing pathways. Our findings also help to identify the teaching module characteristics that support the development of PTs noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01573-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sex Disparity: The Real Crisis in the HBCU Presidential Leadership Crisis Narrative</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-11-2024 05:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2333228?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tracing language teacher professional development through Perezhivanie: an argument for praxis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-11-2024 01:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2340687?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Experienced teachers talking about their mathematics teaching with linguistically disadvantaged learners</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Learners of mathematics who are linguistically disadvantaged for a variety of reasons, including impoverished socioeconomic status, continue to be educationally disadvantaged and at considerable risk of school failure and early dropout. This is the case in many parts of the world. While much has been researched on linguistically disadvantaged learners in the fields of sociology and general pedagogy, little is known about the classroom teaching of mathematical content in language-responsive ways for all learners in school. Experienced mathematics teachers draw on a wealth of knowledge of content teaching in language-responsive ways developed through their practices working with linguistically disadvantaged learners in their classrooms. In this paper we report on interviews with some of these experienced mathematics teachers from seven educational contexts focusing on teaching probability in language-responsive ways. We focus on what we can learn from these teachers that could inform our practice as mathematics teacher educators and our research. We identify three challenges and three practices that add nuance and depth to theoretical research findings and recommendations on language in mathematics teaching, which can potentially develop these findings in more practical and accurate ways.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-11-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09628-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tensions in Teaching Chinese International Students: A Self-Study of Cultural Competence in an Educational Foundations Course</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-10-2024 07:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2339882?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Against Teaching Home As Housing in School: Examining How Teachers Teach Home</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-10-2024 07:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2335891?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of a Learning Trajectory for statistical inference on 9th-grade students’ statistical literacy</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In our data-driven society, it is essential for students to become statistically literate. A core domain within Statistical Literacy is Statistical Inference, the ability to draw inferences from sample data. Acquiring and applying inferences is difficult for students and, therefore, usually not included in the pre-10th-grade curriculum. However, recent studies suggest that developing a good understanding of key statistical concepts at an early age facilitates the understanding of Statistical Inference later on. This study evaluates the effects of a Learning Trajectory for Statistical Inference on Dutch 9th-grade students’ Statistical Literacy. Theories on informal Statistical Inference and repeated sampling guided the Learning Trajectory’s design. For the evaluation, we used a pre-post research design with an intervention group (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 267). The results indicated that students made significant progress on Statistical Literacy and on the ability to make inferences in particular, but also on the other domains of Statistical Literacy. To further interpret the learning gains of this group, we compared students’ results with national baseline achievements from a comparison group (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 217) who followed the regular 9th-grade curriculum, and with international studies using similar test items. Both comparisons confirmed a significant positive effect on all domains of Statistical Literacy. These findings suggest that current statistics curricula for grades 7–9, usually with a strong descriptive focus, can be enriched with an inferential focus.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00487-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Arab teacher educators and the moral work of teaching in Israel</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-09-2024 10:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2337636?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
