<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Revisiting an historic tool of participatory action research: Consciousness-raising as a methodology for transformative change</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Freirean consciousness-raising methodology is an historical, emancipatory tool useful in transforming modern socio-political oppressions in the current War on Women as it can simultaneously raise critical consciousness and ignite social action. Unfortunately, there are no systemic guidelines on conducting consciousness-raising as a research method. Therefore, the purpose of this critical literature review is to examine how consciousness-raising has been used as a research methodology and evaluate its associated tools and procedures. The review (n = 12 studies) revealed ten decision-making processes: assumptions and aims, group composition, governance, environment, rules, session structure, activities, collective data collection and analysis, evaluation, and transition planning. I use an exemplar study of diverse girls exploring how city planning contributed to their experiences of neighborhood violence to integrate experiential knowledge into the literature review findings. The article concludes with a discussion on the implications, limitations, and future directions of the consciousness-raising methodology.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 10:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241248569?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring teacher educators’ challenges in the context of digital transformation and their self-reported TPACK: a mixed methods study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 04:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2340689?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Self-Care is Not Enough: Effects of Self-Care Self-Monitoring Intervention on Teacher Candidates’ Resilience and Self-Efficacy</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 02:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2342906?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Effects of a Social-Emotional Learning Intervention in Brazilian Primary Schools: Findings from Year Two of Implementation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 01:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2322609?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Forced to Redshirt: Quasi-Experimental Impacts of Delayed Kindergarten Entry</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 01:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2333733?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical naming and explaining in teaching talk: Noticing work with two groups of mathematics teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research shows the salient place of mathematical teaching talk, including the mathematical-linguistic practices of naming and explaining, in the enactment of students’ mathematical talk and learning with understanding in the classroom. Our study was developed to examine the noticing of two groups of secondary-school mathematics teachers in one-day workshops with tasks about these practices. The two workshops were mathematically content-specific, with teaching and learning accounts and prompts aimed at guiding focused attention to naming and explaining in the teaching of linear equations and probability. Thematic text analyses led to identify three foci of the two groups’ noticing: (i) missing practices of mathematical naming in own teaching talk; (ii) relative impact of mathematical explaining in teaching talk; and (iii) tensions around mathematical naming and explaining in teaching talk. Our results show that the social construction of teacher noticing is a feature of noticing development that can be documented in the context of one-day workshops. Whereas time for individual thinking and responses to the tasks created a context of support for noticing development, participation in the group discussions allowed the teachers to notice nuances of mathematical naming and explaining in teaching talk unaddressed in the task prompts. The group discussions thus amplified and opened up the opportunities to develop some focused noticing on the content of the workshops, specifically in connection with the teachers’ own teaching practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01576-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics education researchers’ practices in interdisciplinary collaborations: Embracing different ways of knowing</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics education researchers (MERs) use practices unique to the mathematics education discipline to conduct their work. MERs’ practices, i.e., ways of being, interacting, and operating, define the field of mathematics education, are initially learned in doctoral preparation programs, and are encouraged and sanctioned by conferences and publications. Disciplinary practices facilitate MERs’ interactions within mathematics education. When working in interdisciplinary groups, differences in disciplinary ways of being, interacting, and operating can create challenges with completing research and other work. Since MERs’ engagement in interdisciplinary collaborations is encouraged and can result in products contributing to the evolution of the mathematics education discipline, it is important to explore what practices MERs use in interdisciplinary collaborations. We interviewed four MERs who led international interdisciplinary collaborations and used qualitative content analysis to create descriptions of practices described by MERs in their collaborations. Five practices were common between the MERs in interdisciplinary collaborations. MERs conducted interdisciplinary work by using practices that allowed them to situate themselves and others in the group (i.e., being practices), develop ideas (i.e., interacting practices), work towards common goals, and use structures to get the work done (i.e., operating practices). We argue that MERs developed new practices to position themselves and others, interact with practitioners from other disciplines, and get interdisciplinary work done. This study contributes to the evolution of the mathematics education discipline by offering five practices that can orient MERs to conducting interdisciplinary work and discussing how MERs experience interdisciplinary collaborations beyond providing mathematics education expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-19-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00489-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Multiply by 37 (or Divide by 0.027): A Surprisingly Accurate Rule of Thumb for Converting Effect Sizes From Standard Deviations to Percentile Points</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Educational researchers often report effect sizes in standard deviation units (SD), but SD effects are hard to interpret. Effects are easier to interpret in percentile points, but converting SDs to percentile points involves a calculation that is not transparent to educational stakeholders. We show that if the outcome variable is normally distributed, we can approximate the percentile-point effect simply by multiplying the SD effect by 37 (or, equivalently, dividing the SD effect by 0.027). For students in the middle three-fifths of a normal distribution, this rule of thumb is always accurate to within 1.6 percentile points for effect sizes of up to 0.8 SD. Two examples show that the rule can be just as accurate for empirical effects from real studies. Applying the rule to empirical benchmarks, we find that the least effective third of educational interventions raise scores by 0 to 2 percentile points; the middle third raise scores by 2 to 7 percentile points; and the most effective third raise scores by more than 7 percentile points.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-18-2024 12:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241239677?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessment of phonological awareness: Effects of emotional words on preschoolers’ skills</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-18-2024 11:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2341652?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Care for the learning of mathematics – put to the test</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-18-2024 04:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2339802?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ecological perspectives in early language education: Parent, teacher, peer and child agency in interaction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-18-2024 03:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2335791?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to (mis)align participatory approaches with the everyday life? Construction of an improved cookstove in India</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Improved cookstoves aimed at reducing exposure to indoor air pollution have had a lasting presence in development and health discussions. Through this article we contribute to current debates in the field by reflecting on our experiences during a cookstove participatory project in two ‘non-notified’ communities, or ‘slums,’ in Bangalore, India. We interrogate the alignment between some of the central tenets and methods of participation and the lived experiences of participating communities. The current predominant recommendations focus on developing and implementing cookstoves tailored for user needs. Yet, the project implementation entered a space of uncertainty where the priorities and needs of participants were diverse and changing. While urban infrastructures related to housing and work security, drainage systems, access to health care, and aspects of governance, citizenship and rights, may seem to fall outside the scope of ICS projects, our experiences show how inescapably they shape participatory processes and technologies. We highlight the need to take a closer look at how we can include these broader and changing priorities and needs in our methodologies and reflect on how we can better respond and align them with the ways in which people live.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-17-2024 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241234495?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pre-service teachers as learners of formative assessment in teaching practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-17-2024 10:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2338840?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Problem With Perspective: Students’ and Teachers’ Reasoning About Credibility During Discussions of Online Sources</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-17-2024 08:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2340981?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working as facilitators and co-researchers: opportunities, tensions and complexities in educational participatory research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-17-2024 06:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2342824?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Early childhood pre-service teachers’ preparation for using technology with children: a systematic literature review</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-16-2024 09:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2341935?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Taproot, rhizome, disappointment, possibility: action research with(in) sociomaterial perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-16-2024 07:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2342724?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conditioning on the Pre-Test versus Gain Score Modelling: Revisiting the Controversy in a Multilevel Setting</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We consider estimating the effect of a treatment on a given outcome measured on subjects tested both before and after treatment assignment in observational studies. A vast literature compares the competing approaches of modelling the post-test score conditionally on the pre-test score versus modelling the difference, namely, the gain score. Our contribution lies in analyzing the merits and drawbacks of two approaches in a multilevel setting. This is relevant in many fields, such as education, where students are nested within schools. The multilevel structure raises peculiar issues related to contextual effects and the distinction between individual-level and cluster-level treatments. We compare the two approaches through a simulation study. For individual-level treatments, our findings align with existing literature. However, for cluster-level treatments, the scenario is more complex, as the cluster mean of the pre-test score plays a key role. Its reliability crucially depends on the cluster size, leading to potentially unsatisfactory estimators with small clusters.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-16-2024 06:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241246833?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impact of kinesthetic instructional strategies and manipulatives on fourth grader’s self-efficacy and self-confidence toward multiplication</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-16-2024 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2343036?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Awareness as an enactivist framework for the mathematical learning of teachers, mentors and institutions</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01569-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Navigating around marginalizing complexities: the case of mathematics teachers in the Philippines</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Marginalization, widely associated with poverty, inequality, and underdevelopment restricts access to resources, limits freedom of choice, inhibits the development of individual capabilities, and makes it challenging to escape from marginalized circumstances. We examine marginality in mathematics teaching and its complexities in the tightly centralized educational system in the Philippines by identifying the different situations that contribute to how mathematics teachers can be excluded from certain educational practices that would normally fall within their mandate as professional teachers. Adopting Gatzweiler and Baumüller’s (Marginality: Addressing the nexus of poverty, exclusion and ecology, Springer:27–40, 2014) framework, we interviewed 15 mathematics teachers from different geographical locations around the country. We identified and organized the drivers of marginality into biophysical and societal causal clusters that enable or constrain teachers to act as professionals. Biophysical causal clusters include mathematics curriculum and mathematics assessments among others while societal causal clusters include various directives, interpretations, and realities surrounding the biophysical causal clusters. Discussions about the complexities brought about by these clusters and how teachers act or respond as they navigate around them are highlighted. Recommendations for concrete de-marginalization actions are offered.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01571-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I’m a bit out of place here.”—Preservice teachers’ positioning in the figured world of university mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Preservice mathematics teachers are sometimes trained in programs so that they have both their own courses and joint courses with mathematics majors from the beginning of their studies. While this is thought to provide them with both deep mathematical knowledge and teaching-specific content right from the start, many of them report disaffection with and disengagement from mathematics during their very first semester. Current approaches often frame this from an individual’s perspective, investigating cognitive and affective individual differences among students. In contrast, we aim to understand this issue from a sociocultural perspective, examining underlying social processes. In this study, we thus explored preservice teachers’ experiences of the mathematics component of their training, using Holland and colleagues’ theory of figured worlds as a theoretical lens. Three group interviews with 14 preservice higher secondary teachers in a common mixed setting in Germany (one course specific to preservice teachers, one general mathematics course together with major students) were analyzed. Our findings displayed that the preservice teachers experienced two dichotomous figured worlds of mathematics and mathematics teaching. Our further analysis of their positioning between these worlds provided new insights to explain their disaffection, disengagement, and consequent learning behavior. We discuss practical implications, focusing on different teaching systems and interventions in teacher education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10315-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Latinx/a/o Senior Leaders in U.S Higher Education: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Latinx/a/o senior leaders remain underrepresented in the executive ranks, and more research is needed to adequately address equity gaps in higher education leadership. By employing a systematic literature review approach, we examined 57 pieces of scholarship that focused on the experiences of senior Latinx/a/o leaders in postsecondary education. This exploration was aimed at equipping higher education scholars and practitioners with the tools to understand how Latinx/a/o leaders navigate challenges and opportunities in higher education. We identified three major themes: 1) scholarship focusing on individual traits and important identity-based differences; 2) research describing the environmental and structural conditions that shape these leaders’ realities; and 3) literature describing these individuals’ leadership pathways. As an effort to make this body of work more accessible to researchers and decision-makers, we provided implications for research and practice to shape the field of Latinx/a/o leadership in higher education.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-13-2024 04:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241242752?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring secondary school students’ geometrical figure apprehension: cognitive structure and levels of geometrical ability</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The present study examines secondary school students’ geometrical figure apprehension based on Duval’s theoretical framework regarding perceptual, operative, and discursive apprehension. The aim is to explore the cognitive structure of the geometrical figure apprehension dimensions (operative, discursive, and perceptual) in three grades of secondary school students. The tasks in the present study were completed by a sample of 881 students attending public secondary education in Cyprus. Confirmatory factor analysis indicated the stability of the structure of the model concerning secondary school students’ geometrical figure apprehension. However, differences were found in the interrelations among the three main aspects of the model in the examined grades (9, 10, and 11). Moreover, it was observed that students find it easier to solve tasks involving perceptual apprehension compared to discursive apprehension tasks, indicating a possible hierarchical structure of figure apprehension. The present study acts as a pilot study of the constructed instrument. Finally, the results are interpreted in relation to the type of geometrical paradigm in which students work at each hierarchical level.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-13-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10317-5</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
