<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exposure to Adversity and Trauma Among Students Who Experience School Discipline: A Scoping Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;While the disproportional application of school discipline has garnered notable attention, the relationship between trauma or adversity and school discipline is under examined. The purpose of the current scoping review was to map the state of the literature, empirical and theoretical, at the intersection of school discipline, and trauma or adversity. The findings identified a gap in our knowledge as only 14 of the 49 included articles detailed empirical studies focused on the relationship between adversity and school discipline, with very few from outside of the United States. However, this burgeoning body of knowledge points to a significant relationship between trauma/adversity and experiencing school discipline that warrants further study and contextualizes expanded adversities, including poverty and racism as adversity. We believe this is necessary to acknowledging the hidden and unaddressed trauma among students being disproportionally disciplined, leading to a greater understanding of student lives, and evidence-based, trauma-informed, and culturally attuned discipline.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2023 05:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231203674?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of EthnoSTEM-based mathematics modular instruction on Sama students’ mathematical thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2023 01:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2269536?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ties That Bind: An Examination of School-Family Relationships and Middle School Discipline in New York City</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Inequities in exclusionary discipline result from a complex process involving students, families, and school personnel. However, little research has explored the topic from parent perspectives. This study used parent survey data from New York City to investigate the link between school-family relationships and students experiencing exclusionary discipline. Results indicate that stronger parental trust toward teachers is connected to a reduced probability that a student receives an office discipline referral, while greater trust in principals is associated with a lower chance of suspension. Several aspects of school-family relationships, such as parent-principal trust, parental involvement, and school outreach and communication, heterogeneously predict a lower likelihood of experiencing exclusionary discipline by student race and special education status. These findings demonstrate the interdependent role of families and school staff in child development and highlight the need to cultivate positive school-family relationships as a potential strategy for addressing exclusionary discipline disparities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 11:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231203696?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“She didn’t mean it that way”: theorizing gendered Islamophobia in academia</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2268318?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Road Safety Efficiency on Interurban Roads in Spain</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The slowdown in economic development caused by traffic accidents in Spain, together with the disparity in the risk of death or injury due to traffic accidents in its provinces, makes it necessary to evaluate their road safety performance. Therefore, the objectives of the present research are, on the one hand, to find out the level of road safety efficiency of Spanish provinces in the period 2014–2018. On the other hand, it is also aimed to determine to what extent the annual efficiency change is originated by pure changes in efficiency or by technological changes. To achieve both objectives, the nonparametric technique of Data Envelopment Analysis and the Malmquist Index have been used based on the consideration of the Safety Performance Indicators (SPI) as the inputs of the process. The research findings show changes in the level of road safety efficiency in each of the years of the study period. Thus, it is possible to identify a geographical delimitation of the causes that generate changes in efficiency in recent years. A contraction in efficiency and technological progress is identified in part of the Spanish provinces in the north, northeast, and south of Spain.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 05:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231207443?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining Standards Across Five K-12 Academic Disciplines in the United States: Similarities, Distinctions, and Implications for Teacher Preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/45/4&quot;&gt;Volume 45, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Winter 2023, Page 355-372&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 02:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2247372?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/45/4&quot;&gt;Volume 45, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Winter 2023, Page 279-281&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 02:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2260290?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BSRLM day conference proceedings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 02:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2260356?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promoting statistical thinking in year 12 multilingual classrooms: a collaborative study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;There are challenges making connections between language use and mathematics in mathematics education. A lack of connections between the two domains can have negative consequences on student learning and performance. The challenges in statistics classrooms, where language and contexts are important as a medium of instruction, have received little scrutiny. This article reports on collaborative research carried out in three largely Pasifika-dominated year 12 classes. Specifically, we explored the language resources and strategies that appear to enhance the statistical understanding of Pasifika students. Findings from the teacher reflection aspect of the study indicated that some strategies to incorporate student language and communicative resources in their learning worked better than others. Teachers may need to re-evaluate their teaching practices, especially if part of their population is learning English as a second language.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00472-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching and learning in teacher education: agency, reflection and identity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/46/4&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, October 2023, Page 557-560&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-16-2023 11:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2266256?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The relationship between number talks and ambitious instruction: learning from beginning teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-16-2023 10:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2267720?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participatory action research: The woven collective analysis approach to recognize experiential knowledge of poverty</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;When conducting Participatory Action Research (PAR), we risk invalidating the experiential knowledge of people in poverty. Their contributions might only be seen as legitimate when put through a formal PAR process. We have thus developed a “woven collective analysis” approach, intertwining experiential, practical and academic knowledge. Diverse stakeholders reflect together and combine their voices, while ensuring that the experiential knowledge of people living in poverty remains the primary focus. Using the weaving process as a metaphor and a food-autonomy project as an example, we explore the steps involved in this data analysis approach: warping (or the need to recognize different types of knowledge and identify the actions required to use and communicate them); threading (or how to put into place a series of frameworks to allow information on social patterns to emerge, while combining varied knowledge); and sleying (or using targeted collective analysis to tighten up the information, in a recurring and systematic way). These combined operations contribute to the weaving process and the emergence of a new fabric of complex, social and transformational Common knowledge.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-16-2023 08:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231205237?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Framing Effects and the Public’s Attitudes Toward Racial Equity in Education Policy</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Frames shape public opinion on policy issues, with implications for policy adoption and agenda-setting. What impact do common issue frames for racial equity in education have on voters’ support for racially equitable education policy? Across survey experiments with two independent representative polls of California voters, framing effects were moderated by voters’ prior policy preferences. Among respondents concerned with tax policy, a frame emphasizing the economic benefits of equity elicited higher priority for racial equity in education. Among respondents concerned with social justice, an “equal opportunity” frame elicited higher priority ratings. However, exploratory analyses showed frames only mattered when respondents held mixed policy preferences. Among respondents who (a) valued both tax policy and social justice issues, or who (b) valued neither, both frames were equally impactful.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-16-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231200202?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward Inquiry and Problem Posing in Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/74/5&quot;&gt;Volume 74, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 417-421, November/December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2023 09:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231202828?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Appreciation</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/74/5&quot;&gt;Volume 74, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 522-523, November/December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2023 09:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231206439?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reconnecting with the mathematical thought of the Mesoamerican numbers in Ixil: an onto-epistemological dialogue</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Numbers and languages are present around the world. While mathematics is deemed as universal, communities around the world have developed mathematical practices that align with their specific context and needs. Rooted in an Indigenous epistemological framework, this manuscript presents a dialogue among four co-researchers and teachers retelling their experiences teaching and learning Mesoamerican numbers in both monolingual (Spanish) and bilingual (Ixil and Spanish) contexts. With a strong desire to learn about and reconnect with the forces of Indigenous mathematical thought and language that move within the teaching and learning of these numbers, the authors collectively reflected on their “tellings” of prior work. It is worthy of note that these reflections on teaching and learning processes of naming Mesoamerican numbers, their symbols, and numerical values help realize that these concepts are more fully animated when presented in contexts that are onto-epistemologically relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01523-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Review of Practice-oriented Research in Tertiary Mathematics Education by Biehler et al. (2022)</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00228-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining preservice teachers’ sensemaking of teaching children through rigorous and appropriate practices: a case study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2023 05:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2265828?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Erratum to Identifying Informative Predictor Variables With Random Forests</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2023 03:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231204871?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pairwise Regression Weight Contrasts: Models for Allocating Psychological Resources</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Researchers examine contrasts between analysis of variance (ANOVA) effects but seldom contrasts between regression coefficients even though such coefficients are an ANOVA generalization. Regression weight contrasts can be analyzed by reparameterizing the linear model. Two pairwise contrast models are developed for the study of qualitative differences among predictors. One leads to tests of null hypotheses that the regression weight for a reference predictor equals each of the other weights. The second involves ordered predictors and null hypotheses that the weight for a predictor equals that for the variables just above or below in the ordering. As illustration, qualitative differences in high school math course content are related to math achievement. The models facilitate the study of qualitative differences among predictors and the allocation of resources. They also readily generalize to moderated, hierarchical, and generalized linear forms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2023 01:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231200155?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Shame, entitlement, and the systemic racism of mathematics “ability” grouping in Aotearoa New Zealand</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Decades of research has documented the consequences of allocating school students into a hierarchy of classes with narrow ranges of mathematics attainment, a process known as streaming, tracking, setting, or “ability” grouping. The purported benefits of streaming are inconsistent and disputed, but the harms are clear, in particular, (1) the limiting curriculum often available in low streams and (2) the loss of self-confidence that results from being positioned in a low stream. Building on this foundation, we discuss streaming in mathematics as tied to systemic racism in Aotearoa New Zealand, where the harmful effects of streaming fall most heavily on Māori and Pasifika students. Previous analyses of race and streaming have focused primarily on the racial composition of streamed classes, bias in stream allocation, and racialised teacher expectations in streamed settings. In contrast, we focus on the emotional consequences of streaming, arguing that streaming produces racialised emotions of shame and entitlement as unintended but predictable consequences. We illustrate the racialised production of entitlement and shame through collaborative storying, interweaving our own biographies with a re-analysis of student interviews from two prior studies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10266-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mental processes underlying a mathematics teacher’s learning from student thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teachers’ knowledge of students’ mathematical thinking is a growing area of research in mathematics education. The literature has reported plentiful evidence of the interplays between teachers’ mathematical knowledge and their knowledge of students’ mathematical thinking. The present study builds on this body of work to explain how such interplays occur. Over a semester, I worked in partnership with a secondary school mathematics teacher on cycles of task design, interactions with a student, and in-depth reflection on the student’s thinking about linear programming. Adopting and extending Piagetian constructs of assimilation and accommodation, I describe several key mental processes that illuminate the teacher’s learning of mathematics and of the student’s mathematical thinking. I conclude with a discussion of the study’s empirical and theoretical contributions to understanding teachers’ mathematical learning in relation to student thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09601-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Relationships between elementary mathematics specialist certification, knowledge, beliefs, and classroom learning environments</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We report on the differences in mathematics learning environments in classes taught by certified Elementary Math Specialists (EMSs) (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 28) and their peers (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 33) as determined by observations of instruction. We used path analysis to examine how variables such as mathematical knowledge for teaching, beliefs, and background characteristics were related to the learning environment. We used the Classroom Learning Environment Measure (CLEM) observation protocol, which attends to aspects of mathematics lessons such as opportunities for students to justify their reasoning and attend to mathematical concepts. Our analysis revealed that learning environments incorporating such elements were significantly more prevalent in classes taught by EMSs, and that there were two paths indicating mediation effects on the relationship between EMS status and learning environment. One path was related to teachers’ beliefs about the primacy of computation in learning mathematics; the other path was related to teachers’ mathematical knowledge for teaching and their beliefs about the extent to which mathematical knowledge is constructed by the learner. We share implications for EMS programs and recommendations for future research on the impact of EMSs in elementary schools.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09602-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bafflement in an Inquiry-based College Mathematics Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00227-x</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
