<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcement of the Stata Journal Editors’ Prize 2023</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1-2, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231160122?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>artbin: Extended sample size for randomized trials with binary outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 24-52, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We describe the command artbin, which offers various new facilities for the calculation of sample size for binary outcome variables that are not otherwise available in Stata. While artbin has been available since 2004, it has not been previously described in the Stata Journal. artbin has been recently updated to include new options for different statistical tests, methods and study designs, improved syntax, and better handling of noninferiority trials. In this article, we describe the updated version of artbin and detail the various formulas used within artbin in different settings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231161971?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Finite mixture models for linked survey and administrative data: Estimation and postestimation</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 53-85, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Researchers use finite mixture models to analyze linked survey and administrative data on labor earnings, while also accounting for various types of measurement error in each data source. Different combinations of error-ridden and error-free observations characterize latent classes. Latent class probabilities depend on the probabilities of the different types of error. We introduce a suite of commands to fit finite mixture models to linked survey-administrative data: there is a general model and seven simpler variants. We also provide postestimation commands for assessment of reliability, marginal effects, data simulation, and prediction of hybrid variables that combine information from both data sources about the outcome of interest. Our commands can also be used to study measurement errors in other variables besides labor earnings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231161976?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>robustpf: A command for robust estimation of production functions</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 86-96, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We introduce a new command, robustpf, to estimate parameters of Cobb–Douglas production functions. The command is robust against two potential problems. First, it is robust against optimization errors in firms’ input choice, unobserved idiosyncratic cost shocks, and measurement errors in proxy variables. In particular, the command relaxes the conventional assumption of scalar unobservables. Second, it is also robust against the functional dependence problem of static input choice, which is known today as a cause of identification failure. The main method is proposed by Hu, Huang, and Sasaki (2020, Journal of Econometrics 215: 375–398).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231161977?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 151: Puzzling out some logical operators</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 293-297, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162009?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>artcat: Sample-size calculation for an ordered categorical outcome</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 3-23, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We describe a new command, artcat, that calculates sample size or power for a randomized controlled trial or similar experiment with an ordered categorical outcome, where analysis is by the proportional-odds model. artcat implements the method of Whitehead (1993, Statistics in Medicine 12: 2257–2271). We also propose and implement a new method that 1) allows the user to specify a treatment effect that does not obey the proportional-odds assumption, 2) offers greater accuracy for large treatment effects, and 3) allows for noninferiority trials. We illustrate the command and explore the value of an ordered categorical outcome over a binary outcome in various settings. We show by simulation that the methods perform well and that the new method is more accurate than Whitehead’s method.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231161934?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Updates</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 298-299, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162008?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcements</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 300-301, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231161979?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Extended biasplot command to assess bias, precision, and agreement in method comparison studies</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 97-118, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Recently, a new statistical methodology to assess the bias and precision of a new measurement method, which circumvents the deficiencies of the Bland and Altman (1986, Lancet 327: 307–310) limits of agreement method, was developed by Taffé (2018, Statistical Methods in Medical Research 27: 1650–1660). Later, the methodology was extended to assess the agreement. In addition, to allow for inferences, simultaneous confidence bands around the bias, precision, and agreement lines were developed (Taffé, 2020, Statistical Methods in Medical Research 29: 778–796). The goal of this article is to introduce the extended biasplot command, which implements these latest developments, and to illustrate its use by applying it to simulated data included with the command. Note that the Taffé method assumes that there are several measurements by one of the two measurement methods and possibly as few as one measurement by the other for each individual. The repeated measurements need not come from the reference standard but from any of the two measurement methods. This is a great advantage because it may sometimes be more feasible to gather repeated measurements either with the reference standard or the new measurement method.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231161978?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 150: When is it appropriate to xtset a panel dataset with panelvar only?</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 281-292, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162020?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A note on creating inset plots using graph twoway</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 265-275, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Inset plots can be used to “zoom in” on densely populated areas of a graph or to add extra relevant data in the form of, for example, distribution plots. However, the standard Stata command for combining plots, graph combine, does not permit this type of seamless integration. Each plot within a graph combine object is allocated a grid cell that cannot be placed within another grid cell— at least not without certain (invariably unwanted) graphical complications. We present a fairly simple work-around to this issue using reproducible examples. The main idea is to plot insets along a second axis and then artificially modify the range of this axis to constrain the inset plot within a specified area of the main graph. Additional tips are included for producing more intricate, multilayered inset graphs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162022?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 149: Weighted estimation of fixed-effects and first-differences models</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 276-280, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162021?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>acreg: Arbitrary correlation regression</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 119-147, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We present acreg, a new command that implements the arbitrary clustering correction of standard errors proposed in Colella et al. (2019, IZA discussion paper 12584). Arbitrary here refers to the way observational units are correlated with each other: we impose no restrictions so that our approach can be used with a wide range of data. The command accommodates both cross-sectional and panel databases and allows the estimation of ordinary least-squares and two-stage least-squares coefficients, correcting standard errors in three environments: in a spatial setting using units’ coordinates or distance between units, in a network setting starting from the adjacency matrix, and in a multiway clustering framework taking multiple clustering variables as input. Distance and time cutoffs can be specified by the user, and linear decays in time and space are also optional.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162031?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Uniform nonparametric inference for spatially dependent panel data: The xtnpsreg command</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 243-264, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce a command, xtnpsreg, that implements a uniform nonparametric inference procedure for possibly unbalanced panel datasets with general forms of spatiotemporal dependence. We demonstrate how to apply this command via several examples, including 1) the nonparametric estimation of the conditional mean function and its marginal response, 2) the construction of uniform confidence bands for these nonparametric functional parameters, 3) specification tests for parametric model restrictions, and 4) the estimation and uniform inference for functional coefficients in semi-nonparametric models.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162035?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improved tests for Granger noncausality in panel data</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 230-242, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce the xtgrangert command, which implements the panel Granger noncausality testing approach developed by Juodis, Karavias, and Sarafidis (2021, Empirical Economics 60: 93–112). This test offers superior size and power performance to existing tests, which stem from the use of a pooled estimator that has a faster [math] convergence rate. The test has several other useful properties: it can be used in multivariate systems; it has power against both homogeneous and heterogeneous alternatives; and it allows for cross-section dependence and cross-section heteroskedasticity.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162034?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Two-tier stochastic frontier analysis using Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 197-229, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce the sftt command, which fits two-tier stochastic frontier (2TSF) models with cross-sectional data. Like most frontier models, a 2TSF model consists of a linear frontier model and a composite error term. The error term is assumed to be a mixture of three components: two onesided inefficiency terms—strictly nonnegative and nonpositive, respectively—and a symmetric noise term. When providing appropriate distributional assumptions, sftt can fit models with exponential and half-normal specifications. sftt also fits 2TSF models with the scaling property to mitigate concerns over distributional specifications. In addition, we provide two subcommands, sftt sigs and sftt eff, to assist in postestimation efficiency analysis. We provide an overview of the 2TSF literature, a description of the sftt command and its options, and examples using simulated and actual data.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162033?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>statacons: An SCons-based build tool for Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/1&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 148-196, March 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we present statacons, an SCons-based build tool for Stata. Because of the integration of Stata and Python in recent versions of Stata, we are able to adapt SCons for Stata workflows without the use of an external shell or extensive configuration. We discuss the usefulness of build tools generally, provide examples of the use of statacons in Stata workflows, present key elements of the syntax of statacons, and discuss extensions, alternatives, and limitations. We provide recommendations for collaborative workflows and, at the end of the article, installation instructions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 02:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231162032?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Young philosophers: fifth-grade students animating the concept of space</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In many schools across the world, students experience mathematical concepts as ideas empty of wisdom and possibility. In this paper the authors analyze a philosophical conversation in which fifth-grade students were caught up in the animacy of the concept of space. Challenging the common view of mathematics as dealing with absolute truths and certainty, these students, the materials, and the concept itself formed dynamic assemblages that, through movement and the senses reanimated philosophical considerations regarding the concept of space. Over the course of an hour, students emerged as young philosophers whose ideas about space converged with those of philosophers from diverse fields, including physics, indigenous education, feminist theory, and dance. Using a philosophical analysis, the paper focuses on the vibrancy of a space filled with forces—images, movement, ideas, and materials—that shaped students’ relationships with mathematics and language. Based on this analysis, the paper provides insights for reimagining the teaching and learning of mathematical concepts as philosophical topics that can support a renewed understanding of the relationship between learner, language, and mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01483-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book review response. Who wants to know? Author’s response to review of A Contemporary Theory of Mathematics Education Research</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10221-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Culturally crafted Lesson Study to improve teachers&#39; professional development in mathematics: a case study in Italian secondary school</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper describes a Lesson Study in which in-service mathematics secondary-school teachers, collaborating with researchers, involve grade 10 students in tessellation problems. The data are collected by an experiment carried out in the context of the “Liceo Matematico” project, with three volunteer teachers. The experiment goal was to craft a collaborative design of the research lesson between teachers and researchers. The research aim of the paper is to examine the use of Lesson Study in the institutional and cultural context of Italian secondary school with the use of Cultural Transposition as a theoretical framework. The research is qualitative with idiographic aims, based on video research. The educational aim of the research is to provide a solid basis for a revamped in-service teacher education first in the context of the project, then in curricular context. Semiotic mediation is used to provide, within Lesson Study, the conceptual framework for teachers and researchers collaborative design of the research lesson. The results show that Lesson Study, as a foreign practice, is an opportunity for teachers to confront their teaching practices, to enrich their professional development, resulting in more awareness on their didactical action in and outside the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09578-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Perspective of Teachers to Context-Based Learning and Its Use in Science Education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of this study is to determine the thoughts of science teachers about context-based learning and its use in science education. The research was conducted with the case study method of qualitative research. The study group of the research consists of 90 science teachers working in secondary schools. The teachers constituting the study group were determined by the purposive sampling method. The data were obtained from the open-ended questionnaire applied to teachers and semi-structured interviews. The obtained data were analyzed by content analysis method. According to the results of the research, science teachers interpreted the context-based learning approach as presenting examples from daily life. According to science teachers, this approach is advantageous in terms of its contribution to students’ cognitive, affective, interpersonal, and self-management skills. Teachers think that the CBL approach has limitations such as setting the appropriate context for the subject and student level, classroom management in crowded classrooms, and non-compliance with education policies. Teachers stated that they used the approach in teaching many subjects, but they encountered problems such as program content and time management, material selection, appropriate context determination, and classroom management during the teaching process. Teachers do not consider themselves competent in the use of the CBL approach and they want to receive in-service training on this subject.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00266-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Mixed Methods Evaluation of a Pilot Multidisciplinary Breathlessness Support Service</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Breathlessness support services have demonstrated benefits for breathlessness mastery, quality of life and psychosocial outcomes for people living with breathlessness. However, these services have predominantly been implemented in hospital and home care contexts. This study aims to evaluate the adaptation and implementation of a hospice-based outpatient Multidisciplinary Breathlessness Support Service (MBSS) in Ireland. A sequential explanatory mixed methods design guided this study. People with chronic breathlessness participated in longitudinal questionnaires (n = 10), medical record audit (n = 14) and a post-discharge interview (n = 8). Caregivers (n = 1) and healthcare professionals involved in referral to (n = 2) and delivery of (n = 3) the MBSS participated in a cross-sectional interview. Quantitative and qualitative data were integrated deductively via the pillar integration process, guided by the RE-AIM framework. Integration of mixed methods data enhanced understanding of factors influencing the reach, adoption, implementation and maintenance of the MBSS, and the potential outcomes that were most meaningful for service users. Potential threats to the sustainability of the MBSS related to potential preconceptions of hospice care, the lack of standardized discharge pathways from the service and access to primary care services to sustain pharmacological interventions. This study suggests that an adapted multidisciplinary breathlessness support intervention is feasible and acceptable in a hospice context. However, to ensure optimal reach and maintenance of the intervention, activities are required to ensure that misconceptions about the setting do not influence willingness to accept referral to MBSS services and integration of services is needed to enable consistency in referral and discharge processes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2023 11:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231162402?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reprint: How Teacher Education Matters</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/74/2&quot;&gt;Volume 74, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 151-156, March/April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Despite longstanding criticisms of teacher education, the weight of substantial evidence indicates that teachers who have had more preparation for teaching are more confident and successful with students than those who have had little or none. Recent evidence also indicates that reforms of teacher education creating more tightly integrated programs with extended clinical preparation interwoven with coursework on learning and teaching produce teachers who are both more effective and more likely to enter and stay in teaching. An important contribution of teacher education is its development of teachers’ abilities to examine teaching from the perspective of learners who bring diverse experiences and frames of reference to the classroom.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2023 10:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231161863?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reprint: The Problem of Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/74/2&quot;&gt;Volume 74, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 123-126, March/April 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2023 10:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231161446?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
