<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Education Save Us From Ourselves? Three Psychological Challenges to Democracy</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This review brings social science literature into conversation with education to understand how three psychological challenges—motivated reasoning, misinformation, and conspiracy theories—have been studied in educational research. After describing the challenges, how they function, and how they contribute to democratic backsliding, the authors explore the frequency, orientation, and proposed interventions to these challenges in 59 educational research articles published between 2016 and 2022. We categorize approaches to the challenges as Rational, Affective, or Blended Rational/Affective to describe their framing in educational research. Rational frameworks were the most common, while few studies used Affective frames. The few studies featuring an educational intervention emphasized rational thinking over affective or motivational processes. We suggest ways to bolster understanding of problems created by motivated reasoning, misinformation, and conspiratorial thinking and argue for increased attention to the affective and political nature of these challenges in educational research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2024 08:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241288245?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The production of a child in conflict in teacher education – research on available storylines</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2024 04:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2425335?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Theatre of the oppressed for empowerment and research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-06-2024 01:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2419500?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Relational knowledge and young people’s cancer care: how community-based participatory research promotes learning and directs action in practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-06-2024 01:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2420901?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Intra-acting with the self: diffracting reflexivity in action-based research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-06-2024 01:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2424286?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Addressing the pressing issues of our time</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-05-2024 12:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2424023?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Education for Tolerance</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-05-2024 05:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2407245?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creativity in education: International perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-05-2024 04:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2423505?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modelling mathematics for educational research and practice: a comparison of two theoretical approaches</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The production and use of explicit models of mathematics are important elements of research in Didactics of Mathematics. In this paper, we present and compare two different European approaches to didactical modelling. The first, centred around the notion of basic idea (Grundvorstellung), arose in German-speaking countries as a development within Subject Matter Didactics (Stoffdidaktik). The second is the notion of praxeology from the Anthropological Theory of the Didactic, which originated in France. After presenting the genesis and interpretation of these notions as theoretical modelling tools, we provide a detailed case study of actual models produced with these tools, concerning the notion of limits and derivatives. Furthermore, we identify similarities and differences of both models in how they can support didactical research and practice, for instance, by identifying important phenomena or problems. We conclude that the two approaches offer important, different and, to some extent, complementary positions and perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10368-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Taking Time for a Vacation</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-05-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00337-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning Opportunities for Solving Context-Based Calculus Tasks in Nepal’s High School Mathematics Textbooks</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2024 11:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2422232?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of Virtual Tutoring on Young Readers: Results From a Randomized Controlled Trial</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In-person tutoring has been shown to improve academic achievement. Fewer studies have examined the impact of virtual tutoring and have focused on older students. We present findings from the first randomized controlled trial of virtual tutoring for young children. Students in grades K–2 were assigned to 1:1 tutoring, 2:1 tutoring, or a control group. Virtual tutoring increased early literacy skills by 0.05-SD for all students and 0.08-SD for a sample excluding English learners and students with disabilities (i.e., students not eligible for additional support services). One-on-one tutoring tended to produce larger gains, especially for students initially scoring well below benchmark (0.15-SD). Effects are smaller than typically seen from in-person early literacy tutoring programs but still positive and statistically significant.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2024 10:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241288845?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Weeks After the Raid: The Immediate and Sustained Changes in Student Attendance Rates Following Immigration Arrests</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Recent research has shown the ways in which immigration enforcement actions can affect educational outcomes for all students, regardless of their immigrant status. One consequence of particular concern is student absenteeism, a non-academic indicator used by 37 states to evaluate school success under the Every Student Succeeds Act. However, previous research has faced data limitations on the measure of immigration enforcement and relies on aggregated measures of educational outcomes. Using weekly attendance rates of a school district as well as unique data collection on immigration arrests between 2014 and 2018, this study used single and comparative interrupted time series analyses to quantify the immediate and sustained impacts of immigration arrests on student attendance. Findings suggest that incidents involving a greater number of immigration arrests correspond to immediate spikes in student absenteeism, as high as 11% points for certain student demographics. Additionally, the district’s attendance rate sustained a cumulative 2%-point decline following two incidents involving the greatest number of arrests. Implications for policymakers and educators are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2024 10:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241288838?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing Atlanta’s Placed-Based College Scholarship</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;We investigate whether and how Achieve Atlanta’s college scholarship and associated services impact college enrollment, persistence, and graduation among Atlanta Public School graduates experiencing low household income. Qualifying for the scholarship of up to $5,000 per year does not meaningfully change college enrollment among those near the high school GPA eligibility thresholds. However, scholarship receipt does have large and statistically significant effects on early college persistence (i.e., 14%) that continue through BA degree completion within 4 years (22%), although scholarship receipt does not impact graduation from 2-year colleges. We discuss how the selection criteria and processes of place-based programs intended for those from economically disadvantaged backgrounds may influence results for different types of students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2024 05:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241287459?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Marketing a culture of achievement to Black and Brown students: TNTP and neoliberal multiculturalism</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2024 12:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2419133?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing initial notions of variability when learning about box plots</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2024 05:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2421412?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘We are changed yet the same…we can make a difference’: using a critical, creative, collaborative inquiry process to understand and develop professional artistry in nursing</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2024 02:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2420331?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Edgar H. Schein’s Process Consultation: the book that changed my life</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2024 02:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2421971?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Workplace Inclusion in Academia: The Relationship between Diversity Climate and Engineering Faculty Turnover Intentions</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;The purpose of this study is to examine the relationship between engineering faculties’ perception of the diversity climate and their turnover intentions at R1 (Research 1) universities across the U.S. We sampled 1,101 tenure-track engineering faculty for this purpose. Data analysis showed that an engineering faculty’s demographic characteristics (i.e., sex, race/ethnicity, professor rank, age, engineering areas, marriage status, and tenure-track status) are associated with their perceptions of the diversity climate. Furthermore, results from structural equation modeling analyses show that faculty with higher perceptions of organizational fairness and inclusion reported a lower desire to turn over. Implications for the results are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-31-2024 08:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241290741?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tracking Procedures and Criteria and the SES Bias in Teacher Track Recommendations</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The allocation of students to ability tracks is often based on teacher recommendations. These recommendations tend to be biased in favor of students from higher socioeconomic status (SES) backgrounds. While tracking procedures and criteria have been proposed to play a role herein, empirical research is lacking. Using a survey experiment and information from 221 teachers in 69 Dutch schools, I find that teachers in the same school vary in their interpretation of their school’s procedure and (relatedly) their own tracking criteria. Teachers who perceive the school procedure to put more weight on students’ home environment, and/or (relatedly) put more weight on this themselves, show a stronger SES bias in track recommendations in the survey experiment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-31-2024 08:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241288212?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inclusive Strategies for Children With Developmental Disabilities in Mainstream Classrooms in African Countries: A Systematic Review of Stakeholder Experiences, Attitudes, and Perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;African children with developmental disabilities (DD), including autism and intellectual disability, are often excluded from mainstream schools. We systematically reviewed 28 qualitative studies conducted in Africa, aiming to synthesize stakeholders’ perspectives on inclusive teaching strategies for supporting children with DD in mainstream classes. Six interrelated themes were developed using thematic analysis. Teachers strived to meet learners’ needs through teaching and task adaptations (Theme 1) and provide targeted support, reinforcement, and feedback (Theme 2). Teachers’ inclusive pedagogies, while sometimes creating divisions, often reflected a whole-class approach (Theme 3), especially in promoting inclusive environments (Theme 4) and engaging teaching (Theme 5). Authors of reviewed studies often discussed how teachers’ strategies fit in with the evidence base (Theme 6). While teachers’ inclusion efforts appeared progressive, they were mostly based on Western pedagogies and challenged by limited resources and training. Training efforts based on indigenous pedagogies could improve use and outcomes of inclusive strategies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-31-2024 01:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241288247?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Rise and Fall of the Teaching Profession: Prestige, Interest, Preparation, and Satisfaction Over the Last Half Century</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We examine the state of the U.S. K–12 teaching profession over the last half century by compiling nationally representative time-series data on four interrelated constructs: occupational prestige, interest among students, the number of individuals preparing for entry, and on-the-job satisfaction. We find a consistent and dynamic pattern across every measure: a rapid decline in the 1970s, a swift rise in the 1980s extending into the mid-1990s, relative stability, and then a sustained decline beginning around 2010. The current state of the teaching profession is at or near its lowest levels in 50 years. We identify and explore a range of hypotheses that might explain these historical patterns including economic and sociopolitical factors, education policies, and school environments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-31-2024 01:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241276856?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Progression in units coordination: initial counterevidence for a transition that transcends mathematical domains</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2024 12:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2421055?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Need-Based Promise Programs, Performance Funding Bonuses, and the Enrollment of Low-Income Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Certain statewide promise programs require students to demonstrate financial need, while state performance funding policies sometimes incorporate a financial bonus that incentivizes colleges to enroll or graduate low-income students. We use data on public, 4-year colleges from 2007–2008 to 2019–2020, and incorporate difference-in-differences analyses and event studies. We find that colleges affected by promise programs in Louisiana, New York, and Washington observed no changes to the number and percent of first-time, full-time (FTFT) Pell grant recipients. Colleges in states subject to a performance funding bonus experienced no changes to the number and percent of FTFT Pell grants recipients, and colleges in Louisiana subject to both policies experienced no changes to either outcome.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-30-2024 07:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241287410?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
