<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 7 C’s framework for participatory action research: inducting novice participant-researchers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-12-2023 12:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2234417?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Constructivist and Transmissive Mentoring: Effects on Teacher Self-Efficacy, Emotional Management, and the Role of Novices’ Initial Beliefs</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Mentoring is acknowledged as an essential prerequisite for successful teacher induction, but its effectiveness may vary depending on the mentor’s quality of support and the mentee’s initial professional beliefs. Focusing on novice teachers’ self-efficacy and emotional management, this longitudinal study investigates how constructivist- and transmission-oriented mentoring approaches support beginning teachers’ professional development, and how these approaches interact with the novices’ initial beliefs about teaching and learning. The data stem from a sample of 138 beginning teachers who participated in an online survey during their second and third trimesters of practical training in Germany. Moderated regression analyses indicate positive effects of constructivist mentoring on teacher self-efficacy 6 months later, and an enhancing moderation effect of mentees’ mismatching, transmissive beliefs. Results neither support distinct effects of constructivist mentoring on novices’ emotional management nor associations between transmissive mentoring and the outcomes. Implications for mentoring research and practice are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-12-2023 06:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231185371?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Choosing Alone? Peer Continuity Disparities in Choice-Based Enrollment Systems</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We provide novel evidence on the broader impacts of school choice systems by quantifying disparities in peer continuity from middle to high school in New York City. We find that Black and Hispanic students and those in high-poverty neighborhoods attend high school with a much smaller fraction of their middle school or neighborhood peers than their White, Asian, and low-poverty neighborhood counterparts. Disparities also emerge in peer isolation: 27% and 20% of Black and Hispanic students transitioned with no other student from their middle school, while only 7% to 8% of White and Asian students did. Group differences in choice similarity, which in part reflects systematic variation in the number of local school options, drive this result.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-12-2023 03:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231184185?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Multidimensional Partially Compensatory Response Time Model on Basis of the Log-Normal Distribution</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In the existing multidimensional extensions of the log-normal response time (LNRT) model, the log response times are decomposed into a linear combination of several latent traits. These models are fully compensatory as low levels on traits can be counterbalanced by high levels on other traits. We propose an alternative multidimensional extension of the LNRT model by assuming that the response times can be decomposed into two response time components. Each response time component is generated by a one-dimensional LNRT model with a different latent trait. As the response time components—but not the traits—are related additively, the model is partially compensatory. In a simulation study, we investigate the recovery of the model’s parameters. We also investigate whether the fully and the partially compensatory LNRT model can be distinguished empirically. Findings suggest that parameter recovery is good and that the two models can be distinctly identified under certain conditions. The utility of the model in practice is demonstrated with an empirical application. In the empirical application, the partially compensatory model fits better than the fully compensatory model.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2023 09:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231184153?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“They Asked for More, More, and More Paperwork”: Administrative Burdens When Undocumented Youth Claim In-State Resident Tuition Policy Benefits</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Undocumented immigrants face learning, compliance, and psychological costs when confronting in-state resident tuition (ISRT) policy implementation. Building on administrative burdens scholarship and using qualitative data from 19 semi-structured interviews with undocumented youth immigrants, this article examines administrative burdens that may discourage and prevent students from accessing ISRT policy—a public benefit aimed at extending their educational opportunities. Findings demonstrate that undocumented youth navigate multifaceted contexts, including multiple rules at different organizational levels and interactions with admissions officers whose attitudes may facilitate or obstruct access. This study spotlights how some intended beneficiaries may be more affected by stigma and fear, depriving them of accessing public benefits. Furthermore, the study shows how bureaucratic procedures reinforce existing social inequalities by affecting those less well-positioned to address burdens.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231182672?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the impact of an online learning community to support student teachers on school placement</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2023 02:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2232943?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Implementing profession orientation as a design principle for overcoming Klein’s second discontinuity – preservice teacher’s perspectives on interface activities in the context of a geometry course</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01508-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Influences on student decisions to enrol in higher-level mathematics courses</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Addressing the participation rates in senior secondary mathematics courses in Australian schools remains a critically important issue. In this paper, the authors report on quantitative findings from a study in which all year 11 and year 12 (aged 17–18 years) Australian Tertiary Admissions Ranking (ATAR) students in Western Australia were invited to participate. The aim was to explore the perceptions of these students regarding their enrolment in higher-level mathematics courses. Data from 1633 students were collected using a survey instrument comprised of 12, 5-point, Likert-scale items. Data were analysed by applying two statistical procedures: calculating frequencies of the 12 items in the scale and examining associations with demographic characteristics and individual items through generalised linear modelling. Analyses indicated most students agreed that other courses of study were more attractive, with almost half indicating that they did not like mathematics. In addition, approximately half of the students said that they did not need to enrol in any mathematics course for ATAR or for university entrance. Significant findings were also identified for gender, school type, and school gender. The knowledge gained from this research is valuable in understanding students’ reasons for choosing not to enrol in higher-level mathematics courses when they have the option to do so and, more broadly, to address persistently low or declining participation rates in these areas of study.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00467-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“My Discipline is Never Going to Survive if it Continues Being the Discipline of Straight White Men”: Experiences of LGBQ + Science Postdoctoral Scholars in Canada</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;A small but growing body of research confirms that people in the LGBTQ + (lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and other identities) community are among those underrepresented in STEM (science, technology engineering, and math). This is concerning because diversity and inclusion improves science for all. In response, Canadian institutions have developed initiatives aimed to address issues in which LGBTQ + students disproportionately leave STEM fields. LGBTQ + postdoctoral scholars (postdocs) are of particular interest because they have developed clear professional and LGBTQ + identities, they are significant contributors to their fields, and they work at the intersection of STEM students and faculty. Studies have highlighted poor job satisfaction and career opportunities for this group. This qualitative study explored the values, beliefs, and experiences of 14 Canadian LGBQ + postdocs in STEM through semi-structured interviews about coming out, experiences of LGBQ + mentorship/representation, and their beliefs on staying within science and academia. Interview data was analyzed thematically from a post-structural perspective. Main themes emerged: (1) coming out, (2) representation, and (3) mentorship. This exploratory qualitative study offers insight into how the experiences of this understudied group are helpful in disentangling discourses surrounding coming out, representation, and mentorship for LGBQ + researchers in STEM.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-11-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00275-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Relationship Between Epistemic Actions and Mathematics Achievement at the Elementary School Level</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2023 06:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2233349?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Sustained Impact of Future Forward on Reading Achievement, Attendance, and Special Education Placement 5 Years After Participation?</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Future Forward leverages both tutoring and parent engagement to support the literacy development of early primary students. In 2010, Future Forward was awarded an Investing in Innovations grant to develop and test its impact in seven Milwaukee Public Schools, primarily serving Black and Latinx students. A randomized control trial evaluation found 2 years of participation had positive impacts on foundational literacy, reading achievement, and school attendance (Jones &amp;amp; Christian, 2021). We followed participants 5 years past the end of the i3 study to determine whether benefits were sustained. Students receiving Future Forward continued to demonstrate improved reading achievement, school attendance, and were less likely to be placed into special education. Even considering this, Future Forward participants fell behind in their reading development over time.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2023 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231182629?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>New Zealand primary school students’ motivation and strategy use for learning Chinese-as-a-foreign-language</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2023 03:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2227846?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Multiple pathways for developing functional thinking in elementary mathematics textbooks: a case study in China</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;
      Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;
      The mathematics education literature indicates a consensus regarding the importance of developing algebraic thinking in elementary school mathematics. However, the approaches used to implement this concept vary around the world. This study examines how a popular standards-based elementary mathematics textbook series in China provides opportunities to learn about functional thinking, which is a key component of algebraic thinking. Building on the literature, an analytical framework was generated to examine the features of function-related tasks in the textbook series across grades. The results of the fine-grained coding analysis show that four categories of function-related tasks in the textbook provide opportunities to learn about multi-modes of functional thinking. These tasks primarily serve to enhance arithmetic learning, while offering opportunities to learn about functional thinking as an embedded component. Elaborated design and arrangement of the function tasks promote opportunities to learn about multiple modes of functional thinking. In addition, two pathways to support the development of functional thinking are identified. Finally, the implications for task design and textbook development which attempt to develop functional thinking are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10237-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Refutations and Reasoning in Undergraduate Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper concerns undergraduate mathematics students’ understandings of refutation and their related performance in abstract conditional inference. It reports on 173 responses to a refutation instrument that asked participants to: 1) state ‘true’ or ‘false’ for three statements, providing counterexamples or reasons if they thought these false (all three were false); 2) evaluate possible counterexamples and reasons, where reasons were ‘corrected’ versions of the statements but not valid refutations; and 3) choose which of the counterexamples and the corrected statements were better answers, explaining why. The data show that students reliably understood the logic of counterexamples but did not respond normatively according to the broader logic of refutations. Many endorsed the corrected statements as valid and chose these as better responses; we analyse their explanations using Toulmin’s model of argumentation. The data further show that participants with better abstract conditional inference scores were more likely to respond normatively by giving, endorsing, and choosing counterexamples as refutations; conditional inference scores also predicted performance in a proof-based course.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-10-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00220-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racial and Ethnic Disparities in Adolescent Teaching Career Expectations</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Research on the dearth of teachers of color has focused on disparities in college enrollment, completion, and academic major. The present study examines whether disparities may begin earlier. Analyses of nationally representative longitudinal data show that students of color are 2 to 4 percentage points less likely to hold teaching career expectations than White students in Grade 9—a pattern that remains stable during high school and 7 years later. Controlling for academic and socioeconomic backgrounds reduces the gap between Latinx and White students, but the gap persists for students of other racial and ethnic minority groups. Additional findings show early teaching career expectations relate to racial and ethnic disparities among college students who major in education. The study has implications for improving teacher diversity and rethinking pipeline challenges.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2023 09:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231184839?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>AP Calculus and Science Coursetaking: Their Relationships With Choosing a STEM Major and Expecting to Be in a STEM Occupation</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Some researchers have questioned whether there is a causal connection between Advanced Placement (AP) STEM coursetaking and the choice of a STEM college major and a STEM occupation. Their research findings strongly suggest that if prior interest in STEM as well as other possible confounders are taken into account, the relationships of taking AP mathematics to expecting to be in a STEM major and/or a STEM occupation are small to nonexistent. Results from the current study, which uses data from a national longitudinal sample—actual measures of who majors in STEM—and prior interest in STEM along with other possible confounders, indicate that taking AP mathematics and AP science courses is significantly related to majoring in STEM and/or expecting to be in a STEM occupation at age 30—the sole exception being the taking of AP statistics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2023 09:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231184426?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Right to Belong in School: A Critical, Transdisciplinary Conceptualization of School Belonging</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Belonging is a critical factor for supporting student success and well-being in school. Unfortunately, the work of fostering belonging at school for all students continues to face significant challenges. One reason is that the field of education is working from a limited conception of school belonging, based mainly in the discipline of psychology. Belonging is more than just a psychological sense—it is also a social, cultural, and even political process. In this article, Paul Kuttner explores six aspects of belonging that are underemphasized in the school belonging literature, arguing that we should think of school belonging as agentic, intersectional, systemic, political, place-based, and a right. Kuttner proposes a definition of belonging that encompasses these aspects and uses it to suggest future directions for research and practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2023 08:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231183407?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Combined use of the extended theory of connections and the onto-semiotic approach to analyze mathematical connections by relating the graphs of f and f’</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The literature reports that students have difficulties connecting different meanings, multiple representations of the derivative, and performing reversibility processes between representations of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt;. The research goal is to analyze the mathematical connections that university students establish when solving tasks that involve the graphs of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt; when the two functions do not have associated symbolic expressions. Seven students from the first year of undergraduate studies in mathematics from a university in southern Mexico participated. For data collection, two tasks involving the graphical context of the derivative were applied. An analysis of the mathematical activity was carried out by the participants with the analysis model proposed by the onto-semiotic approach, and thematic analysis with types of mathematical connections from the extended theory of connections was carried out to infer the connections made in that mathematical activity, which allowed us to consider the reversibility connection between the graphs of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt; as the encapsulation of a portion of the mathematical activity. Four students establish the reversibility relationship between the graph of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and the graph of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt;. It has been concluded that some students can establish the reversibility connection between the graphs of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;f’&lt;/em&gt;, but the complexity of the mathematical activity that encapsulates the connection explains (by showing everything that the student must do) why some students are not able to establish it.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10246-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Learning from the history of mathematics education. Alexander Karp (Ed.) (2022). Advances in the history of mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-08-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10251-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Entanglements of Mathematics Education Research and Large-Scale Assessment: Rethinking Formulas as Relational</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-06-2023 07:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2222860?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/45/3&quot;&gt;Volume 45, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Fall 2023, Page 183-184&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-06-2023 01:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2228618?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice English Teachers’ Preparedness to Teach: Stakeholders’ Perceptions in Teaching Practicum</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Preservice English language teachers (PSTs) realize and shape their perceptions regarding preparedness to teach during their education. However, being prepared to teach is complex and multifaceted and requires individual factors and interaction with context and other people. Therefore, understanding it from stakeholders’ lens is needed. Within a descriptive and exploratory design, one-on-one, semistructured interviews were conducted with 8 faculty advisors (FAs) and 11 cooperating teachers (CTs) supervising PSTs in primary, secondary, and high schools in a northwestern city in Türkiye. The data collected in teaching practicum stage of field experience was coded and categorized via constant comparison method of analysis. The FAs, except for few issues, regarded the PSTs as unprepared to teach, while the CTs did as prepared to teach. The emergence of a perception gap could show lack of common understanding and mismatch between the stakeholders’ perceptions regarding their standards of and approaches toward high-quality teacher preparation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2023 12:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231185369?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Gender Differences in Leadership Aspirations: A Four-Year Longitudinal Study of College Students From Adverse Backgrounds</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The gender disparity in leadership positions is substantial and critical yet persists despite decades of focused study. Critical developmental periods, such as emerging adulthood, may be particularly relevant to attend to if we hope to find effective interventions to tackle this problem. The present study draws on longitudinal data covering four years of college among a socio-demographically and nationally diverse sample of college students with adverse backgrounds (N = 404) who enrolled at one of 182 four-year colleges or universities across the United States. Results indicate that female students enter college with significantly lower levels of leadership aspirations than their male counterparts. Once in college, despite greater likelihoods of participating in activities conceptualized as “leadership learning experiences,” female disadvantages persist. Overall, development experiences over four years of college had no discernable effect on gender disparities in leadership aspirations. Implications for research and practice are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2023 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231183665?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward a Shared Conception of Children’s Content Area Identities in Literacy, Math, and Science: A Systematic Integrative Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The concept of identity has been used to interrogate a wide range of topics about children’s learning in the content areas, including learning in literacy, math, and science. Despite this, there is a paucity of attention to how the construct of identities is conceptualized across content areas. This systematic integrative review aims to develop an empirically grounded view of how identities are conceptualized in childhood across content areas and to consider the feasibility of a shared conception of content area identities. To do this, the review examines 66 articles on content area identities in early childhood and childhood (birth through Grade 5). Findings show diverse theories are used to examine content area identities in children and at the same time significant consensus in the underlying assumptions about what content area identities are and how they develop. These findings suggest that researchers move away from the current siloed approach to content area identity research and toward a more connected field of study.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-05-2023 06:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231184888?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
