<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modern mathematics: an international movement?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2023 07:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2298119?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical tools for real-world applications: a gentle introduction for students and practitioners</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-24-2023 07:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2023.2298118?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Students to the Role of Assumptions in Mathematical Activity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-22-2023 01:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2023.2293695?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Describing a teacher’s pedagogical mathematical knowledge in STEM teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Describing and analyzing teaching practice has been a focus of researchers interested in the interaction and connections between teachers’ content knowledge and their pedagogical knowledge. This study described the role of a teacher’s mathematical content and pedagogical content knowledge in involving students in learning and solving Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM) problems in an Australian primary school context. The Knowledge Quartet (KQ) is a widely recognised framework originally developed to observe classroom mathematics teaching and analyze mathematics teaching practices. We use the KQ as a theoretical/organizational framework against which to thematically analyze one teacher’s classroom pedagogy to investigate 1) the utility of the KQ framework for describing and analyzing a teacher’s mathematical lesson within an integrated STEM inquiry context and 2) how a teacher’s pedagogical mathematical knowledge supports a focus on inquiry-based STEM integrated teaching. The study involved a teacher and 26 Year 5 students in an Australian classroom. Data included classroom video recordings, researcher observation notes, and students’ artefacts. The video recordings were transcribed and analyzed using the KQ framework. The observation notes and artefacts were used to validate and support this analysis. The paper identifies and provides examples of different aspects of the KQ in the teaching sequence and provides examples of how integrated STEM content can be effectively incorporated into the primary school classroom. The relevance and significance of the KQ framework and the teaching of integrated STEM content in primary school are reviewed and discussed within the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-22-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00480-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Simple Technique Assessing Ordinal and Disordinal Interaction Effects</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Previous research explicates ordinal and disordinal interactions through the concept of the “crossover point.” This point is determined via simple regression models of a focal predictor at specific moderator values and signifies the intersection of these models. An interaction effect is labeled as disordinal (or ordinal) when the crossover point falls within (or outside) the observable range of the focal predictor. However, this approach might yield erroneous conclusions due to the crossover point’s intrinsic nature as a random variable defined by mean and variance. To statistically evaluate ordinal and disordinal interactions, a comparison between the observable range and the confidence interval (CI) of the crossover point is crucial. Numerous methods for establishing CIs, including reparameterization and bootstrap techniques, exist. Yet, these alternative methods are scarcely employed in social science journals for assessing ordinal and disordinal interactions. This note introduces a straightforward approach for calculating CIs, leveraging an extension of the Johnson–Neyman technique.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231217472?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Simpler standard errors for two-stage optimization estimators revisited</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1057-1061, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;“Simpler standard errors for two-stage optimization estimators” (Terza, 2016a, Stata Journal 16: 368–385) offers an analytic simplification of the daunting textbook formulations of the asymptotic variance–covariance matrix of a class of two-stage optimization estimators. Here I revisit that simplification and show that it applies to a much broader class of estimators than was originally considered. I also offer a correction that further enhances the generality of this asymptotic variance–covariance matrix formulation. These points are illustrated via a real-data application.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212445?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Review of A. Colin Cameron and Pravin K. Trivedi’s Microeconometrics Using Stata, Second Edition</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1062-1073, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I review Microeconometrics Using Stata, Second Edition, by A. Colin Cameron and Pravin K. Trivedi (2022, Stata Press).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212446?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Stata Journal Editors’ Prize 2023: Fernando Rios-Avila</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 905-908, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212425?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>pystacked: Stacking generalization and machine learning in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 909-931, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The pystacked command implements stacked generalization (Wolpert, 1992, Neural Networks 5: 241–259) for regression and binary classification via Python’s scikit-learn. Stacking combines multiple supervised machine learners—the “base” or “level-0” learners—into one learner. The currently supported base learners include regularized regression, random forest, gradient boosted trees, support vector machines, and feed-forward neural nets (multilayer perceptron). pystacked can also be used as a “regular” machine learning program to fit one base learner and thus provides an easy-to-use application programming interface for scikit-learn‘s machine learning algorithms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212426?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Review of Alan Acock’s A Gentle Introduction to Stata, Revised Sixth Edition</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1074-1081, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I review A Gentle Introduction to Stata, Revised Sixth Edition, by Alan Acock (2023, Stata Press).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212448?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>ardl: Estimating autoregressive distributed lag and equilibrium correction models</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 983-1019, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We present a command, ardl, for the estimation of autoregressive distributed lag (ARDL) models in a time-series context. The ardl command can be used to fit an ARDL model with the optimal number of autoregressive and distributed lags based on the Akaike or Bayesian (Schwarz) information criterion. The regression results can be displayed in the ARDL levels form or in the error-correction representation of the model. The latter separates long-run and short-run effects and is available in two different parameterizations of the long-run (cointegrating) relationship. The popular bounds-testing procedure for the existence of a long-run levels relationship is implemented as a postestimation feature. Comprehensive critical values and approximate p-values obtained from response-surface regressions facilitate statistical inference.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212434?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Data management and techniques for best–worst discrete choice experiments</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1020-1044, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we present software that is suitable for use with Stata’s choice modeling suite of commands, which begin with cm. Within the context of choice models, we focus on best–worst data. In such data, respondents are presented a set of choices and are required to select a best and a worst choice from among the alternatives. Optionally, respondents may indicate an opt-out choice, in which no best or worst choice exists in the choice set. Such data are simplified versions of experiments in which respondents rank all the choices. Once best–worst data are collected, there are specific types of data expansions that analysts use to take advantage of both explicit and implicit information. The commands described in this article support data expansion and model estimation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212437?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Introduction to Stata for Health Researchers review</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1082-1085, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I review An Introduction to Stata for Health Researchers, by Svend Juul and Morten Frydenberg (2021, Stata Press).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212452?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>csa2sls: A complete subset approach for many instruments using Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 932-941, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We developed a command, csa2sls, that implements the complete subset averaging two-stage least-squares (CSA2SLS) estimator in Lee and Shin (2021, Econometrics Journal 24: 290–314). The CSA2SLS estimator is an alternative to the two-stage least-squares estimator that remedies the bias issue caused by many correlated instruments. We conduct Monte Carlo simulations and confirm that the CSA2SLS estimator reduces both the mean squared error and the estimation bias substantially when instruments are correlated. We illustrate the usage of csa2sls in Stata with an empirical application.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212432?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Speaking Stata: Finding the denominator: Minimum sample size from percentages</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1086-1095, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Percentage breakdowns for a series of classes or categories are sometimes reported without a specification of class frequencies or even the total sample size. This column surveys the problem of estimating the minimum sample size and class frequencies consistent with a reported breakdown and a particular resolution. I introduce and explain a new command, find_denom. Rounding quirks whereby a total is reported as above or below 100% are discussed as a complication.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212453?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Updates</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1096-1096, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212454?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leverage, influence, and the jackknife in clustered regression models: Reliable inference using summclust</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 942-982, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;We introduce a new command, summclust, that summarizes the cluster structure of the dataset for linear regression models with clustered disturbances. The key unit of observation for such a model is the cluster. We therefore propose cluster-level measures of leverage, partial leverage, and influence and show how to compute them quickly in most cases. The measures of leverage and partial leverage can be used as diagnostic tools to identify datasets and regression designs in which cluster–robust inference is likely to be challenging. The measures of influence can provide valuable information about how the results depend on the data in the various clusters. We also show how to calculate two jackknife variance matrix estimators efficiently as a by-product of our other computations. These estimators, which are already available in Stata, are generally more conservative than conventional variance matrix estimators. The summclust command computes all the quantities that we discuss.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212433?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improving flexibility and ease of matrix subsetting: The submatrix command</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1045-1056, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Matrix manipulation in Stata can be a time-consuming and tedious task, especially when it is necessary to subset or rearrange elements from large matrices based on nonconsecutive elements. Compared with Mata, these tasks require more time, more code, and sometimes more complex output. The purpose of this article is to introduce submatrix, a command to manipulate matrix elements using row (and column) names, numbers, and equations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212439?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcements</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/23/4&quot;&gt;Volume 23, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1097-1098, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X231212455?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing Teachers’ Culturally Responsive Classroom Practice in PK–12 Schools: A Systematic Review of Teacher-, Student-, and Observer-Report Measures</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The importance of improving teachers’ use of culturally responsive practice (CRP) in the classroom setting has been widely recognized. Although quantitative data on teachers’ use of CRP has potential to be a helpful decision-making tool in advancing that goal, little is known about the psychometrics of classroom-based CRP measures, their utility in evaluating the impact of interventions designed to improve teacher CRP, or their use to inform teacher professional development in CRP. The current study reports findings from a systematic review of the research on the quantitative measurement of CRP using the 2020 Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic reviews and Meta-Analyses standards to document how CRP is operationalized and measured in prekindergarten–12th-grade classrooms in the United States (U.S.). Searching across six databases, 27 measures were identified for inclusion. The vast majority of measures were teacher self-report surveys, and relatively few were student-report or external observer assessments. We examined the availability of classroom-based observational and survey instruments and critically analyzed each measure through an argument-based approach to validation. We concluded that although some CRP measures hold promise, the validity of their interpretation and use is not adequately supported by evidence, with some exceptions. This lack of empirical evidence is exacerbated by the limitations of single-informant measurement of CRP. More multi-informant assessment approaches are needed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 07:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231208720?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Literature reviews in mathematics education and their significance to the field</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01541-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ professional development needs: a critical analysis of TALIS through structural equation modelling</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2023 10:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2296354?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Summative evaluation” as a teaching method: An opportunity to reduce confirmation bias</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2023 07:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2288840?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How pedagogical content knowledge sharpens prospective teachers’ focus when judging mathematical tasks: an eye-tracking study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teachers’ ability to accurately judge difficulties of mathematical tasks is an essential aspect of their diagnostic competencies. Although research has suggested that pedagogical content knowledge (PCK) is positively correlated with the accuracy of diagnostic judgments, experimental studies have not been conducted to investigate how PCK affects perception and interpretation of relevant task characteristics. In an intervention study with a control group, 49 prospective mathematics teachers judged the difficulty of 20 tasks involving functions and graphs while an eye tracker tracked their eye movements. Some of the tasks included characteristics well known to be difficult for students. Participants’ domain-specific PCK of typical student errors was manipulated through a three-hour intervention, during which they learned about the most common student errors in function and graph problems. We found that the process of perception (relative fixation duration on the relevant area in the tasks) was related to judgment accuracy. Pre-post comparisons revealed an effect of the intervention not only on participants’ domain-specific PCK of typical student errors but also on their perception and interpretation processes. This result suggests that domain-specific PCK of typical student errors allowed participants to focus more efficiently on relevant task characteristics when judging mathematical task difficulties. Our study contributes to our understanding of how professional knowledge makes teachers’ judgment processes of mathematical tasks more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10281-6</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
