<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pushing crisis response towards sustainable transformation? Reflections from a case analysis of crisis-framed policy actions on teacher education in three European settings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-08-2023 09:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2288811?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Children’s subtraction by addition strategy use and their subtraction-related conceptual knowledge</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study is the first to examine the associations between the occurrence, frequency, and adaptivity of children’s subtraction by addition strategy use (SBA; e.g., 712 − 346 = ?; 346 + 54 = 400, 400 + 300 = 700, 700 + 12 = 712, and 54 + 300 + 12 = 366) and their underlying conceptual knowledge. Specifically, we focused on two rarely studied components of conceptual knowledge: children’s knowledge of the addition/subtraction complement principle (i.e., if &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; + &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;b&lt;/em&gt; = &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;c&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;c&lt;/em&gt; − &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;b&lt;/em&gt; = &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;c&lt;/em&gt; − &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; = &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;b&lt;/em&gt;) and their knowledge of different conceptual subtraction models (i.e., understanding that subtraction can be conceived not only as “taking away” but also as “determining the difference”). SBA occurrence was examined using a variability on demand task, in which children had to use multiple strategies to solve a subtraction. SBA frequency and strategy adaptivity were investigated with a task in which children could freely choose between SBA and direct subtraction (e.g., 712 − 346 = ?; 712 − 300 = 412, 412 − 40 = 372, and 372 − 6 = 366) to solve 15 subtractions. We measured both children’s knowledge of the addition/subtraction complement principle, and whether they understood subtraction also as “determining the difference.” SBA occurrence and frequency were not related to conceptual knowledge. However, strategy adaptivity was related to children’s knowledge of the addition/subtraction complement principle. Our findings highlight the importance of attention to conceptual knowledge when teaching multi-digit subtraction and expand the literature about the relation between procedural and conceptual knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-08-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10276-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Réflexions sur le début d’un trimestre</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-08-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00301-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tinkering to Solve Problems That Emerge During Digital Fabrication: Introduction of a New Problem-Solving Model</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The digital age in which we live requires students to be able to solve problems in technology-rich learning environments; however, this skill needs to be better developed in traditional schools. With the growing popularity of Makerspaces in Canadian schools, young people can develop problem-solving skills while working on digital fabrication projects. Nevertheless, how students solve problems in these environments remains to be seen. While many problem-solving models exist, there is an absence of problem-solving models that address how students solve problems that emerge during digital fabrication. Through two of our previous studies on Makerspaces of five New Brunswick schools, we observed the problem-solving process, which brought forth tinkering as an essential phase of the problem-solving process. The purpose of this article is to clarify how students solve problems that emerge during digital fabrication in schools by using data from our previous studies to create a new problem-solving model that highlights the importance of tinkering.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-08-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00294-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The emergence of a distinctive European scholarship of professional development: challenging mainstream conceptualisations, consensus and causality claims</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2023 11:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2289857?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Summative Assessment: A Curriculum Analysis of Pre-Service Language Teacher Education in Sweden and Finland</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The purpose of this study is to investigate the curricular manifestation of summative assessment literacy in language pre-service teacher education at three universities in Sweden and Finland through multiple case studies. Data sources included program guidelines, course curricula, and study guides. A thematic approach was used to analyze the data based on a theoretical framework involving conceptual understandings, skills, and dispositions in summative assessment. The results indicate that all programs emphasize the basic assessment concepts such as validity and alignment and using assessment to inform teaching and learning. However, compared with formative assessment, summative assessment receives less attention in the curriculum. There are differences in addressing summative assessment through stand-alone and embedded courses and in the literacy areas covered. Implications for teacher education to address summative aspects of assessment in line with teachers’ tasks in schools are offered.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2023 11:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231214799?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Dis-Ability a Foregone Conclusion? Research and Policy Solutions to Disproportionality</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Research on disproportionate representation in special education has potential to influence policy in ways that rectify educational inequities. In this study, we investigated how disproportionality researchers have operationalized dis-ability, identified key themes and theories used in disproportionality research, and evaluated the coherence between this research and related policy. We found that studies using medical/rehabilitative frameworks to define disability tended to offer policy recommendations focused on preventing inappropriate identification and enhancing access to early interventions. In contrast, studies situated in social models of dis-ability tended to offer policy recommendations for holistic improvement of educational systems. Finally, disproportionality studies applying legal frameworks tended to advocate for explicit policies regarding race and racism without attending to ableism. Given that federal policy continues to operate from a deficit perspective regarding student variability, we contend that deficit-oriented recommendations for change are unlikely to improve students’ experiences in schools and related outcomes. We discuss the need for disproportionality research to inform policy through frameshifting.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2023 06:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231212935?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Computer Assisted Learning and Academic Performance in Rural Taiwan</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2023 04:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2279167?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does Universal SEL Work under Typical Implementation Practices? Outcomes of a First Grade Effectiveness Trial</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2023 04:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2279124?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reading Skills Transfer Best from Home Language to a Second Language: Policy Lessons from Two Field Experiments in South Africa</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2023 04:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2279123?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Integration of Coding and Computer Science Concepts in Canadian K-8 Curriculum</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this article, the relatively new phenomenon of integrating coding and computer science (CS) related concepts and skills into the K-8 grades is analysed through a comparative analysis of related provincial curriculum initiatives in Canada. First, provincial K-8 curricula that include coding and CS related concepts and skills are identified, as well as the placement of these components within the provincial policy documents. This is followed by a comparative analysis of stated aims and objectives of the curriculum components, and an analysis of the selected concepts and skills themselves. Throughout this analysis, context is provided by theory in the field, as well as the general approaches from jurisdictions outside of Canada, which have been found in the literature. What results is a comparative analysis of this nascent curriculum topic as well as important insights for educators, policy makers, and researchers alike.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00293-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Minoritized Student Representation in Promoting Achievement and Equity Within College STEM Courses</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In the context of continued equity gaps in student success within and beyond STEM, this paper explored the extent to which the representation of underrepresented racial minority (URM) and first-generation college students predict grades in postsecondary STEM courses. The analyses examined 87,027 grades received by 11,868 STEM-interested students within 8,468 STEM courses at 20 institutions. Cross-classified multilevel models and student fixed effects analyses of these data both support the same conclusion: the proportion of URM and first-generation students within a class is positively associated with STEM grades among all students, and these relationships are stronger among students who are members of the minoritized group. Thus, promoting the representation of students with minoritized identities in STEM courses may lead to greater equity in college outcomes.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2023 11:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231209957?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher-Principal Ethnoracial Matching, Geography, and Novice Teacher Career Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Nationally, many school districts face a sustainability crisis in teacher workforce, and job retention for novice teachers of color is a key area of focus for educational leaders and policymakers. In this study, we draw on nine years of administrative data from Texas K–12 public schools to better understand how teacher-principal ethnoracial matching is associated with patterns of teacher retention and system-exit. Teacher labor markets are geographically small, so we link data from the National Center for Education Statistics containing geographic locale information to explore how the relationship between ethnoracial matching and novice teacher career outcomes varies across urban, suburban, rural, and town school contexts. We find that matching is associated with an increase in the probability of retention and a decrease in the probability of system-exit, with important variation for novice Black and Latinx teachers working in some nonurban school locales.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2023 04:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231213344?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preface to Special Issue on “Evaluation of Policy Conflicts Towards Sustainable Development Goals”—II</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2023 04:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X231220474?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Job demands and resources as predictors of well-being in portuguese teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2023 01:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2288552?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring teachers’ understanding of and responses to the school belonging experiences of students from refugee backgrounds</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2023 01:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2291387?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Listening to learn: investigating how teacher leaders elicit and attend to students’ mathematical thinking in clinical interviews</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Eliciting and attending to students’ thinking is an important component of teaching mathematics for understanding. Clinical interview protocols have shown the potential to support teachers in developing these skills. However, less is known about how to support teacher leaders’ knowledge and development of these skills. Given that teacher leaders provide opportunities to foster teachers’ knowledge of these ideas, more needs to be known about teacher leaders’ abilities and knowledge in this area, and how clinical interviews might support teacher leaders’ pedagogical knowledge. This study explored the nuances in understanding the ways in which teacher leaders elicited and attended to student thinking when conducting clinical interviews. Findings show that while the majority of teacher leaders who engaged in conducting clinical interviews asked probing questions and engaged in observational thinking, they also faced challenges in moving toward responsive listening, particularly when students struggled with providing justification for a task.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09614-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learners’ mathematical identities: exploring relationships between high school learners and significant others</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Many researchers have tried to understand why some learners engage in and others disengage from mathematics by exploring learners’ mathematical identities. Significant others (i.e., teachers, peers and family members) offer learners’ different opportunities for mathematical identity support, but no study has explored their collective role in supporting or constraining learners’ identities. In this paper, we explore how relationships between high school learners and different groups of significant others shaped learners’ narrated mathematical identities. Fifty Grade 10 learners responded to a mathematical identity questionnaire. After analysing the results of the questionnaire, six learners were purposively selected for a semi-structured interview, and the interview data were analysed thematically. Identities are described as robust-leaning, mixed or fragile-leaning, depending on learners’ narrated confidence, persistence, beliefs and sense of belonging to or exclusion from mathematics communities. Relationships with teachers, peers and family members are described as robust-enhancing or fragile-enhancing, depending on the kind of identity encouraged by the relationships. The findings show that many learners narrated fragile-leaning identities, and all the learners showed some robustness and fragility in their identities. The more groups of significant others a learner developed robust-enhancing relationships with, the more likely the learner narrated a robust-leaning identity. We argue that understanding learners’ identities requires understanding their relationships with the three different groups of significant others as a collective.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00479-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using ‘Real-World’ Robotics Competitions to Support Digital Technology Implementation: Impacts of Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reports findings from a study where regional, rural, and remote (RRR) educators were involved in a Queensland Government-funded 3-year Central Queensland (CQ) STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) Cluster Project designed to enhance student learning opportunities. This project provided STEM professional development, with a focus on robotics, helping teachers prepare students for a new regional robotics competition via informal school clubs. It was designed to empower RRR teachers to implement engaging, real-world STEM practices in their schools and focused on how aspects of the Australian Digital Technologies Curriculum (DTC) learning area connected with student robotics learning. Data were collected using survey responses from teachers participating in the professional development (PD). Attending PD significantly improved teacher confidence in supporting student robotics clubs. The project provides some evidence that access to physical resources (robotics kits), effective PD design (hands-on and differentiated learning), and partnerships (industry involvement) are all important for creating sustainable STEM education ecosystems within regional areas.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00298-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ Sense of Efficacy During a Time of Crisis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Technology education (TE) has the creating, making, and doing aspects of human activity at its foundation. This article presents a comparison of the teaching sense of efficacy (TSE) of practising TE teachers and teacher candidates (TC) during a forced switch to emergency remote teaching (ERT). In phase 1, the switch to ERT had a significantly negative effect on TE teachers (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 42; &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; = −0.60). In phase 2, TE TCs (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 16) were similarly affected (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; = −0.53). Results of a two-way mixed ANOVA in phase 3 suggest that ERT had a greater negative impact on practising TE teachers’ TSE for student engagement (partial eta squared = 0.11) and classroom management (partial eta squared = 0.19) than it did on TE TCs’ TSE. As novice teachers tend to draw more from contextual factors than mastery experiences, this research suggests that experienced teachers were at a greater loss due to the pandemic than TCs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00291-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>University and democratization: A training project in action research with social movements</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Current challenges call for a university that assumes a proactive role in the search for a fairer, more egalitarian and democratic world. This study puts action and transformation at the center of academic work, as training students in epistemologies and research methodologies in addition to providing them with new skills allows them to immerse themselves in the social fabric that can accompany the stabilization of community processes. In this text, we present a project within a master’s in community participation and development, in which the students have supported a process of participation by irruption. The internship is a Participatory Action Research project within the framework of a process of consolidating and recognizing a social center occupied by squatters, and it shows two potentials; it means the university students can be trained in a transformational way, and it allows the students to be the protagonists of dynamics which transcend hegemonic academic methodologies and, through teaching and action, support processes of community coordination and the stabilization of democratizing irruption dynamics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2023 01:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231219173?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reflections on the Start of a Term</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00300-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Family Child Care Program Closure in Alabama During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Family child care (FCC) is uniquely positioned to address challenges with insufficient early care and education supply and access in the United States. FCC programs were steadily declining before COVID-19, and many child care programs, both center- and home-based, were at risk of closure early in the pandemic. This study examines closure among Alabama FCC providers during COVID-19. Specifically, we examine the timing and predictors of FCC providers’ closure using discrete time-hazard modeling. We analyze administrative data for the 788 FCC programs licensed in March 2020. Over the following 28 months, FCC closure risk was closely linked with COVID-19 disease spread trends. Providers who participated in child care subsidy or national accreditation had lower closure risk than those who did not. The protective effects of subsidy participation were amplified in lower-opportunity communities. Results have implications for mitigating FCC decline and identifying resources to support FCC providers’ continued operation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 10:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231213083?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The accountability paradigm post-NCLB: Policy Ideas and Moral Narratives</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;For decades, policymakers in the U.S. have leveraged accountability policy as a governing tool to lift school performance and close the achievement gap. Accountability become so widespread that it arguably became a “policy paradigm” with the passage of the federal No Child Left Behind (NCLB) Act in 2002. Yet after just 13 years of implementation, policymakers replaced NCLB with the Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA), which gave states more control over the policy tools and mechanisms to regulate school improvement. This qualitative project captured the evolution of the accountability paradigm by studying the policy ideas and moral narratives of policy elites in California and Tennessee during the transition period between NCLB and ESSA. The study finds that interview participants legitimized the core design features of ESSA, but attached their underlying worldviews and beliefs to the flexible design features, which created unique accountability models with different institutional arrangements.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-04-2023 05:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231215487?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
