<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collaborative Troubleshooting in STEM: A Case Study of High School Students Finding and Fixing Code, Circuit and Craft Challenges in Electronic Textiles</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 06:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2334697?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Novel Numerical Method for Solving Unknown Statistical Quantities in Multivariate Regression Models</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Simulation studies are the basic tools of quantitative methodologists used to obtain empirical solutions to statistical problems that may be impossible to derive through direct mathematical computations. The successful execution of many simulation studies relies on the accurate generation of correlated multivariate data that adhere to a particular model with known parameter values. In this article, we use a kernel inspired by path tracing rules to algebraically solve unknown causal effects in the context of a multivariate general linear model. The algebraic solution is the basis of the mathematical extension, which integrates a model solver. Examples are used to illustrate a range of applications, where information regarding parameter values and predictor correlations can be partially specified. Code for examples is provided.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 04:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241240083?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Extant Data to Improve Estimation of the Standardized Mean Difference</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article presents methods for using extant data to improve the properties of estimators of the standardized mean difference (SMD) effect size. Because samples recruited into education research studies are often more homogeneous than the populations of policy interest, the variation in educational outcomes can be smaller in these samples than is reflective of the true variation in the population. This affects effect size estimation since the sample standard deviation is used in the denominator of the SMD. We propose leveraging extant data on sample variance estimates from multiple studies, made available via clearinghouse databases such as the What Works Clearinghouse, to standardize a mean difference. This allows effect sizes to be benchmarked across a common and broad population, thus enabling better comparability across studies and interventions. We derive the new estimators of the population variance and the corresponding SMD, which pool sample variances from multiple studies using both an analysis of variance and a meta-analytic framework. We demonstrate the properties of these estimators via analytic and simulation results and offer recommendations for when these estimators are appropriate in practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 04:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241238478?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strive for Measurement, Set New Standards, and Try Not to Be Evil</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;I consider recent attempts to establish standards, principles, and goals for artificial intelligence (AI) through the lens of educational measurement. Distinctions are made between generative AI and AI-adjacent methods and applications of AI in formative versus summative assessment contexts. While expressing optimism about its possibilities, I caution that the examples of truly generative AI in educational testing have the potential to be overexaggerated, that efforts to establish standards for AI should complement the Standards for Educational and Psychological Testing and focus attention on the issues of fairness and social responsibility, and that scientific advance and transparency in the development and application of AI in educational assessment may be incompatible with the competitive marketplace that is funding this development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 04:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241238479?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improving Researchers’ Capacity to Address Injustice: An Introduction to the Special Issue</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Many education policy researchers have turned to critical policy analysis as a means to better understand and examine injustices in education and beyond. However, such work is still uncommon in educational journals. In this introduction, we describe the purposes of this special issue and offer readers a framework for understanding critical approaches to education policy research, its general tenets, and how it differs from other kinds of policy research. We then outline the contributions of the articles in this special issue. We highlight analytic moves that researchers of all kinds can make based on the critical education policy research tenets we discuss. The introduction concludes with suggestions for where we hope the field will go next.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241239982?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The key-roles of the expert during classroom discussions aimed at fostering formative assessment processes through the use of digital technologies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We study the experts’ practices developed with the support of digital technologies (DT), when they take aware in-the-moment decisions during classroom discussions to promote the development of effective formative assessment (FA) processes. In this investigation, we complement a macro-analysis of paradigmatic examples of classroom activities, focused on the functionalities of DT and on the implemented FA strategies, with a micro-analysis, developed with reference to a theoretical construct useful for interpreting and analysing expert teachers’ roles during classroom discussions (the Model of Aware and Effective Attitudes and Behaviours, M&lt;sub class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;AE&lt;/sub&gt;AB). More specifically, we explore how the expert uses DT to empower these roles with the aim of promoting FA processes. This study has two implications: (1) at the theoretical level, the study will introduce a model aimed at characterising the ways in which the expert can promote FA during classroom discussions when they are mediated by the use of DT; (2) at the pragmatic level, the use of this model to analyse paradigmatic examples from teaching experiments will introduce potential guidelines for teacher professional development aimed at promoting teachers’ autonomous use of DT to carry out effective FA practices.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-08-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01572-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Heterogeneous Patterns of Family Engagement With Educational Technology to Inform School-Family Communication in Linguistically Diverse Communities</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We leverage log data from an educational app and two-way text message records from over 3,500 students during the summers of 2019 and 2020 and in-depth interviews in Spanish and English to identify patterns of family engagement with educational technology. Based on the type and timing of technology use, we identify several distinct profiles of engagement, which we group into two categories: independent users who engage with technology-based educational software independently and interaction-supported users who use two-way communications to support their engagement. We also find that as the demands of families from schools increased during the COVID-19 pandemic, Spanish-speaking families were significantly more likely than English-speaking families to engage with educational technology across all categories of families, particularly as interaction-supported users.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2024 03:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241238651?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does Aid Matter? A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of the Effects of Grant Aid on College Student Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The College Board reported that, in 2022–2023, about two thirds of $177 billion in U.S. financial assistance awarded to undergraduates through programs sponsored by the federal government, state governments, colleges and universities, philanthropic organizations, and other entities was in the form of grants. While researchers have examined the effects of individual grant aid programs on particular college student outcomes, results have indicated varied effects. Moreover, individual study findings have not been widely synthesized or examined to understand why some programs succeed where others do not. We conducted a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis to provide structure to this varied field and better understand programmatic effects. The results of the systematic searching and screening yielded 86 studies, across seven outcome domains, and the meta-analysis synthesized findings from 709 effect sizes from study samples representing 7,656,062 individuals. The meta-analytic results found small but meaningful positive average effects on college enrollment, credit accumulation, persistence, and completion. We cannot conclude from available studies that grant aid increased academic achievement or postcollege labor market outcomes. We also found that grants had larger positive effects on credit accumulation for studies with samples of students at 2-year institutions and studies that combined samples of 2- and 4-year students than for studies with samples of students at 4-year institutions only. Using a relatively new method called an evidence gap map, we illustrate where researchers should focus on producing new evidence.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2024 02:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241239955?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fostering student teachers’ research-based knowledge of effective feedback</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2024 02:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2338841?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Disentangling Person-Dependent and Item-Dependent Causal Effects: Applications of Item Response Theory to the Estimation of Treatment Effect Heterogeneity</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Analyzing heterogeneous treatment effects (HTEs) plays a crucial role in understanding the impacts of educational interventions. A standard practice for HTE analysis is to examine interactions between treatment status and preintervention participant characteristics, such as pretest scores, to identify how different groups respond to treatment. This study demonstrates that the identical patterns of HTE on test score outcomes can emerge either from variation in treatment effects due to a preintervention participant characteristic or from correlations between treatment effects and item easiness parameters. We demonstrate analytically and through simulation that these two scenarios cannot be distinguished if analysis is based on summary scores alone. We then describe a novel approach that identifies the relevant data-generating process by leveraging item-level data. We apply our approach to a randomized trial of a reading intervention in second grade and show that any apparent HTE by pretest ability is driven by the correlation between treatment effect size and item easiness. Our results highlight the potential of employing measurement principles in causal analysis, beyond their common use in test construction.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-05-2024 01:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241240085?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participants’ perceptions of video-enhanced dialogic assessment as reflective practice in international teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 12:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2338847?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student-driven teaching and educational action research combined: an approach to teaching development and student empowerment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 10:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2337213?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reconceptualizing Parents as Policy Agents Within Special Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Existing research on the implementation of special education (SE) has consistently documented racial inequities in the law’s implementation. We present a new theoretical framework to guide future research. SE law requires parents to act as initiators, developers, and enforcers in the implementation of SE policy. Drawing from law and society research, we demonstrate how the law’s design contributes to structural inequalities because it conscripts parents to work as policy agents. Parents may not be adequately resourced for their role, which contributes to inequalities and makes structural changes difficult. We argue that this framework may shift approaches to research within and beyond SE, helping to reorient approaches to understanding parents’ roles and the reproduction of inequities within educational policy implementation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 04:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241238679?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Situating Teacher Movement, Space, and Relationships to Pedagogy: A Visual Method and Framework</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In conversations about pedagogy, researchers often overlook how physical space and movement shape teacher sensemaking. This article offers a comparative case study of classroom videos using a dynamic visual method to map embodied interaction called “interaction geography.” Our analysis proposes an integrative framework to study classroom interactions and teacher movement over space and time comprised of four salient characteristics within lessons: trails, landmarks, material routines, and circulation patterns. We discuss how this visual method and framework can be used and expanded by classroom researchers and teachers as a starting point to better understand teaching as a situative and spatial practice, a crucial step in characterizing responsive forms of instruction. This work has implications not only for teachers and teacher educators but also for architects, administrators, and researchers concerned with the physical design of classrooms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 04:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241238698?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Adapting feedback to the demands of teaching in diverse classrooms. Novel feedback concepts for preservice teachers during practicum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 01:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2338846?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Re-envisioning pre-service teachers’ beliefs and feelings about assessment: the important space of authentic assignments</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 01:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2338854?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interdependency, alternative forms of mathematical agency and joy as challenges to ableist narratives about the learning and teaching of mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Catering for the mathematical needs of disabled learners equitably and productively requires the anti-ableist preparation and professional development of teachers. In CAPTeaM (Challenging Ableist Perspectives on the Teaching of Mathematics), we design tasks that emulate inclusion-related challenges from the mathematics classroom, and we engage teachers with these tasks in workshop settings. In this paper, we focus on evidence from one type of task in which participants engage in small groups with solving a mathematical problem while at least one of them is temporarily and artificially deprived of access to a sensory field or familiar channel of communication. In this paper, we focus on evidence of emerging resignification – discursive and affective shifts in the participating teachers’ sense-making about what makes the construction of mathematical meaning possible and valuably different – as they work on the tasks. By linking Vygotsky’s vision about the educational changes required to empower and include disabled learners with more contemporary ideas from embodied cognition and disability studies, our analyses show how engagement with the tasks affects participants’ realisation and appreciation of interdependencies between learners, teacher, resources, and emotions, highlights alternative forms of mathematical agency and gives opportunities to turn initial sense of impasse and despair into joy.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01565-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Contributions of the anthropological theory of the didactic to the epistemological programme of research in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In the early 1980s, the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;theory of didactic situations&lt;/em&gt; put the analysis of mathematical activity at the core of the didactic analysis, thus initiating a new research programme in mathematics education: the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;epistemological programme&lt;/em&gt;. This paper describes and interprets some of the contributions of the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;anthropological theory of the didactic&lt;/em&gt; (ATD) to the development of this programme. These contributions come from the new institutional and ecological perspective provided by the ATD to approach the didactic problem and from the significance it assigns to macrodidactic phenomena characterised by didactic transposition. They are illustrated with research works involving different fields of school mathematics in which the ATD team led by Spanish researchers played a central role: research in school algebra and its relations with functional modelling, differential calculus, and real numbers. The paper concludes by briefly describing the contributions of the ATD to the dialogue between didactic theories, another domain that has notable Spanish contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01563-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Differential instructional qualities despite equal tasks: Relevance of school contexts for subdomains of cognitive demands</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Cognitive demand is a crucial dimension of instructional quality. Its heterogenous operationalizations call for refined investigations, with respect to discursive richness (generic conceptualizations) and conceptual richness (subject-related conceptualizations). Considering not only teachers’ intended cognitive activation (operationalized, e.g., by tasks), but also the enacted activation and individual students’ participation as realized in the interaction, raises the question of how far the interaction quality is associated with students’ prerequisites, school context, and class composition. In this paper, we present a video study of leader-led small-group instruction (in 49 groups of 3–6 middle school students each) with the same fraction tasks, so that differences in interaction quality can be scrutinized in generic and subject-related conceptualizations. In spite of equal task quality, large differences occurred in interaction quality across heterogenous class compositions. The regression analyses revealed that the enacted activation and individual participation were significantly associated with the school context (of higher-tracked and lower-tracked schools), but much less with individual learning prerequisites. These findings reveal the need to capture students’ collective and individual engagement in cognitive demands in the interaction and in generic and subject-related conceptualizations and to systematically investigate their association with class composition.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-04-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01552-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptualizing White-Ability Saviorism: A Necessary Reckoning With Ableism in Urban Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;White saviorism is a well-documented phenomenon in the education literature. Particularly, researchers have made connections between white saviorism and teacher preparation for urban contexts serving Students of Color negatively impacted by legacies of systemic racism. Scholars are increasingly taking an intersectional lens to understand the ways in which racism and ableism intersect, yet much of the literature on white saviorism does not critically examine the role of ableism. In this meta-ethnography, we review extant qualitative research on urban teacher preparation in an effort to extend the analysis to include a robust examination of ableism and deepen our understandings of white supremacy in these spaces. To this end, we conceptualize white-ability saviorism as a more comprehensive and precise way to understand the dynamics at play in urban teacher preparation that contribute to white supremacy and perpetuate educational inequities for urban Communities of Color.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2024 04:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241241336?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Earth for all: Five policy turnarounds for a sustainable world</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The second in the new series of reviews for Action Research Journal is inspired by, and aims to contribute to, this journal’s focus on transformations towards sustainability. How can we, as action researchers, connect our emancipatory, grassroots work with the big global transformations needed to bring forth a just, harmonious and thriving world? When so much needs to transform, where do we start? In 2022, the Club of Rome offered a possible response in a new report called Earth for All, also published as a book and supporting website. Framed as ‘a survival guide for humanity’, Earth for All calls for ‘five extraordinary policy turnarounds’: ending poverty; addressing gross inequality; empowering women; making our food system healthy for people and ecosystems; and transitioning to clean energy. It is ‘an aspirational, stubbornly optimistic guide to the future’ (p. 26). It argues that action on these five big issues could give us the momentum we need to transform the economy in support of sustainability. Action researchers can help to give this agenda momentum by bringing it into our conversations with citizens and facilitating spaces for dialogue and agonism.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2024 02:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241242333?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial for Volume 26</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2024 01:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2325249?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting prospective mathematics teachers in noticing students&#39; proportional reasoning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigates the effect of a professional development program designed to develop prospective mathematics teachers’ ability to notice students’ proportional reasoning.  It examines how those teachers attended to student thinking, how they interpreted it, and how they decided to respond. Sixteen prospective teachers (PSTs) at a state university participated in a seven-week online professional development (PD) program. We provided participants with a research-based framework for proportional reasoning and engaged them in various ways via interviews with middle school students. They also wrote a reflection paper and received feedback. Combining multiple elements with interviewing was a unique feature of this program. The improvement in participants’ noticing skills was statistically significant. Specifically, in the post-assessment, the participants paid attention to most of the mathematical details of the students’ strategies, provided interpretations supported by conceptual underpinnings and evidence, and made research-based student-oriented decisions that focused on key issues. Implications for future teacher education practices and suggestions for further research are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09621-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoir une influence</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>04-03-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00313-5</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
