<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effective Teacher Professional Development and Its Influencing Factors: A Cross-National Comparison of the United States, China, Finland, and Singapore</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The promotion of effective teacher professional development (ETPD) is a critical issue in the field of teacher education. The present study investigated how ETPD is affected simultaneously by teacher- and school-level factors across the United States, China, Finland, and Singapore. The data were drawn from the Teaching and Learning International Survey (TALIS 2018) and analyzed using a hierarchical linear model. Findings showed that scores on social utility motivation to teach, self-efficacy in student engagement, and school participative climate were positively and significantly correlated with scores on ETPD across the four countries. It was concluded that gender, education background, teaching experience, personal utility motivation to teach, teacher self-efficacy in classroom management, and teacher–student relations made significant, yet inconsistent, differences in ETPD in the four countries. Motivating teachers to teach and creating a democratic, participatory, and caring school culture may be important measures to promote effective professional development of teachers globally.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-23-2024 06:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241254779?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Uncovering the Connections Among Rural Science Teachers: A Social Network Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Using social network analysis, we sought to characterize the professional collaboration and advice networks among rural science teachers. Furthermore, we explored how the characteristics of individual teachers and distance between teachers affected the likelihood of forming connections. Science teachers in publicly funded rural schools were asked whom they collaborate with and seek advice from and the mode and frequency of their communications. Results were analyzed using UCINET to calculate statistical significance of tie formation. Ties among rural teachers were sparse, with a quarter of teachers having no connections within the bounded network. In contrast to other social network studies, characteristics of individual teachers were not a significant predictor of tie formation in our population, but geographic proximity was a strong predictor. Our findings suggest that districts can support teachers in forming supportive ties by providing time, funding, and/or technology tools and training.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-23-2024 05:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241253821?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Stretching Research Legs”: Developing Practitioner-Scholars Through Engagement in Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-22-2024 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2357034?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Growing patterns invention by primary education students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-22-2024 04:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2344211?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining mathematics teachers’ creative actions in programming-based mathematical activities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;There has been a renewed interest in creativity as a twenty-first century skill in K-12 mathematics education. However, previous research has paid less attention to creative actions than to other learning outcomes, which are often product- instead of process-based, especially in a programming context. Thus, situated in the context of mathematical learning in a block-based programming environment, Scratch, this study seeks to investigate how in-service mathematics teachers develop mathematical concepts and programming skills to demonstrate their creative actions as a form of professional development. By conducting task-based interviews and thematic analysis, we found that testing and iterative practices of reusing and remixing are two important kinds of creative actions inspired by the programming environment, which give rise to new possibilities for doing mathematics in terms of generating new ways to engage in mathematical processes and to understand mathematics from a computational perspective. Our findings will inform teacher education and professional development programs addressing creativity in technology-enhanced mathematics classrooms, with particular attention to the role of mathematics, programming, and their interplay in inspiring teachers’ (and students’) creative actions and new possibilities for doing mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01579-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Wayfinding in an indigenous initial teacher education mathematics programme</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper we discuss ongoing challenges for Māori-medium initial teacher education in addressing conceptual, linguistic and pedagogical tensions that impact on developing mathematics education programmes. These include the small pool of applicants with the necessary linguistic and cultural knowledge required to teach in Māori-medium settings. Māori-medium schooling has the dual goals of providing a learning environment where Māori ways of knowing and being are taken for granted and students have access to international notions of academic success. However, many Māori-medium initial teaching education applicants have learnt mathematics in English and have had varying levels of access to Māori practices that could be taught alongside mathematics. To address these challenges, we utilise the cultural symmetry model to guide the design and delivery of Māori-medium initial teacher education tasks using wayfinding. Thereby illuminating Māori practices and school mathematics curriculum simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01589-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ dynamic communication while transforming mathematical representations in a dynamic geometry environment</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In mathematics, students’ abilities to make transformations between mathematical representations are fundamental. The recent implementation of digital technologies, such as Dynamic Geometry Environments (DGEs), have changed students’ access to mathematical representations by providing a variety of different representations, available just by pressing a button. Students use of a DGE may change their mathematical communication to become more dynamic and active. However, it is not clear how the use of DGEs and the change in communication style relate to more epistemological aspects of students’ mathematical work. This study, therefore, investigates the interplay between students’ dynamic mathematical communication and their transformations of mathematical representations when using a DGE from a competency perspective. Based on analyses of instances of lower secondary school students’ dynamic mathematical communication, findings indicate that students’ mathematical communication reflect the new ways of engaging with mathematical representations when using a DGE. Hence, the communication becomes dynamic. Theoretically, the complexity of having “continuous” transformations of mathematical representations may reduce the readiness of the mathematical communication competency. The “continuous” transformation may in fact cause students to unintentionally ascribe dynamic properties to mathematical representation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01575-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring prospective teachers’ stances in making sense of students’ mathematical ideas</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we explore the critical practice of making sense of students’ mathematical ideas. We extend previous research by studying stances prospective teachers adopt, the extent or depth to which they do so, and the types of prospective teachers making sense of students’ mathematical ideas. Analyzing the responses of 123 prospective teachers to students’ different ideas on an ambiguous mathematical task, our study identifies various stances—descriptive, evaluative, comparative, interpretive, inquiry-based, connective, and projective—and explores the complexity of attributing value, meaning, and significance to student ideas. Our findings offer insights into various types of making sense of students’ ideas and suggest that different kinds of attributions are at play for the purposes of observation, assessment, understanding and projection/prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09639-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Critical Roles of a Mathematics Specialist in Establishing Effective, Coordinated Professional Development Systems</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-21-2024 12:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2024.2355076?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Empowering Teacher Educators: Advancing Culturally Responsive Practices Through Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-21-2024 08:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2357088?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The nature and impact of literacy interest in preschool children: Comparing teacher, parent, and child report measures</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-21-2024 06:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2355108?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Profiles of teachers’ assessment techniques and their students’ involvement in assessment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-20-2024 12:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2354410?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Mamá en inglés se dice ‘pre-med’”: bilingual Mexican-origin first-generation college undergraduates aspiring for medical careers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-20-2024 08:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2349879?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From reflective practice to action research and positive change: securing high levels of wellbeing among learners with autism spectrum condition in the mainstream setting</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-20-2024 05:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2355925?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of Unified School Enrollment Systems on School Demographics and Outcomes: Evidence From New Orleans’ Transition to a Centralized School Lottery</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Unified enrollment (UE) systems were designed to improve efficiency, equity, and transparency in school choice processes, but research has focused on efficiency gains. This study examines whether moving from decentralized enrollment processes to UE mitigates or exacerbates racial segregation that often occurs in choice systems. Specifically, we examine a subset of charter schools in New Orleans that had enrolled disproportionately high numbers of White students prior to entering UE. We find that UE entry was associated with increased enrollment of non-White students in these schools without offsetting declines in White enrollment, facilitated by schools also increasing total enrollment after entering UE. We find no meaningful impacts of UE on school accountability measures, student or teacher mobility, or student discipline.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-20-2024 01:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241248513?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging Physical Activities to Support Learning for Young People via Technologies: An Examination of Educational Practices Across the Field</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Many technological interventions have leveraged physical activity (PA, i.e., activities that involve whole-body movements) to provide young people with active and productive learning experiences. However, there is a lack of systematic understanding of how PA can serve as a learning medium—for example, how PA can support learning and how to design technologies to support PA-based learning. This paper conducts a systematic literature review (N = 141) of PA-based, technology-mediated learning experiences for young people with a focus on how PA supports learning, what technologies are involved, and the associated challenges. Through content analysis, we identified four approaches of how PA and learning were combined (i.e., PA embodied learning content, served as a functional input method for learning tasks, guided learners through different learning sites, and generated data for learning activities) and supporting technologies like full-body interaction learning environments and mobile apps. However, many challenges might arise, such as balancing learning and PA, as well as the scalability and reliability of technologies. We conclude with a discussion and reflection on design implications for more PA-based learning experiences and technologies. Overall, this paper provides a systematic overview of the different ways to design physically active learning experiences for young people and can serve as a reference for future designs of physically active learning experiences and technologies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-18-2024 07:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241248464?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Major Selection as Iteration: Observing Gendered Patterns of Major Selection Under Elective Curriculums</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Social scientists have long recognized field of study as an important mechanism of gender differentiation and stratification in U.S. higher education, but they have rarely attended to how elective curriculums mediate gender differentiation in major selection. Under elective curriculums, major selection is an iterative process, in which students select courses in stepwise fashion at the beginning of each academic term, and are able to change majors early in their undergraduate careers. We observe how an elective curriculum mediates gendered patterns of major selection, using a novel data set describing 11,730 students at a large public research university. We find (a) gender and intended major are strongly correlated upon college entry; (b) large proportions of students change majors between entry and declaration; (c) because most changes are to academically adjacent fields, gendered patterns in field of study persist through the undergraduate career. Findings suggest the value of an iterative conception of major selection and offer tractable means for intervening in the process through which students select majors.JEL codes: I21, I24, I26, J16.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-18-2024 06:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241249600?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing Mathematical Deductive Reasoning Competence of Eighth-Grade Students from China</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study aims to develop an evaluation framework to assess the mathematical deductive reasoning competence (MDRC) of eighth-grade students in China based on Program for International Student Assessment (PISA) and Trends in International Mathematics and Science Study (TIMSS). The framework includes four dimensions of MDRC: cognitive level, reasoning context, reasoning form, and reasoning content. A sample of 58,532 students took the test entitled MDRC Assessment in 90 min. Their MDRC was classified into four levels, and the percentages of students who were at level 1 to level 4 are 17.3%, 25.2%, 26.7%, and 30.8%, respectively. Girls performed significantly better than boys in total and in each of the dimensions of the evaluation framework, but the differences were at a low practical level. Students from urban schools outperformed students from rural schools at a significant level and a higher percentage of students in rural areas were at level 1 (poorest performance) than of students in urban areas. This research proposed a framework for assessing MDRC levels of students and used it with Chinese as well as international studies. Implications of gender and geographical inequalities in this performance were also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-18-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00315-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Corrigendum to Spare the Rod, Spoil the Child? A Critical Discourse Analysis of State Corporal Punishment Policies &amp; Practices</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 09:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241257935?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Methodology for a time of eco-social planetary crisis: Action research helping transformations happen</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 06:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241255488?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improving Teaching at Scale: Can AI Be Incorporated Into Professional Development to Create Interactive, Personalized Learning for Teachers?</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Scalable and accessible professional development programs have the potential to address the opportunity gap many teachers experience. Yet many asynchronous online programs lack interaction with and timely feedback to teachers. We addressed this problem by developing a virtual, interactive program that uses intelligent tutoring systems to provide just‐in‐time feedback to teachers. We conducted a randomized controlled trial with teachers across the United States in which teachers were assigned to either this program or no additional training. We found that teachers who completed our program (N = 29) used mathematically richer tasks and created a more coherent, connected learning environment for students to build conceptual understandings than did teachers who were in the business‐as‐usual condition (N = 23).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 06:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241248514?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reading in Relation: Youth Mentors and Adults Co-Constructing Teaching and Learning in a High School Literacy Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 05:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2024.2349298?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fostering participation and change through action research conducted with youth in the foster care system – A note from the field</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The purpose of this note from the field is to review the current state of action research studies involving young people currently or recently involved in the foster care system in the United States. Young people in foster care often report feeling that they have little opportunity for advocacy or self-directed change during their time in the system. Action research is presented as an approach to research that appears to provide opportunities for self-advocacy and real-world change among youth in the foster care system. While noting some challenges associated with recruitment and attrition while working with youth in foster care, this note emphasizes the promising potential of action research as a tool to increase youth autonomy and well-being while generating meaningful knowledge and social change within the U.S foster care system. The note, based on a database search that included 636 articles 2013–2023, hopes to contribute to advancing youth-led research in foster care.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 03:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241253371?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A critical look at the anthropological theory of the didactic</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>05-17-2024 03:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2344754?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
