<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Silent Covenants and Structural Barriers: State Standards Committees and the Maintenance of Race-Evasive Social Studies Standards</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In this qualitative study, researchers used critical race theory to examine the experiences of social studies standards committee members in 18 states and the District of Columbia. They found that while many participants articulated goals of increasing the teaching of race and racism in their state’s social studies standards, at least in part, numerous silent covenants and structural barriers existed to maintain the status quo through race-evasive standards. A smaller group of participants generally avoided advocating for race and racism topics altogether due to their perceived controversial or political status, while others did not mention race or racism as a priority. Recommendations are made for both the policy and practice related to state standards creation, and questions are raised about the ability of social studies standards to foster a racially just social studies curriculum.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-10-2024 11:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241265303?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Climate, Teacher Characteristics, and School Discipline: Evidence From New York City</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;School discipline is a salient problem of educational policy and practice. Teachers play an important role in the production and disruption of racial inequities in school discipline, yet there remains a need to disentangle the relationship between teacher characteristics, their perceptions of school climate, and school discipline patterns. This study uses longitudinal data representing over one thousand public middle and high schools in New York City and linear regression methods to examine the relationship between teachers’ perceptions of school climate, teacher characteristics, and the rates of and disparities in suspensions. Overall, results indicate more positive teacher perceptions of school climate, higher years of teaching experience, and a greater share of Black teachers are independently associated with lower rates of office referrals and suspensions, overall and especially for Black and Latinx students. The study concludes by discussing implications for teacher education and on-the-job support as well as school leadership.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-10-2024 11:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241263860?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unearthing and reconstructing schooling with multiply-marginalized disabled students through an intersectional sociospatial lens</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-10-2024 08:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2386940?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Holding our Ground in the Face of Public Mistrust: The Future of Professionalism in Teaching and Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Globally, enduring skepticism around professionalism in education systems has questioned the efficiency in which teachers meet students’ educational needs and their authority to do so. Presently, efforts toward professionalization in teacher education (TE) are threatened by neoliberal reforms promoting alternative pathways into teaching and performance-based accountability mechanisms to monitor teachers and schools. In the face of public mistrust and external threats, this conceptual paper aims to envision the future of TE in light of the complexities inherent to the notion of professionalism. To this end, two competing ideals of teaching, which represent co-existing conceptions of professional work in education are examined: The teacher as an expert clinician ideal entrenched in expertise-driven professionalism and the teacher as a democratic pedagogue grounded in democratic professionalism. I offer ways in which these competing discourses could be fused to set the discussion about professionalism in teaching and its implications for TE on firmer grounds.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-10-2024 07:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241268552?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Photovoice for promoting empowerment with migrant and refugee communities: A scoping review</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Policymakers and researchers carry a significant responsibility to foster environments and opportunities that authentically enhance migrants’ sociopolitical involvement in host societies. Incorporating participatory action research methods, such as photovoice, is crucial to amplify migrants’ voices and experiences. This scoping review investigates the implementation of photovoice projects with migrant and refugee populations, as well as their impact on empowerment. Following PRISMA guidelines, 65 articles published from 2000 to 2020 were analysed. The findings indicate that photovoice can serve as a potent tool for fostering intrapersonal, interpersonal and citizenship levels of empowerment. However, key epistemological and methodological considerations must be upheld to promote profound levels of empowerment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-10-2024 05:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241269750?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Path Toward Racial Justice in Education: Anti-Racist Policy Decision Making in School Districts</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The U.S. education system has been a critical site in the nation’s ongoing fight for racial equity. Yet, despite many attempts to promote equity within and across schools, efforts fall short in a system designed to uphold norms rooted in whiteness and white supremacy. We need anti-racist educational leaders who can identify and push back at the racial bias embedded in educational policies. Through a research-practice partnership with a Midwestern high school, we sought to understand how an anti-racist policy decision-making protocol can be used to redress inequitable policies to be racially just. The anti-racist policy decision-making protocol promotes social justice by empowering school practitioners to become policy agents. Implications from our findings point to the need for school practitioners to be critically introspective and identify and directly address the politics of whiteness that can ensue when working in partnership to do anti-racist policy change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-10-2024 04:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241271329?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ goal communication in Nordic mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Clear learning goals are an integral part of instructional clarity and seen as a factor influencing students’ motivation and learning processes. However, goal communication and the types of goals teachers set are rarely addressed in classroom studies. To further the understanding of these aspects, the purpose of this study was to investigate communicated learning goals in 146 videotaped lessons across 48 Nordic lower-secondary mathematics classrooms. A two-step analysis focusing goal clarity and types of communicated goals was applied to the data. Analyses indicated that the goals were often implicit and vague, and mostly focused on content and procedural skills, rather than on mathematical competencies and applications of mathematics. We conclude that the focus on content and procedures, coupled with implicit learning goals, could obscure the purpose of a lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-10-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00498-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effect of the development of precursor skills for literacy in Spanish on learning to read in English</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-09-2024 12:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2387644?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Funding and Equity in Australia: Critical Moments in the Context of Text Production Phase of the Education Policy Cycle</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Education policy has long been analyzed as a cycle where various actors influence different stages. However, few such studies have focused on identifying and interrogating the specific moments that shape an education policy’s overall equity trajectory. This article uses Bowe, Ball, and Gold’s policy cycle as an exploratory theoretical framework, focusing on the historic Review of Funding for Schooling (2011) in Australia, which evaluated the nation’s school funding policy. The authors concentrate on the Context of Text Production phase of its policymaking process, and consider the implications for equity. From this work, the authors highlight two “critical moments” that they argue significantly influenced how the appointed panel approached equity. Their theorizing of a “critical moment” offers valuable insights for researchers and stakeholders seeking to understand or influence education policy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-09-2024 11:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241268250?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Continuum of Expressions of Hope and the Influence on Leadership Through Times of Crisis</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Given today’s crisis-laden context filled with educational challenges, it is critical to understand how principals express hope through their leadership to navigate these challenges. Through an extensive qualitative research study conducted in 2019–2022, I examined how 50 principals expressed and used hope in varying degrees to hinder or facilitate increased outcomes, inclusivity, and stable recovery post-crisis to design a better future for their school communities. In so doing, I describe (a) how the context in which principals lead lends itself to expressing high- or low-hope leadership attributes; (b) principals’ expressions of high-hope leadership during and post-crisis; and (c) principals’ expressions of low-hope leadership during and post-crisis. Identifying expressions of hope leadership practices with the potential to cultivate inclusive, equitable school climates proves vital, given the complexity of leadership today and the myriad crises leaders face.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-09-2024 09:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241267785?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bridoux, Grenier-Boley, Leininger-Frézal: Research in University Pedagogy: Towards a Discipline-Based Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-09-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00253-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race, ethnicity, and stratification within the first-generation student experience</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-08-2024 07:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2386954?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student-perceived parents’ and teachers’ expectancies and feedback influence homework motivation and effort</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-08-2024 07:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2385405?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should Religious Schools Be Publicly Funded? Issues of Religion, Discrimination, and Equity</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-08-2024 06:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2381367?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Two-Stage Regression Approach to Detecting Section Score Inconsistency</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;For an assessment with multiple sections measuring related constructs, test takers with higher scores on one section are expected to perform better on the related sections. When the sections involve different test designs, test takers with preknowledge of an administration may score unusually high on some sections but not on others. To address such inconsistency, regression approaches have been successfully applied to compare section scores for many years in operational settings. With a focus on outlier analysis, we propose a new two-stage regression approach to detecting score inconsistency among different sections of a test. It is designed to leverage rich historical information from large-scale assessments to help detect unusually high scores on the easier-to-cheat sections based on the scores on the harder-to-cheat sections in new administrations. This paper presents a statistical framework for the two-stage regression procedure and develops analytical results under a null model of no exposure. It also describes an analysis procedure to guide applications. An empirical example is provided to illustrate the proposed method, to evaluate the performance and robustness of the analytical results in real settings, and to compare with two other methods for the detection of inconsistent section scores.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-08-2024 05:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241263974?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Generally Applicable Variance Estimation Methods for Common-Population Linking</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Educational assessments require periodic administration changes, such as transitioning from paper to digital administration. During such transitions, a linking function relating the metrics of the new and previous administration is estimated, but uncertainty in this estimation introduces variance into comparisons between administrations. Similarly, different assessments provided to overlapping populations may be linked, introducing linking or equating error. We introduce new generally applicable variance estimation methods, generalize prior methods to be more widely applicable, and confirm the validity of the methods via simulation. Our methods account for dependencies between linking and other sources of error, complex sampling, and nonlinear linking functions, while applying to a wide range of score comparisons and statistics such as means, standard deviations, percentiles, and differences.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-08-2024 01:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241263976?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Protest and Resistance: Conceptualizing a Blackamerican Institutional Schema and the Contemporary Relevance of Pre-Brown Educators</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;In the century following emancipation, Blackamericans developed robust and effective schools despite limited resources. Unfortunately, their successes and contributions to the education system are often overlooked. This interdisciplinary theoretical paper draws on historiographies of segregated school systems, examining the struggles of Blackamerican educators within segregated education systems through the lenses of coloniality and institutional work. This examination reveals a distinct Blackamerican institutional schema rooted in community, guiding educators in navigating structural and systemic dynamics that shape educational opportunities and successfully challenge dominant white education standards. We discuss the coloniality of schooling, a structural framework, and a mindset that continues to undergird our contemporary education system and then draw attention to an alternative perspective. Our goal is to work toward more inclusive and equitable education systems by recognizing and acknowledging the protest and resistance of Blackamerican educators, their contributions to alternative epistemologies, and the mindsets that guided their actions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 09:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241269812?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unequal City and Inequitable Choice: The Neoliberal State’s Development of School Choice and Marketization in the Publicly Funded Catholic School Board in Toronto, Canada</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 06:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2381394?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating insight and rigour as separate constructs in mathematical proof</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 03:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2024.2379301?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting early career teachers’ self-regulation and goal pursuit through online coaching during a professional development programme</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 03:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2382820?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impostor phenomenon among racially minoritised university students: ‘who knows how to get rid of this?’</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-07-2024 02:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2386949?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interference of prototypical geometry representations in students’ construction of concepts and development of proofs</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-06-2024 06:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2386619?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“If I bring my whole self to school, I am opening myself up to hurt”: A case study and (re)humanizing counterstory of an early career, multiply-marginalized multiracial teacher with justice commitments</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-06-2024 02:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2386952?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The algebraic learning of middle school students’ evolution during a school year: a statistical large-scale study based on results in mathematics didactics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This large-scale study characterizes the algebraic learning of a cohort of nearly 800 French students during the last year of middle school (9th grade, 14–15 years old) and examines their evolution in relation to the composition of the classes to which the students belong. Based on the Anthropological Theory of the Didactic (ATD), the study is founded both on a reference model of elementary algebra and on technological-theoretical levels characterizing the students’ reasoning and their knowledge regarding institutional expectations. These are used to code the data and define the statistical variables on which multivariate descriptive analyses are carried out. Students’ learning is analyzed through &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Pépite&lt;/em&gt;, an algebra test given at the beginning and at the end of the year. A cluster analysis resulted in three distinct clusters of similar classes and of similar students both at the beginning and end of the grade 9 school year. They are interpreted didactically and could be useful for a teacher who has to manage the heterogeneity of learning in a class. Some classes and students move from one cluster to another between the beginning and the end of the year, showing a wide variety of ways in which students’ algebra learning progresses or regresses over a school year.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>08-06-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10347-z</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
