<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Biological corridors: using participatory action research to map ecological and social relations in conservation work</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2025 08:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2025.2462320?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Spring 2025, Page 1-2&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2025 01:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2025.2461436?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ performance and typical errors in filling empty probabilistic visualizations with probabilities or frequencies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;It has been established that, in Bayesian tasks, performance and typical errors in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;reading&lt;/em&gt; information from filled visualizations depend both on the type of the provided visualization and information format. However, apart from reading visualizations, students should also be able to create visualizations on their own and successfully use them as heuristic tools in modeling tasks. In this paper, we first want to broaden the view on Bayesian reasoning to probabilistic tasks with two binary events in general and embed the whole process of solving these tasks using probabilistic visualizations in a modified modeling framework. Thereby, it becomes apparent that most of the steps remained untouched by existing research. Second, in the present empirical study, we focused on one part of the largely unexplored creation process and examined &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;entering&lt;/em&gt; statistical information into empty visualizations as heuristic tools. &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 172 participants had to enter conditional and joint probabilities or the corresponding frequencies into empty visualizations in a paper-and-pencil test. We analyze (a) students’ performance when entering information in visualizations and (b) typical errors, both dependent on the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;information format&lt;/em&gt; (probabilities vs. natural frequencies), which &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;empty visualization structure&lt;/em&gt; (2⨯2 table, double tree, net diagram) was provided, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;type of information&lt;/em&gt; (conditional vs. joint information). The well-known positive effect of natural frequencies on participants’ performance was evident when entering conditional information into 2⨯2 tables and net diagrams. However, with respect to joint information, no superior effect of frequencies was observed. Furthermore, the theoretical implementation of our research in a modeling cycle allows us to identify desiderata for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10372-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teachers’ noticing of critical events associated with argumentation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study explores secondary-school mathematics teachers’ noticing of Critical Events Associated with Argumentation (CEAs), moments when students’ reasoning or interactions become evident, offering teachers opportunities to promote argumentation in the classroom. Thirty-one teachers analyzed a written classroom scenario, identifying CEAs, interpreting their potential for fostering argumentation, and proposing teaching alternatives. The findings reveal that teachers identified CEAs emphasizing either mathematical arguments, collaborative interactions in constructing and evaluating arguments, or both, with a primary focus on dialogic interactions. The identified CEAs, along with their interpretations and proposed strategies, demonstrated alignment, by focusing on common underlying aspects. The dynamic interconnection among components of noticing—attending, interpreting, and responding—challenges linear models, suggesting iterative and holistic processes. By framing CEAs as opportunities to integrate structural and dialogic aspects of argumentation, this study contributes to refining noticing frameworks and advancing teachers&#39; professional development. Theoretical and practical implications for research on noticing and argumentation in mathematics education are discussed, alongside recommendations for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-05-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-025-09682-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Text-based discussion interactions and engagement with three different text types</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2025 08:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2423177?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring students’ conceptual understanding through mathematical problem solving: students’ use of and shift between different representations of rational numbers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2025 05:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2025.2456840?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teacher educators’ instructional modifications: A cultural-comparative study using a Czech mathematics classroom video</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this cultural-comparative study, we examined the recommendations for instructional modifications made by 12 Czech and 12 non-Czech mathematics teacher educators (MTEs). The non-Czech MTEs were selected from countries culturally distinct from Czechia, including Costa Rica, Japan, Kosovo, Türkiye, the UK, and the USA, with two MTEs from each country. The participants were invited to provide written feedback on a part of a video lesson (teaching segment) in which a Czech elementary mathematics teacher handled student errors. The results demonstrated that the Czech MTEs emphasized individual learning and content, while the non-Czech MTEs’ feedback was more diverse, advocating a more collaborative and reflective learning environment. Drawing on the limitations of our study, implications for future research are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-025-00518-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Feasibility and Comparability of Using Artificial Intelligence for Qualitative Data Analysis in Equity-Focused Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this essay, we explored the feasibility of utilizing artificial intelligence (AI) for qualitative data analysis in equity-focused research. Specifically, we compare thematic analyses of interview transcripts conducted by human coders with those performed by GPT-3 using a zero-shot chain-of-thought prompting strategy. Our results suggest that the AI model, when provided with suitable prompts, can proficiently perform thematic analysis, demonstrating considerable comparability with human coders. Despite potential biases inherent in its training data, the model was able to analyze and interpret the data through social justice perspectives. We discuss the applications of integrating AI into qualitative research, provide code snippets illustrating the use of GPT models, and highlight unresolved questions to encourage further dialogue in the field.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 11:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X251314821?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We are born mentors … It’s in our DNA”: Exploring Indigenous Australian kinship mentoring practices</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 11:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2025.2459944?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Turnover, Social Capital, and Improvement: How Instability Disrupts Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher turnover is a persistent policy concern in public education. Researchers have documented negative impacts of turnover on student outcomes; yet we know little about the causal mechanisms by which turnover influences, or disrupts, schools’ efforts to improve. In our longitudinal qualitative study, we examined how turnover affects relationships, trust, and shared knowledge in organizations—that is, organizational social capital—in ways that can impede school improvement efforts. We found that teacher turnover depletes organizational social capital by disrupting networks and relationships between teachers working in teams, weakening shared meanings and goals in schools, and impeding teachers’ ability to collectively engage in problem-solving and learning. We illuminate the hidden ways in which instability undermines improvement efforts and strains organizations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 07:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241311304?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the knowledge structure of coping strategies in teacher education research using bibliometric analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2025.2458496?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emotions in mathematics learning: a systematic review and meta-analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Academic emotions play a crucial role in mathematics learning, significantly influencing motivation, academic achievement, and career aspirations in mathematics. With the notable increase in research on emotions in recent years, our review uses Pekrun’s control-value theory with two primary objectives: to systematically describe the characteristics of emotions in recent research through a systematic review, and to synthesize evidence on the relationships between specific emotions, control-value antecedents, and mathematics achievement via a meta-analysis. The systematic review of 112 studies revealed that more than 100 specific emotions have been addressed in recent research, which we analyzed based on key emotion characteristics: valence and activation, type of object, temporal stability, and social context. The findings from the systematic review provide an overview of mathematics-specific objects that emotions have referred to in the most recent research. The subsequent meta-analysis demonstrated that mathematics achievement (e.g., test scores and grades) was positively related to enjoyment, hope, and pride (&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\overline{r}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; = .247, .224, and .344, respectively) but negatively related to anger, boredom, frustration, hopelessness, and shame (&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\overline{r}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt;= − .322, − .187, − .207, − .378, and − .291, respectively). Theoretical and practical implications of these results are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01651-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The complexity of mathematics teacher educator expertise</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics teacher education is now a well-established field of research, but it is only in recent years that research attention has turned towards the learning and development of mathematics teacher educators themselves. In this special issue, interest centres on mathematics teacher educator expertise and how this can be represented, developed, and studied. The research studies published in this issue aim to move beyond category-based descriptions of mathematics teacher educator knowledge and explore the broader complexity of expertise as blend of knowing, doing, believing, and being. In doing so they capture the dynamic and interconnected nature of expertise. In this commentary article, I reflect on what we can learn from these studies about the complexity of MTE expertise and use these insights to suggest directions for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-025-09679-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Communities of Practice for Canadian University Mathematics Instructors</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Communities of practice (CoPs) that support the teaching and learning of mathematics in Canada are discussed. In particular, why CoPs are needed for mathematics instruction in Canadian universities, as well as some examples of these CoPs and what they offer, their target audience, and how they benefit mathematics education. CoP examples aimed to reach nationwide include the Canadian Mathematics Society, Canadian Mathematics Education Study Group, and First Year Mathematics and Statistics in Canada. There are also examples of regional and institutional-specific CoPs, such as the Fields Math Ed Forums located in Toronto and online, that are discussed. We conclude with some comparisons of these CoPs and what may lie ahead for CoPs and their impact on university mathematics instructors in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00341-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nurturing preservice teachers’ metacognitive pedagogies through Lesson Study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-02-2025 10:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2025.2451880?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Obstacles to in-service Chinese high school mathematics teachers’ implementation of mathematical modelling in classrooms: an empirical investigation of teachers’ perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This mixed-method study uses interviews and an online questionnaire to investigate the obstacles that hinder teachers’ implementation of mathematical modelling in everyday classrooms in China. Thirty high school mathematics teachers were interviewed, and 200 teachers completed an online questionnaire regarding their perceived obstacles. We identified six critical obstacle groups: missed opportunities to learn mathematical modelling education in professional development and/or teacher education; students’ lack of knowledge and interests; lack of examples in textbooks; lack of suitable teaching materials; non-favourable curricula tradition and school policies; and a strong traditional focus on examination culture. The obstacles identified and their relationship to and role in current in-service teachers’ practices are explored and interpreted from a sociocultural perspective considering, among other factors, the significance of central examinations in China and the historical prevalence of pure, structurally oriented mathematics in school.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-02-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01660-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>To Whom Do These Results Apply? Assessing Evidence for the Generalizability of Social and Emotional Learning Programs Among Specific Racial and Ethnic Groups</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Social and emotional learning (SEL) programs are widely used, yet concerns have arisen about whether the evidence for these programs extends to students of color (SOC). The data in this study include published articles (n = 158) of trials (n = 97) of SEL interventions (n = 32) from the CASEL SELect list of evidence-based SEL programs. Using racial frames common in intervention research, we examined the extent of SOC representation in SEL intervention trials, how authors attend to race/ethnicity in their analyses, and whether and how these analyses show evidence that these programs benefit specific racial/ethnic groups. While doing so, we discuss the complex nature of race and racism in SEL research. Eight interventions provided some evidence that they benefit Black students and four showed some evidence that they benefit Hispanic/Latiné students. No trials provided evidence of benefit to any other groups of SOC. Findings suggest that while representation of SOC in SEL trials has improved, additional research is needed to understand to whom the evidence for SEL program effectiveness applies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 09:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241310184?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘We’re not taught the full story’: Black students’ mistrust of secondary school U.S. history curricula</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 04:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2025.2459946?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Social innovation in the making: Action research on relationship building and role understanding in the co-development of a Participatory Guarantee System in Argentina</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Social innovation (SI) is gaining attention to explore how multistakeholder initiatives create new social practices for local food system development. Participatory Guarantee Systems (PGS) is a group-based certification scheme for sustainable farming, comprising new social practices that require changes in relationships and roles. Research highlights potentials of PGS to produce SI; however, without providing insights into the innovation process, needed to learn how relationship and role building occur and how SI can be facilitated through action research. We addressed these gaps in a four-year action research that co-developed a PGS in Argentina. The overall aim of studying relationship and role building required to establish PGS was operationalized by i) analysing ambitions for change of relationships of involved groups; ii) examining how relationship building evolved and how it was facilitated; and iii) exploring changes in role understanding and performance. Therein, we reflected on how action research can enhance SI and transformation in local food system development. The processual analysis showed that SI was facilitated when narratives of change were shared across stakeholder environments and a socially constructed facilitation mandate was created. Critical role reflection was stimulated, while performance was constrained when individual benefits were uncertain, underscoring the need to elaborate on role expectations in the initiation phase.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 02:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503251316368?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Catherine P. Vistro-Yu &amp;amp; Tin Lam Toh (eds.) (2019) School mathematics curricula – Asian perspectives and glimpses of reform</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10338-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical discussion in classrooms as a technologically-supported activity fostering participation and inclusion</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Whole-class mathematical discussion in a problem-solving activity is recognized as a powerful pedagogical activity but also a challenge for teachers who must consider several difficulties that learners might face, particularly in terms of an overload of Working Memory and Executive Functions. This study investigates how the use of a digital platform (Padlet) can support participatory and inclusive mathematical classroom discussion. We proposed a teaching experiment based on graphical tasks anticipating integral calculus to grade 13 students, and we examined how the use of the digital platform plays a role in the construction and interpretation of new mathematical objects emerging from the activity. The use of Instrumental Genesis and Double Instrumental Genesis frameworks allowed us to make the affordances of the tool emerge. As a result, we got evidence of how mathematical discussion may develop as a network of interactions, feedback, and connection of input and discuss examples of how active participation and inclusion are enhanced by the tool affordances. Indeed, the digital platform allowed easy interaction, with many ways to represent and express the ongoing evolution of personal and shared meanings and the possibility to manage the time of the activity. This fostered students’ participation and students which did not participate in previous discussions were actively engaged in it.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10356-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How much C is in TPACK? A systematic review on the assessment of TPACK in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teachers need technological pedagogical content knowledge (TPACK) for teaching with technology, and its assessment is crucial for research and practice. Previous literature reviews on TPACK assessment were not specific to a content area (e.g., mathematics), although, by definition, the TPACK framework includes content-specific knowledge facets. Consequently, requirements for TPACK assessment could differ depending on the content. Further, reliable assessment of mathematics-specific TPACK depends on the quality of the test instruments used, but there is no consensus on the type of instruments used in past studies. This systematic literature review adds to existing reviews by focusing on TPACK assessment in mathematics, investigating the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;study characteristics&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;instrument characteristics&lt;/em&gt;, and the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;operationalizations&lt;/em&gt; of TPACK. Regarding study characteristics, the findings reveal an increase in the number of studies conducted across various countries worldwide. As for instrument characteristics, researchers frequently used self-developed instruments to assess TPACK, often without providing information on reliability or validity measures. Regarding operationalizations, more than half of the studies used self-report scales to assess mathematics-specific TPACK, followed by observations and material analyses, while knowledge tests were hardly used. Additionally, assessments typically referred to the domain of mathematics as a whole instead of subdomains of mathematics. The results raise questions regarding the validity of the instruments and the comparability across studies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10357-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Decentralising mathematics: Mutual development of spontaneous and mathematical concepts via informal reasoning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper aims to shed light on an overlooked but essential aspect of informal reasoning and its radical implication to mathematics education research: Decentralising mathematics. We start to problematise that previous studies on informal reasoning implicitly overfocus on what students infer. Based on Walton’s distinction between reasoning and argument, and Ernest’s concept of intrapersonal dialogue, we propose two theoretical perspectives for understanding the roles of informal reasoning in argumentation: the semi-formal, and the negotiation perspectives. From the latter perspective, we can say that informal reasoning involves creating alternatives, eschewing the relatively unpromising ones, and choosing the most promising one. To illustrate the advantage of the negotiation perspective over the semi-formal perspective, we present two examples of students’ statistical written reports from a previous study. These examples illustrate that spontaneous concepts influenced the students’ creation of multiple alternatives, and choice of the most promising one, in informal reasoning. Therefore, to better understand the development of mathematical concepts, we need to recognise the role of spontaneous concepts through decentralising mathematics. Finally, we introduce inferentialism as an additional theoretical perspective for investigating both the mathematical development of spontaneous concepts, and the spontaneous development of mathematical concepts. The inferentialist idea of the game of giving and asking for reasons indicates how to empirically investigate the mutual development of spontaneous and mathematical concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10366-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modelling mathematics for educational research and practice: a comparison of two theoretical approaches</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The production and use of explicit models of mathematics are important elements of research in Didactics of Mathematics. In this paper, we present and compare two different European approaches to didactical modelling. The first, centred around the notion of basic idea (Grundvorstellung), arose in German-speaking countries as a development within Subject Matter Didactics (Stoffdidaktik). The second is the notion of praxeology from the Anthropological Theory of the Didactic, which originated in France. After presenting the genesis and interpretation of these notions as theoretical modelling tools, we provide a detailed case study of actual models produced with these tools, concerning the notion of limits and derivatives. Furthermore, we identify similarities and differences of both models in how they can support didactical research and practice, for instance, by identifying important phenomena or problems. We conclude that the two approaches offer important, different and, to some extent, complementary positions and perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10368-8</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
