<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Polarization, Partisan Sorting, and the Politics of Education</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Drawing on annual, nationally representative survey data from 2007–2022, I demonstrate that partisan gaps—the average differences in public opinion between Democrats and Republicans—have widened on many education issues. This pattern consistently exceeds what would be expected due to the changing demographic compositions of the parties alone. Widening partisan gaps are primarily attributable to sorting (alignment of one&#39;s party affiliation and one&#39;s issue positions) rather than polarization (increasing support for more extreme positions relative to more moderate positions). However, polarization is also increasing on some of the most divisive issues. Among those who are sorting, individuals are overwhelmingly switching their issue positions to align with their party affiliations rather than switching their party affiliations to align with their issue positions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 09:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241228280?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Patterns of Absenteeism from Prekindergarten Through Early Elementary School and Their Associations With Children’s Academic Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Using statewide administrative data from a sample of children enrolled in public prekindergarten (pre-K) programs in Massachusetts, I examined heterogeneity in children’s absenteeism patterns from pre-K to Grade 3 and linked these patterns to their Grade 3 academic outcomes. After latent class growth analysis, six absenteeism patterns emerged. The vast majority of children (85%) had consistently low absenteeism, and only a small percentage of children (1%) demonstrated consistently high absenteeism. Four patterns showed variation in absenteeism over time, with two characterized by high absenteeism in only the pre-K year, another with a peak during kindergarten, and a final one with rising absenteeism across grades. Children with always low absenteeism had higher average English language arts and math scores than did children in the other patterns, and children in the two high pre-K absenteeism patterns and peak in kindergarten pattern had higher math scores than those with rising and always high absenteeism patterns.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 08:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241228212?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating Sustainable Mobility: Motorized and Non-motorized Modes in Suburban Areas of Thailand</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The impact of sustainable mobility may be considered through the mode of non-motorization, which may vary by spatial environmental conditions, especially accessibility by active mobility in a necessarily safe, comfortable, and pleasant atmosphere. Sustainable mobility comprises willingness to allow commuting behaviors on non-motorized travel for safety and green ethics. These chiefly participate to create livable places, improve health and well-being, and promote quality of life and economic growth. By contrast, an impoverished street environment decreases the possibility of active mobility and relies on motorization. It is essential to explore the perception of road users through diverse environmental features of street networks and sidewalks directly affecting road user behavior and preferences about motorization and non-motorization. This study evaluated multi-indicators of sustainable urban mobility (SUM) for a group of road users, with data gathered by questionnaire-based survey. 1,998 Pathum Thani Province inhabitants in Thailand were asked to evaluate their neighborhood characteristics by SUM indicators. In addition to different social dimensions and socioeconomic backgrounds, transportation characteristics among diverse trip makers and different perceptions of mobility indicators were classified by factor analysis using principal components and spatial visualization. Results were that traffic management, including intersection controls and signage, as well as information, sidewalk, management, and personal mobility choices, is a key strategy to improve sustainable mobility. This is achieved by tailoring solutions to achieve a modal shift prioritized over other supportive facilities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 07:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241233669?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Calling All Future Educators: Investigating the Influence of a Teacher Recruitment Event</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 07:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2311415?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Alternative Factors Leading to Replication Crisis: Prediction and Evaluation</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Most existing solutions to the current replication crisis in science address only the factors stemming from specific poor research practices. We introduce a novel mechanism that leverages the experts’ predictive abilities to analyze the root causes of replication failures. It is backed by the principle that the most accurate predictor is the most qualified expert. This mechanism can be seamlessly integrated into the existing replication prediction market framework with minimal implementation costs. It relies on an objective rather than subjective process and unstructured expert opinions to effectively identify various influences contributing to the replication crisis.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 06:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241229106?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preparing Novice Teachers to Differentiate Instruction: Implications of a Longitudinal Study</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This longitudinal multi-case study explored four early career teachers’ attempts to differentiate instruction in schools that varied in their level of support for this pedagogical approach. It offered an in-depth examination of the experiences of novices who learned about the pedagogical tools of differentiation with depth and fidelity through the same preservice instruction, developed similar commitments to implementing them, and attempted to implement them in contrasting inservice settings. A large and rich data corpus collected across 4 years included participant interviews, observations of participants’ teaching practices, classroom artifacts, and interviews with participants’ mentors. Findings illustrated novices’ contrasting multi-year learning trajectories related to differentiation embedded within varied school settings. They also revealed the substantive role novices’ shifting visions of the enactment of practice played in appropriating differentiation’s pedagogical tools during their early careers. Recommendations for teacher educators who prepare teacher candidates to differentiate are provided.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 06:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241232419?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How numbers influence students when solving linear equations</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 01:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2314067?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Classrooms as Healing Spaces: Decolonizing Conceptual Frameworks of Black Girls in K-12 School Settings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-20-2024 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2309062?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Self-Care and Wellness Framework in Educator Preparation to Address Burnout, Compassion Fatigue, and Secondary Traumatic Stress</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-20-2024 06:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2319294?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>FINAL Engaging in Video Clubs: Teacher Candidates’ Visioning of Linguistically Responsive Literacy Instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-20-2024 06:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2318225?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Interactional practices of inviting minoritized students to whole‑class mathematics discussions</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-20-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10305-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using positioning theory to think about mathematics classroom talk</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article aims to connect two research areas by using positioning theory to review the literature on talk moves, teacher interactions, and discourse patterns in mathematics education. First, a conceptual review identified 44 articles with 94 concepts describing interactions and discourse patterns. Similar concepts were grouped in a process that developed five categories, each describing one teacher position (a teacher who tells, a teacher who supports, a teacher who uses students’ ideas to create learning, a teacher who orchestrates, and a teacher who participates). Related to each position, we describe rights, duties, and communication acts. We suggest that these five teacher positions represent three transcendent storylines (teachers are providers of insight, teachers are facilitators of learning, and teachers are participants in learning). Using positioning theory enables us to understand the underlying powers that shape the classroom in relation to transcendent storylines, rights, and duties. We use this to explore what the implications are of these storylines and positions for equity and access to important mathematical ideas. This article contributes to our understanding of the complexity of classroom interactions and how transcendent storylines might play a role in subverting or promoting particular classroom communication patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-20-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10295-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Novel Approach for Evaluating a Schoolwide Antiracist Curriculum Intervention</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;This manuscript describes our effort to apply a novel approach to understanding student outcomes associated with a schoolwide antiracist intervention. We report a multimethod quantitative approach to evaluate a 10-week antiracist intervention designed and implemented by school staff by examining patterns of student intervention engagement and measures of key constructs that connect to antiracism, psychological well-being, and school connectedness. Our novel approach combines schoolwide surveys with smaller samples of daily diary participants, documenting variation in intervention engagement and examining postintervention outcomes. Our findings are limited by high attrition rates, small sample size, and data collection during the COVID-19 pandemic; however, our methods offer a promising transferable approach to evaluate school-based antiracist interventions by examining patterns and predictors of intervention engagement, as well as daily fluctuations in student experience throughout the intervention period.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-19-2024 12:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231223476?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Out-of-School Time Programs in the United States in an Era of Racial Reckoning: Insights on Equity From Practitioners, Scholars, Policy Influencers, and Young People</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The out-of-school time (OST) field in the United States has a complex history. The push to offer programming reflects a legacy rooted in moral panics about racially minoritized youth. However, this field is populated by community spaces that act as multipurpose sites of culturally sustaining educational practices supporting positive youth development. We report findings from interviews with OST leaders, youth workers, policy influencers, and youth about how to create, sustain, and protect more liberatory and humanizing practices, demonstrating that racism and deficit-based thinking continue to inform programmatic practices and youth experiences. Furthermore, this study reveals that programs with expansive ideas of youth voice, healing justice, and whole-child approaches to youth development create better opportunities for connection and belonging.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-19-2024 10:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241228824?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Latent Class Analysis of Racial Terminology in Education Research: Patterns of Racial Classifications in AERA Journals</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Education research commonly uses racial terminology but with little understanding of racial classification patterns across the field. In this study, we surface the use of racial terminology using a census of original research published in American Educational Research Association journals between 2009 and 2019. We do so as an ethical quantification exercise, seeking to further social justice goals by encouraging scholarship on racial terminology in education research. Using latent class analysis, we identify six classes of research ranging from about a third of articles that use almost no racial terminology to an eighth of articles that use terminology extensively. More recently published articles are more likely to be part of classes with extensive or narrow racial terminology usage and less likely to be in classes that are absent racial terminology. Qualitative research is more likely to use extensive racial terminology, and quantitative research is more likely to be absent of or narrowly use racial terminology. We conclude with recommendations for how future research can build off of these findings to address questions on how to authentically and purposefully use racial terminology in ways that reflect the complex ways people identify themselves to better situate education research to address racial inequality.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-19-2024 10:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241227901?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Public Preschool Predicts Stronger Third-Grade Academic Skills</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Public preschool boosts academic skills in kindergarten, but little is known about whether that boost lasts to third grade because many studies stop directly assessing children after kindergarten. The current study tests for sustained associations between preschool attendance and an array of repeatedly measured, directly assessed language and math skills; we do this separately for public pre-K and Head Start, the two major publicly funded preschool programs. We draw on a large, racially diverse sample of children from families with low incomes in Tulsa, OK (N = 689, Mage at 3rd = 8.5 years). Using propensity score weighting, we compare children who attended school-based pre-K or Head Start to those who did not attend preschool. Both school-based pre-K and Head Start attenders outperformed preschool nonattenders on numeracy in third grade. There was weaker evidence of a sustained preschool advantage on language and literacy skills, and no evidence that associations differed by preschool program.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-19-2024 10:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231223477?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Meta-Analysis of the Relation Between Syntactic Skills and Reading Comprehension: A Cross-Linguistic and Developmental Investigation</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Theories of reading comprehension have widely predicted a role for syntactic skills, or the ability to understand and manipulate the structure of a sentence. Yet, these theories are based primarily on English, leaving open the question of whether this remains true across typologically different languages such as English versus Chinese. There are substantial differences in the sentence structures of Chinese versus English, making the comparison of the two particularly interesting. We conducted a meta-analysis contrasting the relation between syntactic skills and reading comprehension in first language readers of English versus Chinese. We test the influence of languages as well as the influence of the grade and the metrics on the magnitude of this relation. We identified 59 studies published between 1986 and 2021, generating 234 effect sizes involving 15,212 participants from kindergarten to high school and above. The magnitude of effects was remarkably similar for studies of English (r = .54) and Chinese (r = .54) readers, with similarities at key developmental points and syntactic tasks. There was also some evidence of modulation by grade levels and the nature of syntactic tasks. These findings confirm theory-based predictions of the importance of syntactic skills to reading comprehension. Extending these predictions, demonstrating these effects for both English and Chinese suggests a universal influence of syntactic skills on reading comprehension.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-19-2024 09:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241228185?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Content and Quality of Comparative Tactical Game-Centered Approaches in Physical Education: A Systematic Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Effective teaching pedagogies and curriculum frameworks in school physical education have been regularly changing and widely debated. However, teachers have predominately used technical and sport-based approaches, but tactical game-centered approaches (TGAs) are becoming more common when teaching games in physical education. This review systematically described the content and the quality of research that compared TGAs with other teaching approaches within school physical education. All 24 studies that were found compared a technical approach (TA) or control group with a TGA, and most originated from Western Europe. Studies were conducted equally in primary and secondary schools, most research was mixed-gender, and the majority incorporated a single sport to compare teaching approaches. The quality of reporting was mostly low with a moderate to serious risk of bias. Studies commonly showed that TGAs improved student outcomes in tactical skill; skill execution; affective, procedural knowledge and/or physical activity; and TAs improved skill execution and technical skill.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-19-2024 09:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241227236?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Historicizing Black Educational “Choice”: Toward Black Educational Self Determination</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The linking of school choice and charter schools to the legacy of Black alternative education and civil rights initiatives is a central discursive galvanizing and organizing tool for charter proponents, as it aims to provide legitimacy to the charter movement, while simultaneously coopting Black critiques of the institution of education as a means to further neoliberal restructurings of the state. In this paper, I posit there exists a conceptual and political distinction between school choice and efforts of Black educational self-determination, an approach to challenge white dominance and supremacy. The paper engages in a historical analysis exploring the history of school choice and Black educational self-determination.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-19-2024 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241231953?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Research on teacher education: mirror and compass</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-18-2024 06:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2318687?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evading Race: A Critical Race Analysis of Vocational/Career and Technical Education Policy</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Using critical race theory (CRT) as both our theory and analytical framework, we interrogated vocational, career, and technical education (VCTE) policy as a racial instrument. We applied key CRT themes to examine both primary sources; including historical and contemporary VCTE Acts (e.g., Perkins I-V) and Congressional reports; and secondary sources, including academic analyses of VCTE, its history, and related legislation. Findings demonstrate that VCTE policy upholds race-neutrality, which we argue is problematic because without being designated a special population, racially oppressed students stand to miss out on important funding opportunities that could dramatically alter and improve their lives.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-17-2024 07:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241231956?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ mathematics self-efficacy: a scoping review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students’ mathematics self-efficacy (MSE) is strongly associated with learning behaviours and performance, and students’ future career choices. In our scoping review, we screened what &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;substantive foci&lt;/em&gt; (conceptualization, directionality and role of MSE, change in MSE, and situational specificity of MSE) have been posed and which &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;methodological approaches&lt;/em&gt; (participants, analytical methods, data sources, and congruence of measures) have been used in recent (2018–2022) studies of MSE. Studies of MSE were clearly in the mathematics domain with 21 of 49 included studies exploring specific mathematics areas. The key focus was on strength of MSE. International databases (i.e., PISA) have enabled broad generalization, while in-depth qualitative studies enable minute situation-specificity. Cross-sectional and longitudinal studies using hierarchically nested designs (i.e., students in classrooms) enable us to draw conclusions at both individual, classroom, and school levels. The current state-of-the-art indicates methodological advancement is rapid and we are likely to see further methodological-substantive synergies in the field of MSE in future studies. We see the potential and need for future mixed-methods studies that continue the focus on MSE as a multidimensional and dynamic concept. Careful consideration of the theoretical background of the construct of MSE continues to be important to bring the field forward.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-17-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01548-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is It Any Better? A Comparison of PhD Students’ Experiences and Degree Completion Plans Between the Summers of 2020 and 2021</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;PhD students’ experiences in graduate school and associated outcomes vary by field of study, learning environment conditions, and support structures. In the context of the COVID-19 pandemic specifically, PhD students’ individual educational trajectories were potentially rendered more uncertain, as disruptive conditions for learning and research have continued over the past several years. We compared the reports of 422 PhD students at 12 U.S. institutions in terms of their experiences of support or marginalization and educational plans from the summer of 2020 with follow-up data gathered during the summer of 2021. We then examined factors related to PhD students’ changes in their estimated times to degree. We found lower, but still on average moderate, levels of depression symptoms compared to the previous year and continued experiences of emotional, financial, educational, and career stressors. Findings point to the importance of institutional material and psychological structural supports over time.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-15-2024 06:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241228222?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Heuristics and semantic spaces for the analysis of students’ work in mathematical problem solving</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this research, our objective is to characterize the problem-solving procedures of primary and lower secondary students when they solve problems in real class conditions. To do so, we rely first on the concept of heuristics. As this term is very polysemic, we exploit the definition proposed by Rott (2014) to develop a coding manual and thus analyze students’ procedures. Then, we interpret the results of these analyses in a qualitative way by mobilizing the concept of semantic space (Poitrenaud, 1998). This detailed analysis of students’ procedures is made possible by collecting audiovisual data as close as possible to the students’ work using an action camera mounted on the students’ heads. We thus succeed in highlighting three different investigation profiles that we have named explorer, butterfly, and prospector. Our first results tend to show a correlation with these profiles and the success in problem-solving, yet this would need more investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-15-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10297-y</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
