<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Deficit Beliefs Among High School Math Teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This brief uses national data from the High School Longitudinal Study of 2009 to investigate deficit beliefs, or beliefs that students’ academic underperformance is primarily attributable to deficiencies in their home environments, among high school math teachers. Descriptive results reveal that students in low-level math courses have teachers with more deficit beliefs. Regression results show that net of extensive control variables for both student and teacher characteristics, having a math teacher with stronger deficit beliefs is significantly and negatively associated with students’ math performance. However, this negative association is not more pronounced for youth from minoritized and low socioeconomic status backgrounds.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2025 12:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X251317135?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics education for sustainable futures: a strengths-based survey of the field to invite further research action</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this survey, we introduce and prompt an article collection—&amp;quot;Mathematics Education for Sustainable Futures&amp;quot;—which we are guest editing. The collection will comprise original research articles, written and published over a 2-year period. Recognising the collection title as making reference to what is an emerging area of research, in this introduction, we survey work that has been done. In the spirit of opening and inviting new questions and research directions, we focus on what it means to take mathematics education for sustainable futures seriously, for how we practise and imagine mathematics education, including established topics such as curriculum, knowledge, pedagogy, teacher education, language, modelling, and technology. We structure our review around eight invitations (here arranged into six sections) in the call for collection articles. Each section ends with further invitations for potential authors, or others, wanting to locate and chart their own work in the space. We end drawing out two themes that resonate across the invitations: attention to who and what is marginalised and the importance of a deep reflexivity in our choice/use of concepts. This text is part of the article collection entitled “Mathematics Education for Sustainable Futures” (available at &lt;a href=&quot;link.springer.com/collections/acebaagbha&quot; class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;link.springer.com/collections/acebaagbha&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-12-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-025-10389-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measuring Grading Standards at High Schools: A Methodological Contribution, an Example, and Some Policy Implications</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;At schools with low grading standards, students receive higher school-awarded grades across multiple courses than students with the same skills receive at schools with high grading standards. I show school grading standards vary substantially, enough to affect post-secondary opportunities, across high schools in Alberta, Canada. Schools with low grading standards are more likely to be private, rural, offer courses for students returning to high school after dropping out, have smaller course cohorts, have a smaller percentage of lone-parent households, and have a larger percentage of well-educated parents. The article makes a useful methodological contribution in clarifying the assumptions needed to estimate and interpret a measure of grading standards from course-year-school observations of average school-awarded grades and average external examination grades.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-11-2025 05:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241311537?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How curriculum materials can contribute to implementing instructional innovations: the case of enactment of strategy instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Although curriculum materials are essential for implementing instructional innovations, little is known about how exactly they support teachers’ enactment of innovative approaches and how explicitly they must integrate their key components. The paper contributes to reducing this research gap for one instructional innovation: explicit strategy instruction for word problem comprehension strategies. In our qualitative video study, teachers participated in a professional development on explicit strategy instruction and experimented with it in their classrooms. We compared the teachers’ enactment of strategy instruction in two implementation conditions: in the strong material support condition, teachers received curriculum materials in which components of strategy instruction were explicitly integrated. In the weak material support condition, the curriculum materials only provided the sequence of word problems, but the teachers had to implement explicit strategy instruction themselves. In the qualitative analysis of four cases of teachers’ videorecorded enactment, we unpacked how one teacher with weak support provided only limited learning opportunities by non-targeted enactment, with limited measurable student strategic learning gains. However, in the same condition, another teacher provided productive learning opportunities by explicit and targeted strategy instruction in spite of weak material support. In the strong material support condition, learning opportunities were assured even in a case of partially non-targeted enactment (yet high measurable student strategic learning gains). The findings bear consequences for combining curriculum materials with strong support and professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-11-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01662-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining Task-Specific Incongruous Mathematics Self-Efficacy in University Intermediate Algebra Students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics self-efficacy (MSE), that is students’ beliefs about their ability to be successful in mathematics, is important because it can predict future academic and career achievement, effort, and success on difficult tasks. However, sometimes there students’ self-efficacy may not match their performance, which we call incongruous mathematics self-efficacy (IMSE). Little previous work has examined IMSE and none has examined it at the level of specific mathematics tasks in university intermediate algebra. In this study, fifteen participants were interviewed and asked about their task-specific MSE for three problems, two purely algebraic and one word problem, that they were then asked to solve. We compared participants’ MSE and their solutions to identify instances of incongruous task-specific MSE, finding them for eleven of the fifteen participants. For example, on the word problem, one participant rated the problem as difficult and expressed low confidence in her work but solved the problem correctly. We describe 12 total instances of task-specific IMSE in qualitative detail. Our results have implications for the measurement of MSE as well as for university educators who strive to better support students’ education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-11-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00261-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/aera/62/1&quot;&gt;Volume 62, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 259-264, February 2025. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2025 10:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241308945?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Introduction</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/aera/62/1&quot;&gt;Volume 62, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 3-13, February 2025. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2025 10:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312251317246?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding student errors in comparing data sets with boxplots</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In the boxplot, the box always represents – regardless of its area – the middle half of the data and thus a measure of variability (interquartile range). However, when students first learn about boxplots, they are usual already familiar with other forms of statistical representations (e.g., bar or circle graphs) in which a larger area represents a higher frequency of observations. If students erroneously apply this well-established area-represents-frequency schema to boxplots, it results in a systematic error which we describe as the consequence of an incomplete conceptual change. We empirically validated difficulty-generating characteristics that allow the differentiation between item types with varying complexity (item level) and aimed to identify profiles (person level) that differ depending on which schema was used in which item type. For this purpose, we conducted two cross-sectional studies with &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 100 university students (study 1) and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 297 participants who finished secondary school or higher (study 2) and used generalized linear mixed models (item level) and k-means clustering with predefined cluster centers (person level) to test our hypotheses. We could replicate the systematic error that was described in previous research and found new difficulty-generating characteristics in boxplot items. Our results support the notion of different profiles potentially emerging based on varying degrees of conceptual change. From an instructional perspective, information about individual progress in conceptual change could be considered for tailoring individualized interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-025-10387-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Public engagement of underserved students with open civic data</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Today, various non-governmental organizations proclaim the need for public engagement of citizens, a concept that is integrated into the notion of global citizenship. However, much of the mathematics that students find in the primary school curriculum falls short to support that need. This lack of curriculum alignment with global needs has implications for the development of communities, but they are much more severe for students from underserved populations who systematically suffer different types of exclusions that increase their social disadvantages. This study explores the traits of global citizenship that students from underserved populations exhibit as they progress through a learning experience with open civic data on a global issue (climate change). The learning experience was used as the basis for an individual interview with five participants (9–10 years old) from public schools in low-income neighborhoods of a metropolitan area in northern Colombia. Participants were offered a dataset (data) ready to use and they were asked to undertake data handling actions (data-ing) using freely available web-based software. Participants were asked “What does this dataset say?” and their verbal statements were analyzed. The main findings suggest that in data and data-ing on open civic data reflecting global issues, participants exhibited understanding, belonging and action which are traits of global citizenship. In terms of understanding, participants described the behavior of the variables, suggested informal inferences, and made associations between variables. In terms of belonging and action, participants’ statements suggested including themselves as part of the community, taking responsibility, and proposing transformative actions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01641-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Potential of Research–Practice Partnerships to Support State Education Leaders as Agents of Change</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;State education agencies have increasing influence over educational policy and practice, with responsibilities ranging from vision setting to monitoring compliance with accountability policy. Although state education agency leaders are well positioned to advance change, capacity building at this level of the education system has been traditionally limited. Research–practice partnerships (RPPs) represent a promising venue to support the ability of state leaders to facilitate educational change. In this qualitative study, we drew on semistructured interviews with state education agency leaders and observations of RPP meetings to examine the state-level structures that pose challenges to leaders’ efforts to make change and how participating in an RPP can support leaders in addressing these challenges. Findings reveal how RPP engagement supported state leaders with navigating complex organizational silos and bureaucratic processes by promoting relationship building and supporting the use of evidence-based resources. These insights may inform future research and capacity-building efforts at the state level of the education system.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2025 06:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584251315089?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Metacognitive behaviour when working on modelling problems in small groups</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The use of metacognitive strategies when working on modelling problems in small groups is assumed to lead to goal-oriented and effective processing of the problems. Based on the analysis of eight group processes of grade 9 students working on a modelling problem, this article takes a detailed look at the initiation of metacognitive behaviour by individual students in the group process. For this purpose, videos were coded using a deductive category system in accordance with structuring qualitative content analysis, which was enriched inductively. As a result, the metacognitive strategies initiated by individual students were classified according to two criteria: the time of occurrence (during or between modelling phases) and if they relate to the content of task processing and to the behaviour of group members. Furthermore, seven aims were identified, three of which were related to different areas of metacognitive strategies, and four of which arose from the level of collaborative and socioemotional engagement in the groups. Additionally, the latter could be linked to the extent to which the groups worked together cooperatively or collaboratively and to the extent to which the individual members were included and valued in the work process.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-025-01661-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inclusive education through the critical action research (CAR) approach</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2025 06:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2025.2464050?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Biological corridors: using participatory action research to map ecological and social relations in conservation work</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2025 08:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2025.2462320?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/47/1&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Spring 2025, Page 1-2&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2025 01:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2025.2461436?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ performance and typical errors in filling empty probabilistic visualizations with probabilities or frequencies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;It has been established that, in Bayesian tasks, performance and typical errors in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;reading&lt;/em&gt; information from filled visualizations depend both on the type of the provided visualization and information format. However, apart from reading visualizations, students should also be able to create visualizations on their own and successfully use them as heuristic tools in modeling tasks. In this paper, we first want to broaden the view on Bayesian reasoning to probabilistic tasks with two binary events in general and embed the whole process of solving these tasks using probabilistic visualizations in a modified modeling framework. Thereby, it becomes apparent that most of the steps remained untouched by existing research. Second, in the present empirical study, we focused on one part of the largely unexplored creation process and examined &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;entering&lt;/em&gt; statistical information into empty visualizations as heuristic tools. &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 172 participants had to enter conditional and joint probabilities or the corresponding frequencies into empty visualizations in a paper-and-pencil test. We analyze (a) students’ performance when entering information in visualizations and (b) typical errors, both dependent on the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;information format&lt;/em&gt; (probabilities vs. natural frequencies), which &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;empty visualization structure&lt;/em&gt; (2⨯2 table, double tree, net diagram) was provided, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;type of information&lt;/em&gt; (conditional vs. joint information). The well-known positive effect of natural frequencies on participants’ performance was evident when entering conditional information into 2⨯2 tables and net diagrams. However, with respect to joint information, no superior effect of frequencies was observed. Furthermore, the theoretical implementation of our research in a modeling cycle allows us to identify desiderata for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10372-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Noticing to learn from lesson study: the role of critical events</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Critical events are incidents encountered by teachers in their practice that can potentially provoke questions about the instructional decisions made, gaining an entry to changing and improving teaching practices. Current research often conceptualises critical events as those that occur during instruction, but critical events can also occur before and after instruction, especially in the contexts of lesson study. In this paper, I will unpack the notion of a critical reflection event during the study, plan, and reflect phases of lesson study through three vignettes that happened during a lesson study cycle. This paper examines how lesson study positions teachers to notice critical reflection events that can provoke pedagogical reasoning and action for the purpose of gaining new comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-025-09680-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teachers’ noticing of critical events associated with argumentation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study explores secondary-school mathematics teachers’ noticing of Critical Events Associated with Argumentation (CEAs), moments when students’ reasoning or interactions become evident, offering teachers opportunities to promote argumentation in the classroom. Thirty-one teachers analyzed a written classroom scenario, identifying CEAs, interpreting their potential for fostering argumentation, and proposing teaching alternatives. The findings reveal that teachers identified CEAs emphasizing either mathematical arguments, collaborative interactions in constructing and evaluating arguments, or both, with a primary focus on dialogic interactions. The identified CEAs, along with their interpretations and proposed strategies, demonstrated alignment, by focusing on common underlying aspects. The dynamic interconnection among components of noticing—attending, interpreting, and responding—challenges linear models, suggesting iterative and holistic processes. By framing CEAs as opportunities to integrate structural and dialogic aspects of argumentation, this study contributes to refining noticing frameworks and advancing teachers&#39; professional development. Theoretical and practical implications for research on noticing and argumentation in mathematics education are discussed, alongside recommendations for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-05-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-025-09682-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Text-based discussion interactions and engagement with three different text types</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2025 08:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2423177?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring students’ conceptual understanding through mathematical problem solving: students’ use of and shift between different representations of rational numbers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2025 05:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2025.2456840?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teacher educators’ instructional modifications: A cultural-comparative study using a Czech mathematics classroom video</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this cultural-comparative study, we examined the recommendations for instructional modifications made by 12 Czech and 12 non-Czech mathematics teacher educators (MTEs). The non-Czech MTEs were selected from countries culturally distinct from Czechia, including Costa Rica, Japan, Kosovo, Türkiye, the UK, and the USA, with two MTEs from each country. The participants were invited to provide written feedback on a part of a video lesson (teaching segment) in which a Czech elementary mathematics teacher handled student errors. The results demonstrated that the Czech MTEs emphasized individual learning and content, while the non-Czech MTEs’ feedback was more diverse, advocating a more collaborative and reflective learning environment. Drawing on the limitations of our study, implications for future research are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-025-00518-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Feasibility and Comparability of Using Artificial Intelligence for Qualitative Data Analysis in Equity-Focused Research</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this essay, we explored the feasibility of utilizing artificial intelligence (AI) for qualitative data analysis in equity-focused research. Specifically, we compare thematic analyses of interview transcripts conducted by human coders with those performed by GPT-3 using a zero-shot chain-of-thought prompting strategy. Our results suggest that the AI model, when provided with suitable prompts, can proficiently perform thematic analysis, demonstrating considerable comparability with human coders. Despite potential biases inherent in its training data, the model was able to analyze and interpret the data through social justice perspectives. We discuss the applications of integrating AI into qualitative research, provide code snippets illustrating the use of GPT models, and highlight unresolved questions to encourage further dialogue in the field.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 11:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X251314821?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We are born mentors … It’s in our DNA”: Exploring Indigenous Australian kinship mentoring practices</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 11:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2025.2459944?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Turnover, Social Capital, and Improvement: How Instability Disrupts Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Teacher turnover is a persistent policy concern in public education. Researchers have documented negative impacts of turnover on student outcomes; yet we know little about the causal mechanisms by which turnover influences, or disrupts, schools’ efforts to improve. In our longitudinal qualitative study, we examined how turnover affects relationships, trust, and shared knowledge in organizations—that is, organizational social capital—in ways that can impede school improvement efforts. We found that teacher turnover depletes organizational social capital by disrupting networks and relationships between teachers working in teams, weakening shared meanings and goals in schools, and impeding teachers’ ability to collectively engage in problem-solving and learning. We illuminate the hidden ways in which instability undermines improvement efforts and strains organizations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 07:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241311304?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the knowledge structure of coping strategies in teacher education research using bibliometric analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2025 01:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2025.2458496?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
