<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Democratic pedagogies in initial teacher education: co-constructing a supportive learning framework</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-27-2024 05:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2317202?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Discursive Variability of Mathematics Coaches</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Research on how coaches talk with teachers during coaching cycles is underdeveloped. We analyzed 1,649 discourse moves from 24 mathematics content-focused coaching cycles to determine the extent to which coaches’ discursive tendencies vary. We explored variation between coaches, between planning and debriefing conversations, and between cycles for the same coach–teacher pair. Findings indicate there existed significant variability in the coaches’ discourse moves during coaching cycles. We also found discursive differences from planning to debriefing meetings, noting that coaches were more directive and less reflective in planning conversations compared with debriefing conversations. Across multiple coaching cycles, we found variation across coaches, with one coach increasing the prevalence of directive moves across four planning conversations and another increasing the prevalence of reflective moves across four debriefing conversations. Although we focus on mathematics coaches, the findings and methodology may be applicable to other disciplines.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 11:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241231537?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Discipline, Police Contact, and GPA: A Mediation Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Exclusionary school discipline is one of the primary ways that schools address student behavior. Existing scholarship has focused on examining the implications of exclusionary school discipline for two sets of outcomes: academic achievement and future juvenile and criminal legal involvement. However, these two areas of scholarship are largely treated as separate. In this paper, we bridge these two research areas by drawing on scholarship examining the negative educational consequences of police contact for youth. Specifically, we formally test the proposition that the association between school suspension in childhood and adolescent academic achievement is mediated by police contact experienced in early adolescence. Using data from the Future of Families and Child Wellbeing Study, we find support for this hypothesis: Early adolescent police contact explains approximately 30% of the association between school suspension in childhood and adolescent GPA. By relying on exclusionary school discipline, our results suggest that schools are setting the stage for youth to become involved in the criminal legal system, which, in turn, hinders future academic achievement.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 10:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241231988?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of Information Provision on the Gender Gap in Technology: Experimental Evidence From Course Enrollment and Major Decisions</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article reports on the impacts of a nudge intervention designed to narrow the gender gap in technology education. I randomly assigned approximately 4,000 college freshmen to one of three advising interventions during new student orientation. Students in the treatment group received a brochure containing information about technology courses and were exposed to stereotypical imagery, neutral imagery, or counter-stereotypical imagery. Information provision had a positive impact on both technology course take-up and technology major selection. A stronger response by men led to an overall increase in the gender gap, but this gap is smallest among students exposed to counter-stereotypical imagery.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 05:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241228278?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dual Language Immersion Programs and Student Achievement in Early Elementary Grades</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper presents evidence of the effects of dual language immersion (DLI) programs on the academic outcomes of students in elementary grades. Leveraging enrollment lotteries from four cohorts of DLI applicants across 10 oversubscribed programs, analyses estimate the intent-to-treat effect of access to bilingual education on reading and math test scores. On average, native English-speaking students in Grades 1 through 4 who win access to a DLI program score higher in reading and math by 0.12 and 0.14 SDs, respectively. The achievement gains in test scores are realized as early as first grade.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 05:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241228829?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>After School: An Examination of the Career Paths and Earnings of Former Teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We use a novel linkage of school district administrative data to Internal Revenue Service records to study educators’ post-exit career outcomes. The majority of leavers remain in education and mean earnings are slightly below pre-exit earnings even 8 years later. However, these average changes conceal wide variation in outcomes. Roughly 20% of leavers are unemployed, and the bottom quartile of employed leavers earn less than $20,000 annually. At the same time, earnings among the top quartile of employed leavers are higher than those of nearly all stayers, sometimes exceeding $100,000. Post-exit employment and earnings declines are associated with the presence of children or a high-earning spouse for voluntary female leavers, suggesting a role for family-conscious policies for teacher retention.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241227906?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race Matters: A Family–Educator Antiracist Curriculum Collaboration</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 02:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2308483?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fostering pre-service teachers’ attention to mathematical objects: The realization tree mediator as a teaching representation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Using teaching representations is one of the common means for preparing pre-service mathematics teachers (PSTs) to learn how to teach mathematics meaningfully. However, turning PSTs’ attention to the mathematical objects that students engage with during the lesson is a challenging pursuit. This paper suggests using the Realization Tree Mediator (RTM) as a visual teaching representation for PST learning to implement cognitively demanding tasks in their classrooms. The RTM depicts the mathematical object at the core of a task and its different realizations while illustrating imaginary classroom discussions in which different realizations and the links between them are produced. By analyzing PSTs’ conversations around RTM images, we show how contrasting pairs of RTMs can be used for eliciting conversations about various aspects of cognitively demanding instruction. We discuss the affordances of the RTM as a teaching representation and how it can assist in making the mathematical content and meanings visible, public, and communicable among teachers and teacher educators.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-26-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09622-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial, The transformative power of action research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-25-2024 07:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2321728?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A critical race analysis of Māori representation in university strategic documents in Aotearoa New Zealand</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-24-2024 12:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2306379?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Studying Parole Revocation Practices: Accounting for Dependency Between Competing Events</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;When individuals are released from prison, they typically enter a period of post confinement community supervision. While under community supervision, their behaviors are subject to special conditions requiring them to report to supervisors and prohibiting certain behaviors such as drug and alcohol use. Many supervisees are returned to prison because they violate those special conditions, or because they commit minor crimes that would not result in prison were they not being supervised. But others are returned to prison for serious new crimes. We distinguish the two as nuisance behaviors (the former) and pernicious behaviors (the latter). Our research applies competing events survival analysis to distinguish a structural model that accounts for nuisance behaviors from a structural model that accounts for pernicious behaviors. We demonstrate that returning offenders to prison for technical violations and minor crimes may reduce the incidence of major crimes because the occurrence of nuisance behaviors and pernicious behaviors are highly correlated. Our findings support the theory that nuisance behaviors signal the likelihood of pernicious behaviors.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-24-2024 11:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241234412?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An empirically validated rational number sense framework</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;A theoretical model describing Grade 7 students’ rational number sense was formulated and validated empirically (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 360), hypothesizing that rational number sense is a general construct consisting of three factors: basic rational number sense, arithmetic sense, and flexibility with rational numbers. Data analysis suggested that rational-number tasks can be categorized based on the validated model. The flexibility component reflects thinking about rational numbers in terms of noticing, using, and expressing relations and properties of numbers in patterns, functions, covariation, and complicated computational tasks. It includes utilizing number structure and relational understanding of operations and numbers. Analysis identified three categories of students that represent different rational-number sense profiles. Category 1 students exhibited a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;limited basic&lt;/em&gt; profile that solved mainly traditional school-based tasks. Category 2 students reflected the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;basic emergent arithmetic&lt;/em&gt; sense profile that responded adequately in operation tasks. Category 3 students represented the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;flexible emergent&lt;/em&gt; profile, as they manipulated underlying structures in a variety of situations, indicating an emergent fundamental shift from an arithmetic to an algebraic focus. A discriminant analysis showed that basic and flexible factors could discriminate students best between the three identified profiles of rational number sense.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-24-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00484-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emergence of Uncertainties and Mathematical Problems Through Collective Investigation on Routine Tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article aims to illustrate how the collective resolution of routine mathematical tasks can give rise to uncertainties, fostering and supporting a rich and authentic mathematical activity. While solving routine tasks may not typically be classified as problem-solving, the research presented in this paper shows that, at the collective level, their resolution can give rise to new mathematical tasks to solve in the classroom and generate authentic problem-solving activity. Grounded in the enaction theory of cognition (e.g. Maturana &amp;amp; Varela in Shambhala, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r20&quot;&gt;1992&lt;/span&gt;), this research considers the class as a unit, as a collectivity, which brings forth a mathematical activity. In this article, examples derived from an experiment conducted in elementary-level mathematics classrooms are used to show the emergence of uncertainties, highlighting the mathematical potential resulting from the collective resolution of routine tasks. In conclusion, the article introduces the concept of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;collective mathematical problems&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-24-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-024-00308-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Disenchanting Educational Policy and Leadership: An Introduction</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This introduction provides an overview of the articles in the special issue. Drawing on Sylvia Wynter’s notion of disenchantment, the articles in this special issue interrogate power and inequity in education. They question the given assumptions of education policy and aim to reorient us toward justice and educational transformation, pushing back against claims of “neutrality” or educational projects that reinscribe harm.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-23-2024 12:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241233779?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Framework for Deepening Racial Equity in Prenatal-Grade Three Systems: Lessons From a 10-Year Reflective Case Study</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper uses a reflective, retrospective case study methodology to analyze data from a 10-year University-Community partnership focused on supporting implementation and improvement of a Prenatal-Grade 3 (P3) system in an elementary school. Using a framework for centering equity in Collective Impact approaches, we analyze the steps we took as research partners/program evaluators to address racial and other inequities while highlighting missed opportunities to better center racial equity in the evaluation and P3 Initiative work. Through our analysis, we seek to identify where and how racial inequities surfaced, to describe how systemic racism influenced the evaluation and P3 Initiative process, and how this served to perpetuate the status quo and prevent transformative systems change. Results speak to opportunities for researchers, funders, and policymakers to identify and disrupt conventionally-accepted approaches to educational research and to work more effectively to advance educational equity for children and their families.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-23-2024 12:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241231957?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leaning Into Difficult Topics: Inquiry Communities as Teacher Professional Learning for Turbulent Times</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although teachers make frequent decisions about whether and how to address difficult topics, they typically do so with minimal support. This article reports a case study of an inquiry community of 20 educators who engaged in practitioner inquiry as professional learning for addressing the difficult topics that they teach within their curricula or otherwise encounter within their professional practices. Through an inductive thematic analysis of semi-structured interviews with 12 community participants, the article’s authors identified four themes characterizing how the inquiry community supported teachers to lean into the difficult topics they believed they needed to address. The community helped teachers define difficult-topics inquiry while connecting them across divergent political and professional perspectives. The community assisted teachers in engaging difficult topics through purposefully structured inquiry talk, and it prompted them to (re)conceptualize difficult-topics teaching as inquiry. The article demonstrates the potential of difficult-topics inquiry communities as professional learning for turbulent times.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-23-2024 06:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871241231543?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Streaming (Tracking) in Eighth Grade Mathematics Reinforces Racialized Social Class Inequalities in Aotearoa New Zealand</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-23-2024 04:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2310461?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Numerical magnitude understanding of natural and rational numbers in secondary-school students: a number line estimation study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Rational numbers, such as fractions and decimals, are harder to understand than natural numbers. Moreover, individuals struggle with fractions more than with decimals. The present study sought to disentangle the extent to which two potential sources of difficulty affect secondary-school students’ numerical magnitude understanding: number type (natural vs. rational) and structure of the notation system (place-value-based vs. non-place-value-based). To do so, a 2 (number type) × 2 (structure of the notation system) within-subjects design was created in which 61 secondary-school students estimated the position of four notations on a number line: natural numbers (e.g., 214 on a 0–1000 number line), decimals (e.g., 0.214 on a 0–1 number line), fractions (e.g., 3/14 on a 0–1 number line), and separated fractions (3 on a 0–14 number line). In addition to response times and error rates, eye tracking captured students’ on-line solution process. Students had slower response times and higher error rates for fractions than the other notations. Eye tracking revealed that participants encoded fractions longer than the other notations. Also, the structure of the notation system influenced participants’ eye movement behavior in the endpoint of the number line more than number type. Overall, our findings suggest that when a notation contains &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; sources of difficulty (i.e., rational and non-place-value-based, like fractions), this contributes to a worse understanding of its numerical magnitude than when it contains only &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., natural but non-place-value-based, like separated fractions, or place-value-based but rational, like decimals) or &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;neither&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., natural and place-value-based, like natural numbers) of these sources of difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-23-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10291-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The American Story of Blackness: Moving Beyond the Violence of Whiteness in Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-22-2024 02:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2024.2309094?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evolution of teachers’ and researchers’ praxeologies for designing inquiry mathematics tasks: the role of teachers’ beliefs</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper is focused on the collaborative work of two communities, one of teachers and one of researchers, during a teacher professional development program on the inquiry-based learning approach in mathematics, addressed to lower secondary school in-service mathematics teachers. We conceptualize the design of inquiry mathematics task as the boundary object on which the two communities work collaboratively. We aim to study the evolution of teachers’ and researchers’ meta-didactical praxeologies for designing inquiry mathematics tasks, with the Meta-Didactical Transposition framework, to understand if and how their collaboration favors their convergence toward shared components of final meta-didactical praxeologies. In the results, we show that this convergence is reached thanks to internalization processes of praxeological components for designing inquiry mathematics tasks, as a consequence of the learning mechanisms activated by the common work on the boundary object. In this paper, we address also the issue of understanding the complex relationship between teachers’ beliefs on inquiry mathematics tasks and the meta-didactical praxeologies of teachers and researchers. As a result, we propose a model in which the evolution of teachers’ beliefs is taken into account both as an agent and a consequence of the evolution of the meta-didactical praxeologies of the two communities involved in the teacher professional development program.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09620-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How can procedural flowcharts support the development of mathematics problem-solving skills?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Supporting students’ problem-solving skills, solution planning and sequencing of different stages that are involved in successfully developing a meaningful solution to a problem has been a challenge for teachers. This case study was informed by reflective investigation methodology which explored how procedural flowcharts can support student mathematics problem solving in a senior Mathematical Methods subject in Queensland. The paper used thematic analysis to analyse and report on teachers’ perceptions of the utility of procedural flowcharts during problem solving as well as content analysis on how student-developed flowcharts can support their problem-solving skills. Results show that development of procedural flowcharts can support problem solving as it helps with integration of problem-solving stages.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-22-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00483-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Polarization, Partisan Sorting, and the Politics of Education</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Drawing on annual, nationally representative survey data from 2007–2022, I demonstrate that partisan gaps—the average differences in public opinion between Democrats and Republicans—have widened on many education issues. This pattern consistently exceeds what would be expected due to the changing demographic compositions of the parties alone. Widening partisan gaps are primarily attributable to sorting (alignment of one&#39;s party affiliation and one&#39;s issue positions) rather than polarization (increasing support for more extreme positions relative to more moderate positions). However, polarization is also increasing on some of the most divisive issues. Among those who are sorting, individuals are overwhelmingly switching their issue positions to align with their party affiliations rather than switching their party affiliations to align with their issue positions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 09:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241228280?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Patterns of Absenteeism from Prekindergarten Through Early Elementary School and Their Associations With Children’s Academic Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Using statewide administrative data from a sample of children enrolled in public prekindergarten (pre-K) programs in Massachusetts, I examined heterogeneity in children’s absenteeism patterns from pre-K to Grade 3 and linked these patterns to their Grade 3 academic outcomes. After latent class growth analysis, six absenteeism patterns emerged. The vast majority of children (85%) had consistently low absenteeism, and only a small percentage of children (1%) demonstrated consistently high absenteeism. Four patterns showed variation in absenteeism over time, with two characterized by high absenteeism in only the pre-K year, another with a peak during kindergarten, and a final one with rising absenteeism across grades. Children with always low absenteeism had higher average English language arts and math scores than did children in the other patterns, and children in the two high pre-K absenteeism patterns and peak in kindergarten pattern had higher math scores than those with rising and always high absenteeism patterns.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 08:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241228212?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating Sustainable Mobility: Motorized and Non-motorized Modes in Suburban Areas of Thailand</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The impact of sustainable mobility may be considered through the mode of non-motorization, which may vary by spatial environmental conditions, especially accessibility by active mobility in a necessarily safe, comfortable, and pleasant atmosphere. Sustainable mobility comprises willingness to allow commuting behaviors on non-motorized travel for safety and green ethics. These chiefly participate to create livable places, improve health and well-being, and promote quality of life and economic growth. By contrast, an impoverished street environment decreases the possibility of active mobility and relies on motorization. It is essential to explore the perception of road users through diverse environmental features of street networks and sidewalks directly affecting road user behavior and preferences about motorization and non-motorization. This study evaluated multi-indicators of sustainable urban mobility (SUM) for a group of road users, with data gathered by questionnaire-based survey. 1,998 Pathum Thani Province inhabitants in Thailand were asked to evaluate their neighborhood characteristics by SUM indicators. In addition to different social dimensions and socioeconomic backgrounds, transportation characteristics among diverse trip makers and different perceptions of mobility indicators were classified by factor analysis using principal components and spatial visualization. Results were that traffic management, including intersection controls and signage, as well as information, sidewalk, management, and personal mobility choices, is a key strategy to improve sustainable mobility. This is achieved by tailoring solutions to achieve a modal shift prioritized over other supportive facilities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-21-2024 07:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241233669?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
