<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strategies to Better Identify Student Homelessness Using Data in an Urban School District</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We tested 10 data-based strategies to better identify student homelessness in Camden City School District, which has a student body from minoritized backgrounds. We operationalized strategies through a research-practice partnership, following the federal homelessness definition. Data span 5 years (2014–15 through 2018–19), including integrated education, municipal, and health records. Nine strategies indicated significant unidentified student homelessness (min: 15; max: 5,008; p-values &amp;lt; .001). Consistent with homelessness, six strategies produced groups with lower attendance (p-values &amp;lt; .01) and seven with increased school mobility (p-values &amp;lt; .05). Homelessness was 34% greater in the most conservative interpretation, though counts could be as much as 454% greater. Student homelessness is more prevalent than recognized, data-based strategies can guide proactive outreach, and cross-system partnerships are warranted.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X231215347?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond Prescriptive Reforms: An Examination of North Carolina’s Flexible School Restart Program</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although multiple studies have examined the impact of school turnaround, less is known about reforms under the Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA). To advance this literature, we examine North Carolina’s Restart (NCR) model. NCR aligns with ESSA by giving school leaders increased flexibility. Also, NCR differs from previous turnaround models by repackaging a traditionally sanction-based approach to instead motivate school leaders with increased autonomy. Using comparative interrupted time series models, we find positive NCR effects in math, but not in English Language Arts or on nontest-based student outcomes. Also, nearly a quarter of the positive NCR effect can be explained by decreased teacher and principal turnover. These results provide evidence to support current shifts toward reform models featuring local autonomy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-15-2024 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231218735?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career aspirations of the students preparing to work as teachers in Poland, Latvia and Ukraine</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-14-2024 03:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2301973?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“She didn’t mean it that way”: theorizing gendered Islamophobia in academia</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cree20/27/1&quot;&gt;Volume 27, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, January 2024, Page 39-54&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2024 07:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2268318?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Taking boys seriously: Utilising participatory action research to tackle compounded educational disadvantage</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper presents successive phases of Taking Boys Seriously (TBS), a longitudinal participatory action research initiative bringing together diverse educational bodies and indigenous educators across a highly stratified education system in a contested society. The voices and everyday life and school experiences of adolescent boys are positioned firmly at the centre of a research methodology aimed at re-engaging, empowering, and learning from marginalised boys. We discuss how a collaborative and reflexive process co-produced with a committed steering group has been vital in pursuit of systemic change. New concepts of compounded educational disadvantage, relational education, and an educational ecosystem have been co-theorised and applied in practical ways to counter deficit narratives and support holistic approaches and new partnerships across educational settings in Northern Ireland. Strengths and limitations of our participatory approach are considered, particularly in relation to the role and participation of boys in the research process.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2024 03:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241226894?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mentors Matter Recruitment Replication &amp; Extension: Investigating Effects Across Implementation Years</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 08:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2023.2287615?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Struggles and Successes of Pre-Service Teachers When Implementing a Student-Centered Curriculum in an After-School Program</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/46/1&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Spring 2024, Page 3-20&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 07:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2260344?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nearby Nature: An Interdisciplinary Science, Literacy, and Technology Project Situated within a Traditional Teacher Preparation Program</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/46/1&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Spring 2024, Page 21-37&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 07:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2270923?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preparing Community Teachers Early: Exploring Aspiring Teacher Learning and Identity Development in a Grow Your Own Program</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/46/1&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Spring 2024, Page 38-55&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 07:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2282417?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Applying an Equity Framework to Develop Inclusive Visions of STEM Teaching: Honoring the Voices of Students with Dis/Abilities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/46/1&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Spring 2024, Page 75-93&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 07:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2290250?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>White Preservice Teachers and Antiracist Practice: Enabling Trajectories of Learning and Identity in Teacher Preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/46/1&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Spring 2024, Page 56-74&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 07:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2292628?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/46/1&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Spring 2024, Page 1-2&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 07:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2298163?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reframing teacher education around inclusion, equity, and social justice: towards an authentically value-centred approach to teacher education in Europe</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/46/5&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2023&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 03:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2288556?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pushing crisis response towards sustainable transformation? Reflections from a case analysis of crisis-framed policy actions on teacher education in three European settings</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/46/5&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2023&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 03:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2288811?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reimagining teacher education in light of the teacher shortage and the aftershock of COVID-19: adjusting to a rapidly shifting world</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/46/5&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2023&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 03:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2294697?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why teacher education matters even more</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/46/5&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2023&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 03:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2298631?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking teacher education in/for challenging times: reconciling enduring tensions, imagining new possibilities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/46/5&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2023&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 03:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2299926?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reimagining and remaking teacher education: priorities, practices and dilemmas</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/46/5&quot;&gt;Volume 46, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2023&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 03:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2298632?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ethical dilemmas and professional judgment as a pathway to inclusion and equity in mathematics teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study focuses on ethical dilemmas that arise in moments of inclusion and equity in mathematics teaching and how they might be tackled through teachers’ professional judgment. Skovsmose’s inclusive landscapes of investigation approach was used to design the study and to collect teachers’ joint reflections on moments of inclusion and equity in their teaching. Ethical dilemmas and professional judgment were the analytical foci for a qualitative thematic content analysis. Three explorative workshops were held with two teams of teachers from two schools in Sweden. The analysis identified three themes of ethical dilemma, and ways in which these were responded to by teachers’ professional judgment: &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;(1) dilemmas of diversity and acting justly; (2) dilemmas of resources and allocating them fairly; (3) dilemmas of values and recognising diversity.&lt;/em&gt; We conclude that mathematics teachers’ professional judgments involve showing bravery, going outside of the norm, negotiating values and duties, listening to the students, and throughout this, engaging in collegial learning in the best interests of the learner.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01540-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strongly didactic contracts and mathematical work</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper describes how the notion of the strongly didactic contract can serve to characterize the teaching adopted to implement a task in probability. It is particularly focused on the reality of mathematical work performed by students and teachers. For this research, classroom sessions were developed in an in-service teacher training course designed (and adapted) according to the Japanese Lesson Study model. Through the combined use of the Theory of Didactical Situations (TDS) and the Theory of Mathematical Working Spaces (ThMWS), a coding of the sessions observed was developed. Based on this coding, different patterns emerged which gave each session a specific rhythm and identity from which it was possible to recognize and characterize different strongly didactic contracts. The study highlights the difference between the potential contracts intended by the teachers and those observed in practice. The tools, and especially the coding, developed for the study could be used for future research on instructional situations or in-service teacher training.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10286-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Teachers Satisfied With Their Evaluations? The Importance of Teaching Context and Trends Over Time</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/10&quot;&gt;Volume 10, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2024. &lt;br/&gt;Nationally, teachers have experienced major changes in how their performance is evaluated. Teacher satisfaction with the evaluation system likely influences whether they will use the evaluation data to make instructional improvements, yet we know little about teachers’ perceptions of their evaluations. Using survey data from Chicago Public Schools, we explore teacher satisfaction with the evaluation system and their perceptions of its fairness and accuracy. Sixty percent of teachers reported being satisfied with the district’s reformed teacher evaluation. However, satisfaction declined following the implementation of the district’s more rigorous evaluation system, driven by tenured teachers’ differentially negative impressions. Notably, teacher satisfaction was higher in schools with strong climates, particularly where teachers perceived instructional leadership as effective. These findings underscore the importance of school leaders in the implementation of teacher evaluation policies and suggest that some principals need support fostering school climates focused on instructional improvement and building strong relationships with staff.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2024 08:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584231221539?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Relational perplexities of today’s teachers: social-emotional competence perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2024 05:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2298194?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers Centering Families and Building Rapport During Home Visits</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Collaborative relationships between families and teachers of elementary-aged children are complicated by teachers’ lack of training for family engagement and by hierarchical and racialized power differentials. Home visiting can create a space for teachers to center and honor families’ ways of knowing and being, but those home visits need to be conducted in ways specifically intended to build relationships with families; otherwise, the visits can do damage. In this descriptive exploratory study, we examined how teachers responded to families’ openings during home visits. We articulate a theory that describes actions teachers can employ to build rapport, particularly across difference. This work has implications for research on family engagement and for teacher preparation for home visiting.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2024 07:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231222270?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role and Influence of Exclusively Online Degree Programs in Higher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study leverages national data and a quasi-experimental design to examine the influence of enrolling in an exclusively online degree program on students’ likelihood of completing their degree. We find that enrolling in an exclusively online degree program had a negative influence on students’ likelihood of completing their bachelor&#39;s degree or any degree when compared to their otherwise-similar peers who enrolled in at least some face-to-face courses. The negative relationship between exclusively online enrollment and students’ likelihood of bachelor&#39;s degree completion was relatively consistent among White, Black, Hispanic, Asian, low-income, and military students. Findings focused solely on those students enrolled in exclusively online degree programs revealed that the negative influence of exclusively online enrollment was exacerbated when the student attended a for-profit 4-year institution.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2024 07:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231222264?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
