<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Two-Level Adaptive Test Battery</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A test battery with two different levels of adaptation is presented: a within-subtest level for the selection of the items in the subtests and a between-subtest level to move from one subtest to the next. The battery runs on a two-level model consisting of a regular response model for each of the subtests extended with a second level for the joint distribution of their abilities. The presentation of the model is followed by an optimized MCMC algorithm to update the posterior distribution of each of its ability parameters, select the items to Bayesian optimality, and adaptively move from one subtest to the next. Thanks to extremely rapid convergence of the Markov chain and simple posterior calculations, the algorithm can be used in real-world applications without any noticeable latency. Finally, an empirical study with a battery of short diagnostic subtests is shown to yield score accuracies close to traditional one-level adaptive testing with subtests of double lengths.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2023 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231209447?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analyzing Polytomous Test Data: A Comparison Between an Information-Based IRT Model and the Generalized Partial Credit Model</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Item response theory (IRT) models the relationship between the possible scores on a test item against a test taker’s attainment of the latent trait that the item is intended to measure. In this study, we compare two models for tests with polytomously scored items: the optimal scoring (OS) model, a nonparametric IRT model based on the principles of information theory, and the generalized partial credit (GPC) model, a widely used parametric alternative. We evaluate these models using both simulated and real test data. In the real data examples, the OS model demonstrates superior model fit compared to the GPC model across all analyzed datasets. In our simulation study, the OS model outperforms the GPC model in terms of bias, but at the cost of larger standard errors for the probabilities along the estimated item response functions. Furthermore, we illustrate how surprisal arc length, an IRT scale invariant measure of ability with metric properties, can be used to put scores from vastly different types of IRT models on a common scale. We also demonstrate how arc length can be a viable alternative to sum scores for scoring test takers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2023 06:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986231207879?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/aera/60/6&quot;&gt;Volume 60, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1301-1306, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2023 06:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312231213815?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical competencies in the digital era: Mathematics education in the digital era</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-06-2023 05:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2261401?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Do Informational Interventions Work? Experimental Evidence From New York City High School Choice</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Despite evidence that informational interventions can influence K–12 school choices, we know little about the mechanisms through which they work and the factors that produce heterogeneity in student responses. Through a school-level randomized controlled trial conducted in 473 New York City middle schools serving 115,000 eighth graders, we evaluated three counselor-delivered informational interventions that were designed to help students avoid low-graduation high schools, but differed in their level of individual customization and mode of delivery (paper or online). Every intervention reduced likelihood of application to and enrollment in low-graduation-rate schools (those below the city median of 75%). Simplified paper interventions had the largest impacts and produced lower heterogeneity in effects across subgroups than customizable digital formats. A key mechanism by which interventions worked was through new information replacing students’ default first-choice schools that had low graduation rates and guaranteed admission. We conclude that informational interventions to support school choice can be effectively implemented at scale via school counselors, but that intervention design can lead to differences in who engages, with consequences for inequality.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-06-2023 05:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231203293?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of Teacher Unions on School District Finance and Student Achievement: Evidence From the Great Recession</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;I examine whether the impact of the Great Recession on school district spending, the allocation of resources, and student achievement varied depending on the strength of state’s teachers’ unions. Employing a diff-in-diff-in-diff identification strategy, I find that school districts in states with strong teachers’ unions experienced significantly larger declines in per-pupil expenditures during the economic downtown compared with otherwise similar districts in states with weak teachers’ unions. The larger decline in expenditures in strong union states, however, did not lead to a differential decline in student achievement relative to weak union states.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-06-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737231204349?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: The new mathematics education of new Europe. Alexander Karp (Ed.) (2020) Eastern European mathematics education in the decades of change</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10269-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rera/93/6&quot;&gt;Volume 93, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 942-955, December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2023 08:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543231213380?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Heartbeat recordings in music therapy bereavement care following suicide: Action research single case study of amplified cardiopulmonary recordings for continuity of care</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Bereavement services incorporating family-centered practices are emerging within hospital-based care but are often time-limited and lack personalization. This action research single case study explored one father’s experience of music therapy using amplified cardiopulmonary recordings (ACPR) during bereavement following his son’s death by suicide, to critique current norms and inspire transformative change in systems of care. As co-researchers, a bereaved father, his music therapist, and a music therapy researcher used iterative cycles to qualitatively analyze a series of dialogic reflections upon an 8-year experience of ACPR to construct two overarching themes: 1) continuity experienced as compassion, and 2) process of music therapy with ACPR as tool for resilience and positive growth. Aspects of continuity in the ACPR process, in relation with the music therapist, in journeying through grief, and in the heart and heartbeat were perceived as overwhelming compassion that fostered positive growth in the face of profound loss. We see our study as a first step in promoting culture change by exposing underlying practices, assumptions and policies within the context of hospital-based bereavement care and identifying an exceptional example of possibilities. Our findings add to the literature on action research for transformation by demonstrating that the process of relational knowledge co-creation can be perceived as part of the therapeutic journey.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2023 02:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231207993?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Antiracism in appreciative inquiry: Generative tensions and collective reflexivity</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Appreciative inquiry is an action research methodology focused on revealing an organization’s positive core. As a cross-racial team of antiracist researchers, we were drawn to appreciative inquiry due to its congruences with community-based research perspectives on power-sharing and co-constructing knowledge. Our collaborative reflexivity brought us to question whether Appreciative inquiry’s hyper-focus on positivity would fit our antiracist research paradigm. We articulate reflections of how antiracism theory informed our approach to Appreciative inquiry in a study on the experiences of predominantly racialized settlement workers in schools during the COVID-19 pandemic. We explain how we negotiated tensions between Appreciative inquiry’s focus on positivity and our antiracist framing, in a Canadian settler colonial context where institutional expectations to ignore racism and collapse diversity, loom large. Without a theoretical framework that attends to racism and power, Appreciative inquiry may not fulsomely address participants’ transnational knowledges, nor experiences outside of a positive/negative binary. In our elucidation of how critical reflexivity on racism allowed us to integrate antiracism into Appreciative inquiry, we demonstrate the value of first-person action research for expanding the social justice aims of research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2023 02:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503231210418?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice teachers’ understandings of division and ratios in forming proportional relationships</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study aimed at investigating how preservice teachers’ understandings of division and reasoning about ratios support and constrain their formation of proportional relationships in terms of quantities. Six preservice teachers from a middle-grade preparation program in the USA were selected purposefully based on their mathematics performance in a previous course. An explanatory case study with multiple cases was used to make comparisons within and across cases. Two semi-structured interviews were conducted with each pair. The results revealed that preservice teachers who did not explicitly identify different meanings for division struggled to differentiate between the two perspectives on ratios. The results also showed that those teachers had difficulty forming proportional relationships while solving the proportion tasks. These results suggest that explicit identification of the meanings for both types of division is critical to keeping the two perspectives on ratios separate, which is a key aspect for a robust understanding of proportional relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00410-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pre-service middle school mathematics teachers’ personal concept definitions of special quadrilaterals</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The purpose of the current study was to explore pre-service middle school mathematics teachers’ personal concept definitions of a trapezoid, parallelogram, rectangle, rhombus, square, and kite. The data were collected by a self-report instrument through which the pre-service teachers provided their answers in written form. The participants’ definitions were coded by using Zazkis and Leikin’s (Educational Studies in Mathematics, 69(2), 131–148, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r111&quot;&gt;2008&lt;/span&gt;) framework, which includes the following four main categories for determining mathematical correctness: necessary and sufficient, necessary but not sufficient, sufficient but not necessary, and neither necessary nor sufficient. The findings revealed that about half of the all definitions were correct. More specifically, the participants generated considerably higher proportion of correct definitions for a parallelogram and rhombus, while they displayed a very low performance in defining a kite. The possible reasons of the participants’ varied performance levels in defining the six basic quadrilaterals are discussed based on the linguistic (syntactic, semantic, and lexical) structure of the Turkish names given to the these quadrilaterals. The current study may provide some feedback to teacher education programs regarding the extent of knowledge that should be possessed by the pre-service teachers about definitions of special quadrilaterals before they leave their programs. Such feedback may also help mathematics teacher educators ponder on more fruitful approaches that may promote the development of pre-service teachers’ knowledge and understanding of definitions of special quadrilaterals.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00412-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Successful teaching practices for english language learners in multilingual mathematics classrooms: a meta-analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Due to rapid immigration, many children worldwide are learning mathematics in a second or additional language. This language diversity can be challenging for both teachers and students and carries profound implications for mathematics educators. Research shows that teachers use various ways to support English Language Learners. Research on multilingualism in mathematics classrooms has often focused on qualitative research. This meta-analysis aims to explore the statistically effective successful teaching practices from the studies using quantitative or mixed-method research approaches and aims to inform the research field in a cumulative manner. The specific research question that guided this meta-analysis is: What is the evidence regarding successful teaching of mathematics for Year 1–10 English Language Learners from 2009–2019 in countries where curricula are delivered predominantly in English? Four successful intervention categories were identified: Dual Language Programmes, Curriculum integration, Teacher Professional Development, and Cognitively Focused Interventions. The paper concludes with recommendations for practice and further research in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00414-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting senior high-school students’ measurement and geometry performance: Does spatial training transfer to mathematics achievement?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;It is well established that spatial reasoning skills (i) support mathematics achievement, (ii) are malleable, and (iii) can be improved through training. More recently, there has been interest in using spatial training to causally support corresponding improvements in mathematics achievement; however, findings so far appear to be mixed. The current study explores the effect of a spatial reasoning intervention on Year 11 students’ spatial reasoning skills and mathematics achievement and considers the role of a pedagogical framework and the multidimensional nature of mathematics and spatial reasoning in the design of the intervention. The Experience-Language-Pictorial-Symbolic-Application (ELPSA) pedagogical framework was used to modify an existing spatial intervention program for delivery by high-school educators to Year 11 students (an important but understudied population). The spatial intervention involved training a range of spatial skills over an extended timeframe. Students were randomly assigned to the intervention condition or to a business-as-usual control (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 73). Using a pre-/post-test design, we found the intervention was successful in improving participants’ spatial reasoning skills and performance on measurement and geometry items compared to the control condition but not on number and algebra items. These findings demonstrate that spatial training can support mathematics achievement in certain contexts, highlighting the importance of identifying how individual spatial skills support specific mathematics tasks. Consideration was given for how to use strong pedagogical techniques to scaffold transfer, finding utility in the ELPSA framework. Implications for how to embed spatial training within real mathematics classrooms, as done in the current study, are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00416-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analysing the mathematical activity in a modelling process from the cognitive and onto-semiotic perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of this article is to carry out a work of networking theories which combines two perspectives on the mathematical activity involved in a modelling process, in order to answer the following question: To what extent does the application of the onto-semiotic tools complement the analysis from a cognitive perspective of a mathematical modelling process? To this end, we considered two theoretical frameworks: on the one hand, the onto-semiotic approach, which provides tools for the analysis of any mathematical activity and which here we applied to the activity of modelling; on the other hand, the modelling cycle from a cognitive perspective, which is a reflection on the specific mathematical activity of modelling. Then, we took a modelling problem that we applied to prospective mathematics teachers (at undergraduate and postgraduate level), and we analysed it from the perspective of both frameworks, in order to identify concordances and complementarities between these two ways of analysing the mathematical activity involved in the modelling process. The main conclusion is that both frameworks complement each other for a more detailed analysis of the mathematical activity that underlies the modelling process. Specifically, the analysis with the tools provided by the onto-semiotic approach reveals the phases or transitions of the modelling cycle as a conglomerate of mathematical practices, processes, and the primary objects activated in these practices.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00411-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analysis of mathematical proving in geometry based on Habermas’ construct of rationality</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Habermas’ construct of rationality is a tool adaptated from social sciences into mathematics education to identify the difficulties in the proving process and to plan the teaching of proof for reducing these difficulties. According to Habermas, people engaged in an activity/action are considered to “act rationally” if they choose and use the available criteria and communication tools in the field to reach their aim. Habermas’ construct is composed of three integrated components which are epistemic, teleological, and communicative rationality, and in this study, the proving process of university students was analyzed based on this construct. The aim was to identify the performance of students in the context of rationality components and explore the reasons for the difficulties students experience during the proving process. Freshmen mathematics teacher candidates participated in the study and the researchers focused on the field of geometry. The findings revealed that different interactions between the rationality components considerably affected the proving process of students. On the other hand, during the analysis, the modeling requirements of the epistemic rationality and communicative rationality components needed to be structured with new sub-components. It is thought that this expanded version of Habermas’ construct of rationality can be used more effectively to identify the difficulties students have in mathematical activities such as problem solving, proving, and modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00420-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Elementary teachers’ experience of engaging with Teaching Through Problem Solving using Lesson Study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;For many decades, problem solving has been a focus of elementary mathematics education reforms. Despite this, in many education systems, the prevalent approach to mathematics problem solving treats it as an isolated activity instead of an integral part of teaching and learning. In this study, two mathematics teacher educators introduced 19 Irish elementary teachers to an alternative problem solving approach, namely Teaching Through Problem Solving (TTP), using Lesson Study (LS) as the professional development model. The findings suggest that the opportunity to experience TTP first-hand within their schools supported teachers in appreciating the affordances of various TTP practices. In particular, teachers reported changes in their beliefs regarding problem solving practice alongside developing problem posing knowledge. Of particular note was teachers’ contention that engaging with TTP practices through LS facilitated them to appreciate their students’ problem solving potential to the fullest extent. However, the planning implications of the TTP approach presented as a persistent barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00418-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meeting multiplicative thinking through thought-provoking tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Children’s multiplicative thinking as the recognition of equal group structures and the enumeration of the composite units was the subject of this research. In this paper, we provide an overview of the Multiplication and Division Investigations project. The results were obtained from a small sample of Australian children (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 21) in their first year of school (mean age 5 years 6 months) who participated in a teaching experiment of five lessons taught by their classroom teacher. The tasks introduced children to the “equal groups” aspect of multiplication. A theoretical framework of constructivist learning, together with research literature underpinning early multiplicative thinking, tasks, and children’s thinking, was used to design the research. Our findings indicate that young children could imagine equal group structures and, in doing so, recognise and enumerate composite units. As the children came to these tasks without any prior formal instruction, it seemed that they had intuitive understandings of equal group structures based on their life experiences. We argue that the implications for teaching include creating learning provocations that elicit children’s early ideas of multiplication, visualisation, and abstraction. The research has also shown the importance of observing children, listening to their explanations of their thinking, and using insights provided by their drawings.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 16:05</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00413-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Interplay of Enjoyment, Engagement, and Anxieties: The Characteristics of Upper Secondary School Mathematics Students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 12:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2267936?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning from Lecture and Homework: The Case for Studying Intersections of Milieu</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uiml20/15/4&quot;&gt;Volume 15, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, October 2023, Page 311-330&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 11:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2253023?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics Teachers’ Beliefs About Which Practices They Implement: A Q-Sort Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uiml20/15/4&quot;&gt;Volume 15, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, October 2023, Page 331-347&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 11:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2253077?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Critical Examination of the Relationship Between Social and Personal Constructions of Gender and Race and their Impact on Mathematical Identity</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uiml20/15/4&quot;&gt;Volume 15, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, October 2023, Page 348-366&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 11:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2254152?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Cluster Randomized Controlled Trial on the Effectiveness of the Building Educators’ Skills in Adolescent Mental Health (BEAM) Program for Improving Secondary School Educators’ Confidence, Behavior, Knowledge, and Attitudes Toward Student Mental Health</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Secondary school educators are well placed to recognize and respond to mental illness in adolescents; however, many report low confidence and skills in doing so. A confirmatory cluster randomized controlled trial involving 295 educators (Mean age: 40.10 years, SD: 10.47; 76.6% female, 2.7% Aboriginal or Torres Strait Islander) from 73 Australian secondary schools (22 in rural-regional locations) evaluated the effectiveness of a new professional development training program that aimed to improve secondary school educators’ confidence, behavior, knowledge, and attitudes toward student mental health. Relative to the control, training participants reported significantly greater levels of confidence in recognizing and responding to student mental health issues, perceived mental health knowledge and mental health awareness, and mental health literacy, at post-intervention (10-weeks post-baseline; d = 0.26–0.35) and at 3-month follow-up (d = −0.21 to 0.41). Findings indicate that the Building Educators’ skills in Adolescent Mental health (BEAM) program improves important training outcomes for educators in the domain of student mental health.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2023 07:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231208684?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nascent deductive proof schemes and proof readiness in adolescence</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2023 12:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2261435?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
