<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building mathematical micro-identities through supporting productive struggle</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 11:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2372711?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Catherine P. Vistro-Yu &amp;amp; Tin Lam Toh (eds.) (2019) School mathematics curricula – Asian perspectives and glimpses of reform</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10338-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First- and second-grade prospective teachers reconstructing definitions of polygon diagonals</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The current study examined how prospective first- and second-grade mathematics teachers define the polygon diagonals concept, how they reconstruct their definition during and following an intervention, and how their concept images develop over time. Twenty-three prospective teachers participated in the study, during which they were asked to analyze mathematical events involving a conflict that could be resolved using a precise mathematical definition of a polygon diagonal. Data were collected from prequestionnaires, postquestionnaires, and observations of class discussions. The study findings indicate that before the intervention, all participants provided incorrect definitions and struggled to identify nonprototypical examples of polygon diagonals in the prequestionnaire. However, the process of analyzing mathematical events helped the participants reconstruct their definitions of polygon diagonals and identify the critical attributes of this concept, which improved their ability to extend the concept’s image to include nonprototypical examples. The participants’ improved understanding was evident in the significant improvements in the postquestionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>07-01-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00495-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Children’s mathematical engagement based on their awareness of coding toy design features</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2024 11:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2024.2371513?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘I just want to get my degree and leave’: psychosocial experiences of black male students navigating a historically white South African university</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-29-2024 01:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2371969?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating the difficulty level of aspects of teaching during field placement: from coursework to practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 01:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2370887?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The MTSK model as a tool for designing tasks for teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper studies the knowledge developed by a group of sixty-two pre-service primary teachers during a training session on the definition of a polygon and the mathematical practice of defining. We explore the knowledge developed by pre-service teachers when they carry out a series of training tasks oriented around the practice of defining with primary pupils, within the theoretical framework of the Mathematics Teachers’ Specialised Knowledge model, and using videos of an authentic lesson as prompt. Data were collected by means of video recordings of the implementation of the training tasks, in conjunction with the pre-service teachers’ own written observations as they watched the recorded lesson. A content analysis was carried out on the collected data using the Mathematics Teachers’ Specialised Knowledge model. The results highlight the way in which knowledge of the mathematical practice of defining is constructed, along with the mathematical objects involved in this practice, and pedagogical aspects of defining with young pupils. They also illustrate how a sequence of tasks oriented around a model of teachers’ knowledge can contribute to the development of this knowledge in initial training programmes, and more especially provide orientation about the training of pre-service teachers in the mathematical practice of defining.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01605-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking anti-Asian racism in mathematics education: the hidden racism made visible through AsianCrit</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Racism against Asians is often ignored worldwide, and the field of mathematics education is no exception. The anti-Asian racism unveiled during the COVID-19 pandemic necessitates that we rethink the current discussions of equity and social justice in mathematics education regarding how the needs of many Asian students have been forgotten and often excluded from these discussions. When Asian students are mentioned, it is often for the purpose of reifying a racial hierarchy of mathematical ability (Martin, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teachers College Record&lt;/em&gt; 111(2):295–338, 2009; Martin et al., 2017). Based on an analysis of the particularities of the U.S. context, this essay argues that the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;model minority myth&lt;/em&gt; and other covert forms of anti-Asian racism, such as yellow peril and forever foreigner myths, racialize Asian Americans and create a monolithic view of diverse groups of people with different histories and needs, including within mathematics education. While incorporating current race and racism concepts from Asian Critical Theory (Iftikar &amp;amp; Museus, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;International Journal of Qualitative Studies in Education&lt;/em&gt; 31(10):935–949, 2018), we aim to conceptualize the racialization that Asian-American students experience in mathematics classrooms and how it affects their well-being, and propose implications to (re)construct Asian-American students’ counterstories and identities in mathematics education. We also scrutinize mathematics education researchers’ and educators’ roles in advancing equity for all students by countering the hidden racism toward Asian Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10335-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating a space for them through autoethnography</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Researchers in education have begun to address inclusivity for gender-diverse populations, but the authentic experiences of gender-variant students presented directly by the students themselves are largely unheard in the literature of mathematics education. In this co-authored report, we include the experiences of a genderqueer preservice mathematics teacher over the course of a semester at university through their autoethnography and the reflections of a mathematics teacher educator supervising the research. Through this study, we provide educators a window into some ways that gender-variant students may experience the classroom and academia. One goal of this research is to create a space for the authentic voice of gender-variant individuals in the discussion of gender-inclusive education. We highlight implications for mathematics teacher educators involving gender-variant students’ gender journeys as processes instead of moments of coming out, the interdependent process of building relationships of trust, and the importance of trying and failing and trying again as we seek to be more inclusive educators.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09643-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student Interpretations of Eigenequations in Linear Algebra and Quantum Mechanics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This work investigates how students interpret various eigenequations in different contexts for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(2 \times 2\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; matrices: &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(A\vec {x}=\lambda \vec {x}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; in mathematics and either &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq3&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\hat{S}_x| + \rangle _x=\frac{\hbar }{2}| + \rangle _x\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq4&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\hat{S}_z| + \rangle =\frac{\hbar }{2}| + \rangle\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; in quantum mechanics. Data were collected from two sources in a senior-level quantum mechanics course; one is video, transcript and written work of individual, semi-structured interviews; the second is written work from the same course three years later. We found two principal ways in which students reasoned about the equal sign within the mathematics eigenequation and at times within the quantum mechanical eigenequations: with a functional interpretation and/or a relational interpretation. Second, we found three distinct ways in which students explained how they made sense of the physical meaning conveyed by the quantum mechanical eigenequations: via a measurement interpretation, potential measurement interpretation, or correspondence interpretation of the equation. Finally, we present two themes that emerged in the ways that students compared the different eigenequations: attention to form and attention to conceptual (in)compatibility. These findings are discussed in relation to relevant literature, and their instructional implications are also explored.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-28-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-024-00241-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Opening up creative resources: towards age-friendly communities through rhizomatic thinking and doing</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-27-2024 08:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2024.2370277?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: Mathematics teaching and teacher education against marginalisation, or towards equity, diversity and inclusion</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-024-01608-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Transitioning to proof via writing scripts on the rules of a new discourse﻿</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Coming from the commognitive standpoint, we consider proof-based mathematics as a distinct discourse, the transition to which requires special rules for endorsement and rejection of mathematical statements. In this study, we investigate newcomers’ learning of these rules when being taught them explicitly. Our data come from academically motivated high-school students who took a special course in undergraduate mathematics. The course teacher dedicated three academic hours to introducing and explaining selected rules of proof to support students’ shift to the new discourse. The homework assignment consisted of typical proof-requiring problems and a scriptwriting task, asking students to compose a dialogue between fictional characters about a proof-related mistake of their choice. We analyzed the differences and similarities between the rules discussed in the classroom and those that students addressed and implemented in their proofs. The analysis showed that while students’ solutions to proof-requiring problems required rule implementation, fictitious dialogues opened the space for rule formulation and substantiation. In many cases, the students discussed the rules presented in the classroom, extending, elaborating, and specifying the teacher’s formulations. Furthermore, while the students’ proofs were mainly consistent with the teacher’s expectations, some of their rule formulations were more radical and overgeneralized than expected. These findings suggest that newcomers’ communication about the rules of proof may lag behind their capability to implement those rules to prove mathematical statements.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-27-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10324-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Growth on 2019 State Achievement Tests: Empirical Benchmarks and the Role of Scale Choice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-26-2024 08:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2360534?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Candidate Learning of Interdisciplinary Controversial Issues: Linking Social Studies and Science in the Elementary School Curriculum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-26-2024 08:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2368503?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of knowledge, attitude, and emotions in Spanish pre-service teachers’ willingness to engage in climate change education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-26-2024 07:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2370885?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Development of teacher professional identity: perspectives from self-determination theory</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-26-2024 04:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2371981?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Will we be capable? Creating and validating the AVACIE scale to evaluate pre-service teachers’ self-competence in assessing cyberbullying</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-26-2024 01:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2024.2372448?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Embracing local insights for global advancement</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-26-2024 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-024-09645-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creativity-Fostering Teacher Behaviors in Higher Education: A Transdisciplinary Systematic Literature Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;While society’s demand for creativity is echoed across the world, teachers in higher education often struggle to support students’ development of creative competencies. This transdisciplinary systematic literature review of 58 peer-reviewed empirical studies provides a comprehensive overview of creativity-fostering teacher behaviors identified across all academic disciplines in higher education. In our thematic analysis, we identified 22 themes grouped into six overarching dimensions (the six dimensions of fostering creativity, namely, [a] affective, [b] cognitive, [c] behavioral, [d] metacognitive, [e] creativity-in-action, and [f] uncertainty). Based on these dimensions, we developed a new conceptual model of teacher behaviors for creativity: the “meta-creativity” model. This model highlights the transdisciplinary, interactive, and interdependent nature of creativity-fostering teacher behaviors, which are subject to the conflicting needs and tensions of creative processes. This review provides key practical insights for teachers, administrators, and policymakers and new research directions for a more holistic approach to teaching for creativity.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-25-2024 10:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241258226?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Quantitative Research and Inequality Narratives: A Systematic Review</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-25-2024 07:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2358848?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Costs and Impacts of Descubriendo la Lectura: Evidence From a Multisite Experimental Study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-25-2024 06:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2024.2358824?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>&#39;They don’t really know what they’re getting into&#39;: the impact of neoliberal and colonial policies within Israeli institutions of higher education on Palestinian Jerusalemite students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-25-2024 06:49</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2024.2372444?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developmental Education for College Students with Learning and Attention Disabilities</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;As postsecondary developmental education policy reforms are implemented, increased attention must be given to students with learning and attention disabilities. The purpose of this study was to bring these students into the conversation, by examining their representation in developmental education broadly, as well the effect of this intervention on their college persistence and credit accumulation. Results show students with learning or attention disabilities are overrepresented in developmental education and could experience heterogenous effects on their postsecondary outcomes. Policymakers should be purposeful about consideration of this growing group of students in continued developmental education reforms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>06-25-2024 05:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048241258727?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
