<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Hybrid EM Algorithm for Linear Two-Way Interactions With Missing Data</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We study an Expectation-Maximization (EM) algorithm for estimating product-term regression models with missing data. The study of such problems in the frequentist tradition has thus far been restricted to an EM algorithm method using full numerical integration. However, under most missing data patterns, we show that this problem can be solved analytically, and numerical approximations are only needed under specific conditions. Thus we propose a hybrid EM algorithm, which uses analytic solutions when available and approximate solutions only when needed. The theoretical framework of our algorithm is described herein, along with three empirical experiments using both simulated and real data. We demonstrate that our algorithm provides greater estimation accuracy, exhibits robustness to distributional violations, and confers higher power to detect interaction effects. We conclude with a discussion of extensions and topics of further research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-09-2025 11:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241304015?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Feasibility of the Knowledge, Language, and Inquiry (K.L.I.) intervention for multilingual English learners</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-09-2025 10:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2449035?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Performance Evaluation of University-Based Scientific Research Institutions With a Non-Independent Parallel System</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Performance management in university-based scientific research institutions is essential for driving reform, advancing education quality, and fostering innovation. However, current performance evaluation models often focus solely on research indicators, neglecting the critical interdependence between the education and research systems. This oversight leads to inefficiencies in resource allocation and an underestimation of overall institutional performance, particularly in universities with varying development levels. To address these deficiencies, this study introduces two innovative two-stage data envelopment analysis models: the group-frontier and meta-frontier evaluation models. The findings are validated using data from 144 universities across China. They demonstrate that the proposed models effectively mitigate the underestimation of efficiency in traditional models and accurately reflect the intertwined nature of university subsystems and the disparities in university development. These results offer valuable insights for improving the performance of scientific research institutions and informing the strategic decisions of university administrators and government education departments.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-08-2025 09:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241312823?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8th grade students’ experiences in the laboratory environment and metaverse environment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-08-2025 04:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2024.2446892?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining Teacher Candidates’ Responses to Parental Disclosures During Simulated Conferences and Home Visits</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-08-2025 01:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2024.2442328?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Holistic Examination of How Professional Learning and Curriculum Relate to Ambitious and Culturally Relevant Instruction and Student Engagement</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;To shape professional learning (PL) and curriculum interventions for successfully transforming instruction, we need to better understand how multiple aspects of the system work. Applying structural equation modeling with a sample of 437 teachers in 153 middle and high schools in 11 districts serving 50% or more Black or Latinx students, we found that teachers are significantly more likely to use ambitious and culturally responsive (CR) instruction in the classroom and that student engagement increases when PL and curriculum adoption are (1) targeted toward ambitious and CR instruction, (2) provide clear, specific directions to teachers, (3) are aligned with each other, (4) are supported by teachers, and (5) are accompanied by incentives. PL worked through fostering stronger beliefs in and confidence using CR instruction. The curriculum and PL had both independent and interactive effects on bolstering the use of ambitious and CR instruction.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-07-2025 06:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241310429?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Seven quality choicepoints for ARJ: Ambition is welcome!</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-07-2025 01:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503241306927?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Figure reproduction as a step towards theoretical geometry: analysis of the didactical and a-didactical processes in a classroom setting</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Transitioning from material to theoretical geometry is often considered a significant challenge in compulsory education. Over the last twenty years, research rooted in the Theory of Didactical Situations (TDS) has explored how material geometry can support the teaching and learning of theoretical geometry, promoting continuity in teaching. These studies have defined didactically focused material geometry practices, referred to as “the geometry of tracing,” where figure reproduction is considered a fundamental situation within this geometric practice. In this text, we explore the potential of transposing this fundamental situation into a didactic one within a classroom setting. Based on the analysis of a case study, we examine the relationship between the effective situation and the learning process. We pay attention to the roles and interactions of adaptation and acculturation processes in the observed didactic phenomena. The TDS framework helps us analyze how the combination of the a-didactical potential of the situation and the teacher’s didactic interventions promotes a shift towards theoretical geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-07-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10370-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sleep, Mood, and Economic Preferences</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study used daily experimental data from smart bands worn by 142 respondents to investigate the relationship between the number of minutes slept and self-reported mood. The results showed that more minutes of sleep were associated with improved mood. Time preferences, altruism, and trust were also associated with mood. Finally, our analysis revealed that the only mechanism through which sleep affects mood is positive reciprocity. This study contributes to the existing literature by examining the connections among healthy habits, sleep quality, economic preferences, and their effects on mood.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2025 08:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X241311974?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leaving to Fit In? The Ethnoracial Composition of Principals, Peer Teachers, and Teacher Turnover in New York City</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Retention of teachers of color remains a persistent educational concern, yet little research explores whether teachers of color are less likely to turnover when teaching in schools with principals and peer teaching staff of the same race/ethnicity. This study explores whether principal and peer teacher demographics predict teacher turnover in New York City, and whether they do so differently for teachers of color. We find that Black teachers are less likely to turnover when working in schools with a principal and a higher share of peer teachers of the same race/ethnicity. Results show similar and more consistent patterns for White teachers but no significant difference for Hispanic teachers. We conclude by discussing implications for educational policy, practice, and research.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2025 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737241304388?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bayesian Diagnostic Classification Models for a Partially Known Q-Matrix</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study proposes a Bayesian method for diagnostic classification models (DCMs) for a partially known Q-matrix setting between exploratory and confirmatory DCMs. This Q-matrix setting is practical and useful because test experts have pre-knowledge of the Q-matrix but cannot readily specify it completely. The proposed method employs priors for the Bayesian variable selection to simultaneously estimate the effects of active and nonactive attributes, and the simulations lead to appropriate attribute recovery rates. Furthermore, the proposed method recovers the attribute mastery of individuals at the same as for a fully known Q-matrix. In addition, the proposed methods can be used to estimate the unknown Q-matrix part. A real data example indicates that the proposed Bayesian estimation method for the partially known Q-matrix fits better than a fully specified Q-matrix. Finally, extensions and future research directions are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2025 04:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241301055?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Tension between Money and Culture: Inequality, Economic Capital, Cultural Capital, and High School Students’ Educational Achievements from a Comparative Perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study investigated how income inequality shapes the role of economic and cultural capital in students’ academic performance. By analyzing a multilevel dataset of 72 countries (economies), we found that (1) the associations between economic capital and academic achievements are stronger in unequal societies than in equal ones, whereas the associations between cultural capital and students’ achievements are stronger in equal societies than in unequal ones, and (2) in more equal societies, the associations between cultural capital and students’ achievements are stronger for students with lower economic capital, whereas the associations between cultural capital and students’ achievements are stronger for students with higher stocks of economic capital in unequal societies. The findings contribute to understanding how social context shapes the processes of intergenerational reproduction from a comparative perspective.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2025 01:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241308548?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Disempowering Marketplaces: How School Choice Enrollment Routines Legitimize Educational Inequality</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;As school choice increases, parents are expected to act like consumers choosing from a school marketplace. However, to what extent do parents understand and enact this new role? Drawing on organizational theory, we examine the mismatch between the ostensive (ideal) and performative aspects of the school choice enrollment routine. Analyzing interviews with 136 parents in Chicago, we found that only a small minority perform the enrollment routine as officially envisioned (i.e., researching and applying to multiple schools). Instead, most parents know little to nothing about the enrollment routine. Further, even “educated consumer” parents feel disempowered by the routine. We argue that in a context of deep structural educational inequality, the current enrollment routine works to deflect responsibility onto individual parents.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2025 01:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241308545?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advantaged Families’ Opportunity Hoarding in U.S. K–12 Education: A Systematic Review of the Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A growing body of educational research uses opportunity hoarding as a construct to understand advantaged families’ engagement in K–12 U.S. schooling. Our systematic review of the literature reveals that advantaged parents hoard educational resources and opportunities in three key areas: (1) the creation and maintenance of white space; (2) school choice/selection; and (3) organizational routines. While much can be learned from the extant research, we detail conceptual, empirical, and methodological gaps in the literature as well as outline a future research agenda that can inform equity-oriented educational policy, practice, and scholarship. We argue that the concept of opportunity hoarding serves as a useful analytic tool for understanding how actors advantaged by race and/or class create and maintain educational inequities and can guide efforts to ameliorate it; therefore, it is important to understand how educational researchers might extend its use.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2025 01:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241304766?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical induction in education research: a systematic review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical induction is a powerful method of proof, taught in most undergraduate programs involving mathematics and in secondary schools in some countries. It is also commonly known to be complex and difficult to comprehend. During the last five decades, mathematics education research has produced numerous studies on the learning and teaching of mathematical induction. In this systematic literature review, we consider important features of this body of research. First, we investigate how the nature of mathematical induction is presented in the research literature. Then, we synthesize the findings of the research. In particular, we pay attention to the approaches and findings of teaching interventions and establish the current state of the art.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10373-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meaning(s) of a student perspective in mathematics education research</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This systematic literature review explores meaning(s) of a student perspective in mathematics education research by investigating the intentionalities of research texts that use a student perspective. The study views research texts as being produced in and influenced by the context and the discourses in which they are submerged. In exploring the meaning(s) of a student perspective in mathematics education research, we draw on Skovsmose’s intentionality interpretation of meaning. A total of 98 unique research texts were explored, resulting in three meanings of student perspectives in mathematics education research: ‘feelings, experiences, and views’, ‘evaluating interventions’ and ‘validating effects’. The results show that student perspectives in mathematics education research predominantly consisted of studies with the intentionalities of evaluation and validation having a “regular” student in mind. Perspectives from students with certain characteristics, like underserved students and students in different performance levels, are scarce. While the findings might not be surprising, this literature review nonetheless calls for rethinking student perspectives in mathematics education research to include research &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; students that recognize students’ diverse backgrounds. We end the article by suggesting a desire-based research approach to seriously address students’ hopes, wishes, aspirations, and desires in mathematics education research. &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-024-10374-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Characterizing mathematical modelling tasks in empirical literature</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The choice of mathematical modelling tasks for research purposes is critical, and so is the presentation of tasks in research reports. The openness of modelling tasks positions modellers as decision makers. To assess opportunities for decision making in published modelling tasks, we develop a literature-based framework with 11 features of a modelling task that can hinder or entice decision making within different phases of the modelling process. We use the framework to code the statements of 109 modelling tasks from 67 journal articles published from 2011 through 2020. Subsequent coding addressed the settings in which the tasks were used for data collection. Results indicate that the tasks call for extensive decision making in mathematising and less decision making in structuring and simplifying and in interpreting and validating, suggesting that a notable number of the tasks might target applications of mathematics rather than holistic modelling activity. Our findings expand researchers’ understanding of assumption making by drawing attention to the objects of the assumptions (e.g., typical value, non-quantitative term). The study also offers different ways in which modellers’ identification of variables might be bounded by a task. We further reveal that variable identification might be linked to particular types of assumption making. Our results document minimal attention to implementation information in the published reports, and we thus call authors to provide task implementation details that pedagogically contextualize findings.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00515-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Feedback Practices on Young Students’ Oral Reading: A Systematic Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;When beginning readers read aloud, the teacher’s feedback affects their reader identities. Teacher’s feedback may also imprint a strong model of what reading is and what proficient readers do. This systematic review investigates the characteristics of teachers’ feedback on elementary students’ reading and furthers its potential to support students’ agency in learning to read. A total of 52 empirical studies in K–5 settings were identified and analyzed. Findings suggest clear associations between how feedback was presented and what aspects of reading were targeted: typically, either explicit feedback on decoding or implicit feedback on meaning. Further, support for student agency was more strongly associated with implicit feedback practices. Finally, two groups of students—struggling readers and L2 learners—tended to receive feedback that does not promote agency. The review concludes by discussing the potential of feedback practices to support students in becoming proficient and independent readers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2025 12:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543241306070?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Performance-Based Compensation Systems and Principal Job Performance</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The inequitable distribution of principal effectiveness raises concern among policymakers. Principal sorting likely contributes to wider achievement and opportunity gaps between low- and high-need schools. As a possible policy tool, policymakers proposed performance-based compensation systems (PBCS). Tennessee was one of the states that supported the implementation of PBCS. This study examined the relationship between PBCS and principal job performance in the state, using longitudinal administrative data, principal evaluation data, and unique PBCS data from 2012 to 2019. The study did not find consistently significant, positive relationships between PBCS and principal job performance. However, the relationships were generally more pronounced among high-need schools. The study concludes with detailed discussions about the results, the assumptions behind PBCS, limitations, and implications.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2025 10:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312241303760?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: Teacher–child interactions during shared book reading in the domain of early mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2025 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-024-00510-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Smoothing of Bivariate Test Score Distributions: Model Selection Targeting Test Score Equating</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Observed-score test equating is a vital part of every testing program, aiming to make test scores across test administrations comparable. Central to this process is the equating function, typically estimated by composing distribution functions of the scores to be equated. An integral part of this estimation is presmoothing, where statistical models are fit to observed score frequencies to mitigate sampling variability. This study evaluates the impact of commonly used model fit indices on bivariate presmoothing model-selection accuracy in both item response theory (IRT) and non-IRT settings. It also introduces a new model-selection criterion that directly targets the equating function in contrast to existing methods. The study focuses on the framework of non-equivalent groups with anchor test design, estimating bivariate score distributions based on real and simulated data. Results show that the choice of presmoothing model and model fit criterion influences the equated scores. In non-IRT contexts, a combination of the proposed model-selection criterion and the Bayesian information criterion exhibited superior performance, balancing bias, and variance of the equated scores. For IRT models, high selection accuracy and minimal equating error were achieved across all scenarios.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2025 11:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986241300523?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Swimming in the Deep End: School Board Members Making Sense of Their Roles and Responsibilities</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/11&quot;&gt;Volume 11, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2025. &lt;br/&gt;Little has been dedicated to the experience and potential support for local educational policy actors, school board members, that were at the heart of unprecedented decision and sensemaking during the Covid-19 pandemic. Employing sensemaking theory and an interpretivist case study design, this study conducts interviews with four school board members in a Missouri school district. The study explores their motivations for candidacy and perceptions of the role’s responsibilities, especially as individuals elected during the pandemic. The findings highlight that candidates’ decisions to run are influenced by personal and professional experiences, shaping their initial understanding of the position. However, post-election, a transformative process unfolds in the actual enactment of the role, signifying an evolution in their sensemaking journey. This study contributes to the limited but growing literature on school board members who play critical roles in education and whose roles and responsibilities have often been overlooked in the scholarship.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2025 10:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584241304700?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond Verbal: A Methodological Approach to Highlighting Students’ Embodied Participation in Mathematics Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Despite the growing availability of classroom measures, such measures rarely attended to the embodied nature of learning. This article describes the collaborative development of a practical measure to capture embodied participation in mathematics classrooms with four elementary school teachers—working with students at the intersections of multiply marginalized identities: students of color, emergent bilinguals, and students with disabilities—who informed the measure design and ensured that the data were actionable in their contexts. This article contributes to existing research on classroom measures by highlighting the value of attending to embodied learning through multiple modalities and representations of student participation. We further highlight how such a measure provides practical insights into participation that extend beyond verbal only measures.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2025 09:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241310169?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ahead of the Game? Course-Taking Patterns Under a Math Pathways Reform</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A controversial, equity-focused mathematics reform in the San Francisco Unified School District (SFUSD) featured delaying Algebra I until ninth grade for all students. This study examines student-level longitudinal data on mathematics course-taking across successive cohorts of SFUSD students who spanned the reform’s implementation. We observe large changes in ninth and 10th grades (e.g., delaying Algebra I and geometry). Participation in Advanced Placement (AP) math initially fell 15% (6 percentage points), driven by declines in AP calculus and among Asian/Pacific Islander students. However, growing participation in acceleration options attenuated these reductions. Large ethnoracial gaps in advanced math course-taking remained.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2025 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X241309642?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
