<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Classroom Promotion of Oral Language: Outcomes From a Randomized Controlled Trial of a Whole-of-Classroom Intervention to Improve Children’s Reading Achievement</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Children need rich language learning experiences in school to build language and reading skills. Research suggests that various effective ways to support teacher provision of these experiences. The Classroom Promotion of Oral Language cluster randomized controlled trial (n = 1,360 students; 687 intervention, 673 control) examined whether a teacher professional learning intervention targeting oral language in the first years of school led to improved student outcomes compared to usual teaching practices. The intervention comprised face-to-face professional learning and ongoing support. The primary outcome was student reading ability at Grade 3; secondary outcomes included oral language, reading, and mental health at Grades 1 and 3. No differences were detected between the intervention and control arms. Implications of results and future directions are explored.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-25-2022 05:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221131530?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unveiling the Causal Mechanisms Within Multidimensional Poverty</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Despite improvements in the design of development interventions from the perspective of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), there is still a lack of evaluation methods able to estimate the impact of these interventions on multiple and interrelated outcomes. This paper proposes a methodological framework for complex causal inference in international development that combines machine learning and econometric designs for causal inference. As a study case, the relationship between multidimensional poverty and violence in Colombia is evaluated following this framework. First, Bayesian networks (BN) are used to create a directed acyclic graph (DAG) able to predict how multidimensional poverty components are interrelated and affected by a violence indicator. Second, the DAG output is used to identify instrumental variables (IV) in order to test the effect of multidimensional poverty on a household’s likelihood to be a victim of violence. Minimum living standards—measured in terms of access to water, connection to the sewage system, and the quality of walls and floors—are strong predictors of the education and health dimensions of poverty. Using 2SLS, the results show that having an illiterate person within a household increases by 0.4% the household’s likelihood to be a victim of violence. BNs have the potential to predict complex causal patterns helping to understand the effect of development interventions on multidimensional outcomes such as poverty. Quasi-experimental econometric designs can then be used to test some of these predicted causal connections.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-24-2022 12:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221140936?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mapping the Contributions of the Review of Educational Research to Education, 1931–2020</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The goals of this bibliometric review of the Review of Educational Research were to gain insights into the evolution of the journal and identify its key contributions to the education literature. Bibliographic data associated with the full set of 3,022 review articles published in RER from 1931 through 2021 were exported from Scopus for bibliometric analysis using VOSviewer software. The review confirmed that RER remains rooted in the American education context, with scholars located outside the United States accounting for only 6% of the RER corpus. The review identified authors and documents published in RER that have had the greatest impact on the broader education literature. Author co-citation analysis visualized the “intellectual structure” of the RER corpus, which is anchored by a “school of thought” associated with Teaching and Learning Strategies and Effects. This research stream has been informed by complementary schools of researchers who have generated theory and research on cognition, teaching, and learning as well as motivation and learning. Although conceptual reviews of research are more prominent, meta-analytic reviews have also come to represent a key pillar in the intellectual structure of RER. Journal co-citation analysis validated the centrality of RER’s place within a community of highly ranked education and psychology journals. The findings confirm the strong disciplinary influence of psychology in shaping the journal’s direction and content. Adapting to a changing global research landscape in education was identified as a key challenge facing RER in the next decade.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-24-2022 04:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221132771?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interrogating Policy Diffusion in the Arts Education Sphere</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Defined as the tendency for structures and groups to “grow more alike, to develop similarities” policy convergence is a recognized factor in policy analysis across fields. In the arts education sphere, this can mean adopting similar curriculum standards, imitating an after-school arts program, or even borrowing a large-scale metropolitan arts education partnership model. I argue that policy diffusion helps to illuminate policy convergence in the arts education milieu. In this policy analysis essay, I first detail the conceptual underpinnings of policy diffusion. Next, I offer specific examples from arts education and attempt to show how they exemplify mechanisms of diffusion. I then argue that there are specific contexts/structures within arts education policymaking that facilitate diffusion, and I conclude with discussion based on the analysis.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-24-2022 01:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221131565?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction to: Teachers as designers of instructional tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-24-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00439-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Becoming HOPEless in the 2-Year Sector</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Becoming HOPEless in the 2-year sector addresses the question: what happens when a state-wide policy removes merit-based financial aid from low-income students making satisfactory academic progress? To assess the magnitude of this HOPEless effect, we compared credits attempted, attained, and persistence and graduation indicators of HOPEless students against the outcomes of their not targeted/affected peers. Relying on multiple quasi-experimental analytic techniques (difference in differences [DD], DD in differences, Fuzzy regression discontinuity, and multi-treatment propensity score weighting), two mutually exclusive analytic samples (one longitudinal and one cross-sectional), and over one million observations across four academic years (2009–2010 to 2012–2013), we consistently found that HOPEless students realized worse outcomes and even persisted fewer terms/semesters than students on academic probation. The State saved about $150 million in lottery money (largely funded by lower-income households) but did so at the expense of 665,192 credit hours that would have been attained by HOPEless (low-income) students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2022 09:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120276?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Role of Local Facilitators in Scaling up a Well-Specified Teacher Professional Learning Program</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2022 06:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2146361?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do the Impacts of Healthcare Training Vary with Credential Length? Evidence from the Health Profession Opportunity Grants Program</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2022 05:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2128486?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Convergence and Divergence in Probability Teaching in Elementary and Secondary School in Québec: a Closer Look at Eight Teachers’ Self-reported Practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The first stage of a study in Québec enabled us to draw up a statistical portrait of probability teaching practices self-reported by 626 teachers at the elementary and secondary levels. For the second stage of the study, discussed here, we wanted to elaborate on some of the questionnaire answers and to discuss professional development avenues inspired by the teachers’ experience. We conducted 1-h individual interviews with eight teachers who had taken part in the first stage and whose self-reported teaching practices were considered to be exemplary. By means of a thematic analysis, we explore issues surrounding certain self-reported probability teaching practices through examples related to the social usefulness of probability, professional development associated with probability teaching, the use of the frequentist approach, the connection between probabilistic approaches, unusual tasks, manipulatives, and technological tools for teaching probability.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00241-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race, Gender, and Teacher Equity Beliefs: Construct Validation of the Attributions of Mathematical Excellence Scale</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers’ beliefs can have powerful consequences on instructional decisions and student learning. However, little research focuses on how teachers’ beliefs about the role of race and gender in mathematics teaching and learning influence educational equity within classrooms. This gap is partly due to the lack of studies focused on variation within classrooms, which in turn is hampered by the lack of instruments designed to measure mathematics-specific equity beliefs. In this study of 313 preservice and practicing elementary teachers, we report evidence of construct validity for the Attributions of Mathematical Excellence Scale. Factor analyses provide support for a four-factor structure, including genetic, social, personal, and educational attributions. The findings suggest that the same system of attribution beliefs underlies both racial and gender prejudice among elementary mathematics teachers. The Attributions of Mathematical Excellence Scale has the potential to provide a useful outcome measure for equity-focused interventions in teacher education and professional development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-22-2022 05:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221130999?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching and Learning Probability at the 14th International Congress on Mathematical Education: Continuing the Continuing Work of Topic Study Group 11</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-22-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00244-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Overlap Violations in Clustered Observational Studies of Educational Interventions</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 07:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2144563?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Literacy’s Schrödinger’s cat: capturing reading comprehension with social annotation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 06:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2022.2146088?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effect of School District Consolidation on Student Achievement: Evidence From Arkansas</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;School district consolidation is one of the most widespread education reforms of the last century, but surprisingly little research has directly investigated its effectiveness. To examine the impact of consolidation on student achievement, this study takes advantage of a policy that requires the consolidation of all Arkansas school districts with enrollment of fewer than 350 students for two consecutive school years. Using a regression discontinuity model, we find that consolidation has either null or small positive impacts on student achievement in math and English Language Arts (ELA). We do not find evidence that consolidation in Arkansas results in positive economies of scale, either by reducing overall cost or by allowing for a greater share of resources to be spent in the classroom.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221133394?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher educators’ general beliefs and personal identifications related to mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Dominant cultural beliefs contend that mathematics is exclusive; only some have access to “the gift.” Within classrooms and amidst everyday vernacular, scripts about mathematics and who can “do” mathematics reify such traditional beliefs. Mathematics teacher educators work with preservice teachers (PSTs) to challenge such beliefs, but they only represent a part of the community teaching PSTs. Non-mathematics teacher educators (TEs) may not overtly teach mathematical concepts, but within their hidden curricula, they likely transmit beliefs about mathematics and convey their positions as math people. Little research has been conducted on TEs’ mathematical beliefs and identities; therefore, little is known about how they transmit or challenge traditional beliefs about mathematics to their PSTs. This article aims to start the conversation about the role of TEs in transforming or maintaining mathematical beliefs by reporting the findings from an analysis of seventeen TEs’ responses to questions related to their general beliefs about mathematics and how they position themselves as math people. Most participants articulated innovative, inclusive beliefs about mathematics but refused to identify fully as math people. Self-exclusion explanations given for not identifying as math people included preferences to other content areas; comparisons to others; not having a profession that requires traditional school math; and perceived deficits in mathematical understanding, despite strengths, enjoyment, and/or confidence in mathematics courses and/or real-world problem solving. Analysis revealed avoidance of emotional suffering and risk at the root of some rejections of the “math person” identification. Implications and suggested future steps also are included.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00436-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/30/5&quot;&gt;Volume 30, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2022, Page 687-688&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-20-2022 07:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2134533?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Black and White Students Benefit From Racial Socialization? School Racial Socialization, School Climate, and Youth Academic Performance During Early Adolescence</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;With racial inequalities plaguing the U.S. school system, educators have recognized the importance of establishing inclusive, equitable, and diverse school environments where students from different ethnic-racial backgrounds can feel respected and supported. This study examined the longitudinal links between adolescents’ experiences of school racial socialization, school climate perceptions, and academic performance and tested whether these links varied by race (n = 941; 54% boys; 63% Black, 37% White). Results revealed that adolescents’ experience of school racial socialization practices (i.e., cultural socialization and promotion of cultural competence) predicted positive changes in their perceptions of school climate and, in turn, promoted better academic performance. School racial socialization was linked to positive school experiences and achievement for both Black and White adolescents.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-19-2022 05:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221134771?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Black School Closings Aren’t New: Historically Contextualizing Contemporary School Closings and Black Community Resistance</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Whereas increased scholarly attention is focusing on contemporary school closings, noticeably absent is the placement of this scholarship within the historical context of Black people’s social experiences. This paradigm shift would reveal a much longer history that has had devastating consequences for Black people. In this article, we identify five waves of Black school closings and provide contemporary case studies that reveal an ongoing pattern resulting in the destabilization of Black communities across time and space. Despite persistent attacks on these institutions, our analyses capture Black people’s resistance and agency in maintaining their communities and schools. In addition to providing policy implications, we further suggest the term Black community-killing as a theoretical way of thinking about the consequences of school closings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221131504?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Turnover in Early Childhood Education: Longitudinal Evidence From the Universe of Publicly Funded Programs in Louisiana</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study uses longitudinal data to follow a cohort (N = 4,465) of all early childhood education teachers working in publicly funded, center-based settings in Louisiana over a 3-year period. We present the proportion of teachers still at their sites across six time points between 2016 and 2019, providing the first statewide, longitudinal estimates of within-year and multiyear retention. We find that less than 40% teachers in the fall of 2016 are still at their site by the fall of 2019. Turnover is particularly high among childcare teachers (compared to teachers at Head Start or school-based pre-kindergarten), teachers of toddlers, and teachers new to their sites. Policy implications are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221131505?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Three-Arm Random Assignment Within Sites can Improve Non-Experimental Cross-Site Estimates of the Relationship Between Program Characteristics and Impact</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article considers a new method, called Cross-Site Attributional Model Improved by Calibration to Within-Site Individual Randomization Findings (abbreviated as “CAMIC”), which seeks to reduce bias in analyses of the contributions of a program’s various design, implementation, and contextual characteristics to its overall impacts. It requires a multi-site experiment where some (or all) sites randomize individuals to one of three arms: a standard treatment group, an enhanced treatment group (that receives the standard treatment plus a program “enhancement”), or a control group (that has no access to the program). A recent evaluation—that of the Health Profession Opportunity Grants (HPOG) program—provides a motivating example of this design and its potential for both methodological and substantive lessons; and the article considers other evaluations that would be fitting for deploying and learning from CAMIC. We conclude that the promise for CAMIC lies in situations where the correlations between the selected program enhancement and alternative program characteristics of interest are relatively high, implying that producing an experimental estimate of the enhancement can reduce bias in the estimation of other non-randomized program characteristics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221140614?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bridging Educational Change and Social Justice: A Call to the Field</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The education research community, both within the American Educational Research Association (AERA) and beyond, could and should play a critical role in fundamentally transforming educational institutions and systems. Given its complexity, transformative change in education is best undertaken as a collective endeavor. Yet for researchers to be a valuable resource in educational transformation, we will need to bridge knowledge across subfields that currently have limited interaction. Through two illustrative examples, we demonstrate the need to link knowledge on educational change with knowledge on how to create more equitable, anti-racist, and decolonized spaces for formal and informal learning. While operating in different spaces and initiated at different entry points, the two change efforts exemplify a common set of commitments and actionable pathways for achieving transformational change. This article is a call to action for researchers to join together in supporting educational transformation that fundamentally challenges the inequitable arrangements persisting in educational organizations characterized by systemic racism and colonialism. Bridging knowledge bases and being accountable to serve and support communities and their intersectional identities are essential to making deep, scalable changes in education that promote social justice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221138837?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/47/6&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 777-780, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 12:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221138055?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Indigenous Students and English Learner Identification: A Fifty-State Policy Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;English learner (EL) education is widely conceived as services for immigrant-origin students, however nearly one in ten American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian students are classified in school as EL. Title III of the Every Student Succeeds Act (2015) defines EL eligibility differently for Indigenous, compared to non-Indigenous, students with implications for who is identified as an EL and how best to serve their academic and linguistic interests. This study presents findings from a 50-state review of Indigenous EL identification policy. We find that states fall into four categories ranging from no differentiation in Indigenous EL identification to clear differentiation. We describe each of these four categories and conclude with reflections on how this wide variation in state policies has implications for Indigenous students’ educational resources and experiences.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134697?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Designing for a Productive Politics of Participation in Research Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article considers contested conceptions of community and trajectories toward full participation in research-practice partnerships (RPPs) as key analytical aspects for studying a productive politics of participation. RPPs, as methodology and infrastructure for community participation, frequently surface the character of participation in intersecting communities of practice—making them visible and actionable. I examine two youth-serving RPPs. This analysis considers youth digital media projects as strategies for increasing participation and renegotiating power relations. Findings signal RPPs can help discern the degree to which young people are held on the periphery in communities of practice where marginalizing relations can be reinforced.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134586?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
