<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting Young Children With Disabilities During the COVID-19 Pandemic: Evidence From Caregivers in Virginia</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Early care and education (ECE) experiences shape children’s developmental trajectories, particularly for children who have or may have disabilities. However, caregivers of children with disabilities have faced considerable challenges finding care for their children, which have increased during the COVID-19 pandemic. Using survey data from nearly 3,000 caregivers of preschool-age children in Virginia collected in December 2020 and January 2021, we find that caregivers of children with disabilities were less likely to find ECE programs that met their needs, more likely to experience high levels of stress, and more likely to be concerned about their children’s development than were caregivers of children without disabilities. Concerns about child development were particularly pronounced among caregivers of children with disabilities in remote instructional settings. Our findings suggest a disproportionate impact of ECE disruption on caregivers of children with disabilities and the need for targeted supports for these caregivers moving forward.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2022 12:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221134525?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improvement in action: Advancing quality in America’s schools</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2022 07:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2022.2141603?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A new canon: Designing culturally sustaining humanities curriculum</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2022 07:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2022.2129281?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Productive Disciplinary Engagement as a Framework to Support Mathematics Teacher Leaders</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-03-2022 07:22</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2139095?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Principal Leadership for School-Wide Transformation of Elementary Mathematics Teaching: Why the Principal’s Conception of Teacher Learning Matters</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Supporting teacher learning for normative change in classroom learning environments creates significant demands on principal leadership. We offer an analytic framework that aims to understand principal practice for instructional transformation. The framework examines how the principal’s conception of teacher learning shapes practice in relation to particular contexts and support systems. We illustrate the explanatory power of this framework by using it to make sense of one elementary principal’s practice in leading her school for instructional transformation in mathematics. Our analysis contributes to how leadership efforts to transform instruction might be studied and ultimately supported.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 11:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221130706?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Politics of Progressivity: Court-Ordered Reforms, Racial Difference, and School Finance Fairness</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article contributes to our understanding of American education politics by exploring when and why states redistribute K–12 education dollars to poorer schools. It does so by examining three explanations for intrastate changes in progressivity: court-ordered finance reforms, political trends, and demographic changes. Using state-level data from 1995 to 2016, we find mixed evidence that progressivity increased following a court-ordered school-finance overhaul. Rather, we show that changes in progressivity were most consistently tied to changes in student demography: As students became poorer, or more racially diverse, lawmakers created less progressive finance systems. The article concludes by discussing what these findings mean for advocates seeking to protect and advance gains in education-spending progressivity.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 11:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221126096?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Opportunity Structures for Student Activism, Diversity, and Institutional Change</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;College students across the United States are engaging in protests, sit-ins, and walk-outs, but when do these political acts result in tangible institutional policy changes? This paper draws on qualitative data from interviews and focus groups with 502 participants across the United States to examine when and why college student political behaviors influence institutional changes on college campuses. Findings from this study suggest that higher education institutions present different political opportunity structures for students to engage in activism. These political opportunity structures provide policy windows at the institutional level to affect campus wide change. To the extent that these changes promote diversity, equity, and inclusion though also depends on these varying structures. In this paper, a typology of these structures is presented to explain when student activism shapes institutional change and for whom.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 10:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221127991?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Police Stops and School Engagement: Examining Cultural Socialization From Parents and Schools as Protective Factors Among African American Adolescents</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Police stops often perpetuate racial disparities in academic outcomes, yet few studies have examined factors that mitigate these negative consequences. Using two longitudinal studies (Study 1: n = 483, M-age = 12.88, 53% males; Study 2: n = 131, M-age = 15.11, 34% males), this article tests whether parental and school cultural socialization reduced the negative associations between police stops and youth’s school engagement. Results showed that youth with police encounters reported lower school engagement. Parental cultural socialization conferred protection in one study, while school cultural socialization was a protective factor in both studies. The implications of this work stand to benefit those working to reduce the negative links between policing and African American youth’s school engagement.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 09:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221132533?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing the Effect of Project-Based Learning on Science Learning in Elementary Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This investigation studied the effects of the Multiple Literacies in Project-Based Learning science intervention on third graders’ academic, social, and emotional learning. This intervention includes four science units and materials, professional learning, and post-unit assessments; features of project-based learning; three-dimensional learning (National Research Council, 2012); and the performance expectations from the Next Generation of Science Standards (NGSS Lead States, 2013). The intervention was evaluated with a cluster randomized control trial in 46 Michigan schools with 2,371 students. Results show that students who received the intervention had higher scores on a standardized science test (0.277 standard deviation) and reported higher levels of self-reflection and collaboration when involved in science activities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 09:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221129247?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Strategies Elites Understand: Divestment as an Approach to Social Change</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 06:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2125759?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Radical Shifts: Prefiguring Activist Politicization through Legitimate Peripheral Participation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 06:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2125757?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Museum Facilitator Practice as Infrastructure Design Work for Public Computing</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 05:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2022.2129639?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Viviane Durand-Guerrier, Reinhard Hochmuth, Elena Nardi, &amp;amp; Carl Winsløw (Eds.) (2021) Research and development in university mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10186-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>¿Cuál es la probabilidad de hacer algo nuevo?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-02-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00240-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does ESSA Assure the Use of Evidence-based Educational Practices?</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) of 2015 requires that K-12 educational agencies invest federal education funds in evidence-based practices. We estimated what percentage of Title I funds at a large school district are invested in practices supported by a single study meeting one of the top three tiers of evidence as defined by ESSA. Over 95% met this bar. When studies about each practice from four research repositories were considered, the percentage of funds invested in practices with overall positive or mostly positive ratings fell below 60%. These proportions did not change substantially after the introduction of ESSA.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 11:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221127989?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Posts About Students on Facebook: A Data Ethics Perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Public schools and districts use social media to share announcements and communicate with parents and the community, but alongside such uses run risks to students’ privacy. Using a novel data set of 18 million posts on Facebook by schools and school districts in the United States, we sought to establish how frequently photos of students were shared. Through sequential mixed-methods, we estimated that around 4.9 million posts included identifiable images of students and that approximately 726,000 of these posts also included students’ first and last names and their approximate location. We discuss these findings’ implications from a data ethics perspective.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221120538?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Cautionary Tale of Tutoring Hard-to-Reach Students in Kenya</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 09:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2131661?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Propensity Score Methods and Difference-in-Differences with an Exogenous Time-Varying Confounder: Evaluation of Methods</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 09:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2128485?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Simulation Study on Latent Transition Analysis for Examining Profiles and Trajectories in Education: Recommendations for Fit Statistics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 09:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2118197?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of Cross-Age Peer Mentoring Program within a Randomized Controlled Trial</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 09:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2130119?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Consistency between Household and County Measures of Onsite Schooling during the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 09:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2131660?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Behavioral Insights to Market a Workplace Safety Program: Evidence From a Multi-Armed Experiment</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This paper describes how a multi-armed randomized experiment was used to test multiple variants of a behaviorally informed marketing strategy. In particular, we tested whether specific behavioral messages could be used to increase demand for a safety consultation service offered by the U.S. Occupational Safety and Health Administration. Our experiment used a partial factorial design with 19 study arms and a very large research sample—97,182 establishments—to test the impact of various message, formats, and delivery modes compared with an existing (not behaviorally informed) informational brochure and a no-marketing counterfactual. A secondary research goal was to predict the impact of the most successful marketing strategy (i.e., combination of message, format, and mode) so that OSHA would know what to anticipate if that strategy were implemented at scale. We used two related (but distinct) methods to address these two goals. Both begin with a common mixed (i.e., fixed and random effects) ANOVA model. We addressed the first research goal primarily from the fixed effects; we addressed the second research goal by calculating best linear unbiased predictions (BLUPs) from the full mixed model, where the BLUP involves “shrinkage” as in empirical Bayes (EB) approaches. Marketing via brochures was effective overall, nearly doubling the rate of requests for services. However, the behaviorally informed materials performed no better than OSHA’s existing informational brochure. This study also highlights the conditions under which a factorial design can be used to efficiently address questions about which of several program variants are most effective.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 09:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221136954?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging Mathematics Teacher Leaders in Support of Student and Teacher Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 05:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2140989?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Gender Differentiated Analysis of Healthy Life Expectancy in South Asia: The Role of Greenhouse Gas Emission</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The sluggish progress concerning SDG-9 and SDG 13 has made South Asia an epicentre of household and ambient greenhouse gases emissions. Furthermore, the regional progress concerning attainment of SDG-3 is considerably low. The major research objectives are twofold. First, to explore the impact of GHGs emissions from agriculture, transportation, and manufacturing sector on disaggregated life expectancy. Second, to examine the mitigating impact of renewable energy use, trade integration, and human capital development for practice policy recommendations. These research objectives are realized by employing recently advanced cross-sectional auto regressive distributed lag (CS-ARDL) model on panel data of five South Asian countries such as Bangladesh, India, Pakistan, Nepal, and Sri Lanka from 1990 to 2019. The estimation outcome reveals that the emissions from transportation, manufacturing, and agricultural sectors significantly deteriorate healthy life expectancy of male and female healthy life expectancy in South Asia with different intensity. Especially, we find that long-run impact of GHG is more profound on male healthy life expectancy than female life expectancy. The result further shows that renewable energy and human capital substantially improve healthy life expectancy, whereas the effects of trade integration are insignificant. The finding of moderating variables shows that renewable energy, human capital development, and trade integration have high potential to reduce GHGs emissions. The findings of this study urge South Asia for investments in human capital development and renewable energy along with fostering regional integration to decrease GHG and improve healthy life expectancy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-01-2022 05:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221134850?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
