<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of teacher identity in teacher self-efficacy development: the case of Katie</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article illustrates the role of teacher identity in teacher self-efficacy development during initial teacher education. It has been posited that teacher self-efficacy develops on the basis of information accessed through four self-efficacy sources: vicarious and enactive experiences, social persuasion, and physiological and affective states, and by interacting with a myriad of personal and external factors. The very process of teacher self-efficacy development, however, is not well understood. This phenomenological longitudinal qualitative case study contributes to addressing this issue by illustrating how a pre-service secondary mathematics teacher’s teacher self-efficacy is affected by the way she sees herself. More specifically, the study illustrates how aspects of a strong student teacher identity negatively affect the pre-service teacher’s teacher self-efficacy appraisal, and how her teacher identity, emerging through the processes of autonomous role enactment and social verification, supports teacher self-efficacy development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 01:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09515-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice mathematics teachers’ conceptions of mathematically rich and contextually realistic problems</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigated the middle school preservice mathematics teachers’ conceptualization of what it means for a problem to be mathematically rich and contextually realistic and how their conceptions evolved during a series of professional development activities. Fifteen middle school preservice mathematics teachers were involved in this design-based research. The professional development activities were designed based on L. Shulman and J. Shulman’s (Shulman and Shulman, Journal of Curriculum Studies 36:257–271, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r54&quot;&gt;2004&lt;/span&gt;) reflective and communal clusters with psychological roots in Schön’s notion of “reflective practitioners” and Vygotsky’s social development theory. These professional development activities were integrated into the methods and field experience courses of the teacher education program. The audio records of the whole group and small group discussions and all written products (i.e., problems, criteria list, and reflection memos) were analyzed to understand preservice teachers’ conceptions. This study revealed that the professional development activities helped preservice teachers produce the problems that would be interesting and encouraging for students to develop their own solution methods. Preservice teachers’ conceptions also evolved in a collective and reflective community. In this respect, this study presented &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; way to design professional development for teachers that nurtures their understanding of the components supporting mathematical richness and contextual meaningfulness of a problem. Hence, this study provided implications for teacher education practices and future research on mathematics teacher preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 01:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09512-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tony Brown, A contemporary theory of mathematics education research review</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 01:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09555-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modelling lessons for more than imitation: investigating teachers’ reactions and decompositions of unfamiliar practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The literature highlights differing views on the efficacy of modelling lessons for teacher professional learning. In this study we draw on dissonance theory to discuss lesson modelling that seeks to transcend ‘do as I do’ imitation and provoke teachers’ attention to intended teaching practices: a necessary pre-cursor for changes to practice. A collective case study investigated the experiences and perceptions of 18 practising primary teachers from four school contexts participating in the process of: collectively observing modelling of mathematics lessons in their classrooms, analysing different parts of those practices with the modeller, and enacting them. It was found that modelling lessons associated with inquiry-oriented approaches for developing students’ problem-solving and reasoning in teachers’ own classrooms appeared to confront their assumptions about traditional approaches to teaching and learning mathematics. The teachers’ surprise at their students’ engagement in the challenging learning experiences conflicted with their existing views of teaching and impelled them to reflect on and set goals for improving their practice. Suggestions for pre- and post-lesson protocols for stimulating productive discussions are proposed, along with implications for designing school-based professional learning processes using lesson modelling.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 01:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09516-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Contradictions and their manifestations in professional learning communities in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Professional learning communities (PLC) have increasingly attracted attention in research on teachers’ professional development. The aim of this study is to identify contradictions that can occur and be manifested in PLCs in mathematics. Identifying contradictions in PLCs are important, as the identification and resolution of contradictions are crucial to developing PLCs. We have conceptualized PLCs and contradictions within the Cultural Historical Activity Theory. Our data consist of two iterations of interviews with four teacher leader coaches with extensive experience of coaching teacher leaders of PLCs in mathematics. The study distinguishes 26 manifestations of contradictions, taking the overall forms of dilemmas and conflicts. Our results can be used in designing PLCs in mathematics: they can be used to make visible and increase participants’ awareness of contradictions involved in PLCs and thereby increase the possibility that the contradictions serve as sources of support rather than obstacles in the development of PLCs in mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 01:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09513-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Productive ambiguity in unconventional representations: “what the fraction is going on?”</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We explore the responses of 26 prospective elementary-school teachers to the claim “1/6.5 is not a fraction” asserted by a hypothetical classroom student. The data comprise scripted dialogues that depict how the participants envisioned a classroom discussion of this claim to evolve, as well as an accompanying commentary where they described their personal understanding of the notion of a fraction. The analysis is presented from the perspective of productive ambiguity, where different types of ambiguity highlight the prospective teachers’ mathematical interpretations and pedagogical choices. In particular, we focus on the ambiguity inherent in the aforementioned unconventional representation and how the teachers reconciled it by invoking various models and interpretations of a fraction. We conclude with a description of how the perspective of productive ambiguity can enrich teacher education and classroom discourse.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 01:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09510-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Handling the diversity of research on mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 01:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09559-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Black and White Students Benefit From Racial Socialization? School Racial Socialization, School Climate, and Youth Academic Performance During Early Adolescence</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;With racial inequalities plaguing the U.S. school system, educators have recognized the importance of establishing inclusive, equitable, and diverse school environments where students from different ethnic-racial backgrounds can feel respected and supported. This study examined the longitudinal links between adolescents’ experiences of school racial socialization, school climate perceptions, and academic performance and tested whether these links varied by race (n = 941; 54% boys; 63% Black, 37% White). Results revealed that adolescents’ experience of school racial socialization practices (i.e., cultural socialization and promotion of cultural competence) predicted positive changes in their perceptions of school climate and, in turn, promoted better academic performance. School racial socialization was linked to positive school experiences and achievement for both Black and White adolescents.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-19-2022 05:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221134771?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Black School Closings Aren’t New: Historically Contextualizing Contemporary School Closings and Black Community Resistance</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Whereas increased scholarly attention is focusing on contemporary school closings, noticeably absent is the placement of this scholarship within the historical context of Black people’s social experiences. This paradigm shift would reveal a much longer history that has had devastating consequences for Black people. In this article, we identify five waves of Black school closings and provide contemporary case studies that reveal an ongoing pattern resulting in the destabilization of Black communities across time and space. Despite persistent attacks on these institutions, our analyses capture Black people’s resistance and agency in maintaining their communities and schools. In addition to providing policy implications, we further suggest the term Black community-killing as a theoretical way of thinking about the consequences of school closings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221131504?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Turnover in Early Childhood Education: Longitudinal Evidence From the Universe of Publicly Funded Programs in Louisiana</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study uses longitudinal data to follow a cohort (N = 4,465) of all early childhood education teachers working in publicly funded, center-based settings in Louisiana over a 3-year period. We present the proportion of teachers still at their sites across six time points between 2016 and 2019, providing the first statewide, longitudinal estimates of within-year and multiyear retention. We find that less than 40% teachers in the fall of 2016 are still at their site by the fall of 2019. Turnover is particularly high among childcare teachers (compared to teachers at Head Start or school-based pre-kindergarten), teachers of toddlers, and teachers new to their sites. Policy implications are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221131505?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Three-Arm Random Assignment Within Sites can Improve Non-Experimental Cross-Site Estimates of the Relationship Between Program Characteristics and Impact</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article considers a new method, called Cross-Site Attributional Model Improved by Calibration to Within-Site Individual Randomization Findings (abbreviated as “CAMIC”), which seeks to reduce bias in analyses of the contributions of a program’s various design, implementation, and contextual characteristics to its overall impacts. It requires a multi-site experiment where some (or all) sites randomize individuals to one of three arms: a standard treatment group, an enhanced treatment group (that receives the standard treatment plus a program “enhancement”), or a control group (that has no access to the program). A recent evaluation—that of the Health Profession Opportunity Grants (HPOG) program—provides a motivating example of this design and its potential for both methodological and substantive lessons; and the article considers other evaluations that would be fitting for deploying and learning from CAMIC. We conclude that the promise for CAMIC lies in situations where the correlations between the selected program enhancement and alternative program characteristics of interest are relatively high, implying that producing an experimental estimate of the enhancement can reduce bias in the estimation of other non-randomized program characteristics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221140614?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bridging Educational Change and Social Justice: A Call to the Field</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The education research community, both within the American Educational Research Association (AERA) and beyond, could and should play a critical role in fundamentally transforming educational institutions and systems. Given its complexity, transformative change in education is best undertaken as a collective endeavor. Yet for researchers to be a valuable resource in educational transformation, we will need to bridge knowledge across subfields that currently have limited interaction. Through two illustrative examples, we demonstrate the need to link knowledge on educational change with knowledge on how to create more equitable, anti-racist, and decolonized spaces for formal and informal learning. While operating in different spaces and initiated at different entry points, the two change efforts exemplify a common set of commitments and actionable pathways for achieving transformational change. This article is a call to action for researchers to join together in supporting educational transformation that fundamentally challenges the inequitable arrangements persisting in educational organizations characterized by systemic racism and colonialism. Bridging knowledge bases and being accountable to serve and support communities and their intersectional identities are essential to making deep, scalable changes in education that promote social justice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221138837?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/47/6&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 777-780, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 12:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221138055?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Indigenous Students and English Learner Identification: A Fifty-State Policy Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;English learner (EL) education is widely conceived as services for immigrant-origin students, however nearly one in ten American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian students are classified in school as EL. Title III of the Every Student Succeeds Act (2015) defines EL eligibility differently for Indigenous, compared to non-Indigenous, students with implications for who is identified as an EL and how best to serve their academic and linguistic interests. This study presents findings from a 50-state review of Indigenous EL identification policy. We find that states fall into four categories ranging from no differentiation in Indigenous EL identification to clear differentiation. We describe each of these four categories and conclude with reflections on how this wide variation in state policies has implications for Indigenous students’ educational resources and experiences.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134697?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Designing for a Productive Politics of Participation in Research Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article considers contested conceptions of community and trajectories toward full participation in research-practice partnerships (RPPs) as key analytical aspects for studying a productive politics of participation. RPPs, as methodology and infrastructure for community participation, frequently surface the character of participation in intersecting communities of practice—making them visible and actionable. I examine two youth-serving RPPs. This analysis considers youth digital media projects as strategies for increasing participation and renegotiating power relations. Findings signal RPPs can help discern the degree to which young people are held on the periphery in communities of practice where marginalizing relations can be reinforced.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134586?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Research-Practice Partnerships Responsive to Partners’ Needs? Exploring Research Activities During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Despite everyone’s best intentions, RPP-produced research may still fall short of being responsive to the needs of practice partners. The COVID-19 pandemic arguably magnified the demand for research to help education leaders make informed decisions in unprecedented ways. Were RPPs able to be responsive to practice-side partners in their time of need? We draw upon data collected as part of the 2019, 2020, and 2021 National Network of Education Research-Practice Partnerships’ (NNERPP) annual reports to explore this question. Our findings suggest an increase in design-based projects, in addition to increases in quick-turnaround research syntheses in order to accommodate partner needs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134584?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of School Choice Competition on an Underserved Neighborhood Public School</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This critical ethnography utilizes critical policy analysis and a theoretical understanding of neoliberal racism to examine the practiced reality of school choice in a public, under-resourced, and historically underperforming neighborhood elementary school attended predominantly by Latina/o/x students. Despite improvement initiatives that resulted in performance distinctions, the school under study experienced substantial enrollment decline amidst the poaching of students by charter schools within the attendance zone. Moreover, the competitive school choice market within the school’s district resulted in the reshuffling of teachers, reinforcement of neoliberal improvement discourses, and even the exploitation of dual language students to raise the school’s market profile. The study provides a unique, up-close representation of marketization in public schools and the residualizing effects that school choice policies can have on public education writ large.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134583?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Political Considerations for Establishing Research-Practice Partnerships in Pursuit of Equity: Organizations, Projects, and Relationships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;If the RPP field is to bring our stated commitments to equity to life, it will require engagement with the political dimensions of RPP work, starting at the outset when a partnership is being established. In particular, prospective members must consider how the research process and products might (or might not) lead to more equitable systems. Recognizing that RPP work centering equity sits at the intersection of distinct intellectual genealogies, I argue that research and activist traditions drawing on critical and decolonial traditions—often overlooked in RPP literature—provide particularly relevant insights. Working through questions relevant to the establishment of an RPP on organizational, project-level, and relational dimensions, analyses and examples drawn from scholars, as well as journalists, organizers, educators, and young people illustrate the political considerations inherent in each. I close with implications for new and existing RPPs and directions for future research on RPPs as a methodology.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221130993?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Math cleverly disguised as/with string”: experienced weavers’ engagement with mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2133005?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“What Do You Think She’s Going to Do Next?” Irresolution and Ambiguity as Resources for Collective Engagement</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2022 10:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2022.2129641?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Topic specificity of students’ conceptual and procedural fraction knowledge and its impact on errors</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2022 07:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2135132?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Personal elaborated feedback design in support of students’ conjecturing processes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2022 01:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2137571?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the interplay between targeted motivation interventions and motivational teaching practices in mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Prior research has shown that brief motivation interventions, such as interventions targeting students’ perceptions concerning relevance of the learning material, can have long-lasting effects on students’ motivation and performance. However, the educational contexts in which these interventions have been implemented have their own motivational affordances, such as the extent to which teachers support students’ perceptions of relevance in regular classes. According to the seed-and-soil hypothesis for the effectiveness of psychological interventions, such interventions can be seen like a “seed” that needs to be implemented in a supportive educational context (i.e., the “soil”) in order to work. Therefore, in this study we examined the interplay between a one-time relevance intervention implemented in mathematics classrooms and the mathematics teacher’s relevance support as perceived by the students before and after the intervention. Data stemmed from a cluster-randomized controlled trial with 79 ninth-grade mathematics classes (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 1744 students) in which the intervention was implemented by the mathematics teacher or a master’s student, both trained for this purpose. Multilevel moderation models showed that both intervention conditions had larger effects when students perceived higher relevance support before or after the intervention, thus providing support for the seed-and-soil hypothesis. Furthermore, multilevel mediation models indicated a positive effect of the teacher condition on perceived relevance support at posttest compared with the control condition, which partly explained the positive effect of this intervention condition on utility value at follow-up. The results shed light on the contexts in which these interventions are most effective and the mechanisms through which they work.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01446-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ Mental Health During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;With an emergence of research investigating the educational impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic, empirical studies assessing teachers’ mental health throughout the pandemic have been scarce. Using a large national data set, the current study compares mental health outcomes during the pandemic between pre-K–12 teachers and professionals in other occupations. Further, we compare the prevalence of mental health outcomes between in-person and remote teachers (N = 134,693). Findings indicate that teachers reported a greater prevalence of anxiety symptoms than did those in other professions and that remote teachers reported significantly higher levels of distress than did those teaching in person. We summarize the policy implications of these results.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-15-2022 12:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221134281?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
