<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The identity dilemmas of Early Career Teachers from under-represented groups in the UK</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-15-2022 06:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2022.2118704?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From disruption to ‘Comfort-Zoom’ routine: preservice teachers’ perspectives on remote learning during the Corona year</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-15-2022 06:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2022.2106964?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Multi-dimensional Framework for Documenting Students’ Heterogeneous Experiences with Programming Bugs</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-15-2022 04:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2022.2118279?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Special educators’ knowledge of student mathematical thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;To anticipate and respond to the diverse ways of reasoning students with disabilities use to make sense in inclusive mathematics classrooms, special educators require a deep understanding of a diverse array of student thinking. Unfortunately, historic and contemporary data suggest that opportunities for special educators to develop this knowledge prior to classroom teaching are diminutive. Further inquiry is needed into pre-service experiences that might support growth in teachers’ knowledge. We present results from a US-based semester-long course grounded in neurodiversity and students’ mathematical thinking designed to improve 20 special educators’ pedagogical content knowledge. Qualitative and quantitative analyses were conducted to determine how the pre-service teachers anticipated students’ diverse mathematical thinking before and after experience in the course along with their propensity to adapt problems to respond to diversity during instruction. Furthermore, the pre-test to post-test changes in pre-service teachers’ anticipations of students’ problem-solving strategies and adaptations of problems were statistically significant. Implications for teacher preparation and future research are shared.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 16:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09508-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using scripting tasks to reveal mathematics teacher candidates&#39;  resources for responding to student errors</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Practice-based pedagogies, such as representations of practice and approximations of practice, are increasingly common in mathematics teacher education. More needs to be known about how teacher candidates&#39; (TCs&#39;) productions through such activities make visible the resources they bring to the work of teaching. In this paper, we highlight our use of “scripting tasks,” through which secondary mathematics TCs produced dialogues of classroom interactions and rationales for those scripts in response to a provided classroom scenario. We share how analyses of TCs&#39; scripts and rationales can make visible a range of resources that TCs bring to the work of teaching—tools and practices, vision and dispositions of teaching, and understandings of students and content (Hammerness et al., 2005)—that inform how they respond to student contributions in whole-class discussions as a focal teaching practice. We illustrate a rich example and framework for analyzing TCs&#39; responses to scripting tasks and offer implications for how such analyses can support teacher educators and researchers to make claims about TCs&#39; learning and inform decisions about supports for TCs&#39; development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 16:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09505-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning to design effective professional development: The influence of integrating a coaching tool with an elementary mathematics specialist course assignment</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As content-specific educational coaches, elementary mathematics specialists (EMSs) have emerged as school-based professionals who are needs-driven and work closely with school stakeholders in regard to mathematics teaching and learning. While leading mathematics education organizations have identified the specialized knowledge and skills required for EMS positions, how to best prepare these individuals is knowledge that the field is still exploring. This paper first presents a theoretical model for EMS preparation that aligns an emerging coaching tool, the Decision-Making Protocol for Mathematics Coaching (Baker &amp;amp; Knapp, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r75&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/span&gt;, [DMPMC]) with the Professional Development Design Framework (Loucks-Horsley et al. in Designing professional development for teachers of science and mathematics, Corwin Press, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r35&quot;&gt;2010&lt;/span&gt;). The paper then presents a descriptive case study that examines the application of this model in an EMS preparation course. The findings indicate that assessing the coaching situation fostered administrative partnerships, revisiting goals increased specificity of anticipated outcomes, and applying research-informed practices increased EMS self-efficacy and advanced coaching agendas. Taken together, these findings suggest that integrating the DMPMC into an EMS preparation course led to positive changes in EMS candidate learning of professional development design. Notably, this is one of the first studies that documents the influence of a coaching education tool on EMS candidates’ professional development design.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 16:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09507-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>(Mis)alignment between noticing and instructional quality: the role of psychological and cognitive constructs</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, we investigated the relationship between teachers’ post-instruction noticing (PIN) and the quality of their mathematics instruction. We analyzed the conversations of elementary teachers around five coached lessons and scored their level of post-instruction noticing and the mathematical quality of the instruction of the lesson. We compared teachers’ PIN levels with their instructional quality, using scores from the Mathematical Quality of Instruction (MQI) rubric, for each coached lesson. There was both alignment and discrepancies between the level of PIN and MQI scores. Explorations of the cognitive and psychological constructs that seemed to influence teacher’s noticing showed that mathematical knowledge for teaching (MKT), efficacy, beliefs, emotions, and identity was influential on teachers’ PIN although they seemed to influence teachers differently. In some cases, the constructs appeared to support attentiveness to students’ thinking and in other cases they did not. We discuss implications for professional development and future research on teachers’ noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 16:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09509-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The time is out of joint. Teacher subjectivity during COVID-19</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, we address the issue of mathematics teachers&#39; personal and professional responsiveness to changing circumstances, such as the shift in external demands made on teacher practice due to the COVID-19 pandemic. For investigating a such delicate issue, we take a theoretical approach, which is quite novel in the field of mathematics education: Lacan&#39;s psychoanalytical lens. Specifically, we will use this psychoanalytical lens to analyze a case study focusing on a primary school teacher during the first lockdown in Italy, during which school was organized exclusively in the form of distance education. The analysis of the teacher’s crisis and the strategies she adopted to overcome this crisis give some suggestions about possible directions and issues to consider for future mathematics teacher training proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 16:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09506-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“It’s Not Easy, But It Needs to Be Done”: Educators’ Perceptions of Preparedness to Teach Students With Internalizing Mental Health Needs</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This mixed methods study surveyed 209 K-12 special education teachers about their perceptions of preparedness to teach students with mental health needs that manifest internally (e.g., quiet distress, withdrawal, excessive worry). We used a construct-modeling approach to develop the survey instrument and establish evidence of validity, reliability, and fairness, and it included both multiple-choice questions, used for descriptive and regression analyses, and open-ended items, coded to identify key themes. Results indicated that special educators generally had low perceptions of preparedness to support students with internalizing needs. In addition, we found that participants possessed critical misconceptions about research-based practices for supporting students with these needs in the school context, and that differences in perceptions of preparedness were associated with teachers’ race and the grade level at which they taught.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 12:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871221121278?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using an Emergency Plan to Combat Teacher Burnout Following a Natural Hazard</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A relevant, well-crafted emergency plan can help schools most optimally return to normal following a disaster. During this time, educators find themselves facing unintended responsibilities like operating on the front lines of providing social-emotional support for their students. Researchers conducted 115 interviews with educators impacted by Hurricanes Harvey and Matthew in Texas and North Carolina to assess their mental health and their school’s role in returning to normal. Findings suggest that emergency plans often did not take into account the social-emotional factors of recovery. This paper seeks to provide insight into the experiences of educators following a disaster and propose elements to consider in revising school emergency plans.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 06:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120273?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Finance Equity through Accountability? Exploring the Role of Federal Oversight of School Districts under the Every Student Succeeds Act</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 02:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2109916?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Multiracials’ membership and identification practices on campus: a boundary-work approach</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 01:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2114510?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher bias matters: an integrative review of correlates, mechanisms, and consequences</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-14-2022 01:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2122425?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pushing Through: Developing Teacher Identity Under Times of Crisis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Field experiences during teacher preparation programs support teacher candidates in forming and reforming teacher identities through real-world teaching situations. Trying out teaching approaches with children, reflecting on practice, and collaborating with cooperating teachers support teacher candidates in building a teacher identity. However, at the start of the COVID-19 pandemic in the United States, public schools closed in many states, requiring that field placements either end or change significantly. This is a study of five teacher candidates in an early childhood teacher preparation program. These candidates’ field placement ended in March 2020, requiring that university faculty develop an alternative teaching placement. Using Bourdieusian theoretical concepts of habitus, field, and doxa, this study explores how the candidates perceived this change and how they were able to continue to reflect and build their teacher identities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2022 12:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871221121285?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘Demonstrable experience of being a Mammy or Crazy Black Bitch’ (essential). A critical race feminist approach to understanding Black women Headteachers’ experiences in English schools</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2022 11:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2122520?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Community Policing in Schools and School Resource Officer Transparency</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Following increased attention to racial disparities in police use of force, national conversations have focused on the role of law enforcement, including in public schools. This study examines transparency with regard to the presence of law enforcement in schools. Leveraging novel school-level and district-level data from the state of Florida, this research shows that the majority of schools and about a third of school districts do not make information on law enforcement presence in schools publicly available. Furthermore, the study finds that schools and districts serving more White student bodies have higher levels of transparency around law enforcement than those serving less-White demographics, an important finding given the racialized context of current policy discussions around policing in US schools and society more broadly. These findings inform ongoing debates about law enforcement in schools while also raising implications for policy and practice around the racialized nature of government transparency.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2022 08:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120270?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining peer group mentoring in teaching practicum and its impact on the process of pre-service teachers’ joint reflection</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2022 03:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2122807?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Just what is afropessimism and what’s it doing in a nice field like education?: Unpacking new contributions to Black educational thought</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-13-2022 02:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2122522?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strategies implemented by South African teachers to ensure continuing mathematics education during COVID-19</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic continues to present severe challenges to the education sector more than 2 years after the first case was detected. We explore the strategies South African teachers used to support continued mathematics learning at home during the COVID-19 pandemic across different stages of the response to it and across different contexts. We explore these strategies, first, in relation to the initial shift to emergency remote teaching when learners needed to be reached in their homes under severe lockdown regulations, then through the gradual reopening of schools later as regulations were relaxed. Activity theory informs our perspective on the way in which teachers worked to mediate learning across school and home activity systems. Twenty-five Grade 4–7 mathematics teachers from the Eastern Cape responded to two questionnaires given at the start of the COVID-19 lockdown period and during the phased return to school. Questions focused on the strategies used to support mathematics learning. The results show that strategies focused on engaging caregivers through various technologies and getting resources into the home. WhatsApp, a free internet-based messaging service, was the most frequently used communication app across all types of schools for both messaging parents and sending instructional material and support in the form of videos, pictures and text messages. Department issued workbooks and teacher designed work packs were key resources sent to homes. Differences are evident in the range of use of different technologies across wealthier and poorer schools. Primary teachers’ voices inform possible ways forward for the purpose of managing young student mathematical learning gaps and meeting ongoing learning needs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01408-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Secondary mathematics teachers learning to do and teach mathematical modeling: a trajectory</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study explores secondary mathematics teachers’ perceptions of the experiences that contributed to their capacities to understand mathematical modeling and to facilitate students’ modeling experiences. The retrospective research methods and transformative learning theory frame used in the study honor teachers as adult learners and value their perspectives while providing a way to study the complexity of learning to model and to teach modeling. Data analysis identified triggers and knowledge dilemmas that challenged and prompted teacher learning as well as opportunities to resolve dilemmas through rational discourse and critical reflection. Patterns in teacher-identified meaningful learning experiences reveal a trajectory with strands that address aspects of doing and teaching mathematical modeling: mathematics, social aspects of learning, real-world contexts, student thinking, and curriculum. Results of this study provide a holistic view of learning to do and teach mathematical modeling, complementing studies of designed professional learning interventions that out of necessity target specific parts of the modeling process. The results both support and challenge common teacher education content and practices. The study illustrates the usefulness of retrospective methods to understand teachers as lifelong learners.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09550-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Collaboratively-Derived Research Agenda for E-assessment in Undergraduate Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper describes the collaborative development of an agenda for research on e-assessment in undergraduate mathematics. We built on an established approach to develop the agenda from the contributions of 22 mathematics education researchers, university teachers and learning technologists interested in this topic. The resulting set of 55 research questions are grouped into 5 broad themes: errors and feedback, student interactions with e-assessment, design and implementation choices, affordances offered by e-assessment tools, and mathematical skills. This agenda gives a framework for a programme of research aligned with practical concerns that will contribute to both theoretical and practical development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-12-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00189-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School practicum experiences at the time of Covid-19: Focusing on the implementation of play practices</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-09-2022 06:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2122808?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What might diversity mean in JMTE?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-09-2022 04:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09552-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the Role of Technology in Asian Economies: The Environmental Impact of Remittances and Economic Complexity</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In recent years, scholars have determined various determinants of environmental degradation using the panel and time-series studies. However, technological innovations (TI) and remittances, among the financial system’s essential components, are relatively ignored. In addition, nations’ economic progress and environmental performance also depend upon the nature of their economic structure. This empirical research investigates the effects of TI, remittances and economic complexity (EC) on CO2 controlling economic growth and trade openness (TR) in the selected 15 Asian nations. The study collected panel data of 15 Asian countries from 1990 to 2019 and employed the panel quantile regression and augmented mean group methods to unveil the impacts of variables on CO2 emissions. The empirical findings established that remittances are negatively linked with CO2 emissions. Similarly, EC reduces CO2 emissions in the context of Asian countries. In addition, EC and remittances Granger cause CO2 emissions. These findings indicate that remittances and EC positively contribute to environmental quality in Asian countries. Conversely, TI, economic growth, and TR intensify CO2 emissions in Asian countries. Finally, the study recommended policies to enhance remittances and EC in Asian countries to curb environmental degradation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-09-2022 04:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221120483?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
