<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Applying Lessons From “The Evolving Art of Program Evaluation” in the Next Generation of Evaluations—Comments and Author Responses</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-10-2022 04:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221125299?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tony Brown, A contemporary theory of mathematics education research review</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-09-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09555-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning-Mode Choice, Student Engagement, and Achievement Growth During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic resulted in an unanticipated, near-universal shift from in-person to virtual instruction in the spring of 2020. During the 2020–21 school year, schools began to reopen, and families were faced with decisions regarding the instructional mode for their children. We leverage administrative, survey, and virtual-learning data to examine the determinants of family learning-mode choice and associations between virtual education, student engagement, and academic achievement. Family preference for virtual (versus face-to-face) instruction was highly associated with subsequent school-level infection rates and appeared relatively uniform within schools. We find that students assigned to a higher proportion of instructional days in virtual mode experienced higher rates of attendance but negative achievement growth compared to students who were assigned a higher proportion of instructional days in face-to-face mode. Insights from this study can be used to better understand family preferences as well as to target and refine virtual learning in a post-COVID-19 society.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-08-2022 05:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221128035?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We just do us”: How Black teachers co-construct Black teacher fugitive space in the face of antiblackness</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-07-2022 07:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2122424?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching–Learning Contemporary Physics: from Research to Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As part of Springer, the edited book addresses innovative approaches and pedagogical strategies, the development of effective methods for assessing, and the innovative project in teaching and learning contemporary physics. This volume includes successful experimental and theoretical studies of QM teaching, which the experts or teachers can then adopt or modify the concept into practice in context. The 19 chapters, representing results of original study works dealing with Physics Education, are selected from the contributions in a conference on the teaching and learning of quantum physics. The goal of the book is to introduce contemporary physics to all level schools. Without a doubt, the book is recommended for high school teachers, instructional developers, and scientists to explore and develop the theories, approaches, and strategies in the book to advance teaching/learning of CP.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-07-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00233-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Panel unit-root tests with structural breaks</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 664-678, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce a new community-contributed command called xtbunitroot, which implements the panel-data unit-root tests developed by Karavias and Tzavalis (2014, Computational Statistics and Data Analysis 76: 391–407). These tests allow for one or two structural breaks in deterministic components of the series and can be seen as panel-data counterparts of the tests by Zivot and Andrews (1992, Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 10: 251–270) and Lumsdaine and Papell (1997, Review of Economics and Statistics 79: 212–218). The dates of the breaks can be known or unknown. The tests allow for intercepts and linear trends, nonnormal errors, and cross-section heteroskedasticity and dependence. They have power against homogeneous and heterogeneous alternatives and can be applied to panels with small or large time-series dimensions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124541?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>xtusreg: Software for dynamic panel regression under irregular time spacing</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 713-724, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;We introduce a new command, xtusreg, that estimates parameters of fixed-effects dynamic panel regression models under unequal time spacing. After reviewing the method, we examine the finite-sample performance of the command using simulated data. We also illustrate the command with the National Longitudinal Survey Original Cohorts: Older Men, whose personal interviews took place in the unequally spaced years of 1966, 1967, 1969, 1971, 1976, 1981, and 1990. The methods underlying xtusreg are those discussed by Sasaki and Xin (2017, Journal of Econometrics 196: 320–330).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124567?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Updates</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 725-725, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124568?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>ivcrc: An instrumental-variables estimator for the correlated random-coefficients model</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 469-495, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;We discuss the ivcrc command, which implements an instrumental-variables (IV) estimator for the linear correlated random-coefficients model. The correlated random-coefficients model is a natural generalization of the standard linear IV model that allows for endogenous, multivalued treatments and unobserved heterogeneity in treatment effects. The estimator implemented by ivcrc uses recent semiparametric identification results that allow for flexible functional forms and permit instruments that may be binary, discrete, or continuous. The ivcrc command also allows for the estimation of varying-coefficient regressions, which are closely related in structure to the proposed IV estimator. We illustrate the use of ivcrc by estimating the returns to education in the National Longitudinal Survey of Young Men.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124449?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Stata implementation of second-generation p-values</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 496-520, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I introduce new commands to calculate second-generation p-values (SGPVs) for common estimation commands in Stata. The sgpv command and its companions allow the easy calculation of SGPVs and their associated diagnostics, as well as the plotting of SGPVs against the standard p-values.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124466?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Announcements</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 726-727, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124569?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bunching estimation of elasticities using Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 597-624, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Typical censoring models have mass points at the upper or lower tails, or at both tails, of an otherwise continuous outcome distribution. In contrast, we consider a censoring model with a mass point in the interior of the outcome distribution. We refer to this mass point as “bunching” and use it to estimate model parameters. For example, economic theory suggests that, for increasing marginal income tax rates, many taxpayers will report income exactly at the threshold where the tax rate increases. This translates into a censoring model with bunching at the threshold. The size of this mass point of taxpayers can be used to estimate an elasticity parameter that summarizes taxpayers’ responses to taxes. In this article, we introduce the command bunching, which implements new nonparametric and semiparametric identification methods for estimating elasticities developed by Bertanha, McCallum, and Seegert (2021, Technical Report 2021-002, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System). These methods rely on weaker assumptions than what are currently made in the literature and result in meaningfully different estimates of the elasticity.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124534?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Flexible parametric survival analysis with multiple timescales: Estimation and implementation using stmt</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 679-701, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we describe methodology that allows for multiple timescales using flexible parametric survival models without the need for time splitting. When one fits flexible parametric survival models on the log-hazard scale, numerical integration is required in the log likelihood to fit the model. The use of numerical integration allows incorporation of arbitrary functions of time into the model and hence lends itself to the inclusion of multiple timescales in an appealing way. We describe and exemplify these methods and show how to use the command stmt , which implements these methods, alongside its postestimation commands.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124552?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The inverse hyperbolic sine transformation and retransformed marginal effects</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 702-712, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I show how to calculate consistent marginal effects on the original scale of the outcome variable in Stata after estimating a linear regression with a dependent variable that has been transformed by the inverse hyperbolic sine function. The method uses a nonparametric retransformation of the error term and accounts for any scaling of the dependent variable. The inverse hyperbolic sine function is not invariant to scaling, which is known to shift marginal effects between those from an untransformed dependent variable to those of a logtransformed dependent variable, when all observations are positive.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124553?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Computing decomposable multigroup indices of segregation</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 521-556, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Eight multigroup segregation indices are decomposable into a between and a within term. They are two versions of 1) the mutual information index, 2) the symmetric Atkinson index, 3) the relative diversity index, and 4) Theil’s H index. In this article, we present the command dseg, which obtains all of them. It contributes to the stock of segregation commands in Stata by 1) implementing the decomposition in a single call, 2) providing the weights and local indices used in the computation of the within term, 3) facilitating the deployment of the decomposability properties of the eight indices in complex scenarios that demand tailor-made solutions, and 4) leveraging sample data with bootstrapping and approximate randomization tests. We analyze 2017 census data of public schools in the United States to illustrate the use of dseg. The subject topic is school racial segregation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124471?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Panel stochastic frontier models with endogeneity</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 643-663, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, I introduce xtsfkk as a new command for fitting panel stochastic frontier models with endogeneity. The advantage of xtsfkk is that it can control for the endogenous variables in the frontier and the inefficiency term in a longitudinal setting. Hence, xtsfkk performs better than standard panel frontier estimators such as xtfrontier that overlook endogeneity by design. Moreover, xtsfkk uses Mata’s moptimize() functions for substantially faster execution and completion speeds. I also present a set of Monte Carlo simulations and examples demonstrating the performance and usage of xtsfkk.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124539?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A mixture of ordered probit models with endogenous switching between two latent classes</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 557-596, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Ordinal responses can be generated, in a cross-sectional context, by different unobserved classes of population or, in a time-series context, by different latent regimes. We introduce a new command, swopit, that fits a mixture of ordered probit models with exogenous or endogenous switching between two latent classes (regimes). Switching is endogenous if unobservables in the classassignment model are correlated with unobservables in the outcome models. We provide a battery of postestimation commands; assess via Monte Carlo experiments the finite-sample performance of the maximum likelihood estimator of the parameters, probabilities, and their standard errors (both the asymptotic and bootstrap ones); and apply the new command to model the monetary policy interest rates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124516?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>graphiclasso: Graphical lasso for learning sparse inverse-covariance matrices</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 625-642, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In modern multivariate statistics, where high-dimensional datasets are ubiquitous, learning large (inverse-) covariance matrices is imperative for data analysis. A popular approach to estimating a large inverse-covariance matrix is to regularize the Gaussian log-likelihood function by imposing a convex penalty function. In a seminal article, Friedman, Hastie, and Tibshirani (2008, Biostatistics 9: 432–441) proposed a graphical lasso (Glasso) algorithm to efficiently estimate sparse inverse-covariance matrices from the convex regularized log-likelihood function. In this article, I first explore the Glasso algorithm and then introduce a new graphiclasso command for the large inverse-covariance matrix estimation. Moreover, I provide a useful command for tuning parameter selection in the Glasso algorithm using the extended Bayesian information criterion, the Akaike information criterion, and cross-validation. I demonstrate the use of Glasso using simulation results and real-world data analysis.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124538?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working together as scientific and experiential experts: how do current ethical PAR-principles work in a research team with young adults with Developmental Language Disorder?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 08:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2130386?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Commentary on “Obtaining Interpretable Parameters From Reparameterized Longitudinal Models: Transformation Matrices Between Growth Factors in Two Parameter Spaces”</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;To model growth over time, statistical techniques are available in both structural equation modeling (SEM) and random effects modeling frameworks. Liu et al. proposed a transformation and an inverse transformation for the linear–linear piecewise growth model with an unknown random knot, an intrinsically nonlinear function, in the SEM framework. This method allowed for the incorporation of time-invariant covariates. While the proposed method made novel contributions in this area of research, the use of transformations introduces some challenges to model estimation and dissemination. This commentary aims to illustrate the significant contributions of the authors’ proposed method in the SEM framework, along with presenting the challenges involved in implementing this method and opportunities available in an alternative framework.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 01:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221126747?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-05-2022 07:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2126670?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Moving Through the Pipeline: Ethnic and Linguistic Disparities in Special Education from Birth Through Age Five</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examined Oregon’s early intervention (EI) and early childhood special education (ECSE) pipelines as a function of children’s intersecting ethnicity and home language(s) with a focus on children from Latino/a backgrounds with communication disorders. We found differences in children’s referral source and age of referral, likelihood of evaluation and placement, and type of placement for conditions related to communication, including autism spectrum disorder and hearing impairment. Results showed differences in EI and ECSE; however, disproportionality appeared greatest among Spanish-speaking Latino/a children and non-Latino/a children who spoke languages other than English compared to non-Latino/a English-speaking counterparts. Our findings suggest that attending to children’s intersecting ethnicity and language backgrounds in referral, evaluation, and placement add nuance to examinations of disproportionality. Results also indicate that practices related to characterizing children’s communication disorders likely make substantial contributions to inequities in EI and ECSE. Precise identification of differences in service provision can lead to targeted policy and practice solutions to reduce structural barriers to care in EI/ECSE systems and improve equity, particularly as related to placement for children of color with communication concerns.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-05-2022 01:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221120262?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How early career elementary teachers vary in planning mathematics instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Given that early career elementary teachers face pressure to plan pedagogy that provides equitable opportunities to learn mathematics for understanding, it is important to consider their mathematics lesson planning practices. This study uses interview data to compare the planning practices of four early career teachers (ECTs) who consistently rated highly on an observational measure of high-quality mathematics instruction with those of three ECTs who consistently rated lower. ECTs who scored highly addressed planning challenges in interconnected ways that were responsive to students’ needs, demonstrated more agency in representing mathematics content in their planning, and were more likely to maintain curricular rigor when differentiating. We consider implications for efforts to help ECTs plan lessons that are likely to result in high-quality instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-05-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09551-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Participatory research to address climate change and sustainability</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/30/4&quot;&gt;Volume 30, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, October 2022&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-04-2022 07:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2111187?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
