<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Documenting two emerging sociomathematical norms for examining functions in mathematics teachers’ online asynchronous discussions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigated novice mathematics teachers participating in an online teacher education course focused on covariational reasoning and understanding the behavior of functions. The analysis centered on documenting the emergence of participants’ sociomathematical norms for engaging in online asynchronous discussions. In this paper, we characterized participants’ initial mathematical discourse and documented two emergent sociomathematical norms, namely &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;explaining why&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;emergent shape discourse&lt;/em&gt;. When participants &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;explained why&lt;/em&gt;, they used specific quantities or symbolic representations of functions to justify why function graphs have particular visual features. When participants engaged in &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;emergent shape discourse&lt;/em&gt;, they coordinated change between covarying quantities to justify why function graphs behave in certain ways. This study provides evidence that online settings can provide context for mathematics teachers engaging in legitimate collaborative mathematical activity and that activity can be enhanced by participation in discourse featuring specific sociomathematical norms. We discuss conjectures regarding the potential of reflective discussion activities paired with the Notice and Wonder Framework to support the emergence of generative sociomathematical norms. We also discuss potential relationships between characteristics of participants’ mathematical discourse and their membership with the core and periphery of a social network.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-22-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09563-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stepping in or Stepping On: Mentor Teachers’ Preferences for Mentoring Inside and Outside of Interactive Teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Much research describes how mentor and novice teachers interact when pupils are not present (e.g., co-planning, debriefing). However, little research investigates how mentor/novice pairs interact when K–12 students are present. This gap in the literature is significant because research suggests that without intentional mediation, novices often fail to see much of what happens in classrooms. This article investigates and conceptualizes what 27 mentors think about mentoring practices that occur outside versus inside of instructional time. An analysis of mentor interviews found that mentors prefer to interact with novices outside of instructional time because they fear undercutting novices’ authority and autonomy when interacting with them during instruction. However, findings also suggest that hybrid practices (those that straddle the outside/inside boundary) are valued by mentors although they are rarely enacted. This finding has implications for programs interested in supporting mentors to diversify the practices they employ to support novice teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2022 12:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871221142843?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When “Nice” Isn’t: Confronting Niceness and Whiteness to Center Equity in Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2022 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2022.2158390?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Surfing Semantic Waves: Using Semantic Profiling to Focus on Knowledge in Practicum Lessons</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2022 05:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2022.2158389?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Preparation Programs and Graduates’ Growth in Instructional Effectiveness</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Many prior studies have explored average differences in initial levels of teaching effectiveness among graduates from different teacher preparation programs (TPPs) and the features of preparation that predict these differences. We focus on another important dimension of effectiveness—how graduates from different TPPs improve over time. Examining all graduates from Tennessee TPPs from 2010 to 2018, we find meaningful differences between TPPs in both initial level and early-career growth in teaching effectiveness. We also find that different TPP features explain part of these differences. Yet the features that correlate with initial teaching effectiveness are not the same features that correlate with growth. This article informs policy decisions around TPP evaluation and identifies new directions for future research in TPP effectiveness.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2022 04:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221137798?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice primary school teachers’ attitudes towards mathematics: a longitudinal study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Numerous preservice primary school teachers begin their training with a negative attitude towards mathematics: this phenomenon can have important consequences for their training path and for their future teaching. How teachers’ training programs could affect preservice teachers’ attitudes is one of the main issues in research on future teachers in the field of mathematics education. However, longitudinal studies developed during specific teacher development programs are still rare in the research field of teacher development. In this frame, this paper reports on the results of a longitudinal 2-year study carried out within the initial training of 35 preservice primary school teachers. According to the three-dimensional model of attitude towards mathematics, we developed the analysis of future teachers’ emotional disposition towards mathematics, vision of mathematics, and perceived competence in mathematics, at the beginning of the training path and after 2 years. We found two main results on two different levels. First, a positive change in future teachers’ attitude towards mathematics, generalized over all the three dimensions, occurred during the training period, and this result opens the issue of the relationship between formative choices and change in attitude. Second, our data confirm the strong relationship between the three dimensions of attitudes: every change in one dimension affects the other two dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01455-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Studying while anxious: mathematics anxiety and the avoidance of solving practice problems during exam preparation in college calculus</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students who experience mathematics anxiety have long been suggested to engage in avoidance behaviors that negatively impact their mathematics performance. However, little is known about how these avoidance behaviors manifest for highly anxious students within the context of a mathematics course. Since the use of effortful study strategies has been shown to be an important predictor of students’ academic outcomes, we investigated whether highly mathematics-anxious college students would be less likely to utilize such strategies during exam preparation compared to their less-anxious peers. To measure this, we asked college students (N = 72) enrolled in introductory Calculus to complete a battery of anxiety-related surveys and to retrospectively report how they studied for the final exam in their Calculus course. Using theories of achievement emotion as well as recent research showing a relation between mathematics anxiety and students’ planned exam preparation behavior, we hypothesized that students experiencing mathematics anxiety would retrospectively report less engagement with effortful study strategies during exam preparation compared to their less-anxious peers. In line with our hypothesis, we found that solving practice problems was viewed by students as being one of the most effortful ways to prepare for a mathematics examination, and that mathematics anxiety was negatively associated with the proportion of study time students allocated to solving practice problems during exam preparation. These findings highlight the significant relation between mathematics anxiety and students’ self-regulated exam preparation behaviors, marking it as an important topic to consider when investigating ways to improve the mathematics performance of highly mathematics-anxious individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01456-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Diverse perspectives and experiences of university mathematics teachers on improving the secondary-tertiary transition</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study explores the diversity of university mathematics teachers’ perspectives and experiences in relation to the secondary-tertiary transition (STT). Data for this study consist of responses of 310 university mathematics teachers from 30 countries to a survey. The survey design and data analysis are informed by an adaptation of a theory of improvement for education and by four idealized approaches for improving STT as identified in the literature: jump-oriented, enculturation-oriented, diversity-oriented, and cross-community-oriented. We characterize the diversity of perspectives and experiences in the data and examine ideas for future projects in light of these four approaches. We conclude that while jump-oriented approaches for improving STT are still the most prevalent, in part due to a persistent perspective of STT as a “deficit,” university mathematics teachers’ discourse on STT is becoming more diverse and nuanced. We find it particularly promising that participants’ suggestions for future action are aligned with the four approaches, and most notably, with the cross-community approach expressing the emergent need for greater communication between the secondary and tertiary mathematics education communities.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-21-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10196-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Contextual Characteristics Inside and Outside of School Walls as Predictors of Differential Effectiveness in Teacher Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-20-2022 09:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2141164?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effect of Active Learning Professional Development Training on College Students’ Academic Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-20-2022 08:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2151954?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Taught in the Matrix: A Review of Black Girls’ Experiences in U.S. Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In recent decades, a growing body of work casts light on Black girls’ schooling experiences to inform the emerging field of Black girlhood studies. Our theoretical review applies intersectionality as a guiding analytic framework to synthesize literature in this emerging field. We specifically highlight the macro and microlevel domains of power (interpersonal, cultural, structural, and disciplinary) in U.S. K–12 schools shaping Black girls’ schooling experiences. The data were drawn from a systematic search of 75 research articles. Our analysis indicated that schools perpetuate racial containment through the policies and practices they maintain as well as the cultural artifacts, objects, and people that coalesce to influence school culture, the instructional practices and curricula Black girls encounter, and the social scripts and covert messaging that dictate how Black girls claim agency in school environments. A key contribution of this review aims to situate power—a central concept in intersectionality—to offer new insights and directions for research on Black girls.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-20-2022 06:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221125476?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning to measure the area of composite shapes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Learning to calculate the area of composite shapes is an important application of area measurement but evidence suggests that many middle school students struggle to calculate the area of even simple composite shapes. In this article, I report the findings of a classroom design study conducted to investigate the collective development of strategies for measuring the area of composite shapes. I used the theory of strategy choice from an emergent perspective to analyze the collective strategy choice of two Year 8 mathematics classes (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 31) and the findings revealed that the classes developed a repertoire of strategies to decompose the shapes, measure the area of the constituent shapes, and recompose those areas to calculate total area. The students used their strategies in flexible combinations in response to the varying features of the composite shapes presented and developed justifications to support their emerging adaptive strategy choice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-20-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10191-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘Between think big and hit hard’ exploring the role of teacher agency in becoming action researcher: the Egyptian context</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2022 07:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2159470?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does the depth of the Financial Markets matter for establishing Green Growth? Assessing Financial sector’s potency in decoupling Economic Growth and Environmental Pollution</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;China’s 2060 carbon neutrality agenda requires implementation of policies that can decouple its economic growth from environmental pollution. Consequently, establishing green growth in the Chinese economy is of utmost significance. Against this milieu, this study questions whether the depth of Chinese financial markets matters for establishing green growth in China. Besides, the green growth effects of renewable energy use, technological innovation, and urbanization are also examined. Accordingly, quarterly frequency data from 1990Q1 to 2020Q4 are utilized to perform econometric tests that accommodate structural break concerns in data. Overall, the findings reveal that the depth of the Chinese financial markets facilitates the prospects of greening the Chinese economy. Notably, deepening of financial markets is seen to initially inhibit green growth while stimulating it later on; thus, the financial markets’ depth-green growth nexus is evidenced to depict a U-shape. On the other hand, green growth in China is also found to be catalyzed by the renewable transformation of the Chinese energy sector and through technological innovation in the long-run. Conversely, urbanization is witnessed to inflict anti-green growth impacts. Furthermore, the causality analysis verifies bi-directional causal associations between renewable energy use and green growth while unidirectional causalities running from financial markets&#39; deepening, technological innovation, and urbanization to green growth are also discovered. Therefore, it is recommended that China should try to persistently develop its stock and debt markets so that clean investment can be boosted to decouple economic growth and environmental pollution. Besides, it is also important to undergo renewable energy transition, develop clean technologies, and design low-energy urbanization strategies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2022 06:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221145777?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Experimental Design and Statistical Power for Cluster Randomized Cost-Effectiveness Trials</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2022 06:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2142177?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What 20 Years of MDRC RCTs Suggest About Predictive Relationships Between Intervention Features and Intervention Impacts for Community College Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article provides evidence about predictive relationships between features of community college interventions and their impacts on student progress. This evidence is based on analyses of student-level data from large-scale randomized trials of 39 (mostly) community college interventions. Specifically, the evidence consistently indicates that impacts tend to be larger as the number of intervention components increases and with the degree to which interventions promote full-time enrollment in fall and spring and/or summer enrollment. Less consistent evidence suggests that impacts tend to be larger for interventions that increase advising, tutoring, and, to a lesser extent, financial support. These results provide food for thought about the design of future community college innovations to be tested by researchers or tried by practitioners.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221139493?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We Ask So Much of These Tiny Humans”: Supporting Beginning Teachers to Honor the Dignity of Young People as Mathematical Learners</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2022 04:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2022.2137166?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Candidates’ Communication and Collaboration with Family and Community During COVID-19</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2022 04:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2022.2157905?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of school closures during the COVID-19 pandemic in early 2020 on prospective teachers in a one-semester school internship</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-19-2022 02:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2158808?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Consolidating strategies for innovative business models</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;To help face an unknown future, including ecological and social crisis, the public requires similar opportunities as government in problem solving. Deliberative democracy can facilitate quick responses to complex problems in society, so too, in small and medium-sized enterprises with limited resources. Of the latter’s engagement with deliberative democracy, we know too little. Service design and innovation lays a foundation for transformative service research. This action research brings the theoretical framework of service design into action using the practice of World Café first outlined by Juanita Brown. As a method, participants and organizations can explore various innovation business model topics whilst developing competencies in communication within their own context. The aims of this paper are to identify what can be accomplished through collective consciousness. It offers an example of action research as an integrative examination of how multiple perspectives contribute to the whole. In this study, the authors based in a Non-Governmental Organization for professional development, encourages organizations to reflect on practices and develop critical thinking to suggest action steps for industry innovative services. In the following the reader will: (a) Explore Taiwan SMEs’ efforts to form collective consciousness and to achieve consensus on the innovation industry strategy formulation; (b) Learn how groups’ and organizations’ learning was facilitated with recommendations for the feasibility of future actions; (c) Note how effective group discussion and emotional interaction between SMEs’ members were achieved such that the participants unanimously committed to subsequent actions. In sum, the action research orientation to business development contributed to achieving through collective consciousness by which consensus and action was developed on strategy, opportunities, and resources.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-16-2022 02:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221145335?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publisher Correction: Relevant mathematical modelling efforts for understanding COVID-19 dynamics: an educational challenge</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-16-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01457-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Case Study of Nonresponse Bias Analysis in Educational Assessment Surveys</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Nonresponse bias is a widely prevalent problem for data on education. We develop a ten-step exemplar to guide nonresponse bias analysis (NRBA) in cross-sectional studies and apply these steps to the Early Childhood Longitudinal Study, Kindergarten Class of 2010–2011. A key step is the construction of indices of nonresponse bias based on proxy pattern-mixture models for survey variables of interest. A novel feature is to characterize the strength of evidence about nonresponse bias contained in these indices, based on the strength of the relationship between the characteristics in the nonresponse adjustment and the key survey variables. Our NRBA improves the existing methods by incorporating both missing at random and missing not at random mechanisms, and all analyses can be done straightforwardly with standard statistical software.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-15-2022 10:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221141074?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engaging novice statisticians in statistical communications</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Curriculum change and the ready access to school level appropriate statistical software has seen the focus of statistical practice for novice statisticians move from primarily constructing graphs and calculating statistics to describing and reasoning from distributions. Many multi-faceted concepts and statistical ideas underpin distributions, which students find difficult to navigate and cognitively coordinate. Limited research, however, exists on how to enhance students’ communication when describing distributions. This paper explores the actions of a teacher as she supported 14–15-year-old students to develop notions of distribution and to describe distributions. The findings indicated that the teacher, through knowing, modelling, and listening, supported the development of student statistical language and communication. Students, through engaging in specifically designed instructional activities to engineer learning around the concept of distribution, seem to be able to transition from using their own language to using statistical language to describe distributions that communicated the concepts and features that were identified in the distribution description framework.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-15-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00442-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Knowledge and Risk–Benefit Perception as Predictors of Preservice Science Teachers’ Self-Efficacy Beliefs for Socioscientific Issues–Based Instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper aims to explore the direct relationships between preservice science teachers’ knowledge and risk–benefit perceptions, and self-efficacy beliefs for socioscientific issues–based instruction in the context of genetically modified foods. Data were collected from 1077 junior and senior preservice science teachers and analysed by structural model analysis. Three instruments were used to collect data: Self-Efficacy Beliefs for Genetically Modified Foods–Based Instruction Instrument, Genetically Modified Foods Risk and Benefit Perception Scale, and Genetically Modified Foods Knowledge Scale. Findings of the study showed that preservice science teachers’ self-efficacy beliefs for teaching socioscientific issues–based instruction in the context of genetically modified foods are significantly correlated to their genetically modified foods knowledge and risk perception. Data analysis also showed that benefit perception regarding the socioscientific issue is not correlated to preservice science teachers’ self-efficacy beliefs for teaching in the context of genetically modified foods. Moreover, it was revealed that preservice science teachers’ genetically modified foods knowledge is significantly correlated to their genetically modified foods benefit perception but not to their risk perception. Findings of the study were discussed in light of teacher self-efficacy beliefs literature and implications were provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-15-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00249-8</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
