<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing the Textbook with Professors’ Intended and Enacted Potential Intellectual Need for Infinite Series in Calculus II</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-27-2023 05:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2169490?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inequities at the intersection of race and disability: evidence from community colleges</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-27-2023 05:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2170436?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s in a word? modelling British history for a ‘multi-racial’ society</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-27-2023 05:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2160775?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of a Virtual Coaching Program to Improve Instructional Alignment to State Standards</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-26-2023 04:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2150729?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Challenging anti-Black linguistic racism in schools amidst the ‘what works’ agenda</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-26-2023 04:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2170435?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Differentiation in practice: an exploratory investigation in an Australian mainstream secondary school</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-25-2023 12:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2022.2161508?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The use of Arabic language by mathematics teachers as a resource to support teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In the research described in this paper, we explored the way Palestinian teachers use the Arabic language to teach mathematics in Arabic. First, we address the issue from an historical overview of the context of study. The historical overview allows us to situate the current context of teaching mathematics in Arabic in Palestine. We rely on Halliday’s concept of register to define what we call “Mathematical Arabic For Teaching”. It allows us to focus our study, and to address the issue of combination between this register to be developed by the teachers and the Arabic textbook content. Our theoretical framework is based on a combination of the theories Documentational Approach to Didactics and Mathematical Discourse in Instruction, which allows us to discuss mathematical Arabic for teaching as a resource. We based our exploratory study on the case of three teachers, chosen according to well-defined criteria. We explored the issue through audio recordings of their lessons teaching tenth graders the signs of quadratic functions, and video recorded interviews on their reflections on those lessons. We identified three combinations between the teachers’ Mathematical Arabic For Teaching and the use of the mathematics textbook, namely, complementarity, tension and equivalence. We conclude with some implications of these forms of combination.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-24-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01462-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Principal and Teacher Shared Race and Gender Intersections: Teacher Turnover, Workplace Conditions, and Monetary Benefits</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Recruiting racially minoritized principals is one suggested strategy to increase the racial diversity of teachers, who would then better match their increasingly racially diverse students. However, focusing solely on race ignores the salience of race-gender intersectionality in principal-teacher relations. Using three waves of nationally representative, cross-sectional data with school and year fixed effects, we compared similar teachers in the same school who are and are not race-gender congruent with their principal. We found that better discretionary workplace benefits were concentrated among Black teachers with Black principals, especially Black male teachers with Black male principals, who reported workplace supports almost half a standard deviation higher than did similar non-Black female teachers in their school. Male teachers earned up to $2,890 more supplemental income with male, racially congruent principals; female teachers earned up to $1,050 less with female, racially congruent principals. However, teacher turnover was not consistently responsive to race-gender congruence.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-23-2023 12:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221148156?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student Understanding of the Sign of Negative Definite Integrals in Mathematics and Physics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In a study of student understanding of negative definite integrals at two institutions, we administered a written survey and follow-up clinical interviews at one institution and found that “backward integrals”, where the integral was taken from right to left on the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;-axis, were the most difficult for students to interpret. We then conducted additional interviews focused on backward integrals at a second institution. Our analysis uses the concept image framework and a recent categorical framework for mathematical sense making. We found that students were most successful using the Fundamental Theorem of Calculus to determine the sign of an integral when a symbolic expression was provided. When considering a definite integral in a graphical context, students often had difficulty if they viewed the integral as a spatial area, stating that area must always be positive. Some students were able to conceptualize &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\Delta x\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(dx\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; as a difference or change and thus a signed quantity; when these students were able to view the area as a sum of smaller pieces, they were more successful in justifying a negative backward integral. Students who used amounts or similar images often had difficulty making sense of the negative sign. Even more progress was made when students either invoked or were asked explicitly about a specific physical context to be represented by the backward integral, other than spatial area. The context provided a meaning to the difference represented by &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq3&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\Delta x\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq4&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(dx\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; and thus to the sign of that difference and the definite integral.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-23-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00202-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Australian primary school teachers’ perceived barriers to and enablers for the integration of children’s literature in mathematics teaching and learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This qualitative survey study set out to investigate in-service and pre-service primary school teachers’ perceived barriers to and enablers for the integration of children’s literature in mathematics teaching and learning in an Australian educational context. While research over the past three decades have documented pedagogical benefits of teaching mathematics using children’s literature, research into teachers’ perceptions regarding the use of such resources is virtually non-existent. The study thus filled this research gap by drawing responses from open-ended survey questions of 94 in-service and 82 pre-service teachers in Australia. A thematic analysis revealed 13 perceived barriers classified under five themes with Lack of Pedagogical Knowledge and Confidence, and Time Constraint, representing 75% of all perceived barriers. Moreover, 14 perceived enablers were identified and classified under five themes with Pedagogical Benefits and Love of Stories representing around 70% of all perceived enablers. Findings also showed that most of the teachers in the study (around 75%) never or infrequently used children’s literature in their mathematics classrooms. The study highlights the role of professional learning and teacher training in ensuring that both in- and pre-service teachers have the necessary pedagogical knowledge, experience and confidence in using children’s literature to enrich their mathematics teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09517-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging prospective teachers’ knowledge through their participation in lesson study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study focuses on a lesson study adaptation for bridging prospective teachers’ experiences in a methods course and their field experiences in a teacher education program in Puerto Rico. We ask, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;what opportunities for teacher learning emerge during discussions in lesson study?&lt;/em&gt; Two lesson study teams of secondary mathematics prospective teachers, each led by an experienced mentor, planned technology-based lessons&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; Using the theoretical framework for lesson study by Lewis and colleagues, we analyzed video recordings of the teams’ discussions. The results show learning opportunities in the three dimensions of the framework: &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;teachers’ knowledge and beliefs&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;the creation of a professional community&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;the development of teaching–learning artifacts&lt;/em&gt;. The mentors leveraged prospective teachers’ knowledge, built on topics discussed in the methods course, and created a professional learning community. Three resources introduced in the methods course supported the creation of a hybrid space connecting academic and practitioner knowledge: shared language about teaching moves for using technology in math instruction, the mathematical proficiency framework, and a lesson plan template. The mentors drew upon their subject matter and pedagogical knowledge during their facilitation of lesson study. The intervention exemplifies a lesson study adaptation that is feasible in the context of a teacher education program.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09521-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interactional production of deficit talk in a professional development for mathematics teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, I examine deficit talk, utterances that depict students and/or families based on their perceived deficits, in an equity-oriented professional development (PD) setting. Researchers often attribute deficit talk by mathematics teachers (MTs) to their biased beliefs and perceptions. From an interactional approach, namely conversation analysis and discursive psychology, I offer an alternative perspective on how deficit talk is produced in PD interactions. The analysis shows the rhetorical functions of deficit talk, which are designed for MTs to manage their accountability with a range of potential issues and to portray themselves as competent teachers. The analysis also reveals the action-performing nature of deficit talk (e.g., refusing a request) situated in the social interaction. To conclude, this paper suggests that mathematics teacher educators need to attend to the micropolitical nature of deficit talk and their co-participation in the production of deficit talk as they formulate ways to respond to deficit talk in PD interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09519-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Self-efficacy, practices, and their relationships; the impact of a professional development program for mathematics teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics teaching in a 21st-century educational context requires a shift to active learning. The shift calls on teachers, and the plans countries need to prepare to make the changes through well-designed teacher professional development programs. ARPA (Spanish acronym for &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Activating Problem Solving in Classrooms&lt;/em&gt;), as a professional development program, with an emphasis on collaborative problem solving, provides opportunities and tools for teachers to enrich their classroom activities in a student-centered manner. This study of 149 in-service teachers evaluates the impact of an ARPA workshop on teachers’ self-efficacy and their tendency to choose student-centered practices. The results show that before participating in the program, even if teachers had believed in their ability to solve problems, they did not consider how to connect this ability with the active student-centered problem-solving practices in their classroom. However, teachers’ self-efficacy in performing problem solving significantly affects the teachers’ report of their student-centered practices after participating in the program. Understanding the relationship between teacher confidence and the quality of their classroom activities is essential for the optimization of the outcomes of any teacher’s professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09523-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Processes of decision-making by mathematics PD facilitators: the role of resources, orientations, goals, and identities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Facilitators of professional development (PD) for mathematics teachers currently gain increasing attention, as their practices are crucial for the success of spreading mathematics educational ideas and innovations into schools and strengthening the professional expertise of teachers. So far, mainly two components of facilitation have been empirically researched: facilitators’ knowledge resources and facilitation moves. In this paper, we propose to develop a more comprehensive conceptual framework in order to explain facilitators’ practices and underlying decisions. For this purpose, we lift Schoenfeld’s ROG framework for teachers&#39; decision-making (comprising resources, orientations, and goals) to the facilitator level, and add identity as a fourth component to obtain what we call the ROGI framework. We draw on data collected simultaneously in two PD projects for mathematics teachers in Germany and in Israel. Through three cases of facilitation, we illustrate how the adapted ROGI framework helps to understand processes of decision-making made by facilitators during mathematics professional development sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09518-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Life was brought back into my body”: a critical race feminista analysis of racial microaffirmations</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-21-2023 03:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2165514?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advancing “Intersectional Servingness” in Research, Practice, and Policy With Hispanic-Serving Institutions</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;There has been a surge in the number of Hispanic-serving institutions (HSIs), which are degree-granting, nonprofit, postsecondary institutions that enroll at least 25% Hispanic/Latinx/e undergraduate students. Although HSI scholarship has increased dramatically since around 2010, there is still a gap in knowledge about individuals who fall within the “H” and the diversity among HSIs themselves. Using critical theory and critical methods, the articles in this special topic collection explore the complexities of the Hispanic/Latinx/e identity and the various ways that HSIs fall short of and meet the challenges of serving students at the intersections of identity. This introduction provides a brief overview of the eight articles in this collection and explains the need for this critical approach to HSI scholarship, which we call “intersectional servingness.” We outline the contributions of these eight articles and call on practitioners, scholars, policy intermediaries, funders, and federal agencies to consider the complexities of the “H” while making decisions, advancing research, implementing policies, and creating funding streams that will enhance intersectional servingness.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-20-2023 10:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221148421?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Schools Do Families Want (and Why)? Evidence on Revealed Preferences From New Orleans</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Prior research suggests that families prefer schools with higher test scores, shorter distances from home, and certain student demographics. We build on this using data from New Orleans, a context well suited to identification of parent preferences because of its deferred acceptance algorithm and extensive, standardized, and broadly accessible school information. This allows us to study revealed preferences for a richer set of characteristics. We find that families prefer schools with higher school value-added, more extracurricular activities, and after-school childcare. We also find heterogeneity by family income that is more consistent with income constraints than preference heterogeneity. Finally, we show how methodology and data shape the results.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-20-2023 09:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221134528?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking the Relationship Between Classroom Teacher Characteristics and Time to English Learner Reclassification</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Reclassification is a crucial outcome for English learner (EL) students’ academic progress. Though ELs spend a large portion of their academic time with general education teachers, we know little about the role general education teachers play in developing ELs’ English language proficiency. Drawing from a longitudinal administrative dataset from Tennessee, this study uses discrete-time survival analysis to estimate the relationship between ELs’ likelihood of reclassification and characteristics of their general education English language arts (ELA) teachers in Grades 3–8. The study finds that several measures of teacher effectiveness consistently predict EL reclassification. Sensitivity and robustness checks substantiate these relationships. Findings have important policy implications for the identification and assignment of ELs to effective general education ELA teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-20-2023 09:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221144755?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What should teacher education be about? Initial comparisons from Scotland and Alberta</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-20-2023 06:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2023.2166918?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Relationship Between Varying Levels of Online Enrollment and Degree Completion</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examines the influence of varying levels of online enrollment on community college students’ likelihood of degree completion, with a particular focus on completion outcomes among traditionally underserved subgroups of students. Using institutional transcript data from a high-enrollment community college and a propensity score weighting approach, I find that lower levels of online enrollment have a positive relationship with the likelihood of degree completion for Black, Hispanic, and low-income community college students, but enrolling in all online courses has a negative influence on the likelihood of degree completion across subgroups of community college students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-20-2023 03:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221147522?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Multidimensionality as a feature of the research in mathematics teacher education: different targets to be noticed and different lenses to describe and explain</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2023 23:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09568-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing rural Chinese children’s computational thinking through ­game-based learning and parental involvement</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2023 12:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2023.2167798?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Boys’ motivation profiles in mathematics: relations with contextual factors, wellbeing and engagement in a boys-only school</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study examined the extent to which boys fell into clusters comprised of different levels of motivations and costs. In turn, the antecedents of these clusters and associations with engagement and wellbeing outcomes were considered. Based on survey responses from 168 students across Years 5, 7 and 9 from an all-boys&#39; school in Sydney, Australia, three clusters were identified: &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Positively Engaged, Disengaged&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Struggling Ambitious&lt;/em&gt;. Performance-approach and avoidance achievement goals, mastery classroom goal structure, perceived peer valuing of mathematics and teacher enthusiasm differentially predicted profile membership. Clusters were also found to differ in terms of both wellbeing and engagement, such that students within maladaptive profiles evidenced the most negative outcomes. The study reaffirms prior work, holds implications for addressing student motivation in mathematics, and adds to understanding of the interplay of individual and classroom goal structures in relation to students’ mathematics expectancies, values and resultant outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-19-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01464-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emotions and motivation in mathematics education: Where we are today and where we need to go</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Emotions and motivation are important for learning and achievement in mathematics. In this paper, we present an overview of research on students’ emotions and motivation in mathematics. First, we briefly review how early research has developed into the current state-of-the-art and outline the following key characteristics of emotions and motivation: objects, valence, temporal stability (vs. variability), and situational specificity (vs. generality). Second, we summarize major theories in the field (the control-value theory of achievement emotions, expectancy-value theory of achievement-related motivation, self-determination theory of human motivation, and social-cognitive theory of self-efficacy). Third, we present an overview of instructional characteristics that have been shown to foster emotions and motivation. Fourth, we provide an overview of the contributions to the special issue on “Emotions and Motivation in Mathematics Education and Educational Psychology.” Finally, we suggest directions for future research in the field with respect to advancing theory, improving measurement, and considering diversity and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-18-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01463-2</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
