<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Counter-Deficit Lens in Educational Research: Interrogating Conceptions of Structural Oppression</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Deficit framings of marginalized students, though maintaining widespread social influence, are thoroughly condemned in recent educational scholarship. The goal of this “counter-deficit” scholarship is to challenge racism in schools and improve opportunities for marginalized youth. To meet the lofty ambition of racial equity in education, how scholarship understands racial oppression is a central concern. Sociologists of race have emphasized the duality of racial oppression. Racism is ideological and structural. Ideologically, racism shapes how communities of color are perceived and how they are treated in educational settings. Structurally, racism is embedded in histories and policies that systematically disadvantage racially minoritized people. Both processes matter to educational inequality. However, in this review of counter-deficit literature, we find that racism is primarily understood by way of ideology and seldom by way of structures. This framing has important implications for how schools can support racially minoritized students to overcome racism in schools and communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 12:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221125225?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Dynamic Financial Implications of the Community College Baccalaureate: An Institutional Exploration</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Using generalized difference-in-difference and synthetic control modeling, this study estimates the influence of the community-college baccalaureate (CCB) on institutional finance over time and by intensity. Leveraging data spanning 19 years (1999–2017), I find no impact on overall revenue but suggestive evidence of upfront costs and slight increases in total spending post-adoption. Coupled with increased enrollment, per-full-time-equivalent (FTE) revenue and spending decrease, on average, by approximately 12% and 6%, respectively. Adoption of an additional CCB is associated with a 3% decrease in revenue and a suggestive 2% reduction in spending per FTE. Additional robustness checks suggest that these impacts may vary by state. These results suggest that institutions should consider the trade-offs in broadening access to baccalaureate-level education with the associated strain on resources. Policymakers should consider how best to financially support adoptive institutions as they work to meet student and workforce needs. Implications for policy, practice, and research are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 12:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126473?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to do action research for transformations at a time of eco-social crisis, by Hilary S. Bradbury. Elgar, 2022. Four characters in search of a book review</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;What are the crucial ingredients missing in our search for transformative – structural, cultural, political-economic – changes to entrenched systems of oppression right now? Why do so many smart, informed, data-driven efforts fail? This book says what’s missing is ART: Action Research for Transformation, a contemporary expression of action research. The book offers surprising, counter-intuitive, and most importantly, experienced-based insights on both what ART is, and how to do it. It reveals pathways to disrupt the academic détentes regarding quantitative versus quantitative, objective versus subjective, macro versus micro, and asks what is knowledge and what is it for. The book offers practical approaches, tools, and case studies, while featuring personal narratives from a wide range of active ARTists about their successes, challenges, doubts, and perhaps most importantly, the joy and value they experience performing ART. Its preponderant thesis is this: the problems of eco-social crisis aren’t “out there” so much as within, between and among each one of us, and the types of relationships we create with others. The book is therefore of value to educators and change leaders perhaps especially within our universities’ professional schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221133781?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Frequentist Approach of Probability, from Random Experiment to Sampling Fluctuation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article deals with an introduction of probability at school through sensory modalities. This approach is based on sampling fluctuation with empirical observations of frequencies. Initially, we analyze how students from high school work on such a task by using dice, pencil, and paper. We then identify the use of schemas and data visualization by students. Considering schemas as a primitive form of algorithmic approaches, we observe interaction with mathematics. In class, students know how to use notion of frequency, but linking frequencies with probability appears to be a difficult issue. This absence of a statistical link leads us to identify entry points for probability teaching. We then decide to analyze primary school students when they have to explore a random experiment by using statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00230-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Embodied mathematical pedagogy to liberate racialized and multilingual bodies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When language is defined narrowly in mathematics classrooms, racially and linguistically minoritized students in classrooms could be systematically positioned as “learners of deficiency.” Recent scholarship calls for expanding the notion of language to emphasize embodied expression of mathematical ideas. Taking a critical perspective to understand racialized experiences of using languages in disciplinary learning spaces, this article proposes the reconceptualization of embodiment as a language for racialized multilingual learners. This study was conducted in a Grade 1 classroom in a linguistically and racially diverse school in Canada. Through a series of professional development sessions, we worked with an experienced teacher to redesign the normalized and institutionalized pedagogy toward greater mobility of racialized multilingual learners’ bodies, which was intertwined with their intellectual liberation. Focusing on the spatiality of pedagogy, the previously restrictive areas in the school were transformed into a place that augments embodied expression of mathematical ideas and agentive participation of minoritized learners. The analysis focused on the embodied discourse that participating racialized multilingual students used to actively engage in mathematical discussion. Our findings show that the designed pedagogy, characterized by the spatial and temporal expansion of the learning environment, offered more spaces for uncertainty and spontaneity with the decreased control of the teacher as an explicator. Our article furthers anti-colonial approaches to understand the intersection of racialized bodies and language in mathematics education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10185-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Lesson study beyond its initial adaptation: a case without external support</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Since 2016, Park School in Denmark has consistently used Japanese lesson study as an approach to the professional development of its mathematics teachers. The school has moved beyond the initial adaptation of lesson study, and no longer includes external support. In this article, I investigate how three groups of teachers participated in the maturing lesson-study phases, especially the reflection phase. I apply social practice theory, particularly the concepts of figured worlds and improvisation, to examine the groups’ improvisation of artefacts and actions during lesson study, and the mature, valued outcomes. This study explains how and why the mature lesson-study efforts at Park School offer predominantly superficial learning opportunities to students and teachers alike. It concludes that in countries unaccustomed to lesson study, external support (or other external knowledge sources) is also important at the mature stages of its adaptation. This study proposes three activities that offer such support. 
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09556-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>STEM teacher education programs for preservice and in-service secondary mathematics teachers: a review study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Few studies have elaborated on how different types of integration can support teachers’ learning and build their capacity to teach for the enhancement of students’ STEM competence. Teaching in a STEM education context requires mathematics teachers to be able to effectively choose, design and implement appropriate tasks in their classes. Given the important role of teachers and tasks as vehicles for STEM education, this paper reviews literature on STEM teacher education programs associated with STEM tasks for preservice and in-service secondary mathematics teachers. After searching for and reviewing the 14 relevant articles, the analytical results indicated that (a) teachers’ STEM knowledge and practices have not been commonly assessed as the outcomes of STEM teacher education programs, although they are explicitly counted as the goals of STEM teacher education programs; (b) the approach of multi-disciplinary concepts integrated with uni-disciplinary practice is mostly adopted as the approach to STEM integration; (c) task design features identified from the articles can be classified by elements of task design (i.e., goals, principles and instructional focus) and task design factors (i.e., disciplinary knowledge, cognition and metacognition, affect); and (d) most programs provide both acquisition and participation approaches to developing mathematics teachers’ knowledge in STEM education. The review results shed light on the design and implementation of STEM tasks and STEM teacher education programs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09557-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Early Birds in Elementary School? School Start Times and Outcomes for Younger Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;While research supports later start times for secondary schools, there is little evidence regarding start times for elementary schools. We address this gap with a statewide examination of elementary schools and a quasi-experimental analysis of an urban district that recently changed its elementary start times. We find that earlier start times predict less sleep for students. Regarding academic outcomes, our estimates are small in magnitude and suggest that earlier elementary start times have near-zero effects. Earlier start times predict a slight increase in absences and modestly higher math scores, especially for traditionally disadvantaged students. In districts that need to stagger start times, it may be advisable for elementary schools to start earlier to accommodate later secondary school start times.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-12-2022 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221121799?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Undergraduate Students Think about Summation (Sigma) Notation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reports on a two-part investigation into how students think about and use summation (sigma) notation. During an instructional design experiment, two participating students struggled with this notation, but also reasoned about it in creative ways. This motivated a follow-up study in which we administered a free-response three-item survey to 285 students enrolled in a variety of undergraduate mathematics courses. Our findings suggest that it is not uncommon for students to produce incorrect responses when encoding and decoding sums using summation notation. More significantly, our findings reveal that students are capable of reasoning about this notation in a variety of viable, but unconventional, ways. We argue that these findings have implications for the teaching and learning of both summation notation specifically and mathematical conventions more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-12-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00193-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Behold the Role of the District in Education Finance</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/hpje20/97/4&quot;&gt;Volume 97, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, September-October 2022&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 08:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2125752?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promoting socio-emotional learning competencies in teacher education through online clinical simulations</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2134006?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Narrating Stories about Research Units in Israeli Teacher Education Colleges</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 03:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2133697?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting teacher agency during a collaborative inquiry-based in-service teacher education course</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 03:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2132385?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Primary English teacher education in Portugal: an exploratory study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 03:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2132384?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/44/4&quot;&gt;Volume 44, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Winter 2022, Page 269-270&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 02:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2022.2127303?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fiscal Federalism and K–12 Education Funding: Policy Lessons from Two Educational Crises</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We synthesize and critique federal fiscal policy during the Great Recession and COVID-19 pandemic. First, the amount of aid during both crises was inadequate to meet policy goals. Second, the mechanisms used to distribute funds were disconnected from policy goals and provided different levels of aid to districts with equivalent levels of economic disadvantage. Third, data tools are missing, making it difficult to understand whether funds were used to meet policy goals. Details for these results are provided along with policy recommendations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-10-2022 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221125764?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Applying Lessons From “The Evolving Art of Program Evaluation” in the Next Generation of Evaluations—Comments and Author Responses</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-10-2022 04:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221125299?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preference Compromise and Parent Satisfaction With Schools in Choice Markets: Evidence From Kansas City, Missouri</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Parents desire several features when choosing a school, but they often compromise on some preferences in favor of others. We develop a novel measure of aggregate preference compromise by examining the discrepancy between ideal preferences and those specified under real-world constraints. Relying on data from a representative sample in Kansas City, MO, we find that low-income and less educated parents and those from historically marginalized racial/ethnic backgrounds make a greater degree of preference compromise than other parents do. This is associated with lower satisfaction with chosen schools, suggesting that compromises matter. Less privileged families are also geographically more restricted in making school choices and have more limited access to better performing schools, which can aggravate preference compromises. Implications are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-10-2022 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221121812?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical modelling of exponential growth as a rich learning environment for mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical concepts are regularly used in media reports concerning the Covid-19 pandemic. These include growth models, which attempt to explain or predict the effectiveness of interventions and developments, as well as the reproductive factor. Our contribution has the aim of showing that basic mental models about exponential growth are important for understanding media reports of Covid-19. Furthermore, we highlight how the coronavirus pandemic can be used as a context in mathematics classrooms to help students understand that they can and should question media reports on their own, using their mathematical knowledge. Therefore, we first present the role of mathematical modelling in achieving these goals in general. The same relevance applies to the necessary basic mental models of exponential growth. Following this description, based on three topics, namely, investigating the type of growth, questioning given course models, and determining exponential factors at different times, we show how the presented theoretical aspects manifest themselves in teaching examples when students are given the task of reflecting critically on existing media reports. Finally, the value of the three topics regarding the intended goals is discussed and conclusions concerning the possibilities and limits of their use in schools are drawn.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-10-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01433-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tony Brown, A contemporary theory of mathematics education research review</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-09-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09555-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning-Mode Choice, Student Engagement, and Achievement Growth During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic resulted in an unanticipated, near-universal shift from in-person to virtual instruction in the spring of 2020. During the 2020–21 school year, schools began to reopen, and families were faced with decisions regarding the instructional mode for their children. We leverage administrative, survey, and virtual-learning data to examine the determinants of family learning-mode choice and associations between virtual education, student engagement, and academic achievement. Family preference for virtual (versus face-to-face) instruction was highly associated with subsequent school-level infection rates and appeared relatively uniform within schools. We find that students assigned to a higher proportion of instructional days in virtual mode experienced higher rates of attendance but negative achievement growth compared to students who were assigned a higher proportion of instructional days in face-to-face mode. Insights from this study can be used to better understand family preferences as well as to target and refine virtual learning in a post-COVID-19 society.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-08-2022 05:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221128035?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We just do us”: How Black teachers co-construct Black teacher fugitive space in the face of antiblackness</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-07-2022 07:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2122424?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching–Learning Contemporary Physics: from Research to Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As part of Springer, the edited book addresses innovative approaches and pedagogical strategies, the development of effective methods for assessing, and the innovative project in teaching and learning contemporary physics. This volume includes successful experimental and theoretical studies of QM teaching, which the experts or teachers can then adopt or modify the concept into practice in context. The 19 chapters, representing results of original study works dealing with Physics Education, are selected from the contributions in a conference on the teaching and learning of quantum physics. The goal of the book is to introduce contemporary physics to all level schools. Without a doubt, the book is recommended for high school teachers, instructional developers, and scientists to explore and develop the theories, approaches, and strategies in the book to advance teaching/learning of CP.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-07-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00233-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Panel unit-root tests with structural breaks</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/3&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 664-678, September 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce a new community-contributed command called xtbunitroot, which implements the panel-data unit-root tests developed by Karavias and Tzavalis (2014, Computational Statistics and Data Analysis 76: 391–407). These tests allow for one or two structural breaks in deterministic components of the series and can be seen as panel-data counterparts of the tests by Zivot and Andrews (1992, Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 10: 251–270) and Lumsdaine and Papell (1997, Review of Economics and Statistics 79: 212–218). The dates of the breaks can be known or unknown. The tests allow for intercepts and linear trends, nonnormal errors, and cross-section heteroskedasticity and dependence. They have power against homogeneous and heterogeneous alternatives and can be applied to panels with small or large time-series dimensions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-06-2022 12:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221124541?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
