<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Uneven Progress: Recent Trends in Academic Performance Among U.S. School Districts</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We use data from the Stanford Education Data Archive to describe district-level trends in average academic achievement between 2009 and 2019. Although on average school districts’ test scores improved very modestly (by about 0.001 standard deviations per year), there is significant variation among districts. Moreover, we find that average test score disparities between nonpoor and poor students and between White and Black students are growing; those between White and Hispanic students are shrinking. We find no evidence of achievement-equity synergies or trade-offs: Improvements in overall achievement are uncorrelated with trends in achievement disparities. Finally, we find that the strongest predictors of achievement disparity trends are the levels and trends in within-district racial and socioeconomic segregation and changes in differential access to certified teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2023 11:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221134769?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Underrepresented Minority Students in College: The Role of Classmates</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The role of racial diversity at colleges has been debated for over more than a half a century with limited quasi-experimental evidence from classrooms. To fill this void, I estimate the extent that classmate racial compositions affect Hispanic and African American students at a large and oversubscribed California community college where they are minorities. I find that when minority students are exposed to a greater share of same-race classmates, they are more likely to complete the class with a pass and are more likely to enroll in a same-subject course the subsequent term. The findings are robust to first-time students with the lowest registration priority versus all students and different combinations of fixed effects (e.g., student, class, and instructor race).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221143133?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Discourses of risk and hope in research on mathematical learning difficulties</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics-specific learning difficulties and disabilities (MLD) have received increasing attention in scholarly research. In this study, we place MLD research in its wider context of risk societies by discussing the manufacturing of MLD as &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;a risk&lt;/em&gt;. This framing of MLD builds on a certain idea of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; in how research could provide the means to better understand and support learners with MLD. We conduct a Foucault-informed analysis to understand how scholarly knowledge about MLD has been produced through discourses of risk and hope. Our material consists of 30 influential journal articles published in the three fields of MLD research: cognitive sciences, special education and mathematics education. Our study indicates that MLD has been predominantly conceptualised through a technico-scientific risk discourse that frames MLD as harmful for learners and societies alike; such risk discourse relies on a discourse of hope in scientific methods. We also analyse a social risk discourse that identifies risks in social exclusion and marginalisation of students with MLD, finding hope in inclusive learning environments. Based on our analysis, we propose that the mere conceptualisation of MLD has thoroughly revolved around discourses of current liminalities (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;risk&lt;/em&gt;) and enunciations of better futures (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt;). However, what has been unexplored is the politics of such risk and hope discourses themselves. We propose a socio-politically oriented discourse of risk/hope as a way to reframe scientific knowledge production about MLD. This discourse identifies risks not in MLD itself but in how research manufactures MLD as a threat to both economic growth and student identities. Instead of asking research communities to mitigate the risk of MLD, we call for them to embrace it.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-16-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10204-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analysing the Mathematical Discourse of Biology Assignments: The Case of a Graduate Fisheries Management Course</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this article, an analysis of six fisheries biology assignments involving mathematical models is conducted, focusing on the type of participation that they offer. The purpose of the analysis is to identify the characteristics of the mathematical discourse of the assignments and to expose their relationship with the biological context with the purpose of understanding the role of mathematics discourse in other academic discourses. The theoretical orientation of the study is informed by commognitive theory which views learning of an academic discourse as the process of becoming a participant in that discourse. Data analysis revealed various aspects of mathematics wordings, tools and routines essential in the expected solution trajectories of the assignments and two types of required transitions, intrinsic and extrinsic, between mathematics and biology narratives. The article offers analytical and theoretical explanations for why this is the case as well as directions for future research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-14-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00205-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School library research: Guest editors’ introduction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2023 07:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2160111?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Secondary school mathematics teacher-perceived factors involved in argumentation: an emerging framework</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2023 03:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2156585?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Translating units coordination to units of length and area: a case study of undergraduate interior design students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2023 03:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2160801?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Will we ever teach mathematics again in the way we used to before the pandemic?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;After about two years of emergency remote teaching during the pandemic, the teaching of mathematics is slowly returning to (what used to be called) &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;normal&lt;/em&gt;. However, after the period of mostly teaching online, there is uncertainty about the extent to which we will return to the way we were teaching before. In this survey paper we attempt to give some background to the impact that emergency remote teaching may have had on teaching mathematics. We examine the possible social implications and then focus on the changing mathematics classroom, focusing on the actual mathematics curriculum, learning design and assessment, the role of collaborative activities and social media, educational videos, and the role of family and parents in future. There are indicators from the literature that educators may not return to the traditional way of teaching entirely, especially in secondary and higher education. We conclude with describing some possible new research areas that have developed through emergency remote teaching, including online education for younger learners, local learning ecosystems, the role of family and parents, instructional design, and the mathematics content of curricula.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01460-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning Integrals Based on Adding Up Pieces Across a Unit on Integration</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;
      Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Recent research on integration has shown the importance of quantities-based meanings for integrals. However, this research body is still in need of detailed empirical accounts of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; students develop such understandings across an entire unit on integration. This paper contributes by providing one such account, based on a quantities-based orientation called &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;adding up pieces&lt;/em&gt; (AUP). Our study examines how three separate pairs of students learned definite integrals and integral functions within interview settings over four consecutive interview-lessons, meant to correspond to four consecutive in-class sessions. The first interview developed the partition, target quantity, and sum structure for definite integral, which were solidified in the second interview. The third and fourth interviews extended this AUP structure to a variable upper bound, output, and function structure for integral functions in preparation for the Fundamental Theorem of Calculus (FTC).&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00204-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reflections and Gratitude Completing the Year 2022</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-13-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00258-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Postsecondary Policy Environments in Citizen Legislatures</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Legislative professionalism is central to the politico-institutional context of postsecondary policy adoption in state governments. The core argument in existing research is that as legislative professionalism increases, structural capacity for decision-making increases. Evidence for this argument is mixed, exclusively quantitative, and assumes a bureaucratic logic. The goal of this study is to deepen understanding of legislative professionalism by examining how policy stakeholders perceive the postsecondary policy environment in a “citizen legislature.” The study draws on 26 in-depth interviews with higher education stakeholders in Nevada. The findings contribute empirically to the literature by demonstrating that legislative professionalism can be understood in terms of the meanings assigned distinctive legislative environments. The results also make a conceptual contribution to this literature by showing how loose coupling in interorganizational relations and bounded rationality shape the policy environment—in ways that yield benefits for some institutions and disadvantages for others.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2023 10:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221142050?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Dynamic Nexus Between International Tourism and Environmental Degradation in Top Twenty Tourist Destinations: New Insights From Quantile-on-Quantile Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Tourism is one of the important factors that can affect the environmental and economic situation of any economy. This study investigates the relationship between tourist arrivals and CO2 emission in the top 20 tourist destinations using data from quarterly observations from 1995 to 2018. A unique technique via quantile-on-quantile regression and Granger causality in quantiles was used. In particular, how the quantiles of tourist arrivals impact quantiles of CO2 emission was analyzed. The empirical results suggest a combination of both positive and negative effects of tourist arrivals and CO2 emission in most tourist destinations. Predominantly, at both high and low tails, in the USA, Spain, Hong Kong, and Austria, tourist arrival has a positive effect on CO2 emission, whereas in the case of Canada, France, Germany, Mexico, and Malaysia, the association was negative. On the other hand, China, Greece, Russia, Japan, Italy, South Korea, Thailand, and Turkey have both positive and negative effects of tourism on CO2 emissions at low and high tails. Tourism can be an important factor while formulating policy for environmental and climate aspects.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2023 07:37</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221149809?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Clinical (In)Efficiency in the Prediction of Dangerous Behavior</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The prediction of dangerous and/or violent behavior is particularly important to the conduct of the U.S. criminal justice system when it makes decisions about restrictions of personal freedom, such as preventive detention, forensic commitment, parole, and in some states such as Texas, when to permit an execution to proceed of an individual found guilty of a capital crime. This article discusses the prediction of dangerous behavior both through clinical judgment and actuarial assessment. The general conclusion drawn is that for both clinical and actuarial prediction of dangerous behavior, we are far from a level of accuracy that could justify routine use. To support this later negative assessment, two topic areas are emphasized: (1) the MacArthur Study of Mental Disorder and Violence, including the actuarial instrument developed as part of this project (the Classification of Violence Risk), along with all the data collected that helped develop the instrument; and (2) the U.S. Supreme Court case of Barefoot v. Estelle (1983) and the American Psychiatric Association “friend of the court” brief on the (in)accuracy of clinical prediction for the commission of future violence. Although now three decades old, Barefoot v. Estelle is still the controlling Supreme Court opinion regarding the prediction of future dangerous behavior and the imposition of the death penalty in states, such as Texas; for example, see Coble v. Texas (2011) and the Supreme Court denial of certiorari in that case.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2023 06:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221144727?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editor’s Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/45/1&quot;&gt;Volume 45, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Spring 2023, Page 1-2&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2023 02:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2022.2161245?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Validating psychometric classification of teachers’ fraction arithmetic reasoning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In prior work, we fit the mixture Rasch model to item responses from a fractions survey administered to a nationwide sample of middle grades mathematics teachers in the United States. The mixture Rasch model located teachers on a continuous, unidimensional scale and fit best with 3 latent classes. We used item response data to generate initial interpretations of the reasoning characteristic of each latent class. Our results suggested increasing facility reasoning about fraction arithmetic from one class to the next. The present study contributes two further arguments for the validity of our initial interpretations. First, we administered the same survey to a new sample of future middle grades mathematics teachers before and after 20 weeks of instruction on multiplication, division, and fractions, and we found that from pretest to posttest future teachers transitioned from one latent class to another in ways consistent with increased proficiency in fraction arithmetic. Second, we interviewed 8 of the future teachers before and after the instruction and found that future teachers’ reasoning during interviews was largely consistent with our original interpretation of the 3 latent classes. These results provide further support for our original interpretation of the mixture Rasch analysis, demonstrate the utility of our approach for capturing growth and change in future teachers’ reasoning during teacher education coursework, and contribute innovative applications of psychometric models for surveying teachers’ reasoning at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09564-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating University Students’ Argumentations and Proofs Using Dynamic Mathematics Software in Collaborative Learning, Debate, and Self-reflection Stages</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The purpose of this study is to examine the performances of university students’ using dynamic mathematics software GeoGebra in argumentations and proving processes. A task related to the limit involving &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;sin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(x\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt;/&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; was designed and 18 university students worked on the task during the collaborative learning, scientific debate, and self-reflection stages. Students’ argumentations and proofs were analyzed based on Toulmin’s model and Habermas’ construct of rationality. The results revealed that the rationality components can be used to explain the implicit features of warrant in Toulmin’s model. It was found that the semiotic mediation opportunities offered by GeoGebra and the teamwork and debate stages in the teaching method enabled the students to create geometrically the ranking relation between the value of an angle and the sine and tangent values of this angle. They also facilitated using the various kinds of representation and enhanced the transformations within and/or between the representations. GeoGebra tools as instruments of semiotic mediation helped the students to construct productive arguments, validate them, be productive by providing backing and rebuttal to the collective arguments put forward during the teamwork stage, and reach consensus thanks to scientific debate.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-12-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00207-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using critical reflections in action research to enhance students’ interactivity in online EFL learning contexts</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2023 08:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2165522?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Enhancing teaching and learning through the co-creative learning community approach</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-11-2023 08:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2023.2166090?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Misrepresented Funding Gaps in Data for Some States</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This brief describes how several commonly used per-pupil funding measures derived from federal data include passthrough funding in the numerator but exclude students attached to this funding from the denominator, artificially inflating per-pupil ratios. Three forms of passthrough funding for students not educated by the school district where they reside are included in district-level funding totals: payments to private schools (V91), payments to charter schools (V92), and payments to other school systems (Q11). We illustrate this error in Pennsylvania and New Jersey and use data from all 46 impacted states to show how racial and economic funding gaps are understated as a result.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2023 12:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221133396?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educators Are Not Alright: Mental Health During COVID-19</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Educator mental health sits at the intersection of multiple pressing educational issues. We are among the first to provide estimates of school system employee (SSE) stress, anxiety, and depression during the COVID-19 pandemic. Most participants reported clinically meaningful anxiety and depressive symptoms (77.96% and 53.65%, respectively). Being in the lowest strata of family income was associated with higher stress, a greater likelihood of clinically significant depressive symptoms, and reduced intentions to continue in the same job, portending the current staffing shortages affecting schools. Supporting SSE mental health should become a policy priority.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2023 08:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221142595?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Aftermath of Disproportionality Citations: Situating Disability-Race Intersections in Historical, Spatial, and Sociocultural Contexts</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We used a situated approach to examine the aftermath of citations for racial disparities in special education and discipline. The study was conducted in one suburban school district and examined staff’s interpretations and responses to multiple disproportionality citations. We found that historical, spatial, and sociocultural contexts mediated stakeholders’ interpretations and reactions to citations and the consequences of their responses. Our findings demonstrate how a history of race relations in the district and the community as well as spatial opportunity structures shaped disability and discipline racial disparities; the consequences of a damaged imagery for multiply marginalized youth and their families in explanations of disproportionality citations; and the shortcomings of the district’s symbolic and predominately color-evasive responses as a consequence of ambiguous federal and state policy mandates.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2023 06:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221147007?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice Primary Teachers’ Perceptions of STEM-Based Teaching in Natural Sciences and Technology Classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The teaching of natural sciences and technology in primary schools presents an opportunity to use innovative approaches to teach STEM-based activities. The subject presents opportunities for learners to experience STEM-based instructional approaches in their early school years; therefore, it is essential that preservice primary school teachers are adequately prepared for the task. This study explored the perceptions of preservice teachers of STEM-based teaching in natural sciences and technology classrooms. Using a qualitative research approach and a single case study of a science and technology teaching methods course at a South African university, five participants were purposively selected from a group of 42 preservice teachers who had participated in a project to develop lesson plans and reflect on how to teach STEM. The data collected were analysed using thematic content analysis techniques. The findings indicate that the preservice teachers used natural sciences as an entry point to teach STEM and underestimated the technology component. The preservice teachers had the perception that STEM is taught through activity-based strategies while incorporating assessment for learning. Although they identified activities that could be used to teach STEM, they did not link the activities with developing specific skills in the lesson plans. The study recommends that preservice teachers be taught to link STEM activities with the development of specific STEM skills.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-10-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00252-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Randomization P-Value Test for Detecting Copying on Multiple-Choice Exams</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article is concerned with the statistical detection of copying on multiple-choice exams. As an alternative to existing permutation- and model-based copy-detection approaches, a simple randomization p-value (RP) test is proposed. The RP test, which is based on an intuitive match-score statistic, makes no assumptions about the distribution of examinees’ answer vectors and hence is broadly applicable. Especially important in this copy-detection setting, the RP test is shown to be exact in that its size is guaranteed to be no larger than a nominal α value. Additionally, simulation results suggest that the RP test is typically more powerful for copy detection than the existing approximate tests. The development of the RP test is based on the idea that the copy-detection problem can be recast as a causal inference and missing data problem. In particular, the observed data are viewed as a subset of a larger collection of potential values, or counterfactuals, and the null hypothesis of “no copying” is viewed as a “no causal effect” hypothesis and formally expressed in terms of constraints on potential variables.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-09-2023 09:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221143515?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“We Aren’t Only Here to Teach”: Caring Practices of Teachers in the Context of Inclusive Refugee Education in Jordan</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article examines the complex process of teachers’ care for students in contexts of inclusive refugee education in Jordan, where Syrian refugees and Jordanian students study together. I illustrate that while teachers’ caring practices represent efforts to support refugee students, they are limited by teachers’ inability to see the social, structural, and systemic power dynamics that restrict Syrian refugees, reifying unequal relations of power between refugees and nationals. National teachers are embedded in the social fabric of the societies in which they live and not impervious to the discriminatory attitudes towards refugees, thereby limiting the extent of their care. This article illuminates the complexity of inclusive refugee education and concludes with implications for teacher education and professional development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-09-2023 08:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221138267?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
