<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Images and indicators: mixing participatory methods to build inclusive rigour</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Participatory methods seek to counter the extractive nature of mainstream research methods by putting control into the hands of research subjects. But participation itself does not guarantee against extraction. There is a tension between the desire for researcher-control and the prerogative of community action in participatory methods. How can researchers committed to participation manage this tension? In this paper, we draw on the concepts of “collaborative” and “action-oriented” participatory research to describe how integrating mixed-methodologies can help different research stakeholders attain desirable, fruitful and meaningful levels of ownership and build inclusive rigour. Drawing on our work with participatory indicators and photovoice with conflict affected communities in rural Colombia, we demonstrate how combining different kinds of participatory research methods—in this case, non-visual and visual research—creates opportunities to attend to the sometimes conflicting goals of robust research, policy change and community action. Under the broad umbrella of participatory research, collaborative approaches like participatory indicators and action-oriented approaches like photovoice complement and amplify each other in such settings, embracing complexity and catalyzing multiple ways of ‘knowing-for-action’. The result is participatory research that is attuned to the complexities of conflict-affected settings, inclusively rigorous and potentially transformative.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-11-2022 02:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221137851?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Observed Classroom Practices Related to Student Language/Literacy Achievement?</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this study, we examined the relation of observed classroom practices to language and literacy achievement and the moderation of this relation for students from pre-K to sixth grade. A total of 136 studies (N = 107,882 participants) met the inclusion criteria, of which 108 studies were included for meta-analysis and the other 28 studies were narratively synthesized. The average zero-order (r = .12) and partial correlations (rp = .04) were statistically significant but weak in magnitude. The relation was slightly weaker in upper than in lower grade levels, and stronger for observations capturing macro quality and instructional dimension than those capturing micro measurement and emotional or structural dimension, respectively. The relation did not vary by observation duration, frequency, adopted statistical approach, or type of covariates. Taken together with the narrative synthesis, the results highlight the complex nature of classroom observation and a need for more classroom research, particularly on higher grade levels.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221130687?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptions and Practices of Equity in Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This framework explores the plurality of ways that research-practice partnerships (RPPs) conceptualize issues of equity, and with what consequences for what gets studied, whose voices are included in inquiry, and what knowledge is foregrounded in partnership activity. We draw on institutional theory and the perspectives of members from diverse partnerships to create a framework on the beliefs and practices of equity in RPPs. In terms of their missions, RPPs’ conceptions of equity ranged from a focus on individualism and standardization, to advancing goals of identity, culture, and belonging and attending to power, justice, and anti-racism. Equity was reflected within processes for working together, varying across coordination, collaboration, or transformation of roles and power dynamics. For RPPs, the framework can help develop a common language and shared meanings. For future research, it can serve as an analytic lens to understand when and how RPPs work in service of educational transformation and change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221131566?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Seeing the continuity behind “double discontinuity”: investigating Hong Kong prospective mathematics teachers’ secondary–tertiary transition</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Felix Klein’s notion of “double discontinuity” between university mathematics and secondary school mathematics has persisted in mathematics teacher education. Situating this study in Hong Kong, we investigated three prospective secondary teachers’ experiences in higher education and secondary mathematics classrooms, including their figured worlds, identities, and mathematical knowledge constructed through those experiences. Our analysis revealed their contrasting experiences in these two contexts, adding to our understanding of the phenomenon of “double discontinuity” in terms of not only how it is relevant to Hong Kong but also how it may manifest in the specific cultural context. Moreover, we found coherency and continuity during the prospective teachers’ secondary–tertiary transition; their learning experiences in both environments served as critical resources upon which they reflected to envision their future mathematics teaching. We conclude with implications and suggestions for mathematics teacher education to support prospective teachers’ (and their future students’) transitions between high school and university mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10197-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ Strategic Usage of Formative Quizzes in an Undergraduate Course in Abstract Algebra</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Besides homework assignments, optional quizzes are a commonly used means for formative assessment in tertiary mathematics education. Instructors, for example, implement these to help students detect gaps in their understanding, or to foster a continuous and active engagement with the content. The extent to which these goals are reached, however, strongly depends on how students actually use such quizzes, which is currently an underexplored topic. We investigated this issue in an undergraduate abstract algebra course with a study using a mixed-methods design. Unlike previous research suggesting that students use optional quizzes in tertiary mathematics courses mainly for rehearsal or for a final self-check of their own performance, our study indicates that students also use such quizzes in many other ways, for example for planning their further learning, or for deepening their understanding of the content of the course. Furthermore, our study shows differences regarding students’ quiz usage during the semester and when preparing for the final exam. Finally, the data propose factors that influence the way students use optional quizzes, for example time constraints due to other obligations during the semester, the perceived difficulty of the questions, or the opportunity to discuss these with peers. This leads to several suggestions regarding the implementation of optional quizzes into tertiary mathematics courses.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00194-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Mathematical Work of Chilean Secondary Teachers in the Domain of Probability</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The objective of this qualitative research is to study the mathematical work when solving a mathematical task in the domain of probability presented by Chilean high school mathematics teachers in pre-service and in-service training. We consider as theoretical support the Mathematical Working Space model and methodological design of a collective case study, comprising of five teachers in pre-service training and eight teachers in in-service training. This research design allows us to analyze mathematical objects under semiotic, instrumental, and discursive dimensions, identifying privileged vertical planes, the paradigm applied, and the different strategies used by teachers. The task presented to the participants allows two different correct answers depending on the interpretation of the random experiment in question. Since the definition of the random experiment involved in the task is of utmost importance, according to our results, this notion was not evident in all the productions analyzed, which issue poses a challenge for the teaching and learning of probability.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00235-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selecting Districts and Schools for Impact Studies in Education: A Simulation Study of Different Strategies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2022 08:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2128952?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Explaining the Racial School Climate Gap: Evidence From Georgia</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Research documents positive associations between school climate and student outcomes, and, as such, many policymakers have positioned it among their chief priorities for school improvement. Despite this increased focus, extant research has offered mixed findings on the presence and magnitude of racial school climate disparities. The present study uses administrative data of middle and high schools in Georgia to examine disparities in school-climate perceptions and factors predicting them. I find that Black and “Other” students consistently report worse perceptions on nearly all measures of school climate compared to White students and that these disparities persist within school. Furthermore, Black teachers moderate Black students’ climate perceptions and are critical protective factors against the risks they face in school. Implications suggest that an increased focus on school climate is unlikely to yield equitable returns absent ancillary policy and practices that improve schooling conditions influencing disparities in students’ school climate perceptions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2022 05:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221131529?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collegiate Mathematics Observation Protocols: Current Characteristics and Desired Foci</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Typically, departments and universities evaluate and/or provide feedback to college mathematics instructors on their teaching by conducting classroom observations. When these observations are guided by an observation protocol, the protocol provides a particular lens that focuses the observer’s attention on certain aspects of instruction. To understand the way in which mathematics departments are currently evaluating teaching and investigate whether they align with inquiry-based mathematics education practices, we evaluated 24 observation protocols from universities around the United States. Through our analysis we found that protocols mainly include closed-response items that are evaluative, focus more on the instructor than the students or the content, and rarely attend to inquiry-based mathematics education practices. These results suggest that where we aspire the field to go and where it is currently at requires significant and targeted work to achieve. Moreover, our findings provide suggestions and have implications for both those who develop observation protocols and those who use observation protocols as a measure of teaching practices. Our study highlights the need for careful explicit and clear purposes when observations are used for performance measures.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00199-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking the Power Dynamics of Funding Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this paper two foundation program officers describe their experiences as funders engaged in supporting research practice partnerships in two very distinct settings. The authors set the context for their experiences and walk through the challenges and opportunities in supporting research practice partnerships. They also discuss how supporting these efforts create power dynamics between the strategic initiatives at foundations and the need for researchers to have independence in crafting research agendas for research practice partnerships. The authors provide some lessons learned and prospect how future engagements with research practice partnerships can be set up for success.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134585?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whose Agenda is It? Navigating the Politics of Setting the Research Agenda in Education Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we provide insight into sharing power and balancing practitioner and researcher priorities during the process of establishing a research agenda for a research-practice partnership (RPP). We draw on the literature about effective collaboration within RPPs to identify concepts and factors that can help or hinder the research agenda-setting process. Concepts include boundary spanning, spheres of interest and action, and strategic knowledge leadership. Factors include early and ongoing engagement of partners, adequate representation of diverse perspectives, funder priorities, and the presence of trusting relationships. The authors then use examples from our own experiences in RPPs to illustrate how these concepts and factors play out in the agenda-setting process.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221131567?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Equity and Early Implementation of the Every Student Succeeds Act in State-Designed Plans During COVID</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) reverses a trend toward centralization of education policy and instead provides greater authority to the states. This study explores states’ interpretation and early implementation of ESSA’s equity-related provisions. Using a qualitative case study approach, we find wide variation in the design and implementation of equity-related provisions. We provide an overview of implementation efforts and highlight states that are making significant strides and those that are lagging behind. Our findings highlight the need to build capacity at the state and district levels and to better understand the role of state education agencies in implementing ESSA.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221130994?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>It’s Complicated: Examining Political Realities and Challenges in the Context of Research-Practice Partnerships From the School District Leader’s Perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Growing interest in the potential of education research-practice partnerships (RPPs) as a promising strategy for increasing the relevance and use of research has led the field to create an expanding body of literature documenting both the promise and the potential perils of RPPs. Insightful frameworks abound, outlining the structural and organizational considerations for forming and maintaining a successful RPP. Yet, less is known about how political realities within practice side organizations influence these partnerships. Drawing on Farrell et al.s’ framework describing RPPs as learning at the boundaries, I examine several examples of political challenges confronted by RPPs involving school districts and the degree to which school district leaders’ actions were able to mitigate the political challenges. Power imbalance exacerbated by funder priorities, the ripple effect of leadership change, and school board member priorities will be explored, along with discussions of implications.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221130352?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Breaking Our Silence on Factor Score Indeterminacy</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although many textbooks on multivariate statistics discuss the common factor analysis model, few of these books mention the problem of factor score indeterminacy (FSI). Thus, many students and contemporary researchers are unaware of an important fact. Namely, for any common factor model with known (or estimated) model parameters, infinite sets of factor scores can be constructed to fit the model. Because all sets are mathematically exchangeable, factor scores are indeterminate. Our professional silence on this topic is difficult to explain given that FSI was first noted almost 100 years ago by E. B. Wilson, the 24th president (1929) of the American Statistical Association. To help disseminate Wilson’s insights, we demonstrate the underlying mathematics of FSI using the language of finite-dimensional vector spaces and well-known ideas of regression theory. We then illustrate the numerical implications of FSI by describing new and easily implemented methods for transforming factor scores into alternative sets of factor scores. An online supplement (and the fungible R library) includes R functions for illustrating FSI.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221128810?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Mixed-Methods Exploration of Mastery Goal Support in 7th-Grade Science Classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 07:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2022.2140807?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ practices of integrating challenging demands of inclusive mathematics education in a professional development program</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When implementing educational innovations, teachers’ approaches to integrating new teaching demands are a crucial factor in their professional development. This becomes especially important in inclusive mathematics education, where teachers are demanded to integrate two jobs: (a) create joint learning experiences for all students and (b) provide focused learning opportunities for individuals. These jobs and the orientations in which they are pursued are perceived as conflicting demands by some teachers, while others do not. Within the model of content-related teacher expertise, this qualitative study investigates teachers’ practices for integrating these demands by disentangling the interplay between teachers’ self-reported practices and their underlying orientations about inclusive education. The analysis reveals that only some teachers explicate conflicts between inclusive teaching demands. It also shows that teachers command a variety of different practices for dealing with the new teaching demands and that some complex practices can indeed integrate different demands simultaneously. Implications include the insight that professional development programs on inclusive education should pay careful attention to teachers’ articulated jobs and orientations in order to promote the integration of teaching demands. Beyond this specific professional development content, the search for practices for integrating demands arising from an interplay of jobs and orientations might be a promising professional development research approach for increasing the scope of professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-06-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09560-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/rera/92/6&quot;&gt;Volume 92, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1041-1050, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-05-2022 12:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221137330?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of teacher identity in teacher self-efficacy development: the case of Katie</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article illustrates the role of teacher identity in teacher self-efficacy development during initial teacher education. It has been posited that teacher self-efficacy develops on the basis of information accessed through four self-efficacy sources: vicarious and enactive experiences, social persuasion, and physiological and affective states, and by interacting with a myriad of personal and external factors. The very process of teacher self-efficacy development, however, is not well understood. This phenomenological longitudinal qualitative case study contributes to addressing this issue by illustrating how a pre-service secondary mathematics teacher’s teacher self-efficacy is affected by the way she sees herself. More specifically, the study illustrates how aspects of a strong student teacher identity negatively affect the pre-service teacher’s teacher self-efficacy appraisal, and how her teacher identity, emerging through the processes of autonomous role enactment and social verification, supports teacher self-efficacy development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2022 22:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09515-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice mathematics teachers’ conceptions of mathematically rich and contextually realistic problems</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigated the middle school preservice mathematics teachers’ conceptualization of what it means for a problem to be mathematically rich and contextually realistic and how their conceptions evolved during a series of professional development activities. Fifteen middle school preservice mathematics teachers were involved in this design-based research. The professional development activities were designed based on L. Shulman and J. Shulman’s (Shulman and Shulman, Journal of Curriculum Studies 36:257–271, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r54&quot;&gt;2004&lt;/span&gt;) reflective and communal clusters with psychological roots in Schön’s notion of “reflective practitioners” and Vygotsky’s social development theory. These professional development activities were integrated into the methods and field experience courses of the teacher education program. The audio records of the whole group and small group discussions and all written products (i.e., problems, criteria list, and reflection memos) were analyzed to understand preservice teachers’ conceptions. This study revealed that the professional development activities helped preservice teachers produce the problems that would be interesting and encouraging for students to develop their own solution methods. Preservice teachers’ conceptions also evolved in a collective and reflective community. In this respect, this study presented &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; way to design professional development for teachers that nurtures their understanding of the components supporting mathematical richness and contextual meaningfulness of a problem. Hence, this study provided implications for teacher education practices and future research on mathematics teacher preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2022 22:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09512-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Modelling lessons for more than imitation: investigating teachers’ reactions and decompositions of unfamiliar practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The literature highlights differing views on the efficacy of modelling lessons for teacher professional learning. In this study we draw on dissonance theory to discuss lesson modelling that seeks to transcend ‘do as I do’ imitation and provoke teachers’ attention to intended teaching practices: a necessary pre-cursor for changes to practice. A collective case study investigated the experiences and perceptions of 18 practising primary teachers from four school contexts participating in the process of: collectively observing modelling of mathematics lessons in their classrooms, analysing different parts of those practices with the modeller, and enacting them. It was found that modelling lessons associated with inquiry-oriented approaches for developing students’ problem-solving and reasoning in teachers’ own classrooms appeared to confront their assumptions about traditional approaches to teaching and learning mathematics. The teachers’ surprise at their students’ engagement in the challenging learning experiences conflicted with their existing views of teaching and impelled them to reflect on and set goals for improving their practice. Suggestions for pre- and post-lesson protocols for stimulating productive discussions are proposed, along with implications for designing school-based professional learning processes using lesson modelling.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2022 22:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09516-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Contradictions and their manifestations in professional learning communities in mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Professional learning communities (PLC) have increasingly attracted attention in research on teachers’ professional development. The aim of this study is to identify contradictions that can occur and be manifested in PLCs in mathematics. Identifying contradictions in PLCs are important, as the identification and resolution of contradictions are crucial to developing PLCs. We have conceptualized PLCs and contradictions within the Cultural Historical Activity Theory. Our data consist of two iterations of interviews with four teacher leader coaches with extensive experience of coaching teacher leaders of PLCs in mathematics. The study distinguishes 26 manifestations of contradictions, taking the overall forms of dilemmas and conflicts. Our results can be used in designing PLCs in mathematics: they can be used to make visible and increase participants’ awareness of contradictions involved in PLCs and thereby increase the possibility that the contradictions serve as sources of support rather than obstacles in the development of PLCs in mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2022 22:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09513-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Productive ambiguity in unconventional representations: “what the fraction is going on?”</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We explore the responses of 26 prospective elementary-school teachers to the claim “1/6.5 is not a fraction” asserted by a hypothetical classroom student. The data comprise scripted dialogues that depict how the participants envisioned a classroom discussion of this claim to evolve, as well as an accompanying commentary where they described their personal understanding of the notion of a fraction. The analysis is presented from the perspective of productive ambiguity, where different types of ambiguity highlight the prospective teachers’ mathematical interpretations and pedagogical choices. In particular, we focus on the ambiguity inherent in the aforementioned unconventional representation and how the teachers reconciled it by invoking various models and interpretations of a fraction. We conclude with a description of how the perspective of productive ambiguity can enrich teacher education and classroom discourse.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2022 22:26</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09510-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ Conceptions of Fairness in Classroom Assessment: An Empirical Study</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;With heightened equity pursuits in 21st century schools and the key role of assessment in teachers’ concerns with educational equity, scholars have recently attempted to empirically investigate teachers’ conceptions of fairness in classroom assessment. This study contributes to this growing literature and draws on interview data from 27 experienced high school teachers to further appreciate the factors that propel teachers’ fairness conceptions. The results indicate that the teachers’ conceptions of fairness in classroom assessment were influenced by three themes: (a) individual mechanisms, (b) social mechanisms, and (c) dialectical relationships between individual and social mechanisms. These themes underscored how teachers’ individual philosophies and experiences interacted with their encounters with social conditions of society, schools, and classrooms to influence their conceptions and articulated practices of fairness in classroom assessments. The results contribute to provoke conversations around assessment fairness education during pre- and in-service programs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2022 11:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871221130742?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Deep Reinforcement Learning for Adaptive Learning Systems</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The adaptive learning problem concerns how to create an individualized learning plan (also referred to as a learning policy) that chooses the most appropriate learning materials based on a learner’s latent traits. In this article, we study an important yet less-addressed adaptive learning problem—one that assumes continuous latent traits. Specifically, we formulate the adaptive learning problem as a Markov decision process. We assume latent traits to be continuous with an unknown transition model and apply a model-free deep reinforcement learning algorithm—the deep Q-learning algorithm—that can effectively find the optimal learning policy from data on learners’ learning process without knowing the actual transition model of the learners’ continuous latent traits. To efficiently utilize available data, we also develop a transition model estimator that emulates the learner’s learning process using neural networks. The transition model estimator can be used in the deep Q-learning algorithm so that it can more efficiently discover the optimal learning policy for a learner. Numerical simulation studies verify that the proposed algorithm is very efficient in finding a good learning policy. Especially with the aid of a transition model estimator, it can find the optimal learning policy after training using a small number of learners.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-04-2022 06:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221129847?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
