<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Power Approximations for Overall Average Effects in Meta-Analysis With Dependent Effect Sizes</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Meta-analytic models for dependent effect sizes have grown increasingly sophisticated over the last few decades, which has created challenges for a priori power calculations. We introduce power approximations for tests of average effect sizes based upon several common approaches for handling dependent effect sizes. In a Monte Carlo simulation, we show that the new power formulas can accurately approximate the true power of meta-analytic models for dependent effect sizes. Lastly, we investigate the Type I error rate and power for several common models, finding that tests using robust variance estimation provide better Type I error calibration than tests with model-based variance estimation. We consider implications for practice with respect to selecting a working model and an inferential approach.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2022 07:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221127379?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>History of mathematics in the context of mathematics teachers’ education: a dialogical/ethical perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper deals with the use of original sources in mathematics education, with emphasis on preservice teachers’ education and the exploration of historical texts. In this context, there is a real challenge, for both teachers and learners, to conduct both ‘synchronic’ and ‘diachronic’ reading. As reported extensively in research, learners seem to have a strong propensity to focus on and to ‘translate’ the texts into modern mathematics, which makes it difficult to deepen both their understanding of history and their own set of conceptualizations. Rather than propose practical solutions, in the paper we explore a theoretical positioning that may help us think differently about these difficulties and, ultimately, provide articulated and different avenues for interventions. Drawing on the philosophy of language of Mikhaïl Bakhtin and Valentin Voloshinov, the idea is to question the Saussurean perspective that underpins the notions of synchrony and diachrony. From this theoretical perspective, we propose to think about the challenges associated with the reading of historical texts in terms of the ethical stance of answerability and engagement in the context of preservice mathematics teachers’ education, and we suggest envisioning a third possible reading, namely, that of the educator.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01437-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>It is probably a pattern: does spontaneous focusing on regularities in preschool predict reasoning about randomness four years later?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The many studies with coin-tossing tasks in literature show that the concept of randomness is challenging for adults as well as children. Systematic errors observed in coin-tossing tasks are often related to the representativeness heuristic, which refers to a mental shortcut that is used to judge randomness by evaluating how well a set of random events represents the typical example for random events we hold in our mind. Representative thinking is explained by our tendency to seek for patterns in our surroundings. In the present study, predictions of coin-tosses of 302 third-graders were explored. Findings suggest that in third grade of elementary school, children make correct as well as different types of erroneous predictions and individual differences exist. Moreover, erroneous predictions that were in line with representative thinking were positively associated with an early spontaneous focus on regularities, which was assessed when they were in second year of preschool. We concluded that previous studies might have underestimated children’s reasoning about randomness in coin-tossing contexts and that representative thinking is indeed associated with pattern-based thinking tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10187-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“It Was Hard, and It Still Is . . .”: Women of Color Navigating HSI STEM Transfer Pathways</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Women of color (WOC) continue to be underrepresented in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM), where they often experience racism and sexism within disciplinary contexts that have historically privileged men and Whiteness. Participant narratives gained through focus-group and follow-up interviews illuminate the racialized and gendered STEM transfer experiences of 21 WOC who attended 2- and 4-year Hispanic-Serving Institutions (HSIs). Using a multidimensional intersectional approach, we explore the interplay between the complex identity experiences of WOC and the dynamic intersections of their transfer pathways across 2- and 4-year HSIs and within STEM disciplinary contexts. Findings underscore the inequities that continue to pervade STEM and highlight opportunities for transforming disciplinary and institutional cultures, particularly within HSI STEM transfer pathways, where there is great potential for these diverse institutions to support, validate, and benefit from the unique contributions of WOC.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-15-2022 06:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126480?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Embracing the City: Black Families’ Place Attachments and (Re)imaginings of the City and Suburb in Search of Educational Opportunity</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Like many predominantly Black urban cities, Detroit, Michigan, has experienced significant out-migration among Black residents over the past 30 years. This situation has altered families’ relationships to the communities and schools where they have been nurtured or call home. Therefore, this paper examines how seven Black families’ place attachments influenced their geographic movement and school choices in the Detroit metropolitan region. Findings show that despite families’ movement to surrounding suburbs, varied experiences in Detroit influenced families’ decision-making regarding where to live, their search for sociocultural experiences that supported their families holistically, and their perceptions and navigation of municipal boundaries and borders. Families’ intention toward maintaining connections with Detroit enact what I term embracing the city. Embracing the city helps consider the importance of socio-spatial ties that persist and orient Black families’ community perceptions and school choices in suburban contexts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-15-2022 06:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126479?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Counter-Deficit Lens in Educational Research: Interrogating Conceptions of Structural Oppression</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Deficit framings of marginalized students, though maintaining widespread social influence, are thoroughly condemned in recent educational scholarship. The goal of this “counter-deficit” scholarship is to challenge racism in schools and improve opportunities for marginalized youth. To meet the lofty ambition of racial equity in education, how scholarship understands racial oppression is a central concern. Sociologists of race have emphasized the duality of racial oppression. Racism is ideological and structural. Ideologically, racism shapes how communities of color are perceived and how they are treated in educational settings. Structurally, racism is embedded in histories and policies that systematically disadvantage racially minoritized people. Both processes matter to educational inequality. However, in this review of counter-deficit literature, we find that racism is primarily understood by way of ideology and seldom by way of structures. This framing has important implications for how schools can support racially minoritized students to overcome racism in schools and communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 12:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221125225?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Dynamic Financial Implications of the Community College Baccalaureate: An Institutional Exploration</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Using generalized difference-in-difference and synthetic control modeling, this study estimates the influence of the community-college baccalaureate (CCB) on institutional finance over time and by intensity. Leveraging data spanning 19 years (1999–2017), I find no impact on overall revenue but suggestive evidence of upfront costs and slight increases in total spending post-adoption. Coupled with increased enrollment, per-full-time-equivalent (FTE) revenue and spending decrease, on average, by approximately 12% and 6%, respectively. Adoption of an additional CCB is associated with a 3% decrease in revenue and a suggestive 2% reduction in spending per FTE. Additional robustness checks suggest that these impacts may vary by state. These results suggest that institutions should consider the trade-offs in broadening access to baccalaureate-level education with the associated strain on resources. Policymakers should consider how best to financially support adoptive institutions as they work to meet student and workforce needs. Implications for policy, practice, and research are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 12:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126473?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Action research: Time to act with maturity</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221133981?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to do action research for transformations at a time of eco-social crisis, by Hilary S. Bradbury. Elgar, 2022. Four characters in search of a book review</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;What are the crucial ingredients missing in our search for transformative – structural, cultural, political-economic – changes to entrenched systems of oppression right now? Why do so many smart, informed, data-driven efforts fail? This book says what’s missing is ART: Action Research for Transformation, a contemporary expression of action research. The book offers surprising, counter-intuitive, and most importantly, experienced-based insights on both what ART is, and how to do it. It reveals pathways to disrupt the academic détentes regarding quantitative versus quantitative, objective versus subjective, macro versus micro, and asks what is knowledge and what is it for. The book offers practical approaches, tools, and case studies, while featuring personal narratives from a wide range of active ARTists about their successes, challenges, doubts, and perhaps most importantly, the joy and value they experience performing ART. Its preponderant thesis is this: the problems of eco-social crisis aren’t “out there” so much as within, between and among each one of us, and the types of relationships we create with others. The book is therefore of value to educators and change leaders perhaps especially within our universities’ professional schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 09:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221133781?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Relationships Between Institutional Agents and Student Activists</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 07:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2125761?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Preservice Teachers Learn through a Pedagogy of Enactment in a Middle School Mathematics Methods Course</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 05:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2022.2129636?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Frequentist Approach of Probability, from Random Experiment to Sampling Fluctuation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article deals with an introduction of probability at school through sensory modalities. This approach is based on sampling fluctuation with empirical observations of frequencies. Initially, we analyze how students from high school work on such a task by using dice, pencil, and paper. We then identify the use of schemas and data visualization by students. Considering schemas as a primitive form of algorithmic approaches, we observe interaction with mathematics. In class, students know how to use notion of frequency, but linking frequencies with probability appears to be a difficult issue. This absence of a statistical link leads us to identify entry points for probability teaching. We then decide to analyze primary school students when they have to explore a random experiment by using statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00230-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Embodied mathematical pedagogy to liberate racialized and multilingual bodies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When language is defined narrowly in mathematics classrooms, racially and linguistically minoritized students in classrooms could be systematically positioned as “learners of deficiency.” Recent scholarship calls for expanding the notion of language to emphasize embodied expression of mathematical ideas. Taking a critical perspective to understand racialized experiences of using languages in disciplinary learning spaces, this article proposes the reconceptualization of embodiment as a language for racialized multilingual learners. This study was conducted in a Grade 1 classroom in a linguistically and racially diverse school in Canada. Through a series of professional development sessions, we worked with an experienced teacher to redesign the normalized and institutionalized pedagogy toward greater mobility of racialized multilingual learners’ bodies, which was intertwined with their intellectual liberation. Focusing on the spatiality of pedagogy, the previously restrictive areas in the school were transformed into a place that augments embodied expression of mathematical ideas and agentive participation of minoritized learners. The analysis focused on the embodied discourse that participating racialized multilingual students used to actively engage in mathematical discussion. Our findings show that the designed pedagogy, characterized by the spatial and temporal expansion of the learning environment, offered more spaces for uncertainty and spontaneity with the decreased control of the teacher as an explicator. Our article furthers anti-colonial approaches to understand the intersection of racialized bodies and language in mathematics education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10185-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Lesson study beyond its initial adaptation: a case without external support</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Since 2016, Park School in Denmark has consistently used Japanese lesson study as an approach to the professional development of its mathematics teachers. The school has moved beyond the initial adaptation of lesson study, and no longer includes external support. In this article, I investigate how three groups of teachers participated in the maturing lesson-study phases, especially the reflection phase. I apply social practice theory, particularly the concepts of figured worlds and improvisation, to examine the groups’ improvisation of artefacts and actions during lesson study, and the mature, valued outcomes. This study explains how and why the mature lesson-study efforts at Park School offer predominantly superficial learning opportunities to students and teachers alike. It concludes that in countries unaccustomed to lesson study, external support (or other external knowledge sources) is also important at the mature stages of its adaptation. This study proposes three activities that offer such support. 
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09556-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>STEM teacher education programs for preservice and in-service secondary mathematics teachers: a review study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Few studies have elaborated on how different types of integration can support teachers’ learning and build their capacity to teach for the enhancement of students’ STEM competence. Teaching in a STEM education context requires mathematics teachers to be able to effectively choose, design and implement appropriate tasks in their classes. Given the important role of teachers and tasks as vehicles for STEM education, this paper reviews literature on STEM teacher education programs associated with STEM tasks for preservice and in-service secondary mathematics teachers. After searching for and reviewing the 14 relevant articles, the analytical results indicated that (a) teachers’ STEM knowledge and practices have not been commonly assessed as the outcomes of STEM teacher education programs, although they are explicitly counted as the goals of STEM teacher education programs; (b) the approach of multi-disciplinary concepts integrated with uni-disciplinary practice is mostly adopted as the approach to STEM integration; (c) task design features identified from the articles can be classified by elements of task design (i.e., goals, principles and instructional focus) and task design factors (i.e., disciplinary knowledge, cognition and metacognition, affect); and (d) most programs provide both acquisition and participation approaches to developing mathematics teachers’ knowledge in STEM education. The review results shed light on the design and implementation of STEM tasks and STEM teacher education programs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-13-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09557-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Early Birds in Elementary School? School Start Times and Outcomes for Younger Students</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;While research supports later start times for secondary schools, there is little evidence regarding start times for elementary schools. We address this gap with a statewide examination of elementary schools and a quasi-experimental analysis of an urban district that recently changed its elementary start times. We find that earlier start times predict less sleep for students. Regarding academic outcomes, our estimates are small in magnitude and suggest that earlier elementary start times have near-zero effects. Earlier start times predict a slight increase in absences and modestly higher math scores, especially for traditionally disadvantaged students. In districts that need to stagger start times, it may be advisable for elementary schools to start earlier to accommodate later secondary school start times.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-12-2022 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221121799?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Undergraduate Students Think about Summation (Sigma) Notation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reports on a two-part investigation into how students think about and use summation (sigma) notation. During an instructional design experiment, two participating students struggled with this notation, but also reasoned about it in creative ways. This motivated a follow-up study in which we administered a free-response three-item survey to 285 students enrolled in a variety of undergraduate mathematics courses. Our findings suggest that it is not uncommon for students to produce incorrect responses when encoding and decoding sums using summation notation. More significantly, our findings reveal that students are capable of reasoning about this notation in a variety of viable, but unconventional, ways. We argue that these findings have implications for the teaching and learning of both summation notation specifically and mathematical conventions more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-12-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00193-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Behold the Role of the District in Education Finance</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/hpje20/97/4&quot;&gt;Volume 97, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, September-October 2022&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 08:13</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2125752?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promoting socio-emotional learning competencies in teacher education through online clinical simulations</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2134006?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Narrating Stories about Research Units in Israeli Teacher Education Colleges</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 03:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2133697?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting teacher agency during a collaborative inquiry-based in-service teacher education course</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 03:56</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2132385?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Primary English teacher education in Portugal: an exploratory study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 03:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2132384?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editors’ Notes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uate20/44/4&quot;&gt;Volume 44, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Winter 2022, Page 269-270&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-11-2022 02:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2022.2127303?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fiscal Federalism and K–12 Education Funding: Policy Lessons from Two Educational Crises</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We synthesize and critique federal fiscal policy during the Great Recession and COVID-19 pandemic. First, the amount of aid during both crises was inadequate to meet policy goals. Second, the mechanisms used to distribute funds were disconnected from policy goals and provided different levels of aid to districts with equivalent levels of economic disadvantage. Third, data tools are missing, making it difficult to understand whether funds were used to meet policy goals. Details for these results are provided along with policy recommendations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-10-2022 11:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221125764?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
