<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preparing in Advance to Respond in-the-Moment: Investigating Parallel Changes in Planning and Enactment in Teacher Professional Development</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Despite warrants for classroom discussion, research consistently finds that discussions in K-12 classrooms remain rare. Our research investigates whether and in what ways practice-based teacher learning opportunities focused on discussion facilitation influence opportunities for student talk. Grounded in data from a job-embedded professional development program for fourth- to eighth-grade literacy teachers, we analyzed videos of teachers co-planning and co-facilitating discussions with students. Findings indicate that, across 1 year, during co-facilitated classroom discussions, teacher talk decreased, while student talk increased. In a parallel finding, our analysis of co-planning sessions revealed that the ways teachers planned for discussions also changed. Teachers went from engaging only in what we call proactive pedagogical reasoning to balancing that with what we have come to call responsive pedagogical reasoning.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-21-2022 12:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871221121767?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Educational Stakeholder Sensemaking on Preparing CTE Students for Sub-Baccalaureate Pathways</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Careful implementation of Career and Technical Education (CTE) programs is necessary in order for programs to achieve the policy goal of college and career readiness, which involves expanding student opportunities for career-relevant learning without limiting their academic preparation for postsecondary degrees. As programs become more widespread, little work has examined how practitioners actually implementing CTE make sense of programs’ intended outcomes. Through interviews and observations with 52 education leaders and their partners in workforce development, I found that education stakeholders believed CTE was important for providing students with the option to pursue financially low-risk pathways toward middle-skill careers that didn’t require bachelor’s degrees. Yet in their efforts to valorize sub-baccalaureate (sub-BA) pathways, they sometimes exaggerated the long-term returns to sub-BA credentials, leaving students with inaccurate information on which to base their postsecondary goals.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-21-2022 11:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120277?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptions of Educational Equity</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;“Educational equity” is universally lauded but equally ill-defined. At least five contrasting meanings of equity are in current use: equal distributions of outcomes across populations; equal outcomes for every child; equal resource allocations across students, schools, districts, states, or nations; equal experiences for each child; and equal levels of growth by each child. Furthermore, these conceptions are themselves often subsumed to concerns for benefiting the less advantaged, ensuring educational adequacy, or prioritizing short-term benefits versus long-term structural change. Researchers, educators, and policy makers alike will benefit from understanding these distinctions and trade-offs, not least in order to reimagine and restructure the unjust conditions that make some of those trade-offs unavoidable in the first place.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-21-2022 04:39</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221121344?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reflecting on the Overview of University Mathematics Education Research by INDRUM</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-21-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00195-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Intermediary Public Policy Organizations and the Discursive Evasion of Systemic Racism and Racialized Violence</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The 2020 health pandemic and high-profile police murders of Black people inspired national conversations about racism and police brutality. This study examined how Intermediary Public Policy Organizations (IPPOs) discursively engaged with the racialized nature of the pandemic and the police murder of George Floyd, which have increased awareness of systemic racism in society. Our discursive analysis of IPPO statements published during these events revealed a pattern of humanizing higher education institutions, race evasive policy proposals, and a lack of policy action addressing systemic racism. IPPO evasion of race is consequential because it has the potential to limit the ability of public policy to dismantle systems of oppression and highlights the need for race-conscious policies to support Black, Indigenous, and people of color students and communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-20-2022 10:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120279?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Evolving Identities of HSI and Differentiated Funding</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;To achieve Higher Education Act Title V funding goals, policymakers must reconsider approaches, respond to Hispanic-Serving Institution (HSI) diversity, and prioritize servingness. This study investigated HSI heterogeneity across traditional performance metrics and student-engagement indicators using data sources previously only examined independently. A multi-step TwoStep cluster analysis revealed six clusters of HSIs. The two most important predictors of cluster membership were years with an HSI designation (transitioning and established) and institution type (associate, bachelor, and special focus). Key quantitative metrics may be useful for policy actors seeking an equity-minded Title V award strategy that considers HSI heterogeneity and prioritizes HEA Title V policy aims.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-20-2022 06:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120274?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Critical Qualitative Study of Inequities in Hispanic-Serving Institutions’ Grant-Seeking Competitiveness</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Hispanic-Serving Institutions’ (HSIs) diversification and Title V’s anemic funding present a ripe condition for inequity. Hence, I interviewed 29 institutional actors across 17 HSIs to understand how they view their competitiveness for these grants and sources of inequity of this program. I identified four themes, demonstrating that an HSI’s institutional capacity, (in)actions, knowledge, and leadership inform its competitiveness for Title V funding. The findings show that HSIs have unequal organizational conditions and reveal ways this program may (re)produce inequity among HSIs. Without increased Title V appropriations and policy modification, HSIs will vie for funding on increasingly unequal terms, resulting in greater inequity.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-20-2022 06:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120272?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing algebraic activity through conjecturing about relationships</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This manuscript contributes to research on how algebraic thinking about operations and properties can develop, and relevant forms of curricular activity. The key question asked is: how can students’ early algebraic activity be fostered through focusing on relations involving operations and properties? We adopt Radford’s three aspects of algebraic thinking (indeterminacy, denotation and analyticity), which focus on considering, symbolising and operating on unknown objects. We investigate the work of a class of 11–12 year old students in re-analysing data collected over 20 years ago as part of a project exploring algebraic activity. Our findings point to the proposal that a focus on conjecturing about relationships can be a powerful route into early algebra. On the basis of our analysis we propose an extension to Radford’s third aspect of algebraic thinking (analyticity) to include &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;structuring a mathematical space&lt;/em&gt;, e.g., through a set of conjectures.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-20-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01420-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impact of COVID-19 on the format and nature of academic conferences in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The global COVID-19 pandemic has provided an opportunity to re-examine the possibility of organising virtual conferences in mathematics education, in which the social needs of participants can also be addressed. In this study we investigated the future impact that this change may have on the format and nature of mathematics education conferences. The study was conducted in two phases. We used an online questionnaire in which we asked participants to give us some input on the issues above. In the second phase of the project, focus group interviews were conducted with international mathematics education researchers&lt;strong class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This study is an exploratory study, in which the sample was not developed in a way that could generate comparisons. The aim of the study was to raise possibilities about what may be the future of mathematics education conferences. Findings indicate that although academics are pro-actively thinking about alternative conference formats, the proven value of face-to-face conferences is still very real, showing that it is too early for us to have a clear vision of the future format of academic conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-20-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01421-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From Towers of Linking Cubes to the Binomial Expansion Theorem: What Can Be Learned About Combinatorics?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;While helping proofread a book during my doctoral studies, I came across a chapter that included (among other things) a discussion of a set of problems and tasks involving the building of towers using only two (or three) colours of cubes (Maher &amp;amp; Ahluwali, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r5&quot;&gt;2014&lt;/span&gt;). Later that year, as I started my tenure track position at the University of Regina, I decided to bring one of those tasks, “to account for all possible three-tall towers using two colours” (pp. 567, 568), into the pedagogy and mathematics content courses that I was teaching. My goals were simple: to find out how the students thought about combinatorics using a situation that was most likely unique to them, and to inspire them to actually work with some of the plethora of manipulative materials in our “math lab.” The actual outcomes, however, went well beyond those goals, as problems related to common words used in relation to combinatorics, connections to Pascal’s triangle, and the development of the binomial expansion theorem also emerged during the pre-service teachers’ explorations of the two-coloured towers. As the task expanded into a suite of tasks and learnings over time, it also led the students and me to a new conundrum: “How did the permutations captured in the built towers change to combinations in the binomial expansion theorem?” This article reflects on the journey to an answer, while also leading to some questions about the existing literature related to the two-colour-tower tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-20-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00225-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessment for Learning: developing the required teacher competencies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 12:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2124912?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Special educators’ knowledge of student mathematical thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;To anticipate and respond to the diverse ways of reasoning students with disabilities use to make sense in inclusive mathematics classrooms, special educators require a deep understanding of a diverse array of student thinking. Unfortunately, historic and contemporary data suggest that opportunities for special educators to develop this knowledge prior to classroom teaching are diminutive. Further inquiry is needed into pre-service experiences that might support growth in teachers’ knowledge. We present results from a US-based semester-long course grounded in neurodiversity and students’ mathematical thinking designed to improve 20 special educators’ pedagogical content knowledge. Qualitative and quantitative analyses were conducted to determine how the pre-service teachers anticipated students’ diverse mathematical thinking before and after experience in the course along with their propensity to adapt problems to respond to diversity during instruction. Furthermore, the pre-test to post-test changes in pre-service teachers’ anticipations of students’ problem-solving strategies and adaptations of problems were statistically significant. Implications for teacher preparation and future research are shared.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09508-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using scripting tasks to reveal mathematics teacher candidates&#39;  resources for responding to student errors</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Practice-based pedagogies, such as representations of practice and approximations of practice, are increasingly common in mathematics teacher education. More needs to be known about how teacher candidates&#39; (TCs&#39;) productions through such activities make visible the resources they bring to the work of teaching. In this paper, we highlight our use of “scripting tasks,” through which secondary mathematics TCs produced dialogues of classroom interactions and rationales for those scripts in response to a provided classroom scenario. We share how analyses of TCs&#39; scripts and rationales can make visible a range of resources that TCs bring to the work of teaching—tools and practices, vision and dispositions of teaching, and understandings of students and content (Hammerness et al., 2005)—that inform how they respond to student contributions in whole-class discussions as a focal teaching practice. We illustrate a rich example and framework for analyzing TCs&#39; responses to scripting tasks and offer implications for how such analyses can support teacher educators and researchers to make claims about TCs&#39; learning and inform decisions about supports for TCs&#39; development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09505-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Learning to design effective professional development: The influence of integrating a coaching tool with an elementary mathematics specialist course assignment</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As content-specific educational coaches, elementary mathematics specialists (EMSs) have emerged as school-based professionals who are needs-driven and work closely with school stakeholders in regard to mathematics teaching and learning. While leading mathematics education organizations have identified the specialized knowledge and skills required for EMS positions, how to best prepare these individuals is knowledge that the field is still exploring. This paper first presents a theoretical model for EMS preparation that aligns an emerging coaching tool, the Decision-Making Protocol for Mathematics Coaching (Baker &amp;amp; Knapp, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r75&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/span&gt;, [DMPMC]) with the Professional Development Design Framework (Loucks-Horsley et al. in Designing professional development for teachers of science and mathematics, Corwin Press, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r35&quot;&gt;2010&lt;/span&gt;). The paper then presents a descriptive case study that examines the application of this model in an EMS preparation course. The findings indicate that assessing the coaching situation fostered administrative partnerships, revisiting goals increased specificity of anticipated outcomes, and applying research-informed practices increased EMS self-efficacy and advanced coaching agendas. Taken together, these findings suggest that integrating the DMPMC into an EMS preparation course led to positive changes in EMS candidate learning of professional development design. Notably, this is one of the first studies that documents the influence of a coaching education tool on EMS candidates’ professional development design.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09507-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>(Mis)alignment between noticing and instructional quality: the role of psychological and cognitive constructs</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, we investigated the relationship between teachers’ post-instruction noticing (PIN) and the quality of their mathematics instruction. We analyzed the conversations of elementary teachers around five coached lessons and scored their level of post-instruction noticing and the mathematical quality of the instruction of the lesson. We compared teachers’ PIN levels with their instructional quality, using scores from the Mathematical Quality of Instruction (MQI) rubric, for each coached lesson. There was both alignment and discrepancies between the level of PIN and MQI scores. Explorations of the cognitive and psychological constructs that seemed to influence teacher’s noticing showed that mathematical knowledge for teaching (MKT), efficacy, beliefs, emotions, and identity was influential on teachers’ PIN although they seemed to influence teachers differently. In some cases, the constructs appeared to support attentiveness to students’ thinking and in other cases they did not. We discuss implications for professional development and future research on teachers’ noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09509-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The time is out of joint. Teacher subjectivity during COVID-19</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, we address the issue of mathematics teachers&#39; personal and professional responsiveness to changing circumstances, such as the shift in external demands made on teacher practice due to the COVID-19 pandemic. For investigating a such delicate issue, we take a theoretical approach, which is quite novel in the field of mathematics education: Lacan&#39;s psychoanalytical lens. Specifically, we will use this psychoanalytical lens to analyze a case study focusing on a primary school teacher during the first lockdown in Italy, during which school was organized exclusively in the form of distance education. The analysis of the teacher’s crisis and the strategies she adopted to overcome this crisis give some suggestions about possible directions and issues to consider for future mathematics teacher training proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09506-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What might diversity mean in JMTE?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09552-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bringing the home into school: learning and connecting through mathematics education during the time of a pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic brought with it a new way of being in a changed and uncertain world. Aotearoa/New Zealand took a well-being approach and in turn, we share the positive outcomes which resulted for some low socio-economic schools and communities in relation to teacher learning and relationships with families. In this article, we report on how teachers and schools connected with diverse students and their families during the period of remote learning. We draw on the responses from 20 teachers and school leaders who participated in interviews. Following the wider government focus, schools took a well-being first approach which led to increased connections and positive home/school relationships. The results highlight how a disruptive event such as COVID-19 can also be a time to focus on strengths of diverse communities and gain insights. We demonstrate that while focusing on mathematics, teachers and school leaders gained insights related to their students’ funds of knowledge and saw opportunities for learning for students, parents, and the teachers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10157-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Storylines in public news media about mathematics education and minoritized students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Public media both reflects and shapes societal perceptions and attitudes. Teachers and others around students in mathematics classrooms have expectations for the students, projected with what appears in these media. We are most concerned about the expectations placed on students who are identified with minoritized groups—particularly students who are Indigenous or migrated to Norway. We investigate how minoritized group contexts and mathematics education appear together in Norwegian news media texts. Our analysis uses the notion of storylines to describe the expectations about minoritized groups that news media project. We found seven entangled storylines: “the majority language and culture are keys to learning and knowing mathematics,” “mathematics is language- and culture-neutral,” “minoritized groups’ mathematics achievements are linked to culture and gender,” “extraordinary measures are needed to teach students from minoritized groups mathematics,” “students from minoritized groups underachieve,” “students from minoritized groups put in extraordinary effort and time to learn mathematics,” and “minoritized mathematics students are motivated by gratitude.”&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10161-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When is less more? Investigating gap-filling in proofs without words activities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In activities based on proof without words (PWW), we developed, students are given a PWW– a diagram that alludes to the proof of a mathematical theorem. The students work collaboratively to construct a proof alluded by the PWW, and then each student writes and submits a proof attempt. In a 3-year design-based study, we investigate and develop PWW-based activities for advancing upper secondary students&#39; proficiency in constructing proofs. We use the concept of gap-filling as a theoretical framework. In a nutshell, gap-filling is an action of adding information absent in a text that a reader does for sense-making. We inquire whether secondary school students independently construct a proof when a PWW is at their disposal, what characterizes those gaps that students identify and fill, and how PWW design principles influence students’ gap-filling. We identified four categories of gaps: key idea, generality, constructional, and figure property justifications. We find that students mainly fill key idea gaps but not generality gaps and that PWWs that presented the construction procedure led more students to fill the constructional gaps. However, PWWs that did not explicitly present some figures’ property led more students to fill those justification gaps. We identify five PWW design principles that can enhance secondary students’ gap-filling and conclude that a meticulous design paves the way to implement PWW-based activities for fostering mathematical proving.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10159-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On metaphors in thinking about preparing mathematics for teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract &lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper explores how different schools of thought in mathematics education think and speak about preparing mathematics for teaching by introducing and proposing certain metaphors. Among the metaphors under consideration here are the unpacking metaphor, which finds its origin in the Anglo-American school of thought of pedagogical reduction of mathematics; the elementarization metaphor, which has its origin in the German school of thought of didactic reconstruction of mathematics; and the recontextualization metaphor, which originates in the French school of thought of didactic transposition. The metaphorical language used in these schools of thought is based on different theoretical positions, orientations, and images of preparing mathematics for teaching. Although these metaphors are powerful and allow for different ways of thinking and speaking about preparing mathematics for teaching, they suggest that preparing mathematics for teaching is largely a one-sided process in the sense of an adaptation of the knowledge in question. To promote a more holistic understanding, an alternative metaphor is offered: preparing mathematics for teaching as ecological engineering. By using the ecological engineering metaphor, the preparation of mathematics for teaching is presented as a two-sided process that involves both the adaptation of knowledge and the modification of its environment.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10154-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A bridging study analyzing mathematical model construction through a quantities-oriented lens</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical modelling is endorsed as both a means and an end to learning mathematics. Despite its utility and inclusion as a curricular objective, one of many questions remaining about learners’ modelling regards how modelers choose relevant situational attributes and express mathematical relationships in terms of them. Research on quantitative reasoning has informed the field on how individuals quantify attributes and conceive of covariational relationships among them. However, this research has not often attended to modelers’ mathematization in open modelling tasks, an endeavor that invites further attention to theoretical and methodological details. To this end, we offer a synthesis of existing theories to present a cognitive account of mathematical model construction through a quantity-oriented lens. Second, we use empirical data to illustrate why it is productive for theories of modelling to attend to and account for students’ quantitative reasoning while modelling. Finally, we identify remaining challenges to coordinating different theoretical accounts of model construction.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10163-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ use of rational questioning strategies to promote student participation in collective argumentation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Teachers’ questioning plays an essential role in shaping collective argumentative discourse. This paper demonstrated that rationality dimensions in teacher questions can be assessed by adapting Habermas’ three components of rationality. By coordinating Habermas’ construct with Toulmin’s model for argumentation, this paper investigated how two secondary mathematics teachers used rational questioning to support student participation in collective argumentation. This paper identified various ways in which two participating teachers used rational questioning to support student participation in argumentation via contributions of argument components. The results establish a theoretical connection between the use of rational questions and students’ contributions of components of arguments. The results indicated that not all rational questions were associated with a component of argument, and rational questions may additionally support argumentation in general for the development of a culture of rationality. The study has implications in terms of theory and professional development of teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10160-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pre-service teacher planning for differentiation of instruction in mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study investigated how 46 pre-service teachers (PSTs) planned for differentiation of instruction in mathematics. Content analysis was utilized to explore the differentiation strategies included and student characteristics considered in PST plans and how PSTs used differentiation strategies and student characteristics to differentiate lesson content, process, product, and environment. In addition, a rubric was designed and utilized to analyze the level of detail PSTs provided in their plans. Results indicated that overall, PSTs were developing in their planning for differentiation of instruction, using general terms to describe the modifications they would make to meet student needs. Moreover, results revealed that PSTs included strategies to differentiate lesson content and environment most often in their plans and frequently considered student readiness levels when planning for differentiation. Findings also revealed that PSTs need support in learning how to plan for differentiation based on student cultural backgrounds. Implications for mathematics teacher preparation are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-19-2022 00:19</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10149-1</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
