<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Professional Development and Student Reading in Middle and High School: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This systematic review investigates the effect of teacher professional development (TPD) on adolescent students’ reading achievement in middle and high school. A systematic search of TPD and student reading achievement studies (1975–2020) identified 15 medium-quality articles meeting this study’s inclusion criteria. A meta-analysis of 14 of these studies corrected by Hedges’ g showed that TPD on student reading was associated with a small overall effect of g = 0.062, p &amp;lt; .05 on student reading outcomes. However, the effect size was moderated by delivery of the TPD, TPD hours, student population, and assessment. None of the 14 studies reported TPD theory-driven quality indicators for TPD delivery (e.g., school support, use of technology, and promotion of self-reflection or reported measures of teacher change). Conclusion of findings in literacy TPD includes the need for TPD theory-driven studies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 09:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231153084?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inequitable Interactions: A Critical Quantitative Analysis of Mentorship and Psychosocial Development Within Computing Graduate School Pathways</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Mentorship is vital to increasing graduate school access in computing; however, mentorship must be structured in power-conscious, developmental ways to ensure equitable access to and support within computing graduate pathways. I engage a critical quantitative lens to examine mentoring support among undergraduates with reported graduate aspirations, taking a nuanced look at departmental mentorship to investigate how organizational power in computing may maintain inequitable mentoring outcomes. Descriptive and regression analyses draw from a longitudinal sample of 442 graduate aspirants in computing who completed an introductory course survey (between 2015–2017) and a follow-up survey (fall 2019). Results document significant variation in forms of mentoring support and disciplinary psychosocial beliefs (i.e., computing identity and self-efficacy), with key patterns across graduate aspirants’ social identities and mentors’ organizational power (via their departmental roles). I conclude by discussing structural and social inequities in mentorship, which may underscore disparities in students’ realization of their computing graduate aspirations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-31-2023 04:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221143097?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical modelling in the discourses of the KOM and PISA frameworks and teacher interviews</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 12:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2165536?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The spatial contiguity principle in mathematics textbooks</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 12:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2158122?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Supporting mathematics educators through and towards online learning. Karen Hollebrands, Robin Anderson, and Kevin Oliver (Eds). (2021) Online learning in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 11:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10175-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical strategies and emergence of socially mediated metacognition within a multi-touch Dynamic Geometry Environment</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Our research aimed to investigate the potential learning benefits to young children of implementing digital interactive multimodal technologies that provide both visual and haptic experiences in elementary mathematics classrooms. We studied the ways in which fourth-grade students collaboratively create collective strategies for solving mathematical problems utilizing dynamic geometry software with multi-touch interfaces, a combination we call a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;multi-touch Dynamic Geometry Environment&lt;/em&gt;. We examine in-depth two case studies each illustrating how mathematical strategies, collaboration, and socially mediated metacognition emerge in the small groups of children while working on an activity using the Geometer’s Sketchpad® on the iPad to make sense of an intuitive idea of covariation&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; We found that children’s interactions with their peers, the interviewer, and the mDGE favored the emergence of varied collaborative behaviors and socially mediated metacognitive processes that fostered the co-construction and development of mathematical strategies over a short period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 11:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10170-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Efficacy and Implementation of Michigan’s Partnership Model of School and District Turnaround: Mixed-Methods Evidence From the First 2 Years of Reform Implementation</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The recent Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) requires states to identify and turn around their lowest performing schools, but it breaks somewhat from prior policies by granting states significant autonomy over how they identify and turn around these schools. This mixed-methods study, which draws on administrative, qualitative, and survey data, examines the effectiveness of Michigan’s approach to school turnaround under ESSA. We find that students in turnaround schools experienced significant achievement gains in math and to a lesser extent in English language arts (ELA), with effects concentrated among the lowest achieving students. Analyses of qualitative and survey data suggest that these outcomes were influenced by state-level supports, strategic planning, the threat of accountability for continued low performance, and improved leadership quality in turnaround schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221141415?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exponential behaviour and variational practices in Chilean newscasts: a socioepistemological view</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The research on which we report in this paper was framed within the socioepistemological theory and dealt with the fundamental role of variational practices in the understanding of COVID-19 pandemic graphs. Given the proliferation of mathematical graphs related to the pandemic in the media, we proposed to analyse the variational practices in use in the interpretation of graphs of exponential behaviour that a Chilean newscast of high rating used to inform the population about the pandemic in Chile. For this purpose, a thematic analysis intertwined with documentary analysis techniques was carried out, in order to describe the types of graphs shown in the newscast, and a variational reference system was studied to analyse the use of variational practices. To obtain our results, the types of graphs most frequently shown in the newscast at the beginning of the pandemic were identified and the use of the variational practices of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;comparison, seriation&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;prediction&lt;/em&gt; in such graphs was analysed. In conclusion, the need is discussed for the conceptual evolution of the exponential function to be accompanied by a pragmatic evolution in school that favours the use and development of variational practices in the student body.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01458-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Navigating multiple languages and meanings in cross-cultural research on teachers’ resource use</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Cross-cultural research covering multiple languages and cultures involves negotiating conceptual and linguistic challenges. This paper focuses on how researchers working across cultural and linguistic boundaries navigate the research process and negotiate a common understanding of the constructs under study. Working towards intersubjectivity within a cross-cultural research team is essential, as it deepens understanding of one another’s contexts and our own. We analyze our own research process, as a cross-cultural team studying elementary school teachers’ use of print and digital instructional resources in Finland, Flanders, Sweden, and the U.S. Recorded team conversations served as data to help us explore the way language and culture are intertwined and how these relationships surface when developing research instruments and conducting analysis of the interviews, in which language became a focal point. Challenges emerged particularly within three research aims, namely, naming and describing teaching practices, understanding teachers’ relationships with mathematics resources, and defining digital resources in a cross-cultural survey. Our systematic analysis of instances of conceptual and linguistic inequivalence prompted the team to make language explicit and revealed that these instances varied in several ways that had implications for how and whether they might be bridged. Thus, this paper contributes to understanding the methodological impact of using a shared language, acknowledging that researchers’ lexicons about mathematics teaching are closely linked to their own cultural knowledge and experience. Therefore, working explicitly across language and culture towards mutual understanding is a necessity and a way to reinforce the validity of research outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01466-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Review of the book “Inquiry in university mathematics teaching and learning: the PLATINIUM project”</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09569-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Universal Pre-K and College Enrollment: Is There a Link?</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;In this study, we used data from a cohort of 4,033 Tulsa kindergarten students to investigate the relationship between pre-K enrollment and later college enrollment. Specifically, we tested whether participation in the Tulsa Public Schools universal pre-K program and the Tulsa Community Action Project (CAP) Head Start program predicted enrollment in 2- or 4-year colleges. We used propensity score weighting with multiply imputed data sets to estimate these associations. We found that college enrollment was 12 percentage points higher for Tulsa pre-K alumni compared with former students who did not attend Tulsa pre-K or Head Start. College enrollment was 7.5 percentage points higher for Head Start alumni compared to former students who did not attend Head Start or Tulsa pre-K, but this difference was only marginally significant. Tulsa pre-K attendance was associated with 2-year college enrollment among students from all racial and ethnic backgrounds, but only among Black and Hispanic students did it strongly predict 4-year college enrollment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-28-2023 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221147893?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Comparing the Textbook with Professors’ Intended and Enacted Potential Intellectual Need for Infinite Series in Calculus II</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-27-2023 05:52</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2023.2169490?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inequities at the intersection of race and disability: evidence from community colleges</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-27-2023 05:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2170436?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s in a word? modelling British history for a ‘multi-racial’ society</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-27-2023 05:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2160775?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of a Virtual Coaching Program to Improve Instructional Alignment to State Standards</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-26-2023 04:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2150729?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Challenging anti-Black linguistic racism in schools amidst the ‘what works’ agenda</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-26-2023 04:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2170435?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Differentiation in practice: an exploratory investigation in an Australian mainstream secondary school</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-25-2023 12:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2022.2161508?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The use of Arabic language by mathematics teachers as a resource to support teaching</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In the research described in this paper, we explored the way Palestinian teachers use the Arabic language to teach mathematics in Arabic. First, we address the issue from an historical overview of the context of study. The historical overview allows us to situate the current context of teaching mathematics in Arabic in Palestine. We rely on Halliday’s concept of register to define what we call “Mathematical Arabic For Teaching”. It allows us to focus our study, and to address the issue of combination between this register to be developed by the teachers and the Arabic textbook content. Our theoretical framework is based on a combination of the theories Documentational Approach to Didactics and Mathematical Discourse in Instruction, which allows us to discuss mathematical Arabic for teaching as a resource. We based our exploratory study on the case of three teachers, chosen according to well-defined criteria. We explored the issue through audio recordings of their lessons teaching tenth graders the signs of quadratic functions, and video recorded interviews on their reflections on those lessons. We identified three combinations between the teachers’ Mathematical Arabic For Teaching and the use of the mathematics textbook, namely, complementarity, tension and equivalence. We conclude with some implications of these forms of combination.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-24-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01462-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Principal and Teacher Shared Race and Gender Intersections: Teacher Turnover, Workplace Conditions, and Monetary Benefits</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Recruiting racially minoritized principals is one suggested strategy to increase the racial diversity of teachers, who would then better match their increasingly racially diverse students. However, focusing solely on race ignores the salience of race-gender intersectionality in principal-teacher relations. Using three waves of nationally representative, cross-sectional data with school and year fixed effects, we compared similar teachers in the same school who are and are not race-gender congruent with their principal. We found that better discretionary workplace benefits were concentrated among Black teachers with Black principals, especially Black male teachers with Black male principals, who reported workplace supports almost half a standard deviation higher than did similar non-Black female teachers in their school. Male teachers earned up to $2,890 more supplemental income with male, racially congruent principals; female teachers earned up to $1,050 less with female, racially congruent principals. However, teacher turnover was not consistently responsive to race-gender congruence.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-23-2023 12:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221148156?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Student Understanding of the Sign of Negative Definite Integrals in Mathematics and Physics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In a study of student understanding of negative definite integrals at two institutions, we administered a written survey and follow-up clinical interviews at one institution and found that “backward integrals”, where the integral was taken from right to left on the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;-axis, were the most difficult for students to interpret. We then conducted additional interviews focused on backward integrals at a second institution. Our analysis uses the concept image framework and a recent categorical framework for mathematical sense making. We found that students were most successful using the Fundamental Theorem of Calculus to determine the sign of an integral when a symbolic expression was provided. When considering a definite integral in a graphical context, students often had difficulty if they viewed the integral as a spatial area, stating that area must always be positive. Some students were able to conceptualize &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\Delta x\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(dx\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; as a difference or change and thus a signed quantity; when these students were able to view the area as a sum of smaller pieces, they were more successful in justifying a negative backward integral. Students who used amounts or similar images often had difficulty making sense of the negative sign. Even more progress was made when students either invoked or were asked explicitly about a specific physical context to be represented by the backward integral, other than spatial area. The context provided a meaning to the difference represented by &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq3&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\Delta x\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq4&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(dx\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; and thus to the sign of that difference and the definite integral.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-23-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00202-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Australian primary school teachers’ perceived barriers to and enablers for the integration of children’s literature in mathematics teaching and learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This qualitative survey study set out to investigate in-service and pre-service primary school teachers’ perceived barriers to and enablers for the integration of children’s literature in mathematics teaching and learning in an Australian educational context. While research over the past three decades have documented pedagogical benefits of teaching mathematics using children’s literature, research into teachers’ perceptions regarding the use of such resources is virtually non-existent. The study thus filled this research gap by drawing responses from open-ended survey questions of 94 in-service and 82 pre-service teachers in Australia. A thematic analysis revealed 13 perceived barriers classified under five themes with Lack of Pedagogical Knowledge and Confidence, and Time Constraint, representing 75% of all perceived barriers. Moreover, 14 perceived enablers were identified and classified under five themes with Pedagogical Benefits and Love of Stories representing around 70% of all perceived enablers. Findings also showed that most of the teachers in the study (around 75%) never or infrequently used children’s literature in their mathematics classrooms. The study highlights the role of professional learning and teacher training in ensuring that both in- and pre-service teachers have the necessary pedagogical knowledge, experience and confidence in using children’s literature to enrich their mathematics teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09517-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging prospective teachers’ knowledge through their participation in lesson study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study focuses on a lesson study adaptation for bridging prospective teachers’ experiences in a methods course and their field experiences in a teacher education program in Puerto Rico. We ask, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;what opportunities for teacher learning emerge during discussions in lesson study?&lt;/em&gt; Two lesson study teams of secondary mathematics prospective teachers, each led by an experienced mentor, planned technology-based lessons&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; Using the theoretical framework for lesson study by Lewis and colleagues, we analyzed video recordings of the teams’ discussions. The results show learning opportunities in the three dimensions of the framework: &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;teachers’ knowledge and beliefs&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;the creation of a professional community&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;the development of teaching–learning artifacts&lt;/em&gt;. The mentors leveraged prospective teachers’ knowledge, built on topics discussed in the methods course, and created a professional learning community. Three resources introduced in the methods course supported the creation of a hybrid space connecting academic and practitioner knowledge: shared language about teaching moves for using technology in math instruction, the mathematical proficiency framework, and a lesson plan template. The mentors drew upon their subject matter and pedagogical knowledge during their facilitation of lesson study. The intervention exemplifies a lesson study adaptation that is feasible in the context of a teacher education program.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09521-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interactional production of deficit talk in a professional development for mathematics teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, I examine deficit talk, utterances that depict students and/or families based on their perceived deficits, in an equity-oriented professional development (PD) setting. Researchers often attribute deficit talk by mathematics teachers (MTs) to their biased beliefs and perceptions. From an interactional approach, namely conversation analysis and discursive psychology, I offer an alternative perspective on how deficit talk is produced in PD interactions. The analysis shows the rhetorical functions of deficit talk, which are designed for MTs to manage their accountability with a range of potential issues and to portray themselves as competent teachers. The analysis also reveals the action-performing nature of deficit talk (e.g., refusing a request) situated in the social interaction. To conclude, this paper suggests that mathematics teacher educators need to attend to the micropolitical nature of deficit talk and their co-participation in the production of deficit talk as they formulate ways to respond to deficit talk in PD interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09519-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Self-efficacy, practices, and their relationships; the impact of a professional development program for mathematics teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics teaching in a 21st-century educational context requires a shift to active learning. The shift calls on teachers, and the plans countries need to prepare to make the changes through well-designed teacher professional development programs. ARPA (Spanish acronym for &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Activating Problem Solving in Classrooms&lt;/em&gt;), as a professional development program, with an emphasis on collaborative problem solving, provides opportunities and tools for teachers to enrich their classroom activities in a student-centered manner. This study of 149 in-service teachers evaluates the impact of an ARPA workshop on teachers’ self-efficacy and their tendency to choose student-centered practices. The results show that before participating in the program, even if teachers had believed in their ability to solve problems, they did not consider how to connect this ability with the active student-centered problem-solving practices in their classroom. However, teachers’ self-efficacy in performing problem solving significantly affects the teachers’ report of their student-centered practices after participating in the program. Understanding the relationship between teacher confidence and the quality of their classroom activities is essential for the optimization of the outcomes of any teacher’s professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-22-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-021-09523-2</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
