<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Relations of Morphological Awareness with Language and Literacy Skills Vary Depending on Orthographic Depth and Nature of Morphological Awareness</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We examined the relation of morphological awareness with language and literacy skills, namely phonological awareness, orthographic awareness, vocabulary, word reading, spelling, text reading fluency, and reading comprehension. We also examined potential moderators of the relations (grade level, orthographic depth of language, receptive vs. productive morphological awareness, inflectional vs. derivational vs. compound morphological awareness, and L1/L2 status). After systematic search, a total of 232 articles (965 unique samples, N = 49,936 participants, and 2,765 effect sizes in 17 languages) met inclusion criteria. Morphological awareness was, on average, moderately related to phonological awareness (r = .41), orthographic awareness (r = .39), vocabulary (r = .50), word reading (r = .49), spelling (r = .48), text reading fluency (r = .53), and reading comprehension (r = .54). Importantly, morphological awareness had a stronger relation with word reading in orthographically deep languages (.52) than in orthographically shallow languages (.38). The relation with vocabulary was stronger for upper elementary grades than for primary grades. The magnitude of the relation also varied by the nature of morphological awareness: productive morphological awareness had a stronger relation with phonological awareness and vocabulary than receptive morphological awareness; derivational morphological awareness had a stronger relation with vocabulary and word reading compared to inflectional morphological awareness; and compound morphological awareness had a weaker relation with phonological awareness but a stronger relation with vocabulary compared to inflectional morphological awareness. These results underscore the importance of morphological awareness in language and literacy skills, and reveal a nuanced and precise picture of their relations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2022 12:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221123816?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reviewer Appreciation</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/73/5&quot;&gt;Volume 73, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 538-539, November/December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2022 11:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871221123892?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Agents, Agency, and Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/73/5&quot;&gt;Volume 73, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 445-448, November/December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2022 11:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871221123724?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The view from Robinswood Hill: a story of asset-based community development and a community-based participatory research partnership in South Gloucestershire</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2022 01:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2126379?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-30-2022 01:58</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2022.2115786?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using theoretical and empirical background information to affect noticing of geometrical thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of the current study was to investigate whether exposing teachers to theoretical and empirical background information regarding pedagogical aspects of geometrical thinking would affect their noticing abilities. Forty-one in-service Mathematics teachers participated in this study. The research tools used in the study included a lesson taken from the VIDEO-LM project and articles that were all presented to the teachers. Our work with an open-ended questionnaire and mixed-methods analysis revealed that exposing in-service teachers to theoretical and empirical articles may affect the three components of their professional noticing performance: attending, interpreting, and responding. After the exposure to the articles, the teachers exhibited a greater focus on the specific difficulties inherent in the specific task at hand and their subsequent interpretations of those difficulties and responses to those difficulties were also more specific than they had been before the intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 16:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10176-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking foreshadowing in mathematics teachers’ planned practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper provides an empirical exploration of mathematics teachers’ planned practices. Specifically, it explores the practice of foreshadowing, which was one of Wasserman’s (2015) four mathematical teaching practices. The study analyzed n = 16 lessons that were planned by pairs of highly qualified and experienced secondary mathematics teachers, as well as the dialogue that transpired, to identify the considerations the teachers made during this planning process. The paper provides empirical evidence that teachers engage in foreshadowing as they plan lessons, and it exemplifies four ways teachers engaged in this practice: foreshadowing concepts, foreshadowing techniques, foregrounding concepts, and foregrounding techniques. Implications for mathematics teacher education are discussed.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 16:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10152-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Arithmetic word problem solving. Analysis of Singaporean and Spanish textbooks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The success or failure of education systems in promoting student problem-solving skills depends on attitudinal, political, and pedagogical variables. Among these variables, the design of mathematics textbooks is thought to partially explain why students from high-achieving countries show better problem-solving ability in international assessments. In the current study, we delved into this question and compared the frequency and characteristics of arithmetic word problems (AWPs) contained in primary school math textbooks in two countries with different levels of performance in international assessments—Singapore and Spain. In our analyses, we focused on (1) the quantity of arithmetic word problems, (2) the variety of problems in terms of their additive or multiplicative structures and semantic-mathematical substructures, and (3) the quantity and nature of illustrations that were presented together with arithmetic word problems. Although a larger proportion of AWP activities was found in Singaporean textbooks, the results showed a similar variety of AWPs in both Singaporean and Spanish math textbooks. Furthermore, in both countries, math textbooks emphasized the structures classified as (additive) combine 1 and (multiplication) simple rate in AWPs. Notably, the Singaporean textbook contained a larger percentage of illustrations that reflected the semantic-mathematical structures of the problems and helped students learn how to solve AWPs (e.g., bar models). The findings are discussed in light of theories that posit that textbooks constitute a fundamental part of the teaching–learning process in the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 16:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10169-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do mathematicians and undergraduates agree about explanation quality?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Offering explanations is a central part of teaching mathematics, and understanding those explanations is a vital activity for learners. Given this, it is natural to ask what makes a good mathematical explanation. This question has received surprisingly little attention in the mathematics education literature, perhaps because the field has no agreed method by which explanation quality can be reliably assessed. In this paper, we explore this issue by asking whether mathematicians and undergraduates agree with each other about explanation quality. A corpus of 10 explanations produced by 10 mathematicians was used. Using a comparative judgement method, we analysed 320 paired comparisons from 16 mathematicians and 320 from 32 undergraduate students. We found that both mathematicians and undergraduates were able to reliably assess the quality of a set of mathematical explanations. Furthermore, the assessments were largely consistent across the two groups. Implications for theories of mathematical explanation are discussed. We conclude by arguing that comparative judgement is a promising technique for exploring explanation quality.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 16:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10164-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing covariation as a form of conceptual understanding through comparative judgement</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper focuses on the importance of covariational reasoning within the processes of mathematics teaching and learning. Despite the internationally recognized relevance of covariation, research shows that only a small percentage of students and teachers is able to adopt covariational reasoning and the majority of mathematics curricula do not contain explicit references to covariational skills. In particular, when covariational reasoning manifests as conceptual knowledge, it becomes challenging to assess, and the need for innovative methods of assessment emerges; there is a need for suitable assessment to highlight the characteristics of covariation and capture the various features that characterize conceptual understanding. Comparative judgement (CJ) is an innovative assessment method based on collective expert judgements of students’ work rather than requiring scoring rubrics. Due to its holistic approach, CJ is particularly suitable for assessing complex mathematical competencies, and, as we shall see in this study, it proved to be appropriate for the covariation’s assessment. In details, our study aims to investigate the perception and relevance attributed by mathematics teachers to covariation as a theoretical construct and the way CJ can help in the assessment of covariational reasoning skills underlying a less structured modelling task.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 16:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10178-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Changes in students’ self-efficacy when learning a new topic in mathematics: a micro-longitudinal study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Self-efficacy in mathematics is related to engagement, persistence, and academic performance. Prior research focused mostly on examining changes to students’ self-efficacy across large time intervals (months or years), and paid less attention to changes at the level of lesson sequences. Knowledge of how self-efficacy changes during a sequence of lessons is important as it can help teachers better support students’ self-efficacy in their everyday work. In this paper, we expanded previous studies by investigating changes in students’ self-efficacy across a sequence of 3–4 lessons when students were learning a new topic in mathematics (n&lt;sub class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Students&lt;/sub&gt; = 170, n&lt;sub class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Time-points&lt;/sub&gt; = 596). Nine classes of Norwegian grade 6 (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 77) and grade 10 students (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 93) reported their self-efficacy for easy, medium difficulty, and hard tasks. Using multilevel models for change, we found (a) change of students’ self-efficacy across lesson sequences, (b) differences in the starting point and change of students’ self-efficacy according to perceived task difficulty and grade, (c) more individual variation of self-efficacy starting point and change in association with harder tasks, and (d) students in classes who were taught a new topic in geometry had stronger self-efficacy at the beginning of the first lesson as compared to those who were taught a new topic in algebra (grade 10), and students in classes who were taught a new topic in fractions had steeper growth across the lesson sequence as compared to those who were taught a new topic in measurement (grade 6). Implications for both research and practice on how new mathematics topics are introduced to students are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 16:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10165-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Luc Trouche, Ghislaine Gueudet, &amp;amp; Birgit Pepin (Eds.) (2019) The ‘resource’ approach to mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 16:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10146-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Connecting characterizations of equivalence of expressions: design research in Grade 5 by bridging graphical and symbolic representations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;One typical challenge in algebra education is that many students justify the equivalence of expressions only by referring to transformation rules that they perceive as arbitrary without being able to justify these rules. A good algebraic understanding involves connecting the transformation rules to other characterizations of equivalence of expressions (e.g., description equivalence that both expressions describe the same situation or figure). In order to overcome this disconnection even before variables are introduced, a design research study was conducted in Grade 5 to design and investigate an early algebra learning environment to establish stronger connections between different mental models and representations of equivalence of expressions. The qualitative analysis of design experiments with 14 fifth graders revealed deep insights into complexities of connecting representations. It confirmed that many students first relate the representations in ways that are too superficial without establishing deep connections. Analyzing successful students’ processes helped to identify an additional characterization that can support students in bridging the connection between other characterizations, which we call restructuring equivalence. By including learning opportunities for restructuring equivalence, students can be supported to compare expressions in graphical and symbolic representation simultaneously and dynamically. The design research study disentangles the complex requirements for realizing the design principle of connecting multiple representations, which should be of relevance beyond the specific concept of equivalence and applicable to other mathematical topics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 16:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10158-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Supporting English non-dominant language authors’ efforts to publish: perspectives from the editors-in-chief of highly recognised journals in Mathematics Education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this article, we document the support provided by highly recognised journals in Mathematics Education in response to the challenges faced by English non-dominant language (EnDL) authors when they attempt to publish in English. To address this issue, we first conducted a synthesis of research literature related to those influences that direct EnDL authors’ publication efforts towards English language journals and the associated challenges that result. Second, we gathered survey and interview data from participant editors-in-chief of leading journals in Mathematics Education about the support, enacted and planned, provided by their journal for EnDL authors and associated challenges. Finally, we discuss the findings of the study from the perspective of heteroglossia. Findings indicate that while a range of initiatives have been employed to support EnDL authors, current journal policies lag somewhat behind the plans of editors-in-chief, which have been limited, to date, by available resources.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 16:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10174-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Framing and Efficacy of University-Required Diversity Courses in the Research Literature</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This literature review examines the research in the last 30 years in relation to university-required diversity courses, as well as highlights areas that have been understudied. Utilizing the social justice rationale for diversity, this review analyzes 25 quantitative and qualitative research articles that address university-required diversity courses. This literature review unpacks the mixed results from quantitative studies as well as analyzes the case studies presented in qualitative research. The results highlight that addressing student bias is an important goal and framework for these courses, but that the ability to shift quantitative measures of bias is not clear. I also argue that research examining student work produced in required diversity courses and course design for strategies is largely absent from the field of study.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 05:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221123793?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The learning and teaching of number. Paths less travelled through well-trodden terrain</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 05:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2022.2129139?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effect of COVID on Oral Reading Fluency During the 2020–2021 Academic Year</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Education has faced unprecedented disruption during the COVID pandemic. Understanding how students have adapted as we have entered a different phase of the pandemic and some communities have returned to more typical schooling will inform a suite of policy interventions and subsequent research. We use data from an oral reading fluency (ORF) assessment—a rapid assessment taking only a few minutes that measures a fundamental reading skill—to examine COVID’s effects on children’s reading ability during the pandemic. We find that students in the first 200 days of the 2020–2021 school year tended to experience slower growth in ORF relative to prepandemic years. We also observe slower growth in districts with a high percentage of English language learners and/or students eligible for free and reduced-price lunch. These findings offer valuable insight into the effects of COVID on one of the most fundamental skills taught to children.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 04:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221120254?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Structures and representations used by 6th graders when working with quadratic functions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study lies within the field of early-age algebraic thinking and focuses on describing the functional thinking exhibited by six sixth-graders (11- to 12-year-olds) enrolled in a curricular enhancement program. To accomplish the goals of this research, the structures the students established and the representations they used to express the generalization of the functional relationship were analyzed. A questionnaire was designed with three geometric tasks involving the use of continuous variables in quadratic functions. The students were asked to calculate the areas of certain figures for which some data were known, and subsequently to formulate the general rule. The results show that the participating students had difficulties expressing structures involving quadratic functions. However, they displayed the potential to use different types of representations to establish the functional relationship. The originality of this study lies in the differences observed in the process of generalization with discrete variables, since, in the case of continuous variables, students could recognize the general expression from analyzing the set of values that can be attributed to the variables in an interval.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01423-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Distance mathematics education in Flanders, Germany, and the Netherlands during the COVID 19 lockdown—the student perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In March 2020, many schools worldwide were closed due to the COVID-19 pandemic. This closure confronted mathematics teachers with the challenging transition to emergency remote teaching (ERT). How did students experience ERT, and how did these experiences relate to context variables and to their teachers’ beliefs and practices? In particular, what didactic approaches and formative assessment practices did secondary mathematics students experience, and which beliefs did they hold concerning digital mathematics education? How were these student experiences and beliefs related to student context variables (gender, need to support family, personal home equipment), teacher beliefs, delivery modes, and student appreciation of mathematics? To investigate these issues, we set out online questionnaires for mathematics teachers and their students in Flanders—the Dutch-speaking part of Belgium—, Germany, and the Netherlands. Data consisted of completed questionnaires by 323 mathematics teachers and 2126 of their students. Results show that even though students preferred regular face-to-face teaching, they were content with the quality of their teachers’ distance mathematics teaching. Students reported that they were taught new topics often, but did not experience teachers initiating peer feedback. High student appreciation of mathematics, good home environment, and more synchronous delivery of ERT were related to ERT experiences and more positive beliefs concerning digital mathematics education. These findings have implications for ERT teaching strategies in future, as well as for hybrid teaching practices.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01409-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“How to meme it”: reverse engineering the creative process of mathematical Internet memes</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical Internet memes are examples of how the creative thrust characterising the Web 2.0 environment reaches the field of mathematics, translating mathematical statements into a new digital form endowed with an epistemic potential that is capable of initiating a process of mathematical argumentation. The research presented in this paper aims to shed light on the creative process of mathematical memes, contributing to building a body of knowledge on mathematical memes that, prospectively, could enable educators to profit from these objects in their teaching. Theoretically, this is based on a widened concept of creativity that focuses on the connection linking digital culture with mathematics, and on distinguishing and merging three perspectives to disclose the meanings of mathematical memes. Methodologically, the process of mathematical memes’ creation is investigated through a reverse engineering approach on a dataset of about 2100 items collected in a 3-year-long ethnographic observation within online communities. The result is a heuristic action model of the creation process, that is validated by creating two new mathematical Internet memes that are shared online within the observed communities to explore if they retain the mathematical and epistemic characteristics of Web-found ones.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-29-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10173-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The multi-dimensionality of early algebraic thinking: background, overarching dimensions, and new directions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Early algebraic thinking is the reasoning engaged in by 5- to 12-year-olds as they build meaning for the objects and ways of thinking to be encountered within the later study of secondary school algebra. Ever since the 1990s when interest in developing algebraic thinking in the earlier grades began to emerge, there has been a steady growth in the research devoted to exploring ways of fostering this thinking. While in its early days this research had to grapple with the question of what kinds of algebraic thinking might be feasible for the younger student, the evolution of the field over the past 30 years has led to an ever-increasing range of activity that is truly multi-dimensional. In this survey paper, I have framed the multi-dimensionality of early algebraic thinking according to three overarching types, namely, that of analytic thinking, structural thinking, and functional thinking, with generalizing being the scarlet thread that runs through all three. The first part of the paper looks back to the history of the notion of early algebra and the initial research efforts aimed at characterizing early algebraic thinking. The second part delineates the three overarching theoretical dimensions of early algebraic thinking, presents a sampling of past empirical findings, and points to some of the more recent work in the field, including the contributions to this Special Issue. The paper concludes by highlighting the new directions of this domain of research and offering suggestions for further research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-28-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01435-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of algebraic thinking in dealing with negative numbers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;To date, of the many studies on early algebraic thinking, none, to our knowledge, has examined the relationships between algebraic thinking and negative numbers. Students encounter persistent difficulties in dealing with these numbers, and we believe that these could be addressed through the development of algebraic thinking. We are particularly interested in relational thinking, a form of algebraic thinking involved in generalised arithmetic, characterised by the ability to identify the structure of an expression as well as the relationships between numbers. The idea of the ‘subtractive number’ has been highlighted in this context. The aim of the study was to investigate the role of relational thinking in dealing with negative numbers. We submitted a paper-and-pencil test to 166 grade 6 students in order to analyse their skills in operations with integers, as well as their relational thinking in questions relating to the compensation strategy in subtraction. We then examined the extent to which the students who answered the compensation questions correctly performed the operations with integers better than those who answered them incorrectly. Our results showed that students’ ability to see the subtraction operation as a ‘transformation’ involving a unary use of the minus sign appears to be a factor in their success in operations with negatives. Few students demonstrated this ability, yet it can be seen as an essential stage on which to base the progressive development of relational thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-28-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01402-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mis-in and mis-out concept images: the case of even numbers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reports on concept images of 38 secondary school mathematics prospective teachers, regarding the evenness of numbers. Written assignments, individual interviews, and lesson transcripts uncover salient, erroneous concept images of even numbers as numbers that are two times “something” (i.e., &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;2i&lt;/em&gt; is an even number), or to reject the evenness of zero. The notion of concept image serves in the analysis of the findings, and the findings serve in offering two refinement notions: &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;mis-in&lt;/em&gt; concept images that mistakenly grant non-examples the status of examples (e.g., &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;2i&lt;/em&gt; is an even number), and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;mis-out&lt;/em&gt; concept images that mistakenly regard examples as non-examples (e.g., zero is not an even number). We discuss possible benefits in distinguishing between these two refinement notions in mathematics education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-28-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10183-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ understanding and development of the definition of circle in Taxicab and Euclidean geometries: an APOS perspective with schema interaction</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Action-Process-Object-Schema (APOS) theory and the triad of schema development are used as the framework in this study to investigate students’ understanding of the concept of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;circle&lt;/em&gt;. In this report, results are presented from the data analysis of responses to questions in semi-structured interviews of 15 students enrolled in a college geometry course at a university. This report utilizes a framework describing the interaction of the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Taxicab geometry&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Euclidean geometry&lt;/em&gt; schemata to determine what components of these, and what relationships between them, were evoked when these participating students elaborated on their understanding of the circle concept. By adapting and transferring their knowledge of concepts back and forth between these two geometries, the participants demonstrated a variety of levels of schema interaction when responding to interview questions pertaining to circles. As a result, a model of schema interaction and pedagogical suggestions to help students better develop their &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;circle schema&lt;/em&gt; are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-28-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10180-2</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
