<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The multi-dimensionality of early algebraic thinking: background, overarching dimensions, and new directions</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Early algebraic thinking is the reasoning engaged in by 5- to 12-year-olds as they build meaning for the objects and ways of thinking to be encountered within the later study of secondary school algebra. Ever since the 1990s when interest in developing algebraic thinking in the earlier grades began to emerge, there has been a steady growth in the research devoted to exploring ways of fostering this thinking. While in its early days this research had to grapple with the question of what kinds of algebraic thinking might be feasible for the younger student, the evolution of the field over the past 30 years has led to an ever-increasing range of activity that is truly multi-dimensional. In this survey paper, I have framed the multi-dimensionality of early algebraic thinking according to three overarching types, namely, that of analytic thinking, structural thinking, and functional thinking, with generalizing being the scarlet thread that runs through all three. The first part of the paper looks back to the history of the notion of early algebra and the initial research efforts aimed at characterizing early algebraic thinking. The second part delineates the three overarching theoretical dimensions of early algebraic thinking, presents a sampling of past empirical findings, and points to some of the more recent work in the field, including the contributions to this Special Issue. The paper concludes by highlighting the new directions of this domain of research and offering suggestions for further research.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-28-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01435-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mis-in and mis-out concept images: the case of even numbers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper reports on concept images of 38 secondary school mathematics prospective teachers, regarding the evenness of numbers. Written assignments, individual interviews, and lesson transcripts uncover salient, erroneous concept images of even numbers as numbers that are two times “something” (i.e., &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;2i&lt;/em&gt; is an even number), or to reject the evenness of zero. The notion of concept image serves in the analysis of the findings, and the findings serve in offering two refinement notions: &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;mis-in&lt;/em&gt; concept images that mistakenly grant non-examples the status of examples (e.g., &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;2i&lt;/em&gt; is an even number), and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;mis-out&lt;/em&gt; concept images that mistakenly regard examples as non-examples (e.g., zero is not an even number). We discuss possible benefits in distinguishing between these two refinement notions in mathematics education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-28-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10183-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ understanding and development of the definition of circle in Taxicab and Euclidean geometries: an APOS perspective with schema interaction</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Action-Process-Object-Schema (APOS) theory and the triad of schema development are used as the framework in this study to investigate students’ understanding of the concept of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;circle&lt;/em&gt;. In this report, results are presented from the data analysis of responses to questions in semi-structured interviews of 15 students enrolled in a college geometry course at a university. This report utilizes a framework describing the interaction of the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Taxicab geometry&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Euclidean geometry&lt;/em&gt; schemata to determine what components of these, and what relationships between them, were evoked when these participating students elaborated on their understanding of the circle concept. By adapting and transferring their knowledge of concepts back and forth between these two geometries, the participants demonstrated a variety of levels of schema interaction when responding to interview questions pertaining to circles. As a result, a model of schema interaction and pedagogical suggestions to help students better develop their &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;circle schema&lt;/em&gt; are provided.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-28-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10180-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Clearing up misconceptions about project-based learning</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 26-31, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; After 30 years of practicing, researching, and teaching project-based learning (PBL), Steven Wolk offers insight into what he has learned. He discusses what PBL is and responds to common misunderstandings about how it works. He describes how PBL units are structured, the role of direct instruction in PBL, how students learn content and skills through PBL, and the importance of a culture of inquiry to a PBL classroom. And he shares inspirational ideas for how teachers and schools can take PBL even further, such as by designing problem-based PBL units.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130630?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Person: Lessons in obedience — and resistance</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 56-57, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Long-time educator Dr. Sidney Trubowitz recalls his years as an elementary school student in the late 1930s. His teachers were rigid, students were taught to be quiet and compliant, and Trubowitz learned to follow instructions without questioning them. When one teacher went too far with her discipline, his mother, an immigrant, stood up for him — one of many acts of rebellion that Trubowitz observed with satisfaction. He draws on these memories to underscore the importance of bringing children into the learning process and treating them, in all their complexity, as complete and curious independent beings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130636?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On Leadership: Getting the community on the path toward equity</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 58-59, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Soon after Xavier Botana took over as superintendent of Maine’s Portland Public Schools, he realized that, despite the district’s professed commitment, efforts to promote equity were embedded in other programs rather than being its own goal. He knew that if he were going to make his vision for equity a reality, he would need to get the community’s commitment to the effort. Joshua Starr discusses why community engagement is essential to the success of equity initiatives and describes how leaders like Botana can build a team of supporters within the school district and across the wider community.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130637?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under The Law: Prayer huddle</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-61, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Past U.S. Supreme Court rulings have held that schools and school employees must be careful to engage in religious activities while at school that could appear to endorse a particular religion above others or coerce students to engage in religious activities. However, the June 2022 Kennedy v. Bremerton School District opinion suggests that the current Court is far more concerned about violating school employees’ free exercise rights. In this case, the Court found that not allowing a football coach to pray, often with students, on the 50-yard line immediately following public school football games violated the coach’s religious free exercise rights. Robert Kim discusses the Court’s history with cases involving religious practice in schools and the potential implications of the Kennedy decision.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130638?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Truly open to all: Three ways to diversify teacher leadership</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 32-36, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Teacher leadership recently has gained prominence as an important method for school improvement and reform, yet the ranks of teacher leaders do not match the racial and ethnic diversity of the students they serve. Jori S. Beck, KaaVonia Hinton, and Brandon M. Butler conducted a study of teacher leadership that garnered almost 800 survey responses and included 31 interviews with administrators and teachers. They discovered how the lack of diversity in the teacher workforce, the myth of meritocracy, and the isolation of teachers of color present barriers to diversifying the teacher leader workforce. Potential solutions include equity audits, revisions to hiring practices, and the distribution of teachers of color within school buildings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130631?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How a university and a school district made change together</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 37-43, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; The University of Rochester and East High School in Rochester, New York, entered into a partnership in 2015, hoping to transform the school to prevent shut down by the state. Both partners were wary because of the district’s failed attempts at reform and the history of similar partnerships elsewhere. A new state-level reform option allowed the partners to form an educational partnership organization (EPO) so that they could become equal partners with some autonomy from the district. The partners decided that to succeed, they would need to involve the community. They learned from listening sessions that the community wanted the school to remain open but also wanted everything about it to change. So, instead of taking an incremental approach, they chose to transform the school’s structures, culture, leadership model, and curriculum and instruction. Valerie L. Marsh, Shaun C. Nelms, Sarah Peyre, and Joanne Larson describe how the university and the school worked together to transform East on all these fronts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130632?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leading through crisis</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 44-49, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; The COVID-19 pandemic, societal racial reckonings, and pressure from parents and the media have put education leaders in a crisis. Carole Learned-Miller of the Leadership Academy in New York spoke with school and education organization leaders who saw their organizations through a variety of challenges, including the pandemic, racial inequities, a teacher strike, and a financial crisis. These leaders shared some of the principles that helped them through. These include building relationships, communicating clearly, listening to other views, having trusted advisers, being true to their values, and staying hopeful. Leaders describe how these principles helped them weather difficult times.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130633?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What middle schoolers need: Respect, accountability, and grace</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 22-24, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; The 2022 National School Counselor of the Year Alma Lopez talks about how her students at California’s Livingston Middle School were impacted by the pandemic. Livingston Middle School is a Title 1 school in California’s Central Valley, with 850 students in 6th, 7th, and 8th grades. Most families in this rural community are farm laborers or food production workers. Livingston Union School District serves about 2,500 students, 80 percent of whom are Latinx. Students and their families suffered losses during the pandemic, and middle schoolers missed out on key opportunities for connection and belonging.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130628?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reaching for consensus about preschool curricula</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 50-55, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; The need for equitable access to high-quality preschool has recently gained unprecedented attention. As states and districts strive to expand access while promoting quality, curriculum quality has emerged as a critical component of preschool programs that promote young children’s learning. Yet many educators make curricular decisions with insufficient guidance on what constitutes curricular quality. Indeed, deep divisions in the field are evident regarding how to define quality in preschool curricula. Jeanne L. Reid and Sharon Lynn Kagan explore the areas of consensus and disagreement among early education leaders. They argue that — using guidance from a study at the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine and drawing from international models of curriculum frameworks — the field can move toward consensus on what constitutes a high-quality curriculum and thus help to fulfill the promise of equitable access to high-quality preschool.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130634?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>‘You just have to get through it’: Letting go of enduring stereotypes about middle school</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 6-10, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; The prevailing cultural narrative about middle school is that those years are extremely difficult, and the best students can hope for is to endure them until finding relief in high school. Nancy Deutsch argues that these years are, in fact, a time of great potential if schools can abandon their stereotypes about young adolescents and create school cultures that build on their energy and willingness to explore new things. Deutsch discusses some common stereotypes about middle school and research findings that reveal the truth about the potential of students in the middle grades.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130624?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: Teacher told to accept feedback more gracefully</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 64-65, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; In the October 2022 Career Confidential, Phyllis Fagell has advice for teachers who are unhappy about the feedback they receive from their principals. An ESOL teacher has trouble accepting critical feedback from a principal who hasn’t taught for more than a decade and has no experience with English learners. Another teacher went through an entire school year without receiving feedback from her principal. She doesn’t want to appear needy, but she’d like to get some ideas for how to improve.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130640?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Artistic License: Celebrating the talents of students and educators</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 72-72, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; This monthly column features an acrylic painting of a school staff member’s pet cat by student Samiksh Laxmana Medudula and an acrylic painting of a bear by K-12 art teacher Sarah Bennett Winter.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130647?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Underchallenged and overly bored: Why rigor is important in the middle school classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 11-16, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Middle schools often struggle to provide students with the necessary academic rigor to promote academic growth. Many students experience academic stagnation when schools fail to provide appropriate academic services. Dani Tinkel’s article examines how the limited priorities of middle school inadvertently promote disengagement and underachievement and what schools can do to ensure that all middle school students have opportunities to be cognitively challenged, including through programs like Advancement Via Individual Determination (AVID) and the Schoolwide Enrichment Model (SEM), by providing a vision for a balanced middle school experience.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130626?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet students in the middle: A culturally responsive, near-peer literacy program</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 17-21, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; The middle school years are important for social and emotional learning, and the COVID-19 pandemic exacerbated social-emotional learning needs. At this age, young people are paying attention to the social world and exploring their identities and need learning environments that respond in kind. Jessica Shiller and Inte’a DeShields describe a model for middle school learning built on their need to connect with their peers, learn about their cultural identities, and receive social and emotional support. Pairing college students with middle schoolers, the model for literacy instruction produced positive results.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130627?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Backtalk: Educate, don’t erase</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 66-67, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; When hate-fueled acts of vandalism or violence happen, school leaders’ impulse is often to sweep them away as quickly as possible. Todd Pittinsky encourages them to use these incidents as opportunities to educate. Students and community members may not be aware of the antisemitism and other forms of hate within their own communities and going public can serve as a wake-up call. Creating educational events in response can give students a sense of empowerment.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130642?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: There’s opportunity in the middle</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; The prevailing narrative about middle school is that it’s a miserable, chaotic time. But, as Teresa Preston explains, the articles in the October 2022 issue of Kappan show that this narrative is based on stereotypes. On the contrary, the characteristics of young adolescents that make them seem awkward and difficult are the same characteristics that make middle school an exciting time for growth. The role of adults is to recognize the potential of middle school students and provide a fertile ground where they can explore, be challenged, connect, find support, and develop their identities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130622?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: How teachers can help middle schoolers</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 68-68, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Educators Rising student officers share stories of the teachers who helped them in middle school. These teachers provided a sanctuary, gave them a vision for the work they could do in the future, and pushed them to try new things.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130643?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 69-69, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; In this regular column, Kappan authors recommend books and articles that have influenced them. Nancy Deutsch shares an article from Human Development that helped her put a name — m(ai)cro — to the combination of forces that guide people’s development. Steven Wolk shares how Carl Rogers’ Freedom to Learn inspired him to see new possibilities when he was beginning his teaching career.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130644?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: The case for democratic reforms in urban school districts</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 62-63, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; The voices of students of color often are left out of discussions of urban school reform conversations when they should be central to reform efforts. Jonathan Collins suggests looking at democratic reform as an avenue to bring those voices forward. Participatory budgeting, for example, introduces students to the idea that they could decide how money is spent at their schools. This allows them to shape their environment and address the problems they see as most pressing.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130639?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: Organizational news about PDK International</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/2&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 2&lt;/a&gt;, Page 71-71, October 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Educators Rising, the preservice division of PDK International for future educators, is devoting the 2022-23 school year to service. Each year, a theme is chosen for rising educators, the membership of Educators Rising, to coalesce aligns their activities around with that year’s theme, all leading up to the group’s national conference. This year’s conference, whose theme is “Serving our community.” The conference will take place at the Renaissance SeaWorld Orlando, from June 29-July 2, 2023.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221130645?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interpreting literal symbols in algebra under the effects of the natural number bias</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-27-2022 01:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2022.2128276?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
