<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Professional Development and Student Reading in Middle and High School: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This systematic review investigates the effect of teacher professional development (TPD) on adolescent students’ reading achievement in middle and high school. A systematic search of TPD and student reading achievement studies (1975–2020) identified 15 medium-quality articles meeting this study’s inclusion criteria. A meta-analysis of 14 of these studies corrected by Hedges’ g showed that TPD on student reading was associated with a small overall effect of g = 0.062, p &amp;lt; .05 on student reading outcomes. However, the effect size was moderated by delivery of the TPD, TPD hours, student population, and assessment. None of the 14 studies reported TPD theory-driven quality indicators for TPD delivery (e.g., school support, use of technology, and promotion of self-reflection or reported measures of teacher change). Conclusion of findings in literacy TPD includes the need for TPD theory-driven studies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 09:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231153084?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Mathematics Teaching Approaches in Tanzanian Higher Education Institutions: Lecturers’ Perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The success of the teaching - learning process in terms of learning outcomes is determined by several factors, primarily the lecturer’s teaching approach used. Despite the importance of the teaching approach, little is known concerning the teaching approaches used by mathematics lecturers in Tanzanian higher education institutions. This study explores the lecturers’ perspectives regarding the teaching approaches they normally use in teaching mathematics, and what motivates their choices, within an emerging economy context. Data are collected through semi-structured interviews with 15 lecturers. Data are analysed using content analysis and descriptive statistics. The findings reveal that lecturers are more likely to choose teacher-centred approaches and that &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;assurance of the right content&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;content coverage&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;time-saving&lt;/em&gt; aspects are associated with choosing this approach. These findings provide insights into the current state in mathematics classroom regarding teaching approaches, and the motivation behind lecturers’ teaching approach choices, complementing current findings in the literature. We categorise the teaching approaches for mathematics teaching – learning by describing the interactions between the different actors in the classroom (teachers, students, and content) in order to inform and influence successful mathematics teaching practices in emerging economies such as Tanzania.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-023-00212-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring, Testing, &amp; Selecting Curriculum Through Lesson Study</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 82-89
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p82.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Subtraction, Decomposition, and Argumentation</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 90-98
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p90.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Big Is a Leaf? Mathematical Modeling Through STEM Inquiry</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 99-107
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p99.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking Wait Time: What Can 3 Seconds Do?</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 108-114
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p108.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Judicious Telling to Strengthen Literacy in Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 115-123
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p115.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Alternative Approach for Defining a Quadratic Function</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 124-131
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p124.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Data Revolution</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 78-79
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p78.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Problems to Ponder</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 132-136
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p132.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GPS: Data Display Development</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 137-142
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p137.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Math, Culture, Language, and Identity for Emergent Bilinguals</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 143-145
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p143.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Is a Journey: Faculty Speech at Closing Assembly</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 146-148
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p146.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Reflections on High-Quality Math Instruction”</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 149-155
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p149.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>My Funny (Mathematical) Valentine</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 2&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 156-156
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/2/article-p156.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inequitable Interactions: A Critical Quantitative Analysis of Mentorship and Psychosocial Development Within Computing Graduate School Pathways</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Mentorship is vital to increasing graduate school access in computing; however, mentorship must be structured in power-conscious, developmental ways to ensure equitable access to and support within computing graduate pathways. I engage a critical quantitative lens to examine mentoring support among undergraduates with reported graduate aspirations, taking a nuanced look at departmental mentorship to investigate how organizational power in computing may maintain inequitable mentoring outcomes. Descriptive and regression analyses draw from a longitudinal sample of 442 graduate aspirants in computing who completed an introductory course survey (between 2015–2017) and a follow-up survey (fall 2019). Results document significant variation in forms of mentoring support and disciplinary psychosocial beliefs (i.e., computing identity and self-efficacy), with key patterns across graduate aspirants’ social identities and mentors’ organizational power (via their departmental roles). I conclude by discussing structural and social inequities in mentorship, which may underscore disparities in students’ realization of their computing graduate aspirations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-31-2023 04:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221143097?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical modelling in the discourses of the KOM and PISA frameworks and teacher interviews</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 12:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2165536?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The spatial contiguity principle in mathematics textbooks</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 12:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2158122?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Book Review: Supporting mathematics educators through and towards online learning. Karen Hollebrands, Robin Anderson, and Kevin Oliver (Eds). (2021) Online learning in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 11:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10175-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical strategies and emergence of socially mediated metacognition within a multi-touch Dynamic Geometry Environment</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Our research aimed to investigate the potential learning benefits to young children of implementing digital interactive multimodal technologies that provide both visual and haptic experiences in elementary mathematics classrooms. We studied the ways in which fourth-grade students collaboratively create collective strategies for solving mathematical problems utilizing dynamic geometry software with multi-touch interfaces, a combination we call a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;multi-touch Dynamic Geometry Environment&lt;/em&gt;. We examine in-depth two case studies each illustrating how mathematical strategies, collaboration, and socially mediated metacognition emerge in the small groups of children while working on an activity using the Geometer’s Sketchpad® on the iPad to make sense of an intuitive idea of covariation&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; We found that children’s interactions with their peers, the interviewer, and the mDGE favored the emergence of varied collaborative behaviors and socially mediated metacognitive processes that fostered the co-construction and development of mathematical strategies over a short period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 11:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10170-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Efficacy and Implementation of Michigan’s Partnership Model of School and District Turnaround: Mixed-Methods Evidence From the First 2 Years of Reform Implementation</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The recent Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) requires states to identify and turn around their lowest performing schools, but it breaks somewhat from prior policies by granting states significant autonomy over how they identify and turn around these schools. This mixed-methods study, which draws on administrative, qualitative, and survey data, examines the effectiveness of Michigan’s approach to school turnaround under ESSA. We find that students in turnaround schools experienced significant achievement gains in math and to a lesser extent in English language arts (ELA), with effects concentrated among the lowest achieving students. Analyses of qualitative and survey data suggest that these outcomes were influenced by state-level supports, strategic planning, the threat of accountability for continued low performance, and improved leadership quality in turnaround schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221141415?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exponential behaviour and variational practices in Chilean newscasts: a socioepistemological view</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The research on which we report in this paper was framed within the socioepistemological theory and dealt with the fundamental role of variational practices in the understanding of COVID-19 pandemic graphs. Given the proliferation of mathematical graphs related to the pandemic in the media, we proposed to analyse the variational practices in use in the interpretation of graphs of exponential behaviour that a Chilean newscast of high rating used to inform the population about the pandemic in Chile. For this purpose, a thematic analysis intertwined with documentary analysis techniques was carried out, in order to describe the types of graphs shown in the newscast, and a variational reference system was studied to analyse the use of variational practices. To obtain our results, the types of graphs most frequently shown in the newscast at the beginning of the pandemic were identified and the use of the variational practices of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;comparison, seriation&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;prediction&lt;/em&gt; in such graphs was analysed. In conclusion, the need is discussed for the conceptual evolution of the exponential function to be accompanied by a pragmatic evolution in school that favours the use and development of variational practices in the student body.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01458-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Navigating multiple languages and meanings in cross-cultural research on teachers’ resource use</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Cross-cultural research covering multiple languages and cultures involves negotiating conceptual and linguistic challenges. This paper focuses on how researchers working across cultural and linguistic boundaries navigate the research process and negotiate a common understanding of the constructs under study. Working towards intersubjectivity within a cross-cultural research team is essential, as it deepens understanding of one another’s contexts and our own. We analyze our own research process, as a cross-cultural team studying elementary school teachers’ use of print and digital instructional resources in Finland, Flanders, Sweden, and the U.S. Recorded team conversations served as data to help us explore the way language and culture are intertwined and how these relationships surface when developing research instruments and conducting analysis of the interviews, in which language became a focal point. Challenges emerged particularly within three research aims, namely, naming and describing teaching practices, understanding teachers’ relationships with mathematics resources, and defining digital resources in a cross-cultural survey. Our systematic analysis of instances of conceptual and linguistic inequivalence prompted the team to make language explicit and revealed that these instances varied in several ways that had implications for how and whether they might be bridged. Thus, this paper contributes to understanding the methodological impact of using a shared language, acknowledging that researchers’ lexicons about mathematics teaching are closely linked to their own cultural knowledge and experience. Therefore, working explicitly across language and culture towards mutual understanding is a necessity and a way to reinforce the validity of research outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01466-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Review of the book “Inquiry in university mathematics teaching and learning: the PLATINIUM project”</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-30-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-023-09569-4</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
