<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing ‘deep mathematical thinking’ in geometry with 3- and 4-year-olds: a collaborative study between early years teachers and university-based mathematicians</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-07-2022 04:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2022.2119497?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preparing emerging educators to provide ethnic studies instruction through participatory action research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2022 10:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2118145?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing equations in early algebra</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The overwhelming presence of a procedural meaning of equality and equations reported in previous research has led to a call for suitable pedagogical interventions to nurture a relational meaning of these concepts. This paper is a response to that call. Drawing on the theory of objectification, the first part deals with the configuration of a Grade 3 (8–9-year-old students) teaching–learning activity that seeks to create the classroom conditions for the formation of the mathematical operations and operation-based rules that underpin the algebraic simplification of linear equations. Instead of using problems involving abstract open arithmetic sentences or alphanumeric equations (e.g., &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(5 + \_\_\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; = 16; &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(2n + 3 = 11\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt;), the teaching–learning activity resorts to story-problems. Two visual semiotic systems serving to model and solve the story-problems were devised. The story-problems were framed in narratives that allowed the teacher and the students to infuse equations, their equating parts, and the mathematical operations with contextual meanings. The first part of the paper includes the theoretical assumptions about the teaching–learning activity and its configuration, and a rationale behind the devisal of the semiotic systems. The second part presents a Vygotskian multimodal genetic analysis of the teaching–learning activity; that is, an analysis that shows the formation of concepts &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;in motion&lt;/em&gt;, in the process of their genesis. The genetic analysis sheds some light on the way students, in their work with the teacher, encountered and refined the cultural-historical algebraic meanings of the equal sign and equations, and the concepts required in solving equations.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01422-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Roles of technologies for future teaching in a pandemic: activity, agency, and humans-with-media</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Research literature on the role of mathematics teachers during the COVID-19 crisis shows that teacher preparation for emergency situations is required. In reporting on this exploratory study, we present and analyse lesson plans created by seven future teachers for mathematics classes during the pandemic. Data were collected between April and October 2021 from 16 four-hour class sessions in a Mathematics Degree Program at a public university in Medellín, Colombia. The notion of Humans-with-Media and the Learning by Expanding theory were used as frameworks to understand what roles prospective mathematics teacher (PMTs) assign to technologies for teaching in pandemic conditions. The PMTs’ uses of technology for teaching mathematics during a pandemic were categorized. The results show that technology was used to reorganize and reproduce mathematics teaching practices. This report addresses the impact of technology on the activity system, and we conclude with a discussion of opportunities and limitations of students’ conceptions about teaching and technology during a pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01429-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Undergraduate Students’ Perceptions of Features of Active Learning Models for Teaching and Learning to Teach Mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The recent push toward active learning – engaging students in the learning process – is meant to benefit students. Yet there is still much to learn about students’ perceptions of this phenomenon. We share results from an interview study of students’ perceptions of features of two active learning models institutionalized at a large doctoral-granting university – a model for teaching foundational mathematics courses and an early field experience model for teaching preservice secondary students to teach mathematics. These models were implemented simultaneously in a single precalculus course. Interviews were conducted with both student populations (i.e., precalculus students and preservice teachers) to understand which in-class features of the models students noticed and identified as beneficial to their learning. Precalculus students identified specific opportunities related to active learning in the undergraduate mathematics teaching model – working in groups on mathematics tasks that engaged students in sensemaking and interacting with their instructor around mathematics. Preservice teachers identified specific opportunities related to three features of the university field experience model – observing a mathematics instructor enacting ambitious instructional practices, planning and teaching a “real” lesson, and observing student thinking and practicing teaching moves during groupwork. We conclude with pedagogical recommendations about particular features of the models that may help mitigate student resistance to active learning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00191-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the Perceived Relevance of University Mathematics Studies by First-Semester Teaching Students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;As earlier research results suggest that many mathematics teaching students criticize a missing relevance in their studies, we explore explanations and interrelationships of their relevance assessments. We aim at finding out how one could support the students in attributing relevance to their study programs. A two-fold model for relevance assessments in mathematics teacher education is proposed, consisting of relevance content and relevance reasons. We investigate students&#39; relevance perceptions of mathematical topics and of topics’ complexities, as well as their rating of individual and societal/ vocational relevance reasons, all in relation to their perception of the relevance of their overall program of study. Contrary to earlier research findings, our results suggest that mathematics teaching students already do attribute relevance to many content areas and that a preparation for the teaching profession is not the only reason for them to assign relevance. There also seem to be many students who would attribute relevance if they could develop as individuals and pursue their interests. We suggest that giving students opportunities to set individual priorities in their studies could hence support their relevance assessments. As low relevance assessments seem to be connected to students’ motivational problems, students might profit from motivational support, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-06-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00188-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Centering Equity in Teacher Education Evaluation: From Principles to Transformative Enactment</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Since the early 2000s, accountability and evaluation have been regarded by policymakers as key mechanisms for “fixing” teacher education and by many teacher education leaders as vehicles for elevating the status of the profession and uniting a fragmented field. Although educational inequity has been an enduring and endemic problem during the same time period, most major policy proposals regarding teacher education evaluation and accountability have said very little about equity. This article makes an argument for equity-centered teacher education evaluation and accountability by highlighting nine innovative examples that collectively illustrate what it means and what it looks like to position equity at the center of teacher education evaluation/accountability. Together, these examples are intended to be generative, providing a lens into how the interrelated dimensions of strong equity-centered evaluation play out at different sites of practice and how equity initiatives emerge and operate at different levels of policy.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2022 10:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871221123728?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Institutional Change and the Rise of an Ecosystem Model in Education Philanthropy</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2022 09:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120271?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Examination of State Statutes and School District Policies Addressing Minors With Do Not Resuscitate Orders</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Due to advances in medical treatments, students with terminal illnesses are more likely to attend public schools, increasing the possibility that they may die on school property. However, educational health plans often fail to consider end-of-life care decisions. In the absence of federal or state statutes, school boards are left to navigate the issue of minors with Do Not Resuscitate Orders while at school. We examine state statutes and school board polices for minors with Do Not Resuscitate Orders attending or wishing to attend school. Themes from school district policies are discussed, and recommendations for federal, state, and local policymakers are made.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2022 05:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120278?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estimating the Impact of Emergency Assistance on Educational Progress for Low-Income Adults: Experimental and Nonexperimental Evidence</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Methods for estimating causal impact aim to either remove or reduce bias. This study estimates the degree of bias reduction obtained from regression adjustment and propensity score methods when only a weak set of predictors are available. The study uses an experimental test of providing emergency financial assistance to participants in a job training program to estimate an experimental benchmark and compares it to nonexperimental estimates of the impact of receiving assistance. When estimating the impact of receiving assistance, those who received it constitute the treatment group. The study explores two different comparison groups: those who could have (because they were assigned to the experimental treatment group) but did not receive emergency assistance; and those who could not receive emergency assistance because they were randomly assigned to the experimental control group. It uses these groups to estimate impacts by applying three estimation strategies: unadjusted mean comparison, regression adjustment, and inverse propensity weighting. It then compares these estimates to the experimental benchmark using statistical tests recommended by the within-study comparison literature. The nonexperimental approaches to addressing selection bias suggest large positive impacts. These are statistically different from the experimental benchmark, which shows that receipt of emergency assistance does not improve educational progress. Further, over 90% of the bias from a simple comparison of means remains. Unless a stronger set of predictors are available, future evaluations of such interventions should be wary of relying on these methods for either unbiased estimation of impacts or bias reduction.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2022 02:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221118454?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Correction: Learning as a critical encounter with the other: prospective teachers conversing with the history of mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-05-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01428-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The effect of the use of concept cartoons on students’ success in mathematics (time measurement)</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-03-2022 03:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2022.2117127?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Observing Intellectual Need and its Relationship with Undergraduate Students’ Learning of Calculus</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The concept of intellectual need, which proposes that learning is the result of students wrestling with a problem that is unsolvable by their current knowledge, has been used in instructional design for many years. However, prior research has not described a way to empirically determine whether, and to what extent, students experience intellectual need. In this paper, we present a methodology for identifying students’ intellectual need and report the results of a study that investigated students’ reactions to intellectual need-provoking tasks in first-semester calculus classes. We also explore the relationship between intellectual need, affective need, and students’ learning. Although the overall percentage of students who reported experiencing an intellectual need was low, we found positive associations between intellectual need and learning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-03-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00192-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sites of Educational Conflict</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Books for and in schools are commodities. They form a central part of the political economy of publishing. They are also, profoundly, sites of cultural and ideological conflict. While always there, there are periods when these economic and ideological conflicts are even more powerful. This is just such a time. This reality asks us to also examine places in school buildings that might (often wrongly) seem to some people to be “less important.” Among these places is the school library as a resource, a teaching device, an access point to things seen as controversial, a mirror of conflicts and economic and political transformations, and for many students, at times a sanctuary. American Public School Librarianship: A History provides us with a richly sourced account of the development of a key pedagogic site in schools and of many of the personal, institutional, and political reasons why they do—and do not do—certain things.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2022 06:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120275?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Algebraic reasoning in years 5 and 6: classifying its emergence and progression using reverse fraction tasks</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper builds on our previous research and investigates how students’ fractional competence and reasoning can provide clear evidence of non-symbolic algebraic thinking and its progressive transition towards fully generalised algebraic thinking. In a large-scale study, 470 primary students completed a written paper and pencil test. This included three reverse fraction tasks which required students to find an unknown whole when presented with a quantity representing a fraction of that whole. Seventeen students from one participating primary school undertook a semi-structured interview which included reverse fraction tasks, similar to those on the written test, but with progressive levels of abstraction, starting with particular instances and becoming more generalised. Two important products of the study are the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Classification Framework for Reverse Fraction Tasks&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Emerging Algebraic Reasoning Framework&lt;/em&gt;. The interview results highlight two critical transition points for the emergence of students’ algebraic reasoning. The first is the ability to transition from additive strategies to multiplicative strategies to solve reverse fraction problems. Students reliant on diagrams and additive strategies struggled to solve more generalised tasks that required multiplicative rather than additive strategies. The second transition is the shift from multiplicative thinking to algebraic reasoning where students could generalise their multiplicative knowledge to deal with any quantity represented in a reverse fraction task.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-02-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01426-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Situating Expectancies and Subjective Task Values Across Grade Levels, Domains, and Countries: A Network Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In their recently renamed theory, situated expectancy-value theory (SEVT), Eccles and Wigfield (2020) emphasized the importance of situations in influencing individuals’ motivational beliefs and academic choices. Adopting a novel approach—network analysis—this study aimed to examine how situations may impact the associations among expectancies, subjective task values, and achievement from a holistic perspective. In this study, situations were operationalized as grade levels (i.e., 6th –9th grade), subject domains (i.e., language arts and math), and countries (i.e., Finland and Germany). Adolescents from Finland (N = 4,062) and Germany (N = 449) were included in the study. Results showed that, overall, the networks are mostly subject bound, yearly varied, and country specific, supporting the situative nature of SEVT. We also found that expectancies were consistently the closest motivational beliefs to achievement, whereas utility values were the least close, implying that expectancies, not utility, might be the most desirable intervention targets for achievement improvement.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2022 12:57</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221117168?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the Evolution of Environment, Social and Governance Research: Novel Implications From Bibliometric and Network Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Given the scarcity of comprehensive review studies in the literature, this bibliometric analysis thrives on taking a scientific approach to delivering quantitative and qualitative information on the ever-evolving field of ESG. Utilizing the performance analysis and science mapping techniques which includes citation analysis, co-word analysis, the study reports a holistic overview of 693 (ESG) papers from 1991 to 2020. The paper aims to provide a unified perspective on the evolution and further identify future research directions in this field. The findings point to the most important countries, authors, studies, and top journals in this field. Results show that published articles on ESG gained momentum after 2006; however, an exponential rise is being observed in the past 5 years, with research focusing on sustainable finance, sustainable development, ESG, and CSR with themes extending to risk management, stakeholder engagement, and portfolio construction, among others. Furthermore, the research identifies how the practice of ESG reporting affects many variables such as financial performance, social performance, environmental performance, and sustainability score. The findings also indicate that the field of ESG is still evolving, with numerous unexplored themes. The work is novel and relevant on the pretext that it uses the Scopus and Web of Science databases for bibliometric mapping, whereas previous studies have used the Scopus database but have lacked a robust methodology, so the findings of this study provided strong support for identifying emerging paradigms in the ESG literature.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2022 12:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221121244?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Districts Using Weighted Student Funding Formulas Deliver More Dollars to Low-income Students?</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2022 04:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2109912?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Non-Randomised Studies of Interventions Provide Unbiased Effect Estimates? A Systematic Review of Internal Replication Studies</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Background: Non-randomized studies of intervention effects (NRS), also called quasi-experiments, provide useful decision support about development impacts. However, the assumptions underpinning them are usually untestable, their verification resting on empirical replication. The internal replication study aims to do this by comparing results from a causal benchmark study, usually a randomized controlled trial (RCT), with those from an NRS conducted at the same time in the sampled population. Objectives: We aimed to determine the credibility and generalizability of findings in internal replication studies in development economics, through a systematic review and meta-analysis. Research Design: We systematically searched for internal replication studies of RCTs conducted on socioeconomic interventions in low- and middle-income countries. We critically appraised the benchmark randomized studies, using an adapted tool. We extracted and statistically synthesized empirical measures of bias. Results: We included 600 estimates of correspondence between NRS and benchmark RCTs. All internal replication studies were found to have at least “some concerns” about bias and some had high risk of bias. We found that study designs with selection on unobservables, in particular regression discontinuity, on average produced absolute standardized bias estimates that were approximately zero, that is, equivalent to the estimates produced by RCTs. But study conduct also mattered. For example, matching using pre-tests and nearest neighbor algorithms corresponded more closely to the benchmarks. Conclusions: The findings from this systematic review confirm that NRS can produce unbiased estimates. Authors of internal replication studies should publish pre-analysis protocols to enhance their credibility.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2022 02:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221116721?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Consideration of Alternative Sample Spaces Used in Coin-Toss Problems</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper examines coin-toss comparison questions from two recent studies involving undergraduate students and high school teachers and connects to findings from two prior studies in the literature. Considering possible sample spaces employed by participants, this is a reflection on whether one sequence could be more likely depending on the interpretation of the question. To critique the choice of sequences and determine possible scenarios in which one sequence may be more likely than the other, three alternative sample spaces were explored. It was determined that different sample spaces can lead to one sequence being more likely to occur than the other. Further evaluation discusses whether alternative sample spaces may have been utilised by the participants in each of the studies, and hence, the paper concludes with an advocacy to enquire deeper into participants’ reasoning when investigating coin-toss questions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00224-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Volume 11: Issue 1 (Sep 2022): September 2022</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/11/1/mte.11.issue-1.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of Mathematics Teacher Educator on Our Colleagues and Our Field</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 11&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 3-8
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/11/1/article-p3.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Design Principles That Support Course Design Innovation for Elementary Mathematics Methods Courses</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 11&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 9-25
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/11/1/article-p9.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Filling a “Void”: The Mathematical Quality in Planning Protocol for Mathematics Teacher Educators</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher Educator&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 11&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 26-39
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>09-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mte/11/1/article-p26.xml</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
