<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Factors explaining students’ engagement and self-reported outcomes in a project-based learning case</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2022 07:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2022.2150997?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emerging Proof Productions of Freshmen in Euclidean Geometry Proof Tasks between Conjecturing and Proving</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/uiml20/14/4&quot;&gt;Volume 14, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, October 2022, Page 320-342&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2022 06:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2145100?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racial identity exploration and academic belonging: LatinX faculty navigating the counters of Latinidad</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2022 05:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2154373?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Testimonios of teaching from four latina first-year teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2022 05:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2154332?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Asian Americans and the battle against affirmative action: opposition to race-based admissions as neoliberal racial subjectivity performance</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2022 05:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2154331?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Improving Children’s Understanding of Mathematical Equivalence: An Efficacy Study</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-07-2022 03:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2144787?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>(Re)Constructing Teacher Knowledge: Old Quests for New Reform</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jtea/74/1&quot;&gt;Volume 74, Issue 1&lt;/a&gt;, Page 5-9, January/February 2023. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2022 05:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871221137622?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preparing educational leaders through action research</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article explores the development, structure, and continuous improvement model of an Action Research education doctorate program research methodology course sequence. The aim of the study is to articulate a rigorous Action Research methodology course sequence and the collaborative faculty process utilized to create and continuously improve upon the research curriculum. The doctoral program under study utilizes a qualitative-dominant Action Research methodology as its signature pedagogy, integrating cycles of research into coursework before students implement and evaluate their action steps. To ensure students receive a thorough understanding of Action Research methodology, the program requires a four-research course sequence. These courses have been designed with a scaffolded approach that progressively reinforces and extends Action Research methods in ways that promote change agency, inclusivity, and social justice. This research course sequence is designed to build a rigorous foundation for students to conduct high quality Action Research that impacts their professional practice and academic scholarship and leads to transformative learning experiences for students, faculty, organizations, and communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2022 04:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221143872?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>In-between the West and the other: Postcolonial contradictions in Korean Students’ understandings of Islam</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2022 01:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2022.2154372?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating pre-service teachers’ statistical literacy capabilities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In recent years, numeracy has had an increasing focus in the Australian educational system, with policies and assessments in place for both students and teachers. In order to address the requirements of their careers, teachers need to have sufficient numeracy capabilities. In our study, we explored the numeracy capabilities of post-graduate pre-service teachers enrolled in a numeracy unit at an Australian university. Specifically, we investigated participants’ statistical literacy capabilities by examining responses to a multi-part question involving the analysis of Australian National Assessment Program—Literacy and Numeracy (NAPLAN) data presented graphically. Participants’ multiple-choice answers were analysed quantitatively. To assess the depth of participants’ statistical literacy reasoning, the explanations for their responses were analysed qualitatively using an adaptation of the Structure of Learning Outcomes (SOLO) taxonomy levels. Although the vast majority of participants exhibited strong basic statistical literacy skills, few participants demonstrated high-level statistical reasoning. Surprisingly, there were few differences in the response patterns of participants who had or had not studied university mathematics in their undergraduate studies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00438-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Thirty-One Teachers’ Epistemic Beliefs as They Worked with Random Generators: an Explorative Study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study explores the epistemic considerations that seemed to govern thirty-one Indian teachers’ beliefs while teaching certain concepts of probability, especially using random generators. It focuses on knowing how these teachers make transitions between the different interpretations of probability, namely, Logical (sometimes also known as Classical), Empirical, Subjective, and Propensity. Following the tenets of the interpretative paradigm, design tasks have been used in this study to know the selected teachers’ prevalent epistemic considerations as they worked with an isomorphic resource that has characteristics similar to a commonly used object to teach randomness, the cube. Sequencing the pedagogic strategies that teachers suggested while working with unfamiliar objects (in teaching probability) helped in unraveling their dispositions of the perceptual properties, structural aspects of the object, and other externally generating conditions as determinants for their probabilistic deductions. The study concludes that perceptual reasoning that emerges by analyzing the physical and generating conditions of the activity during an experiment serve as tools on which further probabilistic deductions get based.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-06-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00243-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Combining a Local Comparison Group, a Pretest Measure, and Rich Covariates: How Well Do They Collectively Reduce Bias in Nonequivalent Comparison Group Designs?</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examined bias reduction in the eight nonequivalent comparison group designs (NECGDs) that result from combining (a) choice of a local versus non-local comparison group, and analytic use or not of (b) a pretest measure of the study outcome and (c) a rich set of other covariates. Bias was estimated as the difference in causal estimate between each NECGD and a carefully appraised randomized experiment with the same intervention, outcome, and estimand. Results indicated that bias generally declined with the number of design elements in an NECGD, that combining all three sufficed to eliminate bias but was not necessary for it, and that this pattern of results was largely replicated across five different replication factors.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2022 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221136565?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Linking Trait Affectivity, Cognitive Ability, and Preferences Among Top Managers: Insights From a Lab-In-The-Field Experiment</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Even though there has been increasing interest in the role of cognition in leadership and in identifying the personality traits of effective leaders, there is a paucity of studies that investigate the unique influence of managers’ trait affectivity and cognitive ability on their different risk and time preferences. This paper investigates the role of managers’ trait affectivity and cognitive ability in their loss aversion and present bias among 623 top managers at textile and garment firms in Vietnam. We combine data on preferences elicited through a lab-in-the-field experiment with survey data. We find that managers with high positive affectivity (PA) or cognitive ability are less subject to loss aversion and present bias. In contrast, a manager with high negative affectivity (NA) is more likely to be impatient and loss averse. Furthermore, heterogeneity of trait affectivity and cognitive ability determines different loss aversion and present bias levels of managers in SMEs vis-à-vis their counterparts in large firms. Remarkably, we observe striking evidence that trait affectivity and cognitive ability significantly affect loss aversion and present bias levels of managers who were born during the Vietnam War. Still, it is not the story of their counterparts born after the Vietnam War. The results of our study are expected to provide valuable information regarding the role played by trait affectivity and cognitive ability in determining managers’ loss aversion and present bias in different pathways.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2022 11:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221143829?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Organisational Learning and Resilience in Hungarian Schools During COVID-19 Distance Education – Study of Two Cases</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2022 07:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2154205?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional Development at Scale: The Causal Effect of Obtaining an SEI Endorsement Under Massachusetts’s RETELL Initiative</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We apply a difference-in-difference design to measure the causal effect of a teacher obtaining an endorsement in Sheltered English Immersion under Massachusetts’s Rethinking Equity in the Teaching of English Language Learners initiative on student’s learning outcomes. More than 35,000 in-service public school teachers completed the semester-long course. We find no effect on English learners’ (ELs) average test scores, but modest positive spillovers for students with disabilities and other non-EL students. Training benefited teachers recently hired by their district but had no effect on longer serving teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221136101?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Politics at the Boundary: Exploring Politics in Education Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The challenges of transforming our educational systems to fulfill enduring needs for equity, justice, and responsiveness will take a multitude of partners. Research-practice partnerships (RPPs) arrange collaboration and engagement with research to bring about shared commitments and resources to tackle these challenges. Just as sociocultural and political dynamics can shape educational politics generally, without close and intentional attention to the politics of starting, operating, and sustaining RPPs, those political dynamics can potentially derail a partnership. In this article, we consider the emerging research on the politics in and around RPPs pursuing educational transformation and propose a framework to reflect these dynamics. To introduce this special issue, we also deconstruct RPP politics into four major phases of RPP work, and describe the articles addressing each phase. This compilation of articles contributes a wealth of expertise and evidence illuminating how politics can shape both RPPs and their goals of equity and transformation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2022 07:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134916?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mindfulness for in-service and preservice teachers: an empirical map of the discourse from 2000 to 2020</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2022 05:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2153669?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Government Bonds and COVID-19. An International Evaluation Under Different Market States</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study evaluates the sensitivity of government bond yields from the countries most affected by the COVID-19 pandemic to variations in some international risk factors during the period between January 2020 and April 2021. This sample period allows us to focus the study on the first, and the subsequent waves of the COVID-19 pandemic. Specifically, we propose an extended risk factor model estimated using the quantile regression approach. In addition, this study compares the COVID-19 pandemic period with a pre-pandemic and a post-vaccination period. Interesting differences among them are observed, remarking that gold is the key risk factor during the pandemic, whereas VIX and crude oil play that role in the pre-pandemic and the post-vaccination periods, respectively, mainly for bearish states. As expected, the explanatory power of the model is better at extreme quantiles, showing relevant differences between sensitivities, because the found effects are quantile-, country- and risk factor-dependent. The results during the pandemic are robust to the inclusion of a country-specific factor and a factor accounting for the mutual influence of the government bonds.JEL classificationC22, C51, F21, G12, G32, H12
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2022 02:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221143680?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“In accordance with age and maturity”: Children’s perspectives, conceptions and insights regarding their capacities and meaningful participation</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Embedded within family law proceedings and the United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child (UNCRC, 1989) there is ambiguity surrounding the terms rights, participation, best interests, and capacity. Research furthering the rights of children is necessitated across academic literature and practice. Across research, literature and practice there is an evident reliance upon age in relation to the participation of children in family law settings. There is considerably limited research regarding strong characterisations of such concepts, and significantly less literature involving the voices of children and their perspectives regarding the topic. This qualitative action research aimed to gather the perspectives of children aged 6–12 regarding concepts relating to their capacity to participate using child-friendly methods of assessment, specifically the use of play, art, and narrative activities. This research aim to explore the research questions, how do children aged 6–12 demonstrate, understand and describe participation capacities, what does capacity, rights and participation mean to them? How can children demonstrate and increase their understanding of complex concepts through the use of child-friendly methods such as narrative, play, and drawing? This research allowed children to meaningfully share their unique perspectives, educated the participants, and provided one further step in actualizing the rights of children. Further, this research has offered recommended various methodologies for future endeavours involving children’s participation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2022 09:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221143877?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Relevant mathematical modelling efforts for understanding COVID-19 dynamics: an educational challenge</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The purpose of the work described in this paper is to emphasize the importance of using mathematical models and mathematical modelling in order to be able to understand and to learn possible behaviours in epidemic situations such as that of the COVID-19 pandemic, besides suggesting modelling techniques with which to evaluate certain sanitary decisions and policies which do, in fact, affect society as a whole. The mathematical tools that are used derive from nonlinear systems of difference equations (possibly viable at a high school level, using spreadsheets or adequate software) as well as nonlinear systems of ordinary differential equations (therefore using mathematical tools and software well within the reach of undergraduate students of many courses). This purpose is accomplished by motivating students and learners to study existing SIR-type models and modifying them in order to have a fully understandable translation of dynamics for infectious diseases such as COVID-19 in several different realistic scenarios, that is to say, situations that consider social distancing policies, widespread vaccination programmes, as well as possible and even probable results when in the presence of negationist postures and attitudes. Several modelling choices referring to real-life situations are shown and explored. These models are analysed and discussed, implicitly proposing similar attitudes and evaluations in learning environments. Conclusions are drawn, stimulating further work using the described mathematical tools and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01447-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating the Safe-Haven Abilities of Bitcoin and Gold for Crude Oil Market: Evidence During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic poses a serious threat to investors in the crude oil market. Furthermore, investors have an increasing need to find a safe haven in their investment portfolios when facing unprecedented risks in crude oil markets during the COVID-19 pandemic. According to a review of the literature, there are contradictory findings on which investment is the safer haven for the oil market. Therefore, this paper aims to evaluate whether bitcoin is a safer haven for the crude oil market than the commonly used gold during the COVID-19 pandemic. Three spillover measurements based on the time, and frequency domains, and a network framework are employed to quantify the return spillover effects among bitcoin, gold and three major crude oil futures markets. We divide the sample into two periods, pre-COVID-19 and post-COVID-19. The results show that bitcoin has a weak safe-haven effect on the crude oil market only over a short period, while gold maintains a good safe-haven ability for crude oil futures across various time horizons (frequencies), both before and after the outbreak of the COVID-19 pandemic. The findings of this study have important implications for policy-makers, crude oil producers and global investors. In particularly, investors cannot ignore the importance of bitcoin and gold in selecting more profitable portfolio policies when searching for safe-haven assets.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 12:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221141812?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evidence Gap Maps in Education Research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 06:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2139312?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Planning Framework Foregrounding Equity in Mathematics Teaching and Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 06:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2150462?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 03:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2022.2153970?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
