<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analyzing Prospective Elementary Teachers’ Evidence of Conceptual Understanding and Procedural Fluency</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2022 11:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2139112?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Critical Translingual Perspectives on California Multilingual Education Policy</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Policies restricting bilingual education have yielded to policy frameworks touting its benefits. This shift corresponds with evolving lines of debate, focusing now on how bilingual education can best support racialized bilingual learners. One element of this new debate is the perspective on language underlying curriculum in bilingual programs, with a focus on translanguaging– normalization of the language practices of bilingual communities and positing that bilinguals draw from a singular linguistic repertoire. This article examines initiatives undertaken in California between 2010 and 2019 using Critical Policy Analysis. The work highlights that while opportunities for translanguaging have arisen, tensions between heteroglossic perspectives and the impulses toward standardization and commodification of language undermine such possibilities, and that notable gaps remain between teacher preparation frameworks and intended pedagogical practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2022 11:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221130342?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whiteness and Ability: Discourses in Disability History Curriculum Legislation</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This Policy Discourse Analysis (PDA) explores 19 state legislative documents focused on the teaching of disability history in K-12 schools. Framed through critical perspectives on constructions of disability and race, alongside discourse theory, we iteratively analyzed these legislative documents to understand (a) how disability and disability history are constructed (particularly in relation to whiteness); and (b) the stated purpose of the legislation and who is meant to benefit materially as a result of the laws. We find the legislation upholds dominant notions of whiteness and ability as part of school curriculum, while simultaneously constructing disability history as in the past and disability justice as already achieved, centering the learning and awareness of white, nondisabled students. We offer discussion and implications for research and practice surrounding policy implementation of teaching disability history.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2022 11:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221127986?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Forecasting Undergraduate Majors: A Natural Language Approach</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Committing to a major is a fateful step in an undergraduate education, yet the relationship between courses taken early in an academic career and ultimate major issuance remains little studied at scale. Using transcript data capturing the academic careers of 26,892 undergraduates enrolled at a private university between 2000 and 2020, we describe enrollment histories by using natural-language methods and vector embeddings to forecast terminal major on the basis of course sequences beginning at college entry. We find that (a) a student’s very first enrolled course predicts their major 30 times better than random guessing and more than one-third better than majority-class voting, (b) modeling strategies substantially influence forecasting metrics, and (c) course portfolios vary substantially within majors, such that students with the same major exhibit relatively modest overlap.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2022 10:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126516?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The ‘Impact’ of YPAR: In their own words</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2022 08:10</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2135119?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Elementary Mathematics Specialists as Emergent Informal Teacher Leaders in Urban Schools: Engagement and Navigations</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2022 04:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2139096?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ethnomodeling: Extending Mathematical Modeling Research in Teacher Education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2022 04:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2139092?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring a Diverse Learner’s Equipartitioning Learning Trajectory</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2022 04:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2139090?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Handling the diversity of research on mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-28-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09559-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Examining a Coaching Routine to Support Teacher Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2022 01:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2139094?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing Cohesion through Collective Doubting: Framing Practice-Based Professional Learning for Mathematics Coaches</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2022 01:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2139091?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Remembering Ed Dubinsky and his Visionary Work</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-27-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00201-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Theory of action: The care and feeding of your mission</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 42-47, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; In education, we share a common commitment to supporting students’ growth and development, but we often have different ideas about what that support looks like. A theory of action describes how a specific education organization intends to work to create the outcomes it wants. Abby Javurek Andres and Chase Nordengren describe how to develop and enact a theory of action that meets the needs of the school community. The process involves bringing people together to gain understanding of the problem, learning what is going well and building a shared vision of success, and aligning communications and decision-making around the shared vision.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136598?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond the pandemic accountability freeze: A conversation with Anne Hyslop</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 30-35, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Anne Hyslop, the director of policy development at All4Ed, talks about the differences between ESSA and the previous federal education law, NCLB. Hyslop, who worked on regulations and guidance of ESSA implementation at the U.S. Department of Education, also discusses the implications of the recent NAEP scores and what may happen to ESSA accountability and school improvement plans in the post-pandemic world.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136596?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to respond to community concerns about critical race theory</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 48-53, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Many school leaders responded to the controversies over critical race theory with denial. That approach can backfire, according to Emily Hodge, Francesca López, and Joshua Rosenberg. They suggest proactive messaging, which can help prevent leaders from falling into the trap of reactively defending their practices and letting the direction of the conversation be guided by those with the most extreme views.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136599?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Be accountable for teacher diversity</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 22-23, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Rudy Ruiz and Faith Connolly propose a new accountability measure that captures the percentage of students in a school that have a teacher of a similar ethno-racial background. The measure would hold school districts accountable for the percentage of students who have a teacher who looks like them. Adding this measure would bring attention to recruiting and retaining teachers of color and improve outcomes for students of color.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136594?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can grades be an effective form of feedback?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 36-41, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Although grades are often portrayed as detrimental to students’ motivation and interest in learning, closer analysis of the evidence indicates that when used appropriately, grades can be a meaningful and effective form of feedback. Thomas R. Guskey clarifies how studies on grades are frequently misinterpreted, explains how grades offer important but insufficient information on students’ learning progress, and describes conditions that must be met for grades to serve as a meaningful and effective form of feedback for students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136597?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Defining, measuring, and supporting the success of equity officers</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 18-21, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; As more K-12 school districts have hired equity officers, questions have arisen about their role and effectiveness. A recent Heritage Foundation report, for example, found that schools with equity officers have the lowest achievement outcomes. Mary Rice-Boothe and Tanji Reed Marshall point out, however, that student achievement is not the only metric for determining the success of equity officers. When holding equity officers accountable, it’s important to be clear about the expectations for the role, establish appropriate measurements to assess their effectiveness, and provide supports that set the leaders up for success.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136593?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Abeyance agreements: Evading Accountability for disciplinary actions?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 24-28, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Schools across the United States use abeyance agreements as an alternative to suspension or expulsion, yet little is known about them. These agreements allow students to avoid or reduce suspensions or expulsions, if they meet the terms of the agreement and waive certain due process rights. David Perrodin argues that these agreements enable school districts to circumvent requirements to report disciplinary data, a requirement intended to ensure schools’ disciplinary practices are fair and nondiscriminatory. These agreements appear to give students on the brink of suspension a second chance, but the terms are sometimes difficult to follow, and once the terms are broken, students may be subject to suspension without due process. They also bring disciplinary investigations to a quick close, sometimes without a clear understanding of the root causes of the misbehavior. And the lack of data about abeyance agreements means that authorities lose information that is useful in identifying potential safety threats or uncovering schools’ violations of students’ rights. Perrodin argues for the elimination of abeyance agreements for school discipline or for more standardized processes that can be tracked and that do not interfere with students’ rights.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136595?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: There’s opportunity in the middle</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; School accountability programs tend to focus on students’ academic performance, as measured by standardized tests, But, as the authors in the November issue of Kappan explain, this presents an incomplete picture. Teresa Preston summarizes the arguments made in the issue on “Reframing Accountability.” These include discussions of limitations of testing, the need for other accountability measures, the use of data to promote improvement, and the importance of capacity building in any accountability system.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136586?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond ‘good’ and ‘bad’: Disrupting narratives about school quality</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 6-11, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Parents and the public use accountability data to judge if schools are doing a good or a bad job educating their students. However, using the current data, schools perceived as “good” tend to be in better-resourced districts and enroll higher percentages of wealthy and white students. Schools perceived as “bad” tend to be in more economically oppressed districts and enroll higher percentages of low-income students and students of color. James Noonan and Jack Schneider suggest more equitable collection of better and more nuanced data about schools can provide more complete pictures of strengths and weaknesses and could offer a way to spur investment in under resourced schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136587?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School accountability: Yesterday, today, and tomorrow</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 12-17, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; Results-based school accountability has been the linchpin of education reform in the United States for at least two decades. But the COVID-19 pandemic led many schools, states, and districts to put their testing and accountability programs on hold. Chester E. Finn, Jr., argues that it is time for the accountability holiday to end and makes recommendations for how to ensure the accountability programs are effective. Requirements for effective accountability include rigorous standards; assessments and other metrics; consequences for failing to meet, meeting, and exceeding standards; and the capacity to make changes needed to improve.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136588?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Person: Lamenting Earl — and other chronically absent students</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 54-55, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; When Amber Northern was a beginning teacher 30 years ago, one of her students, Earl, was in 9th-grade English for the third time. He only came to class once or twice a week and intended to quit school, with his father’s permission, once he turned 17. Northern delves into the research on chronic absenteeism and considers which, if any, evidence-based interventions might have been helpful for Earl. She finds that three strategies of the five she considered passed the test.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136600?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On Leadership: The architecture of equity</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/3&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;, Page 56-57, November 2022. &lt;br/&gt; The work of a school leader can be compared to that of an architect, who must bring a team together to create something original on a solid foundation. Aaron Spence, superintendent of Virginia Beach City Public Schools, came to the district nine years ago, ready to serve the district where he’d grown up. His previous experiences in school leadership had given him a vision for equity-based transformation, but the district had a more immediate need — getting all schools accredited. Joshua P. Starr explains how focusing on this urgent need enabled him to build relationships that helped him when it was time to turn to more transformative goals. This initial work proved to be the foundation on which the new work could rest.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-26-2022 11:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221136601?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
