<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rôles des interactions enseignant-élèves dans l&#39;intégration d&#39;un logiciel de géométrie dynamique: le cas d&#39;un enseignant du primaire en Tunisie</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we investigate how teacher-student interactions taking place while using a technological resource inform teaching practices and how these interactions subsequently influence the integration of the resource into teaching. Using the documentational approach and the theory of instrumental orchestration as a framework, we look at this issue from a documentational genesis perspective. In our study, we examine the documentational work of a primary teacher who is using the technological resource GeoGebra to introduce the properties of parallelograms to grade 6 primary students (age 11–12). Our research reveals the importance of the adjustments the teacher makes to the lesson plan during in-class implementation. New practices begin to take shape, as shown through the emergence of two types of instrumental orchestrations, translating into more precise guidance of the students’ work and stemming from the interactions between the students and the teacher. Such interactions then become a resource for the teacher who is developing in-class practices.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-08-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00257-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Earning to Learn: Working While Enrolled in Tennessee Colleges and Universities</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Although some students choose to work while enrolled in college, others may have no choice but to work, even if work may be detrimental to their chances of succeeding in college. Leveraging 17 years of statewide student-level records from Tennessee, the authors examine the relationship between working while enrolled and degree completion, time to degree, credit accumulation, and grade point average. The authors aim to increase understanding of how the timing and intensity of work relate to student outcomes and to explore how these relationships differ by college sector, industry of employment, and student characteristics. The authors find consistent negative associations between work and academic success, especially at higher levels of work intensity. Working students attempt and earn fewer credits and are 4 to 7 percentage points less likely to complete college. Among completers, working students take longer to graduate, even though they earn similar grade point averages and complete their attempted credits at similar rates to nonworking students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-07-2023 12:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221140410?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Culturally Responsive Disposition: How Professional Learning and Teachers’ Beliefs About and Self-Efficacy for Culturally Responsive Teaching Relate to Instruction</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Persistent social inequities in the United States demand attention to culturally responsive (CR) teaching, which requires a specific disposition toward students and teaching. Using survey data of secondary teachers (N = 417) in seven urban districts across the country engaging in equity-oriented professional learning (PL) initiatives, we examine the relationship between teachers’ beliefs about, self-efficacy for, and engagement in PL around CR teaching and their self-reported CR teaching practices. We find correlational evidence that teacher-reported self-efficacy with CR teaching and engagement in PL focused on CR teaching are associated with higher self-reported frequency of CR teaching. We also find that teachers who have beliefs aligned with CR teaching have a stronger relationship between their CR teaching self-efficacy and self-reported CR teaching practices. Finally, we find evidence that changes in CR teaching self-efficacy are associated with changes in self-reported CR teaching—suggesting that CR teaching self-efficacy may drive changes in CR teaching.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-07-2023 12:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221140092?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A dialogue between two theoretical perspectives on languages and resource use in mathematics teaching and learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we turn to the notion of networking theories with the aim of contrasting two theoretical mathematics education perspectives inspired by Vygotsky’s work, namely, the Theory of Objectification and the Documentational Approach to Didactics. We are interested in comparing/contrasting these theories in accordance with the following three main questions: (a) the role that the theories ascribe to language and resources; (b) the conceptions that the theories bring forward concerning the teacher, and (c) the understandings they offer of the mathematics classroom. In the first part of the paper, some basic concepts of each perspective are presented. The second part includes some episodes from a lesson on the teaching and learning of algebra in a Grade 1 class (6–7-year-old students). The episodes serve as background to carry out, in the third part of the paper, a dialogue between proponents of the theoretical perspectives around the identified main questions. The dialogue shows some theoretical complementarities and differences and reveals, in particular, different conceptions of the teacher and the limits and possibilities that language affords in teaching–learning mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-07-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01459-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Point? A Case Study Characterizing Teacher Candidates’ Purposes for Practitioner Inquiry</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2023 10:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2022.2157906?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Persistence of Poverty: How Measures of Socioeconomic Status Have Changed Over Time</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Socioeconomic status (SES) is a common measure used to gauge social, cultural, and financial capital in scientific literature. Over time, SES research has produced an extremely wide and inconsistently used variety of SES variables and components. This study will review research that estimates SES and will examine common components and trends from the inception of its measurement to present data. A systematic review protocol was used to gather literature related to SES, and a historical analysis was conducted to examine the SES variables and their components that were most commonly used in the literature. Results displayed varying trends by decade, with earlier SES measures including components on social capital and more recent measures incorporating aspects of cultural and economic capital. Subjective perspectives of social class became more common toward the turn of the century, and few measures included components from more asset-based frameworks. The Big 3 measures (parental education, parental occupation, and income) have been common measures across time.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2023 07:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221141409?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Widening Achievement Gap Between Rich and Poor in a Nordic Country</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We study a decade of achievement gaps for fifth-, eighth-, and 10th-grade students in Norway using administrative population data. Norway is a wealthy and egalitarian country with a homogeneous educational system, yet achievement gaps between students at the 90th and 10th percentiles of parental income and between students whose parents have at least a master and at most a high school degree are found to be large (0.55–0.93 and 0.70–0.99 SD), equivalent to about 2 to 2.5 years of schooling, and increasing by grade level. Achievement gaps by parental income, but not by parental education, increased over the time period, underscoring the different ways these two socioeconomic status components relate to achievement and the potential for policy to alter gaps.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2023 06:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221142596?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Racial-Religious Decoupling in the University: Investigating Religious Students’ Perceptions of Institutional Commitment to Diversity</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;Muslims face racism based on their racialized religious identities, yet few address their experiences through critical race theory or campus racial climate. This paper addresses how religious students rate institutional commitments to campus diversity when considering racial and religious respect. This study examines undergraduate experience surveys across nine campuses and a Muslim student photovoice project through a mixed-methods design. I argue that racial and religious respect derived from interpersonal, discursive, and material sources influence Muslim students’ perceptions of institutional commitment to diversity. I introduce racial-religious decoupling to refer to how the separation of race and religion as distinct social experiences hinders campus commitments to diversity, equity, and inclusion for addressing anti-Muslim racism and intersections of race and religion. This study uses critical race theory to demonstrate how hegemonic Whiteness embedded in higher education includes Christian normativity, which racializes non-Christians as outsiders who have to justify their needs and resources for their communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221121339?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Boundaries of Competition: Examining Charter Schools’ Impact on Traditional Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;For decades, charter schools have been promoted as a panacea for increasing competition in the educational marketplace. Supporters argue that increased choice forces neighboring schools to innovate, while opponents contend that charters “skim” students and funds away from traditional public schools (TPS). We test the two differing views by comparing academic achievement and school segregation in TPS in South Florida facing competition from charter schools compared to TPS with no competition. We find that when a charter school moves into the community, it fails to substantively change test scores or diversity of the nearby TPS, even 10 years after a charter is established.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2023 04:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221142049?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The school librarian equity gap: Inequities associated with race and ethnicity compounded by poverty, locale, and enrollment</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2023 03:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2023.2160112?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Encountering ideas about teaching and learning mathematics in undergraduate mathematics courses</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We study the ideas about teaching and learning mathematics that undergraduate students generate when they encounter tasks designed to embed approximations of teaching practice in mathematics courses taken by a general population of students. These tasks attend to the dual goals of developing an understanding of mathematics content and an understanding of how teachers provide classroom experiences that foster mathematics learning. The study employs a qualitative, multiple-case study methodology, with four cases bounded by the content areas of abstract algebra, single variable calculus, discrete mathematics, and introductory statistics. The data for the study come from undergraduate students’ written work on mathematical tasks, interviews with a subset of students from each course, and interviews with each instructor throughout the term during which they implemented the tasks. Our findings indicate that students identified the broad applicability of teaching skills (discussed by 32 of the 61 interviewed students), recognized the value of examining hypothetical learners’ mathematical work (discussed by 59 of the 61 interviewed students), and reported empathy for hypothetical learners (discussed by 38 of the 61 interviewed students). These findings persisted across the course content and course levels we studied, leading us to conclude that our findings can transfer to additional mathematics courses in secondary mathematics teacher preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01454-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The impacts of two curricula on middle-level students’ engineering understanding</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 08:33</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2022.2158156?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the Stakes: The Influence of Accountability Policy Options on Teachers’ Responses</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Under test-based accountability, side-effects —including practices to inflate test results, often seen as cheating—are usually associated to so-called high-stakes policies. However, the influence of different types of stakes in the generation of this type of practices has been overlooked in education research. Based on a survey experiment, our results indicate that the type and level of stakes of accountability systems (e.g., high- vs. low-stakes, material vs. symbolic) do not differ in triggering side-effects. Counterintuitively, individual symbolic consequences trigger similar reactions among teachers than material incentives. In-depth interviews give insights into the social mechanisms that lead to symbolic effects having such an influence in understanding teachers’ reactivity to accountability.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 06:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221142048?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Updates</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 1004-1004, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221141069?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>power swgee: GEE-based power calculations in stepped wedge cluster randomized trials</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 811-841, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Stepped wedge cluster randomized trials (SW-CRTs) are increasingly being used to evaluate interventions in medical, public health, educational, and social science contexts. With the longitudinal and crossover natures of an SW-CRT, complex analysis techniques are often needed, which makes appropriately powering SW-CRTs challenging. In this article, we introduce a newly developed SW-CRT power calculator embedded within the power command in Stata. The power calculator assumes a marginal model (that is, generalized estimating equations) for the primary analysis of SW-CRTs, for which other currently available SW-CRT power calculators may not be suitable. The command accommodates complete cross-sectional and closed-cohort designs and includes multilevel correlation structures appropriate for such designs. We discuss the methods and formulas underlying our SW-CRT calculator and provide illustrative examples of the use of power swgee. We provide suggestions about the choice of parameters in power swgee and conclude by discussing areas of future research that may improve the command.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221140953?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Stata Journal Editors’ Prize 2022: Christopher F. Baum</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 727-733, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221140932?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>portfolio: A command for conducting portfolio analysis in Stata</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 941-957, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Portfolio analysis is widely used in empirical asset pricing to explore the cross-sectional relation between two or more variables. In this article, we introduce the methodology of portfolio analysis and describe a new command, portfolio, that provides a one-step solution for portfolio analysis. portfolio calculates the equal- or value-weighted returns with a t statistic for the portfolio and tests the significance of a long-short strategy in portfolios. portfolio also provides the Newey–West standard-error adjustment option for alleviating the impact of potential autocorrelation and heteroskedasticity in financial time series.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221141021?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>printcase: A command for visualizing single observations</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 958-968, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce the printcase command, which outputs data from a specific observation into an easy-to-read Microsoft Word or PDF document. printcase allows analysts to focus on a single observation within a dataset and view that observation in its entirety. The output displays fields in table format, with all variables identified by their corresponding labels and all responses identified by their corresponding value labels. We explain how printcase works, give examples of circumstances under which this type of table-based quasiquestionnaire would be useful, and provide code for printing single observations.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221141022?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>qpair: A command for analyzing paired Q-sorts in Q-methodology</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 884-907, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce qpair as a new command written in Stata for the analysis of paired Q-sorts in Q-methodology, which is used for studying subjective issues and is a combination of qualitative and quantitative techniques. The quantitative component of Q-methodology employs a by-person factor analysis technique. However, currently there is no systematic approach for analyzing paired Q-sorts or longitudinal data in Q-methodology. We introduce the only statistical command available for the analysis of paired Q-sorts. The qpair command employs the factor extraction and factor rotation techniques in Stata. The command is illustrated using a dataset representing perceptions of 50 information technology professionals on person–organization fit regarding their training and development priorities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221141002?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 147: Porting downloaded packages between machines</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 996-997, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221141067?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>rcm: A command for the regression control method</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 842-883, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;The regression control method, also known as the panel-data approach for program evaluation (Hsiao, Ching, and Wan, 2012, Journal of Applied Econometrics 27: 705–740; Hsiao and Zhou, 2019, Journal of Applied Econometrics 34: 463–481), is a convenient method for causal inference in panel data that exploits cross-sectional correlation to construct counterfactual outcomes for a single treated unit by linear regression. In this article, we present the rcm command, which efficiently implements the regression control method with or without covariates. Available methods for model selection include best subset, lasso, and forward stepwise and backward stepwise regression, while available selection criteria include the corrected Akaike information criterion, the Akaike information criterion, the Bayesian information criterion, the modified Bayesian information criterion, and cross-validation. Estimation and counterfactual predictions can be made by ordinary least squares, lasso, or postlasso ordinary least squares. For statistical inference, both the in-space placebo test using fake treatment units and the in-time placebo test using a fake treatment time can be implemented. The rcm command produces a series of graphs for visualization along the way. We demonstrate the use of the rcm command by revisiting classic examples of political and economic integration between Hong Kong and mainland China (Hsiao, Ching, and Wan 2012) and German reunification (Abadie, Diamond, and Hainmueller, 2015, American Journal of Political Science 59: 495–510).
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221140960?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stata tip 148: Searching for words within strings</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 998-1003, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221141068?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conditional evaluation of predictive models: The cspa command</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 924-940, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we introduce a new command, cspa, that implements the conditional superior predictive ability test developed in Li, Liao, and Quaedvlieg (2022, Review of Economic Studies 89: 843–875). With the conditional performance of predictive methods measured nonparametrically by the conditional expectation functions of their predictive losses, we test the null hypothesis that a benchmark model weakly outperforms a collection of competitors uniformly across the conditioning space. The proposed command can implement this test for both independent cross-sectional data and serially dependent time-series data. Confidence sets for the most superior model can be obtained by inverting the test, for which the cspa command also offers a convenient implementation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221141014?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Machine learning using Stata/Python</title>
        <description>
          
            The Stata Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/stja/22/4&quot;&gt;Volume 22, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 772-810, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;I present two related commands, r_ml_stata_cv and c_ml_stata_cv, for fitting popular machine learning methods in both a regression and a classification setting. Using the recent Stata/Python integration platform introduced in Stata 16, these commands provide hyperparameters’ optimal tuning via K-fold cross-validation using grid search. More specifically, they use the Python Scikitlearn application programming interface to carry out both cross-validation and outcome/label prediction.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-05-2023 05:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1536867X221140944?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
