<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advancing Institutional Change to Encourage Faculty Participation in Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;University faculty have the talent, creativity, and training to tackle the serious challenges confronting our education system today, but the incentive structure in universities is often at odds with real-world contributions. What tensions are experienced by faculty who may be interested in partnership-oriented, engaged scholarship? How can these tensions be addressed? This chapter explores the tensions, particularly in the context of education research-practice partnerships, and provide examples from universities that are taking steps to lessen the tensions and encourage faculty participation in partnerships. By adopting new structures and incentives, these universities are providing a pathway to engaged scholarship that may ultimately increase the power of research to address the problems that educators face each day. However, university leaders who are implementing institutional change must grapple with long-established norms and traditions, and show how new ways of assessing the value of research will benefit universities as well as their communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-30-2022 06:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221131564?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students making sense of statistics through storytelling: a theoretical perspective based on Bruner’s narrative mode of thought</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;A persistent problem in teaching introductory statistics has been helping students overcome their fears and the abstract nature of what they need to learn. Students’ own contextualised stories are argued to present an opportunity for humanising the abstract, helping reduce student fears to complement traditional teaching approaches. This paper applies Bruner (Actual minds, possible worlds, Harvard University Press, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r7&quot;&gt;1986&lt;/span&gt;) theoretical perspectives on narrative mode of thought to understand how students’ own contextualised stories might support them in making sense of university introductory statistics. An exploratory, design research study was undertaken where 31 student participants were interviewed across a two-year period. All participants had completed an introductory statistics course where they wrote contextualised children’s stories about normal distributions and sampling distributions of the mean. Using an assumption-based, conjecture-driven, reflective analysis, participant interview data was analysed to generate preliminary research findings. Two preliminary findings are detailed in this paper. One revealed that participants initially don’t seem to naturally make connections with statistics using their own stories, while another showed that once they did so, their stories helped initiate pathways of access for making sense of their statistical learning. To test the preliminary findings, Bruner (Actual minds, possible worlds, Harvard University Press, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r7&quot;&gt;1986&lt;/span&gt;) theoretical perspectives on narrative mode of thought—presupposition, subjectification, and multiple perspectives—were used to develop an analytical tool. The methodology in the study provides new insights for understanding how students’ own contextualised stories might help them make sense of their learning. The implications of the study are relevant for statistics education, particularly in the areas of statistical thinking processes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-30-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00440-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Long-Term Impacts of Corequisite Mathematics Remediation with Statistics: Degree Completion and Wage Outcomes</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Community colleges are essential for United States higher education, but their students have low retention and graduation rates. Community college students assigned to mathematics remediation are particularly unlikely to graduate. Corequisite remediation (college-level coursework with additional support) has shown short-term increased student success. The current study examined the 7-year results of a randomized controlled trial of corequisite remediation with college-level statistics. Students assigned to the corequisite group were 50 percent more likely to complete associate’s degrees within 3 years, and 100 percent more likely to complete bachelor’s degrees within 5 years. Corequisite students also earned, on average, $3,000–$4,500 more in years 5 to 7. Mediation analysis further suggests that the wage treatment effect was due to shortened time to degree.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-29-2022 07:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221138848?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>High School Students’ Reasoning on the Frequency Approach of Probability When Facing a Non-routine Problem</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This work reports the results of an investigation that aimed to know the informal reasoning of high school students with and about the frequency approach of probability and the law of large numbers when they were faced with a problem about random intervals. The research question was as follows: What features of students’ reasoning about the frequency approach of probability are revealed when they solve a task on random intervals? To advance the answer, an activity was carried out involving students between ages 16 and 17 who built random intervals through manipulative and computational simulations, the latter with the software Fathom. In addition, they were provided with a worksheet with questions for them to express their reasoning. Their responses were coded and ranked. At the end, we summarize the results and highlight prediction and variability as essential features to understand the frequency approach to probability.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-29-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00232-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nonparametric Classification Method for Multiple-Choice Items in Cognitive Diagnosis</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The multiple-choice (MC) item format has been widely used in educational assessments across diverse content domains. MC items purportedly allow for collecting richer diagnostic information. The effectiveness and economy of administering MC items may have further contributed to their popularity not just in educational assessment. The MC item format has also been adapted to the cognitive diagnosis (CD) framework. Early approaches simply dichotomized the responses and analyzed them with a CD model for binary responses. Obviously, this strategy cannot exploit the additional diagnostic information provided by MC items. De la Torre’s MC Deterministic Inputs, Noisy “And” Gate (MC-DINA) model was the first for the explicit analysis of items having MC response format. However, as a drawback, the attribute vectors of the distractors are restricted to be nested within the key and each other. The method presented in this article for the CD of DINA items having MC response format does not require such constraints. Another contribution of the proposed method concerns its implementation using a nonparametric classification algorithm, which predestines it for use especially in small-sample settings like classrooms, where CD is most needed for monitoring instruction and student learning. In contrast, default parametric CD estimation routines that rely on EM- or MCMC-based algorithms cannot guarantee stable and reliable estimates—despite their effectiveness and efficiency when samples are large—due to computational feasibility issues caused by insufficient sample sizes. Results of simulation studies and a real-world application are also reported.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 06:04</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221133088?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Backtalk: It’s time to (re)evaluate evaluation</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 66-67, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; The summer after Amanda S. Frasier left K-12 teaching to return to high education, she received an email stating that her students’ end-of-year assessments were in. When she looked at the scores, she was pleased to see they had done so well, even though she questions the value of standardized accountability measures and didn’t learn anything new from the results. Frasier discusses why these scores are not helpful and advocates more meaningful measures.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142991?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students Speak Up: What helps students feel safe?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 68-69, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; Educators Rising students share how safe they feel at school and what kinds of measures would help them feel safer.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142992?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Career Confidential: Teacher wants to motivate an apathetic student</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 64-65, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; In this monthly column, Phyllis Fagell answers work-related questions from educators. This month, an elementary school teacher wants suggestions for how to help a formerly diligent student who now won’t do any work. A teacher at a competitive high school is worried about the high level of stress among her students. And a teacher who is new at her school wonders if it’s already time to leave after her department chair screamed at her because of a scheduling conflict.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142990?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 70-70, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; In this monthly Kappan column, authors recommend books that have influenced and inspired them in their education careers. This month, David Labaree recommends Confessions of a School Reformer by Larry Cuban, and Nina Weisling and Wendy Gardiner recommend The Price of Nice: How Good Intentions Maintain Educational Inequality, edited by Angelina E. Castagno.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142994?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PDK Connection: Heritage News</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 71-71, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; PDK members can serve their community be getting involved with Educators Rising. Opportunities include serving as a judge at an Educators Rising conference, leading a breakout session at the national conference, assisting Educators Rising teacher leaders in their district, and creating new Educators Rising chapters.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221143005?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>De-escalating ‘dataveillance’ in schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 23-27, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; T. Philip Nichols and Alexander Monea explore the spread of data-driven surveillance (i.e., dataveillance) technologies in schools, which are increasingly used as a strategy for mitigating safety risks. They argue that the sense of security schools derive from these technologies often comes at the cost of students’ actual well-being and privacy. Drawing on research with teachers and administrators, they highlight several ethical challenges dataveillance technologies raise as they are incorporated into classrooms. They conclude with suggestions for how educators might de-escalate their dependence on dataveillance without compromising students’ safety.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142978?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Helping schools prepare for and prevent the worst: A conversation with Jaclyn Schildkraut</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 30-33, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; About 95% of schools nationwide hold lockdown drills for students and staff in response to security concerns, including an active shooter. Jaclyn Schildkraut, the interim executive director of the Regional Gun Violence Research Consortium, talks about the importance of performing lockdown drills in a trauma-informed way. Through her work and research with the Syracuse City School District, she recommends best practices and stresses the importance of training for school staff.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142979?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Editor’s Note: No easy answers on safety</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 4-4, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; As incidents of violence in schools proliferate and receive media attention, members of the public have expressed support for a variety of safety measures. However, it’s not clear which measures are most effective, and some measures come with downsides. In this Editor’s Note for the December 2022/January 2023 issue of Kappan, Teresa Preston discusses some of the questions raised in the issue about how schools can keep students safe.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142973?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>School safety for all students</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 6-11, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; In the wake of school shootings, attention invariably turns to how to make schools safer. But many of the strategies intended to secure schools against external threats yield unintended negative consequences for marginalized students, exacerbating racial and other inequalities. Meg Caven advocates for a definition of school safety that centers on equity and attends to students’ safety from emotional as well as structural violence. She concludes by highlighting the role that culturally responsive research can play in helping schools direct resources and refine safety strategies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142974?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Artistic License: Celebrating the talents of students and educators</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 72-72, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; This monthly column features a teacher’s photographic self-portrait using shadows and reflections and a student’s pointillist drawing of a solitary rabbit that expresses her feelings of solitude.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221143006?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Safe, supported, and empowered</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 18-22, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; Many effective strategies exist to keep students safe, supported, and engaged in school. Restorative practice (RP) is a powerful approach for achieving these goals as it elevates student voice and can strengthen school climate. Annie M. White and John Kenneth Weiss share findings from an initiative through which high school student-faculty teams learned strategies to use RP practices and incorporate student voice to improve school climate. After two years, students gained the confidence to work for school change. They offer implementation recommendations, including prioritizing relationship-building, reaching a critical mass, and providing structure for engagement. Ultimately, they found that student voice and engagement may be key to improving school climate.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142976?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Seeking safety in a ‘code’</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 12-17, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; Although metal detectors, guards, and law enforcement officers are intended to protect students and maintain a safe educational environment, the actual effectiveness of such measures is unclear, especially when it comes to protecting Black students. Charles Bell interviewed Black students from urban and suburban schools across Michigan and learned that they did not feel safe at school. The absence of reliable safety measures at school leads students to rely on a “code” that provides protection in school by encouraging students to fight to demonstrate their toughness, win respect, and form alliances to ensure group safety. Among other things, the code of the school transforms suspension into a status symbol that undermines school authority, potentially increases school violence, and leads to the criminalization of Black students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142975?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>No more nice mentors</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 42-47, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; There is a cultural mismatch between teachers and students in classrooms across the U.S. that, despite teachers’ best intentions, too often leads to student harm. Mentors are uniquely positioned to interrupt conscious and unconscious bias that leads to inequitable practices but often have difficulty holding the necessary hard conversations. Among the reasons for this is socialized niceness, particularly in women, which prioritizes comfort and avoids conflict at all costs. Nina F. Weisling and Wendy Gardiner provide insights for recognizing, naming, and working through socialized niceness in mentoring to ensure all students have opportunities to learn in safe and rigorous classrooms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142983?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The fraught connection between state and school</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 34-40, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; Public schooling in the 19th century cultivated in students a shared sense of identity as citizens with a common culture. However, posits David Labaree, U.S. schools are less effective than they used to be at serving this purpose, making their value to the nation-state open to questioning. Labaree considers three common functions that public schools serve for the state — legitimacy, economic productivity, and civic community — and questions how well schools serve, or even undermine, these purposes. Schools rely on the state for support, but that support is in danger if systems of schooling promote division and are not perceived as promoting a common good.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142982?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On Leadership: Expectations and exceptions</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 60-61, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; It’s not always easy to balance high expectations with the need to make exceptions when students are struggling. The pandemic has made educators and the public more aware of how social-emotional needs can affect students’ ability to learn, but students still need to meet some academic standards. Joshua Starr suggests that knowing students personally and using data to understand students’ stories can help educators attend to student needs in ways that also support their academic development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142988?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Policy Solutions: The policy of school policing</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 62-63, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; More than half of U.S. schools have no police presence on their campuses. Jonathan E. Collins proposes that all school buildings be free of police. School resource officers (SROs), he writes, do more harm than good. An alternate policy that would remove SROs from schools involves the framework of the community policing model. This model focuses on engaging students in full and deep discussions and problem-solving that reveals what students think of school safety and the root cause of school violence.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142989?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A lesson in motion stays in motion: If students lead, will teachers follow?</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 48-53, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; While endorsed as critical for promoting learning, students’ interest in a topic has had minimal, if any, influence on curriculum development. Teachers thus are challenged to promote students’ interest within an established curriculum. After students demonstrated misunderstandings after reading an article about bacteria, Sarah Stallings and Samuel Miller, a 4th-grade teacher and university researcher, decided to base their instruction on students’ queries and concerns. This one lesson provided the impetus for a series of activities across the school year that allowed students to become more actively involved in choosing what they would learn and how they would learn it. What students viewed as important and interesting determined the nature and format of their daily studies.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142984?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First Person: How I gamified my classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 54-56, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; Former elementary school teacher Kasandra Singh shares how she used gamification to encourage her 5th-grade students to drive their own learning. Students were initially divided into groups based on their demonstrated ability to get their work done. Those in Level 1 were given direct instruction, those in Level 2 worked together to complete lessons with some teacher guidance, and students at Level 3 worked through assignments with limited teacher guidance when requested. Students and teacher worked together to determine when and how students could level up. As students showed mastery of lesson material, they received “badges” showing their accomplishments. And students motivated each other by awarding “awesomeness points” to deserving classmates. The system enabled students to learn to monitor and direct their own learning.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142985?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Under the Law: School safety: A legal labyrinth</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/4&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 4&lt;/a&gt;, Page 57-59, December 2022/January 2023. &lt;br/&gt; An array of federal, state, and local laws and policies come into play when situations arise that could compromise student safety. These laws and district policies combine to form an intricate and sometimes inconsistent patchwork of protocols that schools must follow. Robert Kim discusses the interplay between federal, state, and local laws governing schools’ responses to student misbehavior; the differing regulations surrounding different kinds of behavior; and the legal gray areas and judgment calls school personnel face when making disciplinary decisions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-28-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217221142987?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
