<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>International Perspectives on Knowledge and Quality: Implications for Innovation in Teacher Education Policy and Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 07:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2138324?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ digital competence for global teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-20-2022 08:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2135855?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mechanisms of Exclusion: Group Homogenization and Deficit Thinking in Integrated Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;School integration and inclusion are important for educational equity, yet inclusionary educational policies often end up being exclusionary in practices. In this article I contribute to our understanding of school level mechanism underlying this process. I draw on 2 years of data collection in a progressive culturally responsive school implementing a voluntary students assignment policy to increase the share of low-income students of color in the school. I show how a conflict with dissenting mothers over gender-unlabeled bathrooms became a conflict over the meaning of inclusion when school leaders applied deficit thinking that saw low-income parents of color as less likely to support the program, despite heterogeneity in dissenting mothers’ background, and how as result dissenting mothers felt excluded from the school community and the needs of transgender students were unmet. These findings have important implications for theory and practice and for creating inclusive schools.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-20-2022 06:41</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221127988?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Probability of Doing Something New?</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-20-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00238-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>In Defense of Dignitary Safety: A Phenomenological Study of Student Resistance to Hate Speech on Campus</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-19-2022 07:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2125760?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Antiracism Education Activism: A Theoretical Framework for Understanding and Promoting Racial Equity</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Although antiracism activism has contributed to substantive progress under certain circumstances and in certain contexts, little research attempts to theorize how antiracism activism is manifest across contexts. In this article, we explore individual and collective antiracist actions within and outside schools. We introduce a theoretical framework that identifies four domains of activism—policy, community, leadership, and teaching and learning—in which activists operate to make a positive difference in promoting racial equity and antiracism in education. The framework offers a systemic way of thinking about antiracist activism in education and the importance of recognizing that several aspects of antiracist activism usually conceived as distinct are interrelated within and across domains. Indeed, antiracist education activism must be understood holistically and systemically if we seek to dismantle the racism that is woven into every piece of the education system.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-19-2022 05:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126518?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analysing mathematical modelling tasks in light of citizenship education using the COVID-19 pandemic as a case study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we discuss the theoretical background of mathematical modelling and its connection to citizenship education. Citizenship education in this context means that young people are equipped with competencies to respond as responsible citizens in situations relevant for society. To outline the connection between mathematical modelling and citizenship education in theory, we discuss the aims of mathematical modelling, modelling competences and the connection between numeracy and modelling. Based on these reflections we present an extended modelling cycle that specifically highlights modelling steps relevant to citizenship education. To show how the theoretical connection between mathematical modelling and citizenship education can be used in teaching practice, we describe three different examples of modelling tasks and analyse them with the help of the extended modelling cycle. We argue that the three tasks support different learning aims in relation to citizenship education and require modellers to carry out different steps of the extended modelling cycle. As an example of context, we used the pandemic caused by COVID-19, as it affected the quality of human life greatly, as all students in the Western world experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-19-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01440-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>ZIZO: a history-based approach to mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we discuss the zoom in and zoom out approach to mathematics teacher education (ZIZO), which is intentionally designed to foster commognitive conflicts through the exploration of historical sources and the engagement with collective discussions. ZIZO is structured in three interconnected moments: firstly, participants are invited to immerse in primary sources, as a means of shaking their comfort zones regarding legitimate mathematical procedures and criteria; secondly, they engage in plenary discussions on the historical contextualisation of mathematical ideas, supported by the study of secondary sources; finally, they return to the source to unveil specific aspects of historical practices. This approach is part of a broader proposal, which builds upon participants’ collective experiences to stimulate the development of a problematising stance toward knowledge production and teaching of mathematics. We exemplify ZIZO by a case in which the study of books I and II of Euclid’s &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/em&gt; was used to problematise usual approaches to the teaching of Pythagoras’ theorem and areas in Brazilian secondary school. Our findings suggest that the engagement with Euclidean practices led teachers to problematise their views on the teaching of areas as geometrical magnitudes and as measurements, as well as the pedagogical uses of manipulable materials. These results highlight ZIZO’s potential for teacher education, especially regarding the problematisation of views on what mathematics is and how it is learned and taught.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-19-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01439-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impact of Economic Policy Uncertainty and Pandemic Uncertainty on International Tourism: What do We Learn From COVID-19?</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Uncertainty is an overarching aspect of life that is particularly pertinent to the present COVID-19 pandemic crisis; as seen by the pandemic’s rapid worldwide spread, the nature and level of uncertainty have possibly increased due to the possible disconnects across national borders. The entire economy, especially the tourism industry, has been dramatically impacted by COVID-19. In the current study, we explore the impact of economic policy uncertainty (EPU) and pandemic uncertainty (PU) on inbound international tourism by using data gathered from Italy, Spain, and the United States for the years 1995–2021. Using the Quantile on Quantile (QQ) approach, the study confirms that EPU and PU negatively affected inbound tourism in all states. Wavelet-based Granger causality further reveals bi-directional causality running from EPU to inbound tourism and unidirectional causality from PU to inbound tourism in the long run. The overall findings show that COVID-19 has had a strong negative effect on tourism. So resilient skills are required to restore a sustainable tourism industry.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2022 12:54</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221132125?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A teacher’s positioning of a multilingual learner in the first month of the academic year</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2022 08:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2133004?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating a method as part of the action research process: education journey maps</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2022 08:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2113416?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Difficulties scatter plots pose for 11th grade students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2022 07:53</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2022.2128018?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Effects of providing domain information on facilitating hypothesis generation in inquiry learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-18-2022 06:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00220671.2022.2124219?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“I don’t like to put labels on it”: Activism, Political Identity Development, and the Cultivation of Student Political Fluency</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2022 12:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2125756?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Regardless, my students and I pressed on”: How Early-Career Teachers Develop Activist Identities</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2022 12:17</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0161956X.2022.2125758?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Power Approximations for Overall Average Effects in Meta-Analysis With Dependent Effect Sizes</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Meta-analytic models for dependent effect sizes have grown increasingly sophisticated over the last few decades, which has created challenges for a priori power calculations. We introduce power approximations for tests of average effect sizes based upon several common approaches for handling dependent effect sizes. In a Monte Carlo simulation, we show that the new power formulas can accurately approximate the true power of meta-analytic models for dependent effect sizes. Lastly, we investigate the Type I error rate and power for several common models, finding that tests using robust variance estimation provide better Type I error calibration than tests with model-based variance estimation. We consider implications for practice with respect to selecting a working model and an inferential approach.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2022 07:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221127379?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>History of mathematics in the context of mathematics teachers’ education: a dialogical/ethical perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper deals with the use of original sources in mathematics education, with emphasis on preservice teachers’ education and the exploration of historical texts. In this context, there is a real challenge, for both teachers and learners, to conduct both ‘synchronic’ and ‘diachronic’ reading. As reported extensively in research, learners seem to have a strong propensity to focus on and to ‘translate’ the texts into modern mathematics, which makes it difficult to deepen both their understanding of history and their own set of conceptualizations. Rather than propose practical solutions, in the paper we explore a theoretical positioning that may help us think differently about these difficulties and, ultimately, provide articulated and different avenues for interventions. Drawing on the philosophy of language of Mikhaïl Bakhtin and Valentin Voloshinov, the idea is to question the Saussurean perspective that underpins the notions of synchrony and diachrony. From this theoretical perspective, we propose to think about the challenges associated with the reading of historical texts in terms of the ethical stance of answerability and engagement in the context of preservice mathematics teachers’ education, and we suggest envisioning a third possible reading, namely, that of the educator.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01437-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From the historical text to the classroom session: analysing the work of teachers-as-designers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;While classical studies have highlighted the many potential benefits of using original historical sources in the classroom, few studies have documented actual classroom practices outside of research contexts. In this case study, I aim to describe and explain how five French high school teachers autonomously designed and implemented classroom sessions starting from the same document, namely an excerpt from Euler’s &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Elements of Algebra&lt;/em&gt; presenting an algorithm for square root approximation. From a methodological viewpoint, it enables me show how two general frameworks for the study of teachers’ professional practices—the Documentational Approach to Didactics and the Didactic and Ergonomic Double Approach—can be tailored to fit the specific challenges of using historical sources. The empirical results provide fresh insights into the conditions for a mathematically rich use of historical sources in the classroom, and on the connections between this use and the integration of a historical perspective in the teaching of mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01434-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>It is probably a pattern: does spontaneous focusing on regularities in preschool predict reasoning about randomness four years later?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The many studies with coin-tossing tasks in literature show that the concept of randomness is challenging for adults as well as children. Systematic errors observed in coin-tossing tasks are often related to the representativeness heuristic, which refers to a mental shortcut that is used to judge randomness by evaluating how well a set of random events represents the typical example for random events we hold in our mind. Representative thinking is explained by our tendency to seek for patterns in our surroundings. In the present study, predictions of coin-tosses of 302 third-graders were explored. Findings suggest that in third grade of elementary school, children make correct as well as different types of erroneous predictions and individual differences exist. Moreover, erroneous predictions that were in line with representative thinking were positively associated with an early spontaneous focus on regularities, which was assessed when they were in second year of preschool. We concluded that previous studies might have underestimated children’s reasoning about randomness in coin-tossing contexts and that representative thinking is indeed associated with pattern-based thinking tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-17-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10187-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“It Was Hard, and It Still Is . . .”: Women of Color Navigating HSI STEM Transfer Pathways</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Women of color (WOC) continue to be underrepresented in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM), where they often experience racism and sexism within disciplinary contexts that have historically privileged men and Whiteness. Participant narratives gained through focus-group and follow-up interviews illuminate the racialized and gendered STEM transfer experiences of 21 WOC who attended 2- and 4-year Hispanic-Serving Institutions (HSIs). Using a multidimensional intersectional approach, we explore the interplay between the complex identity experiences of WOC and the dynamic intersections of their transfer pathways across 2- and 4-year HSIs and within STEM disciplinary contexts. Findings underscore the inequities that continue to pervade STEM and highlight opportunities for transforming disciplinary and institutional cultures, particularly within HSI STEM transfer pathways, where there is great potential for these diverse institutions to support, validate, and benefit from the unique contributions of WOC.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-15-2022 06:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126480?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Embracing the City: Black Families’ Place Attachments and (Re)imaginings of the City and Suburb in Search of Educational Opportunity</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Like many predominantly Black urban cities, Detroit, Michigan, has experienced significant out-migration among Black residents over the past 30 years. This situation has altered families’ relationships to the communities and schools where they have been nurtured or call home. Therefore, this paper examines how seven Black families’ place attachments influenced their geographic movement and school choices in the Detroit metropolitan region. Findings show that despite families’ movement to surrounding suburbs, varied experiences in Detroit influenced families’ decision-making regarding where to live, their search for sociocultural experiences that supported their families holistically, and their perceptions and navigation of municipal boundaries and borders. Families’ intention toward maintaining connections with Detroit enact what I term embracing the city. Embracing the city helps consider the importance of socio-spatial ties that persist and orient Black families’ community perceptions and school choices in suburban contexts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-15-2022 06:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126479?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Counter-Deficit Lens in Educational Research: Interrogating Conceptions of Structural Oppression</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Deficit framings of marginalized students, though maintaining widespread social influence, are thoroughly condemned in recent educational scholarship. The goal of this “counter-deficit” scholarship is to challenge racism in schools and improve opportunities for marginalized youth. To meet the lofty ambition of racial equity in education, how scholarship understands racial oppression is a central concern. Sociologists of race have emphasized the duality of racial oppression. Racism is ideological and structural. Ideologically, racism shapes how communities of color are perceived and how they are treated in educational settings. Structurally, racism is embedded in histories and policies that systematically disadvantage racially minoritized people. Both processes matter to educational inequality. However, in this review of counter-deficit literature, we find that racism is primarily understood by way of ideology and seldom by way of structures. This framing has important implications for how schools can support racially minoritized students to overcome racism in schools and communities.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 12:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221125225?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Dynamic Financial Implications of the Community College Baccalaureate: An Institutional Exploration</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Using generalized difference-in-difference and synthetic control modeling, this study estimates the influence of the community-college baccalaureate (CCB) on institutional finance over time and by intensity. Leveraging data spanning 19 years (1999–2017), I find no impact on overall revenue but suggestive evidence of upfront costs and slight increases in total spending post-adoption. Coupled with increased enrollment, per-full-time-equivalent (FTE) revenue and spending decrease, on average, by approximately 12% and 6%, respectively. Adoption of an additional CCB is associated with a 3% decrease in revenue and a suggestive 2% reduction in spending per FTE. Additional robustness checks suggest that these impacts may vary by state. These results suggest that institutions should consider the trade-offs in broadening access to baccalaureate-level education with the associated strain on resources. Policymakers should consider how best to financially support adoptive institutions as they work to meet student and workforce needs. Implications for policy, practice, and research are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 12:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126473?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Action research: Time to act with maturity</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-14-2022 10:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221133981?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
