<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Exploration of the Experiences of Substitute Teachers: A Systematic Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article reports on a systematic review of literature on the experiences of substitute teachers, also known as casual or relief teachers. This occupational group are an essential part of school improvement efforts, allowing release time for other teachers to participate in professional learning, complete administrative duties, and attend to personal matters. Although a ubiquitous component of the teaching workforce, little is known about their work conditions, motivations, experiences, and support. This study involved a mixed-methods research synthesis approach. Peer-reviewed studies and dissertations that examined the experiences and needs of substitute teachers in primary/elementary, middle, and secondary/high schools were examined. The study found that, although substitute teachers are a heterogeneous group, their conditions and experiences are less than satisfactory, exacerbated by a lack of targeted support. Education systems need to consider professionalizing this occupational group further. In addition, systems need to develop policies and practices that improve substitute teachers’ work.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2023 11:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221149418?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging What Students Know to Make Sense of Texts: What the Research Says About Prior Knowledge Activation</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This systematic literature review examined the research on prior knowledge and its activation to ascertain how these terms are defined, what specific techniques have been empirically investigated, and the conditions under which prior knowledge activation facilitated students’ comprehension. Fifty-four articles met the inclusion criteria and revealed that the terms prior knowledge and prior knowledge activation were often vaguely defined. Further, 30 unique techniques for activating readers’ prior knowledge representing eight different categories were identified. Those categories were open-ended prompts, procedural or strategic supports during reading, visual representations, analogical reasoning, text alteration, augmented activation, extratextual activities, and spontaneous activation. Techniques meant to facilitate knowledge activation prior to reading were most common, although the prompting of students’ existing knowledge was beneficial during and after reading as well. Variability in the effectiveness of activation techniques was related, in part, to the amount, accuracy, and specificity of students’ knowledge. Based on the key findings identified in this review, recommendations for future inquiry are forwarded, including suggested definitions of prior knowledge and prior knowledge activation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2023 11:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221148478?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Thematic Review of STEM Education for Disadvantaged Students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The present study proposed to thematically examine the studies on STEM education for disadvantaged students. International and national well-known databases (e.g., ERIC, PROQUEST Dissertations and Theses Global, ULAKBIM, Scopus, YOK-National Theses Center, and Google Scholar) were searched by means of keyword patterns (pattern 1: STEM education and disadvantaged students; pattern 2: STEM education and nondominant students; pattern 3: STEM education and underrepresented students). Then, the inclusion (e.g., STEM education for disadvantaged students, STEM careers/plans and their reasons) and exclusion (e.g., racial microaggressions in STEM education) criteria were applied. Thus, a total of 37 studies were appearant for the thematic review. Afterwards, the studies were analyzed in regard to the matrix (i.e., aims, methodologies, disadvantaged groups, intervention programmes, conclusions, and implications). The findings showed that such factors as socio-economic status, gender, ethnic/racial minority, and learning gap/disability influenced the disadvantaged students’ STEM careers. Therefore, future studies should cultivate these factors as moderator variables to drive disadvantaged students to the STEM careers and develop their potential competencies of STEM fields.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00247-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptions and consequences of mathematical argumentation, justification, and proof</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2023 03:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2165537?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investigating a teacher-perspective on pedagogical mathematical practices: possibilities for using mathematical practice to develop pedagogy in mathematical coursework</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;One of the challenges of university mathematics courses in secondary teacher preparation is incorporating pedagogical discussions. The focus in a mathematics course is—and should be—on mathematics. But research also suggests that without addressing pedagogical implications these content courses are not meaningful to secondary teachers’ future classroom practice. The thrust of this paper is exploring ideas for how to leverage mathematical practice in university mathematics courses—and, in particular, what have been described as Pedagogical Mathematical Practices (PMPs). The paper reports on a study of (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 10) pre- and in-service mathematics teachers that explored the viability of the PMP construct, with the intent of specifying particular PMPs. Drawing on interviews with teacher participants who had recent experiences in an inquiry-oriented discrete mathematics course, the study reports on the ways in which they identified a set of mathematical practices as being productive pedagogically. The study contributes a teacher-perspective on the construct of PMPs, including the identification of four PMPs from the study data: explicit visualization; multiple approaches; concrete exemplification; and informal justification. Implications for their potential use in university mathematics courses with regard to teacher education are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01468-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prospective Secondary Teachers’ Emergent Knowledge and Beliefs: Inquiry-Oriented Differential Equations Contributing to Teacher Preparation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article reports on the evolution of prospective secondary teachers’ knowledge (meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt;) and beliefs (about teaching and learning mathematics) in a semester-long inquiry-oriented differential equations class. Students entered the course with limited, primarily procedural, meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt;. Throughout the semester, they engaged in collaborative mathematical inquiry using a research-based curriculum. As viewed through the emergent perspective, students’ meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq3&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; and their beliefs about teaching and learning mathematics co-evolved with community norms and practices through the classroom discourse. Students’ end-of-term portfolios and portfolio presentations were analyzed for evidence of meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq4&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; and beliefs about students’ roles, instructors’ roles, and the general nature of learning mathematics. In these, students expressed rich, multifaceted meanings for &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq5&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\(\frac{dy}{dt}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; and beliefs about learning as an active process of meaning-making. While many prospective teachers do not see the relevance of advanced mathematics coursework to their career, these students reflected on their experiences in the course and volunteered ways in which their emerging knowledge and beliefs would influence their future practice. We emphasize that the classroom norms supported students in pursuing connections themselves, and conjecture that similar norms would support the development of reflective practitioners in other contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-023-01469-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Lower secondary students’ encounters with mathematical literacy</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Worldwide, there has been an increased emphasis on enabling students to recognise the real-world significance of mathematics. Mathematical literacy is a notion used to define the competencies required to meet the demands of life in modern society. In this article, students’ encounters with mathematical literacy are investigated. The data comprises interviews with 22 students and observations of 16 mathematics lessons in three grade 9 classes in Norway. The analysis shows that students’ encounters with mathematical literacy concern specific mathematical topics and contexts from personal and work life. Students’ encounters with ML in school is characterised by an emphasis on developing mathematical knowledge within the school context.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00386-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Complementary measures of conceptual understanding: a case about triangle concepts</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics curricula from many countries have emphasized conceptual understanding as more important than the mastery of isolated skills. However, researchers and educators have used different measures to access students’ conceptual understanding of mathematics. Thus, it seems necessary to further explore whether and to what extent different measurement techniques could lead to coherent findings. Therefore, this study compares the techniques that are commonly used in school settings with those proposed by researchers as effective in addressing conceptual understanding. Specifically, this study compares three techniques used to assess the quality of the conceptual understanding of triangles, conducted among a class of grade 8 students in China. The three techniques were a definition-example-nonexample test, a concept-mapping task, and a traditional paper-and-pencil test on the operations of the concepts and their relationships. The results show that these techniques provide complementary, rather than convergent, insights into students’ conceptual understanding. Their strengths and limitations in addressing students’ conceptual understanding were identified. The findings not only provide information for researchers, educators, and classroom teachers in identifying alternative techniques in assessing conceptual understanding but also a more holistic view of students’ conceptual understanding when different perspectives of this understanding are made explicit.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00381-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Elementary prospective teachers’ visions of moving beyond mathematics anxiety</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Previous studies of prospective elementary mathematics teachers’ mathematics anxiety have documented that many prospective teachers often worry about managing their repeated experiences of anxiety while developing their pedagogical and content knowledge to teach mathematics. The literature further indicates the importance of developing learning opportunities for prospective teachers to confront their past experiences while they (re)learn and learn to teach mathematics during methods courses. This study is situated within one such learning opportunity and seeks to analyze potential mathematics anxiety coping strategies generated by forty-eight prospective elementary teachers enrolled in a mathematical methods course. Written responses generated by the prospective teachers were subjected to qualitative thematic analysis to identify patterns of key ideas related to lesson planning for content they felt anxious and/or not confident about teaching and patterns focused on episodes of mathematics anxiety they might experience in the moment of teaching mathematics. Findings indicate that prospective teachers envision using between two and seven strategies grouped across eight coping strategy themes when given the opportunity to reflect on how they might deal with future instances of anxiety when they are tasked with teaching mathematics to their students. We highlight how some of the coping strategies that the prospective teachers envisioned as a means to cope with mathematics anxiety may have more potential to be helpful than others and present implications of our research for mathematics teacher educators.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00379-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Embracing pivotal teaching moments: elementary teachers’ role in advancing high cognitive levels of mathematics discourse</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The study of pivotal teaching moments (PTMs) offers significant insights into mathematics classroom interactions. PTMs are student-generated instances within a lesson that provide opportunities for teachers to modify planned instruction (Stockero &amp;amp; Van Zoest, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r32&quot;&gt;2013&lt;/span&gt;). Given the importance of interactions and discourse in students’ mathematical growth and understanding, we examine them in the context of &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;PTM episode triples.&lt;/em&gt; PTM episode triples consist of three main elements: (1) a PTM, (2) a teacher response to the PTM, and (3) the immediately ensuing student utterance. Analysis of data from nine elementary mathematics lessons shows that teacher responses that explicitly “pursued students’ thinking” elicited significantly higher cognitive levels of student discourse than teachers who &amp;quot;ignored or dismissed&amp;quot; PTMs or simply &amp;quot;acknowledged [PTMs] but continued as planned.&amp;quot; While many researchers have focused on PTM episode “doubles” (combinations of student-generated interruptions and the teacher’s response), no studies to our knowledge have addressed PTM episode “triples” as we have. Implications of these findings prove helpful for identifying concrete ways that educators can increase the cognitive level of student discourse within their classrooms. Further, our integration and modification of existing theory and frameworks for analyzing PTM episode triples—incorporating the relationship between PTMs and teachers’ responses to them, on the one hand, and the cognitive level of the ensuing student utterance, on the other hand—are a unique contribution to the field and provide a method by which researchers and educators can study classroom practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00374-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Eliciting mathematical reasoning during early primary problem solving</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical reasoning, which plays a critical role in students’ capacity to make sense of mathematics, is now emphasised more strongly in various curricula internationally. However, reasoning is sometimes difficult for teachers to recognise, let alone teach. This case study considers video of one teacher’s implementation of a problem-solving lesson in a year 1 primary school class in Australia. It examines the opportunities this teacher provided to leverage reasoning and contributes to the body of knowledge on ways reasoning may be elicited during problem solving. The new Eliciting Mathematical Reasoning Framework arising from the analysis of the data in this study builds on and extends previous research. It provides a tool to support researchers, teacher educators, professional learning providers, and teachers in recognising and eliciting reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00376-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Making the most of packing away: identifying mathematical opportunities for very young preverbal children</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Very young preverbal children (aged around 12 months) actively engage with their environment, whether at home, on outings, or in early learning centres. Their engagement with their environment can occur in many different ways involving physical and mental activities. In an early learning centre, there are many activities that very young preverbal children engage with on a daily basis. These activities may be fully child-initiated, fully educator-initiated, or somewhere in-between, but all will involve mathematics. It is important that the mathematics that these very young preverbal children might demonstrate in the actions undertaken during their activities are identified as it will provide the early childhood educator with an indication of the child’s mathematical understandings. Psychological research has demonstrated very young children engage in mathematical thinking, which leads to the question of how the mathematical thinking of very young preverbal children in a learning centre setting can be identified. This paper uses 360° video to explore how an everyday activity that would occur for very young preverbal children—packing away toys—could be used to identify the mathematical thinking the very young preverbal child may engage with by examining their actions. The identified mathematics is linked to research and documentation that outlines what mathematics very young preverbal children may understand. The importance of identifying the mathematics in the actions of very young children as part of the role of the early childhood educator is also considered.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00383-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can a number of diagrams linked to a proof task in 3D geometry improve proving ability?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The current study attempts to investigate whether using multiple diagrams attached to a geometry task could reduce difficulties in the proving process regarding concepts in three-dimensional geometry. Ninety 12th-grade students participated in the study. The research included the use of a questionnaire whose items invited open-ended responses regarding two tasks. Interviews were also conducted with some participants. Qualitative and quantitative analyses were performed. The results revealed a correlation between the students’ responses and the number of diagrams they received. Students who were given several diagrams gave more correct responses and correct and complete proofs than students who were given only one diagram presenting several diagrams attached to the proof task reduce the visual obstacles that students face in constructing geometrical proofs. The findings from the interviews support the results from the questionnaires; interviews revealed presenting further diagrams allow students to adapt their proving processes.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00385-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A qualitative metasynthesis of video-based prompts and noticing in mathematics education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We conducted a qualitative metasynthesis of research focused on prompts used to elicit noticing following video observations within mathematics education. Forty-nine, peer-reviewed articles were selected based on specific criteria and analyzed using a defined approach to better understand the variations in the prompts mathematics teacher educators used as they supported teacher noticing. We also focused on research findings from articles with different types of prompts. Forty-five percent of articles included a general prompt and 55% a specific prompt. Findings based on articles in which authors used specific prompts reported the following: (a) video is a helpful tool to support the learning of noticing, (b) noticing is a skill that can be developed, (c) noticing ability differs between novice and expert teachers. Findings from articles with general prompts indicate the following: (a) teachers experienced a shift in noticing, (b) how teachers’ noticed changed, (c) video selection is critical for influencing teacher noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00378-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Young children’s mathematical problem solving and thinking in a playworld</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In the literature in recent years, a number of developmental studies have demonstrated the importance of children entering the school environment with a solid foundation of mathematical content knowledge and argued that problem solving, as an important mathematical process, should be acknowledged in early childhood mathematical education. However, there is less research on how children process mathematics information through problem solving in play-based early childhood education settings. This paper draws upon a cultural-historical concept of play, motives and pedagogical process of a playworld approach to investigate how &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical Playworld&lt;/em&gt; creates the motivating conditions for young children to achieve a meaningful learning experience about repeating patterns? We argue that &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematical Playworld&lt;/em&gt;, as a new pedagogical approach within the worlds of imaginary situations, should be promoted, as it builds the motivating conditions that support meaningful learning of mathematical concepts in the double sense created in children. This study also contributes to understanding young children’s mathematical problem-solving processes in the collective imaginary situation, considering how learning processes become personally meaningful for children and capturing teachers’ role in play for supporting children’s mathematisation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00373-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can (perceived) mental-rotation performance mediate gender differences in math anxiety in adolescents and young adults?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Math anxiety is a negative affective reaction in situations concerning mathematics and is related to poor math performance and a lower mathematical self-concept. Gender differences appear in math anxiety even though gender differences in math abilities are non-existent or minimal in effect size. In the present study, gender and age differences in math anxiety, mental-rotation performance, and perceived mental-rotation performance are investigated as well as (perceived) mental-rotation performance as possible mediators of the relation between gender and math anxiety. Ninety-seven children (54 females) between 11 and 15 years and 84 undergraduate students (59 females) solved a mental-rotation test, rated their performance in this test, and filled out a questionnaire about math anxiety. Increasing gender differences with age were found for math anxiety, mental-rotation performance, and perceived mental-rotation performance. Mental-rotation performance and perceived mental-rotation performance were significant individual mediators for gender differences in math anxiety. Adequate measures should be discussed to enhance females’ mental-rotation abilities and their perception of these skills to reduce gender differences in math anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00387-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematics teacher educators’ knowledge sources in teacher education practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study aims to document and examine mathematics teacher educators’ (MTEs) knowledge sources in teacher education practices. The study adopts a mixed-method, embedded research design. Data were collected via a questionnaire with elicitations about MTEs’ descriptive features as well as with open-ended items. Target population was all MTEs working in mathematics education departments across Turkish universities. The questionnaire was emailed to all MTEs, and 281 out of 522 returned with their answers. MTEs’ written statements were examined via inductive thematic analysis. A post hoc quantitative analysis was also conducted to explore the relationships between knowledge sources and four variables: gender, self-identification, teaching experience and academic ranking. The analysis allowed the determination of a variety of knowledge sources in teacher education practices and established certain relationships. The findings are discussed with regard to MTEs’ professional development, conceptions of knowing and learning and the contribution of different sources to the teacher education practices.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00382-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Characteristics of high enjoyment teachers of mathematics in primary schools</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Despite teacher enjoyment of teaching being associated with a range of benefits for teachers and their students, little research exploring the characteristics of teachers who enjoy teaching mathematics exists. Semi-structured interviews were conducted with ten teachers who scored in the top third in terms of their enjoyment of teaching mathematics from a sample of 118 generalist, early-year primary school teachers. Thematic analysis of interview data revealed that negative-to-positive turning point experiences were commonplace amongst high-enjoyment primary teachers, but so too were reports of consistently positive feelings towards mathematics throughout their entire lives. While most articulated a passion for teaching mathematics, all teachers considered instances when students experienced ‘light bulb’ moments in their mathematical understanding that made a mathematics lesson enjoyable to teach. An important implication of our research is that one need not be a ‘maths person’ to come to love teaching mathematics. Rather, positive experiences in one’s pre-service teacher education, or in-service teacher professional learning, have the potential to transform one’s attitude towards teaching mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 23:02</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-021-00372-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Education Students’ Perceptions About Bilingualism and Emergent Bilingual Students</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 12:01</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01626620.2023.2174203?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing mathematical thinking skills through technology-based learning: a review of “technology-enabled mathematics education: optimising student engagement”</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-03-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09561-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BSRLM Day conference proceedings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-02-2023 11:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2169746?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Developing an analytical tool for radical socially-just teacher educator action research about language diverse mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-02-2023 11:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2150675?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The CRT culture war in the suburbs</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/5&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 18-23, February 2023. &lt;br/&gt; The suburbs are on the frontlines of a politicized culture war with critical race theory (CRT) at its center. States are passing legislation censoring teachers and administrators from using CRT in schools. This war threatens the intellectual freedom of educators and school leaders. The voices of the teachers, especially teachers of color, are largely absent. Antony Farag shares his experiences on the front lines and provides strategies for teachers and school leaders to navigate this war. He suggests that educators need to be a unifying force and that they must not be limited by censorship laws taking away their intellectual freedoms.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-02-2023 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231156225?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bookshelf: Kappan authors on their favorite reads</title>
        <description>
          
            Phi Delta Kappan, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/pdka/104/5&quot;&gt;Volume 104, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, Page 69-69, February 2023. &lt;br/&gt; In this regular column, Kappan authors recommend books that have inspired them as educators. This month, Mario Jackson recommends the 1970 classic Pedagogy of the Oppressed by Paulo Friere. And Rachel S. White recommends the 2014 young adult novel in poetry The Crossover by Kwame Alexander.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-02-2023 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00317217231156247?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
