<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the meaning of teacher education: the voice of the stakeholders</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/cete20/45/5&quot;&gt;Volume 45, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2022, Page 577-580&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2023 08:55</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2160287?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Everything That’s Hard Got Harder”: Preservice Teachers’ Attempts at Rigorous and Responsive Instruction During Pedagogical Rehearsals in the COVID Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;At the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic, our teacher preparation program shifted to an online setting, disrupting a key feature of practice-based teacher preparation: preservice science teachers’ (PSTs) approximation of rigorous and responsive instruction during extended pedagogical rehearsals, called macroteaching. Given this unplanned shock to their preparation, we examined how PSTs viewed macroteaching and their evolving participation in the teaching rehearsal. Using a situative perspective, we collected multiple forms of data. We found that although PSTs wanted to enact rigorous and responsive instruction, their participation was deeply affected by the sudden shift to an online setting. Our analysis of video-recorded lessons confirmed PSTs’ observations that their instruction became less rigorous and responsive over time. We conclude with questions about teacher preparation during the pandemic.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2023 05:11</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221139774?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Instructional quality of two beginning mathematics teachers for three years: what professional competency makes a difference?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics teaching is challenging particularly for teachers who have just started their careers. Research on this sort of teacher has focused separately on their knowledge, identity, or instructional quality. Yet, teaching mathematics as a profession requires synthetic and comprehensive competency. To fill this gap, this study investigates the relationship between changes in instructional quality and professional competency for teaching mathematics in terms of knowledge, skills, and identity. The current study recruited two beginning mathematics teachers who had the same teacher education backgrounds and worked at the same high school. We collected and analyzed video and audio recordings of their instruction and meetings and interviews about instruction. The findings reveal how their instructional quality changed during the first 3 years of teaching in addition to their heterogeneous professional competency for teaching mathematics. While both had high levels of mathematical knowledge for teaching, they differed in the extent of their skills for ambitious teaching and identity concerning mathematics instruction. Based on the findings, we argue that teacher education needs to value all aspects for professional competency synthetically, for indeed possessing mathematical knowledge alone is insufficient for a high quality of instruction. We also discuss approaches in teacher education about skills and identity for teaching mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10195-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Twenty years of research on technology in mathematics education at CERME: a literature review based on a data science approach</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Mathematics education is like many scientific disciplines witnessing an increase in scientific output. Examining and reviewing every paper in an area in detail are time-consuming, making comprehensive reviews a challenging task. Unsupervised machine learning algorithms like topic models have become increasingly popular in recent years. Their ability to summarize large amounts of unstructured text into coherent themes or topics allows researchers in any field to keep an overview of state of the art by creating automated literature reviews. In this article, we apply topic modeling in the context of mathematics education and showcase the use of this data science approach for creating literature reviews by training a model of all papers (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 336) that have been presented in Thematic Working Groups related to technology in the first eleven Congresses of the European Society for Research in Mathematics Education (CERME). We guide the reader through the stepwise process of training a model and give recommendations for best practices and decisions that are decisive for the success of such an approach to a literature review. We find that research in this period revolved around 25 distinct topics that can be grouped into four clusters: digital tools, teachers and their resources, technology experimentation, and a diverse cluster with a strong focus on student activity. Finally, a temporal analysis of these topics reveals a correlation between technology trends and research focus, allowing for reflection on future research in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10202-z</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The relation between attitudes towards mathematics and dropout from university mathematics—the mediating role of satisfaction and achievement</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The transition from school to university mathematics is a challenging process for many students, which is reflected in high dropout rates during the first year at university. Using mediation analysis, we want to shed light on the role of students’ attitudes towards mathematics—especially their interest in mathematics and their mathematical self-concept—for early dropout and investigate the underlying mechanisms for the relations between attitudes and dropout. Informed by frameworks of person-environment-fit and results from educational psychology, we consider satisfaction with one’s studies and achievement as potential mediators, influencing the relations between attitudes and early dropout. Our results within a sample of 274 first-year students, enrolled in a pure mathematics or a teacher education program at a German university, show that interest in university mathematics and mathematical self-concept are associated with less risk to drop out. In the case of interest, this relation is mediated by students’ satisfaction, and in the case of self-concept, this relation is mediated by satisfaction and achievement. Based on these results, we discuss how to support students during the transition from school to university mathematics in order to prevent early dropout.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-04-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10198-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Development of affect at the transition to university mathematics and its relation to dropout — identifying related learning situations and deriving possible support measures</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The transition from school to university mathematics is a challenging process for many students. This phenomenon is reflected by high dropout rates from mathematics programs especially during the first year at university that may be related to the development of students’ mathematical interest and self-concept. Taking a learning psychological perspective, it is a relevant question if all students have similar development patterns of these variables or if students who are at risk to drop out show an unfavorable development. Moreover, for didactical issues, it is of particular relevance which factors influence this development. Within a longitudinal study, 556 first-semester students stated their interest and self-concept at the beginning and the middle of the first semester; dropout was measured at the beginning of the second year. By using regression analyses, we found that the development of students’ interest and self-concept is related to dropout. It seems that interest in university mathematics and mathematical self-concept of students, who dropped out, decreased significantly in contrast to the characteristics of students who continued their studies. In an exploratory follow-up study, we identified factors which probably influenced the development of students’ self-concept by asking 18 students in a first-semester mathematics course “linear algebra” about learning situations in which they experienced the emergence or the decline of self-concept. Using qualitative content analysis, we found that most of these situations occurred when students worked on mathematical homework tasks or got criterial feedback on their solutions. Based on the presented results, we discuss implications for teaching and learning of undergraduate mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-03-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10200-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Politics of Belonging and Implications for School Organization: Autophotographic Perspectives on “Fitting In” at School</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;The notion of belonging is an often-referenced but under-theorized concept in studies of school organization. The purpose of this study is to examine the politics of belonging in schools and accompanying implications for how schools are organized and led. This research employs an autophotographic methodology. Student participants took photographs across 2 years of data collection of spaces where they did and did not “fit in” and participated in interviews to explain their photographs. Students identified four themes in their photographs regarding their sense of membership at school: (a) the importance of spaces where belonging is noncontingent; (b) the distinction between calm spaces and surveilled spaces; (c) anxiety in public, “wild” spaces where no help was available; and (d) generally positive but mixed impressions of teachers. An increased understanding of organization leadership for belonging is linked to numerous other timely concerns in educational administration, including equity and inclusion.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-02-2023 12:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221139766?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Middle and High School Students Who Take Care of Siblings, Parents, and Grandparents: Associations With School Engagement, Belonging, and Well-Being</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/9&quot;&gt;Volume 9, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2023. &lt;br/&gt;This partnership-based study identified how many middle and high school students take care of parents, siblings, and grandparents at home, via student surveys across Rhode Island public schools (N = 48,508; 46% White non-Latinx; 21% Latinx; 47% girls). Further, we investigated how students’ caregiving for family related to their school engagement, belonging, and emotional well-being. A sizable proportion of students reported caring for family for part (29%) or most of the day (7%). Girls and Black, Asian, Latinx, Native, and multiracial youth were more likely to care for family, compared to boys and White non-Latinx youth. Caregiving students from all demographics were more likely to experience intense sadness compared to noncaregivers, revealing a need to support caregiving youth in schools. In addition, caregiving girls reported lower levels of school engagement and school belonging. However, caregiving for part of the day was related to greater belonging among Black and Native youth.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-02-2023 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221140337?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Design principles for simulation-based learning of hypothesis testing in secondary school</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-02-2023 10:27</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2022.2161288?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Primary students’ learning about citizenship through data science</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Much of the mathematics that children experience in school neglect the skills increasingly needed for citizenship, particularly the power of complex data to investigate and make sense of the world. We draw on the relatively new field of data science as a multi-disciplinary approach to investigate problems through analysis of massive, non-standard, incongruous and/or messy data. Our exploratory qualitative study had as its research question: What can children learn about citizenship when they engage with data science? The case study in this paper illustrated ways that children’s learning about citizenship were enriched through an age-appropriate data science investigation. The study analysed classroom video from a Year 4 classroom (aged 9–10) over six lessons that integrated curricula in digital technologies, health, and mathematics. In these lessons, the children generated and analysed non-standard data and debated social, well-being and privacy issues as they considered their activities in cyberspace. The video data were analysed using a framework based on critical citizenship education literature that examined dimensions of power, collective engagement, individual responsibility and action. Three key findings emerged. First, the case study highlighted skills in citizenship education developed through data science, positioning children as agents and advocates. Second, the study showed how a complex data investigation in citizenship education was achievable with primary children through meaningful curriculum integration. This is important given that problems that citizens address are typically interdisciplinary. Finally, the findings revealed a gap between data science skills and those developed in the mathematics curriculum, and recommend ways that the maths curriculum could be updated.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-02-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01450-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Preservice elementary teachers’ mathematical achievement and attitudes: A study of blended learning</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The primary purpose of this quasi-experimental mixed-methods study was to examine whether a blended learning approach was more effective than traditional face-to-face instruction in improving the mathematical achievement and attitudes of preservice elementary teachers. The secondary purpose was to determine what specific features of blended learning were deemed most helpful to prospective teachers’ learning of mathematics. Sixty-three prospective teachers participated in a foundational mathematics course in either a face-to-face (F2F) traditional or blended learning format. At pre- and post-test, participants completed a researcher-developed mathematics achievement test and the Dutton’s Attitude Scale (Dutton in ESJ 68:259–264, 1968) . Blended learning participants also completed a post-course researcher-developed questionnaire on their perceptions of blended learning. Results indicated that participants who were enrolled in the blended learning format had significantly better attitudes at post-test than teachers in the F2F format, but no condition differences were found for mathematical achievement. Participants in the blended learning condition valued the flexibility of course structure and control over instructional pace but expressed that time management and decreased physical presence of the instructor were challenges. These findings suggest important elements to consider when designing blended learning courses.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-02-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10857-022-09565-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Five Keys for Growing Confident Math Learners</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 8-15
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p8.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Same Task but Different Learning Goals</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 16-24
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p16.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Life and Times of a Third-Grade Pencil</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 25-28
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p25.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Variations on a Theme of Fibonacci 1</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 29-47
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p29.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Approximating Pi</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 48-51
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p48.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>MTLT: Updates and Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 2-4
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p2.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Problems to Ponder</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 52-55
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p52.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GPS: Iterating and Partitioning</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 56-59
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p56.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>NCTM’s Activity Gems for the Classroom</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 60-61
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p60.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Is a Journey: Coaching as a Springboard</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 62-64
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p62.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Fostering Mathematical Thinking and Problem Solving: The Teacher’s Role”</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 66-74
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p66.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Visualizing Mathematics Through Knitting</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal Name: Mathematics Teacher: Learning and Teaching PK-12&lt;br/&gt;Volume: 116&lt;br/&gt;Issue: 1&lt;br/&gt;Pages: 76-76
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>01-01-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://pubs.nctm.org/view/journals/mtlt/116/1/article-p76.xml</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Experiences of preservice mathematics teachers during their education in times of pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, educational institutions at all levels closed their doors and began to operate remotely. In this paper, we analyze the educational experiences of preservice mathematics teachers (PMTs) enrolled in mathematics teacher education programs from three South American universities, as the pandemic was unfolding. An exploratory study was conducted, based on an inductive and thematic qualitative text analysis of narratives written by 24 PMTs. Based on the study, we report on the following aspects: (1) experiences of PMTs in the passage to remote education (RE) mode (considering characteristics of remote classes—interactions, the rhythm of the class, teaching work—time management, home–classroom fusion, and physical and psychological discomfort), and (2) opportunities and limitation experienced by PMTs in relation to the use of technologies. The results of the study suggest the need to rethink teacher education programs regarding the integration of technologies in mathematics classes, the opportunities offered by hybrid education, and teacher education for distance teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-31-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01461-4</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
