<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Stability of Families’ Revealed Preferences for Schools</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;I investigate longitudinal preferences for schools revealed by families’ applications to middle and high schools within a large urban school district’s universal enrollment system. I find that preferences for schools’ racial/ethnic composition are more stable than preferences for quality and proximity to home, even after concurrently controlling for all characteristics. White and Hispanic families’ preferences for composition are more durable than those of Black families, though stability overall attenuates when focusing on subgroups. Because preferences are not rigid over time, research and policy might continue exploring whether families can be guided toward options that improve academic outcomes and/or address segregation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-25-2022 10:25</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221125778?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using decision theory to understand preservice teachers’ implementations of mathematical modelling</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study, we aim to explain choices that groups of preservice teachers made to implement modelling tasks in primary school. We found that the preservice teachers decided to facilitate everyday-inspired contexts for the tasks and that this could be explained by their reasoning that modelling is supposed to be an activity close to reality. Essentially, the groups preferred two different approaches to introducing students to the tasks: (1) by inviting students to physically participate in situations related to their local communities that were familiar to them (e.g. trash picking), and (2) through pre-structured problems that were recognisable to students (e.g. estimation of the number of beads in an irregular box). We found evidence that the preservice teachers tended towards avoiding focusing on possible mathematical answers to the tasks. This could be explained by lacking experience with how to find approximate solutions, or that the preservice teachers were engaged in observing students’ solution strategies and mathematical behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-25-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00433-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Has “Who Comes Back” Changed? Teacher Reentry 2000–2019</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Studies of early-career teachers in the 1970s–1990s find that one-quarter to one-half of teachers who left the classroom eventually returned and that returning was associated with teachers’ gender and their child-rearing responsibilities. However, much has changed in the last forty years. Women are more likely to continue to participate in the labor force after having children, and teacher labor markets have been impacted by federal policy (e.g., No Child Left Behind, Race to the Top) and the Great Recession. Using data from the National Longitudinal Survey of Youth 1997 (NLSY97), I find that only one-fifth of teachers who exited the profession from 2000–2019 returned. This is a substantially lower rate of return compared to similar work using a previous cohort of teachers from NLSY79. Furthermore, I do not find evidence that teacher reentry is associated with gender or child-rearing status. These findings have implications for teacher labor markets, as reentering teachers can expand the pool of experienced teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-24-2022 11:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221122746?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>First-year university students&#39; self-regulated learning during the COVID-19 pandemic: a qualitative longitudinal study</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;When the COVID-19 pandemic began, many universities switched to fully online teaching. This unexpected switching to online teaching was challenging for both teachers and students, and restrictions that were put in place because of pandemic made this challenge even greater. However, new ways of teaching might also open new opportunities for students’ learning. The research question driving our study was as follows: how do students regulate their learning and specifically their choice of resources and peer learning in university mathematics classes that are fully taught online as offered during the COVID-19 pandemic? We report on a longitudinal, qualitative study in which students recorded a brief audio diary twice a week over one whole semester (14 weeks). We focused on three students who completed 70 interviews in total and finished the semester with varying degrees of success. The results show how the students structured their studying (e.g., the roles that deadlines or synchronous teaching events played). They illustrate the strengths and limitations of digital materials provided by the lecturer and the use of complementary media. Further, the pandemic uncovered the double-edged role of simple, often anonymous exchanges (e.g., via Discord servers), with few binding forces for either side, and the significance of stable learning partnerships for students’ success. Our research highlights aspects that should be focal points when comparing traditional instruction and online instruction during the pandemic from a self-regulatory perspective. Practical implications refer to how these aspects can be combined sensibly in fully online courses, but also in blended learning contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-24-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01444-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the challenges of learning quadratic equations and reflecting upon curriculum structure and implementation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;An important topic of study in secondary mathematics is non-linear functions, including quadratic equations. In this study, findings from 25 Year 11 students indicated that difficulties with critical prerequisite concepts such as algebraic conventions impeded students’ success in understanding and working with quadratics. Analysis of student errors identified misconceptions associated with the null factor law, and the nature of quadratic equations. This paper proposes that these findings are a result of limited timeframes nominated for learning quadratic topics outlined in the enacted curriculum. The implication of this is that the enactment of the Australian Curriculum: Mathematics F-10 did not support the development of conceptual understanding or procedural fluency with key mathematical concepts for these students. Without purposeful attention to prerequisite knowledge, and suitable time allocated to develop understanding and fluency, students’ proficiency with topics such as quadratics is negatively influenced. A mastery approach to the hierarchically organised curriculum is supported by findings of this study.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-24-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00434-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Component-Wise Reasoning as a Mechanism of Sense-Making in Real Analysis</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Undergraduate concepts are often first introduced in a single-dimensional setting and then extended to multiple dimensions. For instance, many undergraduate real analysis students will first learn of the metric topology on &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq1&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\({\mathbb{R}}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; before being exposed to more general metric spaces. I conducted a paired teaching experiment (Steffe &amp;amp; Thompson, &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus citation-ref citationid-c-r27&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/span&gt;) with introductory real analysis students that explored their learning of the general metric function. In this experiment, I was able to observe the students’ mathematical activity as they made sense of analytic ideas in increasingly general settings. I present a construct, called component-wise reasoning, that offers an explanatory mechanism for the ways that the students leveraged their understandings of phenomena on &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus inline-equation id-i-eq2&quot;&gt;
                    
                    &lt;span class=&quot;a-plus-plus equation-source format-t-e-x&quot;&gt;\({\mathbb{R}}\)&lt;/span&gt;
                    
                  &lt;/span&gt; to construct new schemes for similar phenomena in other metric spaces. I discuss how component-wise reasoning can offer explanatory power for students’ sense-making in abstract spaces across the undergraduate curricula.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-24-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00198-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the nature of arithmetical concepts–important content for the education of primary mathematics teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-23-2022 05:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2022.2139101?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Insights From the Health Profession Opportunity Grant Program’s Three-Armed, Multi-Site Experiment for Policy Learning and Evaluation Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Administered by the Office of Family Assistance in the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services’ Administration for Children and Families (ACF), the Health Profession Opportunity Grants (HPOG) Program provided education and training to Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) recipients and other adults with low incomes for occupations in the healthcare field. The impact evaluation for the first cohort of grantees (HPOG 1.0) leveraged the program’s implementation across many locations, using a three-armed evaluation design (including a second treatment arm) in some places, as a way to examine whether any of three selected program components, or enhancements, contributed to the program’s overall impact. This article tells the story of the evaluation and draws lessons from that experience, discussing implications for future implementation of multi-armed experiments in a multi-site evaluation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-22-2022 01:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221133420?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-22-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00196-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mathematical Knowledge for Teaching Proof: Comparing Secondary Teachers, Pre-Service Secondary Teachers, and Undergraduate Majors</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The calls for reasoning and proof to have a prominent place in secondary mathematics classrooms raise the question of knowledge that teachers need to support student learning of reasoning and proof. Several conceptualizations of Mathematical Knowledge for Teaching Proof (MKT-P) have been proposed over the years, yet some key questions about the nature of MKT-P remain unclear, such as whether MKT-P is a special kind of knowledge specific to teaching or whether it is just common mathematics knowledge. Another question is whether MKT-P can be improved through targeted intervention. Our study attempts to respond to both questions. An MKT-P questionnaire was administered to in-service secondary teachers, undergraduate mathematics and computer science (M&amp;amp;CS) majors, and pre-service secondary teachers before and after taking a capstone course&lt;/em&gt; Mathematical Reasoning and Proving for Secondary Teachers. &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The results suggest that MKT-P is indeed a specialized type of knowledge, which can be improved through targeted intervention.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-22-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00187-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is a substitute the same? Learning from lessons centering different relational conceptions of the equal sign</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Understanding of the equal sign is associated with early algebraic competence in the elementary grades and equation-solving success in middle school. Thus, it is important to find ways to build foundational understanding of the equal sign as a relational symbol. Past work promoted a conception of the equal sign as meaning “the same as”. However, recent work highlights another dimension of relational understanding—a &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;substitutive&lt;/em&gt; conception, which emphasizes the idea that an expression can be substituted for another equivalent one. This work suggests a substitutive conception may support algebra performance above and beyond a sameness conception alone. In this paper, we share a subset of results from an online intervention designed to foster a relational understanding of the equal sign among fourth and fifth graders (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; = 146). We compare lessons focused on a sameness conception alone and a dual sameness &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; substitutive conception to each other, and we compare both to a control condition. The lessons influenced students’ likelihood of producing and endorsing sameness and substitutive definitions of the equal sign. However, the impact of the lessons on students’ approaches to missing value equations was less clear. We discuss possible interpretations, and we argue that further research is needed to explore the roles of sameness and substitutive views of the equal sign in supporting structural approaches to algebraic equation solving.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01405-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fourth graders’ expression of the general case</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This study forms part of a classroom teaching experiment on the development of a group of 25 9–10 years old students’ algebraic thinking. More specifically, it explored their reasoning while solving word problems built around functional relationships to determine how they generalized through questions posed using natural language, drawn figures or the keyword ‘many’. Their written and oral answers to those questions were analyzed qualitatively to determine which approach most effectively supported the expression of their generalization. The results reveal the benefits of posing questions about the general case in different ways while teaching students to use conventional algebraic representations. According to these findings, representing indeterminate quantities with the keyword ‘many’ induces generalization more successfully than representing them with letters. The use of letters prompts students to seek meaning for the letters, either conventionally, as an unknown or variable quantity, or otherwise, as a label or specific values assigned according to their own criteria. Identifying the most effective procedures may help teachers and curriculum designers formulate mathematical tasks that encourage students to express the generality they perceive in particular cases. Determining the communication demands of each approach is likewise highly useful.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01398-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Variables in early algebra: exploring didactic potentials in programming activities</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper we consider implications of the current world-wide inclusion of computational thinking in relation to children’s development of algebraic thinking. Little is known about how newly developed visual programming environments such as Scratch could enhance early algebra learning. The study is based on examples of programming activities used by mathematics teachers in Sweden, teaching students aged 10–12 years during the first two years of implementing programming in the mathematics curriculum. Informed by Chevallard’s praxeology in terms of praxis and logos, we describe, unpack, discuss and expand these activities. Core issues related to algebra found in the three activities are as follows: making implicit variables explicit; using a counter variable; and identifying parameters as a specific type of variable. Our findings show that, in addition to already identified uses of variables in early algebra, programming activities in the early years bring in new aspects and new ways of treating variables that could, potentially, enhance students’ understanding of variables and generalization, provided that programming praxis is embedded in an appropriate algebra logos.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01384-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The use of cultural contexts for patterning tasks: supporting young diverse students to identify structures and generalise</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;A key aspect of young children’s development of algebraic reasoning is the process of visualising and identifying structures to both abstract and generalise. There has been a growing body of research focused on how students form generalisations, this article adds to the existing body of research by examining how young culturally diverse students identify mathematical structures in contextual growing patterns and the teaching and learning actions that assist them to generalise. Data were collected from one classroom of 29 Year Two (6 years old) students in a low socio-economic school in New Zealand. Results from the analysis of lessons related to two tasks showed that the contextual tasks led students to notice different mathematical structures. Specific pedagogical actions were used to facilitate students’ engagement with the growing patterns. These included positioning students to engage with different representations (pictorial and numerical, tabular, and natural language) to represent thinking, the use of classroom discussions, noticing and responding to student thinking, and pressing students to find far terms. The findings highlight that both the contextual patterning tasks and teacher actions supported the young students to develop a range of sophisticated generalisations related to the underlying mathematical structure and functional relationships of the growing patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01386-y</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of variables in relational thinking: an interview study with kindergarten and primary school children</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Relational thinking and dealing with variables are two essential aspects of algebraic thinking. Relational thinking means viewing mathematical expressions and equations as a whole rather than as individual computing processes. It is characterized by using relationships between mathematical objects, and refers to the relations of equality and inequality. In this study, to examine the relational thinking of kindergarten and primary school children, this perspective was applied using non-symbolic representations in the form of boxes and marbles. Using multiple variables is a very powerful but also difficult tool of algebra. The study had the aim of examining how kindergarten children and primary school children establish relationships between several variables which are represented with real materials. The interview study was conducted with children aged 5–10 years. Marbles and different colored boxes represented equations with unknowns and quantities depending on each other. Initially, two approaches could be differentiated, namely, number-oriented and structure-oriented approaches. It could be shown that certain conceptualizations of variables were related to children’s ability to show relational thinking. Kindergarteners are stimulated to think relationally by unknown quantities which can be determined. This process was observed in primary school children dealing with quantities that depended on each other. In addition, the conceptualization of the variables represented as boxes was examined. The concepts of general number and variable as changing quantity were categorized. Further conceptualizations resulted from the interview data, namely, categories of the undeterminable, the specific number, and the quasi-general.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01419-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The centrality of student-generated representation in investigating generalizations about the operations</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article addresses the nature of student-generated representations that support students’ early algebraic reasoning in the realm of generalized arithmetic. We analyzed representations created by students for the following qualities: representations that distinguish the behavior of one operation from another, that support an explanation of a specific case of a generalization, and that support justification of a generalization. One key finding is that representations in the form of pictures, diagrams, arrangements of manipulatives, or story contexts that embody the meaning of the operation(s) allow students to distinguish between operations. Such representations can be used by young students to illustrate relationships conveyed in specific instances of a general claim. Further, extending these representations to class of numbers is a mechanism for proving a general claim.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01379-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Seeds of algebraic thinking: a Knowledge in Pieces perspective on the development of algebraic thinking</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we elaborate the &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;seeds of algebraic thinking&lt;/em&gt; perspective, drawing upon Knowledge in Pieces as a heuristic epistemological framework. We argue that students’ pre-instructional experiences in early childhood lay the foundation for algebraic thinking and are a largely untapped resource in developing students’ algebraic thinking in the classroom. We theorize that seeds of algebraic thinking are cognitive resources abstracted over many interactions with the world in children’s pre-instructional experience. Further, we provide examples to demonstrate how the same seeds of algebraic thinking present in early childhood can be invoked in reasoning across contexts, grade levels, and different levels of formality of algebraic instruction. The examples demonstrate how the seeds perspective differs from other accounts of the relationship between children’s early activity and their engagement in algebraic reasoning processes. We anticipate this new theoretical direction for characterizing the nature and development of algebraic thinking will lay the foundation for a robust agenda that sheds light on the development of algebraic thinking and informs algebra instruction, particularly how teachers notice and respond to children’s developing algebraic thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01374-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Coordinating invisible and visible sameness within equivalence transformations of numerical equalities by 10- to 12-year-olds in their movement from computational to structural approaches</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;“They are the same” is a phrase that teachers often hear from their students in arithmetic and algebra. But what do students mean when they say this? The present paper researches the notion of sameness within algebraic thinking in the context of generating equivalent numerical equalities. A group of Grade 6 Mexican students (10- to 12-year-olds) was presented with tasks that required transforming the given numerical equalities in such a way as to show their truth-value. The students initially indicated this by calculating and demonstrating that the total was the same on both sides. When asked not to calculate, their approaches evolved into more structural transformations involving decomposition so as to arrive at an equality with the same expression on each side. Students used the language of sameness—both visible and invisible—to describe the truth-value of their transformed expressions and equalities. The visible sameness referred to the resulting identical form of each side of the equality and the invisible sameness to the top–down equivalences that they had generated by their decomposing transformations—both types of sameness being characterized by their hidden numerical values. These findings suggest implications for transitioning to the algebraic domain of equations with their similarly hidden values.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01355-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Design of a pattern and correspondence unit to foster functional thinking in an elementary mathematics textbook</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Given the significance of functional thinking as one of the main routes to foster early algebraic thinking, in this paper we describe how a current elementary mathematics textbook’s unit titled “Pattern and Correspondence” was developed in the Korean context. The following four key instructional elements for fostering functional thinking were extracted from the literature review: (a) correspondence relationships in real-life contexts; (b) various pattern tasks; (c) exploration for a correspondence relationship; and (d) symbol variables to represent a correspondence relationship. These elements were employed to analyze the strengths and weaknesses of the unit covering pattern and correspondence in the previous mathematics textbook. Based on this analysis, a new draft for the pattern and correspondence unit was designed and implemented in an elementary school to test its appropriateness and ability to enhance students’ functional thinking. Students’ responses using the new draft were analyzed in terms of the four elements. Performance between the students with the new draft and their counterparts with the previous textbook was compared. The students with the new draft were more successful than their counterparts in exploring and representing the relationship between two quantities. The final version of the unit was developed and has been applied to all schools. The whole process of developing the unit can be an example of how to foster functional thinking through changes to curricular resources.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01411-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Starting points: understanding children’s pre-instructional intuitions about function tables</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Functional thinking is an established route into algebra. However, the learning mechanisms that support the transition from arithmetic to functional thinking remain unclear. In the current study we explored children’s pre-instructional intuitive reactions to functional thinking content, relying on a conceptual change perspective and using mixed methods. The sample included 20 grade 3 students and 24 grade 5 students. First, we assessed children’s arithmetic skills and intuitive responses to generalisation tasks involving variation tables. The quantitative analysis showed that students’ arithmetic skills correlated with functional aspects such as the following: identifying, and expressing function rules with words but not with the symbolic expression of function rules. The qualitative analysis revealed that students constructed framework theories that generated different intuitive conceptions of the algebraic ideas involved in noticing and expressing generalisation. Students’ conflicts were concentrated in areas that determine key differences between arithmetic and algebra, such as generalisation, indeterminate quantities, and variable notation. We discuss how these results contribute to explaining the construction of algebra concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01424-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Fifth graders’ learning to solve equations: the impact of early arithmetic strategies</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study we aimed to inquire into the impact of the use of early arithmetic strategies by a group of fifth-grade students, on their solving of equations involving two representations of unknowns. Pre- and post-tests consisting of equation-solving items involving two representations of unknowns (number sentences containing empty ‘brackets’, as in the example 5 + (∙) = 10, or equations containing &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;x,&lt;/em&gt; as in 5 + &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; = 10), were administered to 126 fifth-grade students in a regular class setting. We found a notable difference between students’ success rates on these two types of equations and their strategy use. Most students used the inversing strategy (arithmetic operations) after formal instruction on equation solving. Several students even used both the inversing and formal strategies (performing the same operation on both sides) for the same equation. When the unknown &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; appeared as the subtrahend or the divisor, the success rate dropped dramatically, and students tried to use the formal solving method of performing the same operation on both sides to solve such equations. The findings of this study not only suggest how teachers can be sensitive to students’ different interpretations of unknowns, but also highlight the importance of using students’ prior sense making to teach equation solving and of helping students gain an in-depth understanding of equation solving and representations of unknowns.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 22:25</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01417-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>International Perspectives on Knowledge and Quality: Implications for Innovation in Teacher Education Policy and Practice</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 07:05</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2138324?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Who Benefited More From the Developmental Education Reform in Florida? The Role of Exemption Status</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Under Florida’s developmental education (DE) reform since 2014, recent public high school graduates and active-duty military personnel became exempt from DE and traditional placement tests. The legislation also required colleges to provide accelerated instruction strategies for students remaining in DE and offer enhanced advising and support services for all incoming students. Focusing on the differential policy impacts on exempt and nonexempt students, we used statewide administrative data to examine changes in first-year completion rates for gateway math and English courses before and after the reform. Overall, and for those deemed to be college-ready, nonexempt students benefited more from the reform; however, the opposite is true for students who were not college-ready, with exempt students benefiting more. This study confirms that each component of the reform has played a role in contributing to its success.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 05:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221126474?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Integrating the Soliya Connect Program into a Classroom Course on Critical Intercultural Communication</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>10-21-2022 05:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2137821?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
