<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Becoming HOPEless in the 2-Year Sector</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Becoming HOPEless in the 2-year sector addresses the question: what happens when a state-wide policy removes merit-based financial aid from low-income students making satisfactory academic progress? To assess the magnitude of this HOPEless effect, we compared credits attempted, attained, and persistence and graduation indicators of HOPEless students against the outcomes of their not targeted/affected peers. Relying on multiple quasi-experimental analytic techniques (difference in differences [DD], DD in differences, Fuzzy regression discontinuity, and multi-treatment propensity score weighting), two mutually exclusive analytic samples (one longitudinal and one cross-sectional), and over one million observations across four academic years (2009–2010 to 2012–2013), we consistently found that HOPEless students realized worse outcomes and even persisted fewer terms/semesters than students on academic probation. The State saved about $150 million in lottery money (largely funded by lower-income households) but did so at the expense of 665,192 credit hours that would have been attained by HOPEless (low-income) students.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-23-2022 09:47</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221120276?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Race, Gender, and Teacher Equity Beliefs: Construct Validation of the Attributions of Mathematical Excellence Scale</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Teachers’ beliefs can have powerful consequences on instructional decisions and student learning. However, little research focuses on how teachers’ beliefs about the role of race and gender in mathematics teaching and learning influence educational equity within classrooms. This gap is partly due to the lack of studies focused on variation within classrooms, which in turn is hampered by the lack of instruments designed to measure mathematics-specific equity beliefs. In this study of 313 preservice and practicing elementary teachers, we report evidence of construct validity for the Attributions of Mathematical Excellence Scale. Factor analyses provide support for a four-factor structure, including genetic, social, personal, and educational attributions. The findings suggest that the same system of attribution beliefs underlies both racial and gender prejudice among elementary mathematics teachers. The Attributions of Mathematical Excellence Scale has the potential to provide a useful outcome measure for equity-focused interventions in teacher education and professional development.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-22-2022 05:42</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221130999?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Overlap Violations in Clustered Observational Studies of Educational Interventions</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 07:50</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2144563?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Literacy’s Schrödinger’s cat: capturing reading comprehension with social annotation</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 06:09</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10476210.2022.2146088?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effect of School District Consolidation on Student Achievement: Evidence From Arkansas</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;School district consolidation is one of the most widespread education reforms of the last century, but surprisingly little research has directly investigated its effectiveness. To examine the impact of consolidation on student achievement, this study takes advantage of a policy that requires the consolidation of all Arkansas school districts with enrollment of fewer than 350 students for two consecutive school years. Using a regression discontinuity model, we find that consolidation has either null or small positive impacts on student achievement in math and English Language Arts (ELA). We do not find evidence that consolidation in Arkansas results in positive economies of scale, either by reducing overall cost or by allowing for a greater share of resources to be spent in the classroom.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221133394?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher educators’ general beliefs and personal identifications related to mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Dominant cultural beliefs contend that mathematics is exclusive; only some have access to “the gift.” Within classrooms and amidst everyday vernacular, scripts about mathematics and who can “do” mathematics reify such traditional beliefs. Mathematics teacher educators work with preservice teachers (PSTs) to challenge such beliefs, but they only represent a part of the community teaching PSTs. Non-mathematics teacher educators (TEs) may not overtly teach mathematical concepts, but within their hidden curricula, they likely transmit beliefs about mathematics and convey their positions as math people. Little research has been conducted on TEs’ mathematical beliefs and identities; therefore, little is known about how they transmit or challenge traditional beliefs about mathematics to their PSTs. This article aims to start the conversation about the role of TEs in transforming or maintaining mathematical beliefs by reporting the findings from an analysis of seventeen TEs’ responses to questions related to their general beliefs about mathematics and how they position themselves as math people. Most participants articulated innovative, inclusive beliefs about mathematics but refused to identify fully as math people. Self-exclusion explanations given for not identifying as math people included preferences to other content areas; comparisons to others; not having a profession that requires traditional school math; and perceived deficits in mathematical understanding, despite strengths, enjoyment, and/or confidence in mathematics courses and/or real-world problem solving. Analysis revealed avoidance of emotional suffering and risk at the root of some rejections of the “math person” identification. Implications and suggested future steps also are included.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-21-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00436-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;a href=&quot;/toc/reac20/30/5&quot;&gt;Volume 30, Issue 5&lt;/a&gt;, December 2022, Page 687-688&lt;br/&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-20-2022 07:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09650792.2022.2134533?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do Black and White Students Benefit From Racial Socialization? School Racial Socialization, School Climate, and Youth Academic Performance During Early Adolescence</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;With racial inequalities plaguing the U.S. school system, educators have recognized the importance of establishing inclusive, equitable, and diverse school environments where students from different ethnic-racial backgrounds can feel respected and supported. This study examined the longitudinal links between adolescents’ experiences of school racial socialization, school climate perceptions, and academic performance and tested whether these links varied by race (n = 941; 54% boys; 63% Black, 37% White). Results revealed that adolescents’ experience of school racial socialization practices (i.e., cultural socialization and promotion of cultural competence) predicted positive changes in their perceptions of school climate and, in turn, promoted better academic performance. School racial socialization was linked to positive school experiences and achievement for both Black and White adolescents.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-19-2022 05:43</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221134771?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Black School Closings Aren’t New: Historically Contextualizing Contemporary School Closings and Black Community Resistance</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Whereas increased scholarly attention is focusing on contemporary school closings, noticeably absent is the placement of this scholarship within the historical context of Black people’s social experiences. This paradigm shift would reveal a much longer history that has had devastating consequences for Black people. In this article, we identify five waves of Black school closings and provide contemporary case studies that reveal an ongoing pattern resulting in the destabilization of Black communities across time and space. Despite persistent attacks on these institutions, our analyses capture Black people’s resistance and agency in maintaining their communities and schools. In addition to providing policy implications, we further suggest the term Black community-killing as a theoretical way of thinking about the consequences of school closings.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221131504?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teacher Turnover in Early Childhood Education: Longitudinal Evidence From the Universe of Publicly Funded Programs in Louisiana</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study uses longitudinal data to follow a cohort (N = 4,465) of all early childhood education teachers working in publicly funded, center-based settings in Louisiana over a 3-year period. We present the proportion of teachers still at their sites across six time points between 2016 and 2019, providing the first statewide, longitudinal estimates of within-year and multiyear retention. We find that less than 40% teachers in the fall of 2016 are still at their site by the fall of 2019. Turnover is particularly high among childcare teachers (compared to teachers at Head Start or school-based pre-kindergarten), teachers of toddlers, and teachers new to their sites. Policy implications are discussed.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221131505?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Three-Arm Random Assignment Within Sites can Improve Non-Experimental Cross-Site Estimates of the Relationship Between Program Characteristics and Impact</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article considers a new method, called Cross-Site Attributional Model Improved by Calibration to Within-Site Individual Randomization Findings (abbreviated as “CAMIC”), which seeks to reduce bias in analyses of the contributions of a program’s various design, implementation, and contextual characteristics to its overall impacts. It requires a multi-site experiment where some (or all) sites randomize individuals to one of three arms: a standard treatment group, an enhanced treatment group (that receives the standard treatment plus a program “enhancement”), or a control group (that has no access to the program). A recent evaluation—that of the Health Profession Opportunity Grants (HPOG) program—provides a motivating example of this design and its potential for both methodological and substantive lessons; and the article considers other evaluations that would be fitting for deploying and learning from CAMIC. We conclude that the promise for CAMIC lies in situations where the correlations between the selected program enhancement and alternative program characteristics of interest are relatively high, implying that producing an experimental estimate of the enhancement can reduce bias in the estimation of other non-randomized program characteristics.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221140614?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bridging Educational Change and Social Justice: A Call to the Field</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The education research community, both within the American Educational Research Association (AERA) and beyond, could and should play a critical role in fundamentally transforming educational institutions and systems. Given its complexity, transformative change in education is best undertaken as a collective endeavor. Yet for researchers to be a valuable resource in educational transformation, we will need to bridge knowledge across subfields that currently have limited interaction. Through two illustrative examples, we demonstrate the need to link knowledge on educational change with knowledge on how to create more equitable, anti-racist, and decolonized spaces for formal and informal learning. While operating in different spaces and initiated at different entry points, the two change efforts exemplify a common set of commitments and actionable pathways for achieving transformational change. This article is a call to action for researchers to join together in supporting educational transformation that fundamentally challenges the inequitable arrangements persisting in educational organizations characterized by systemic racism and colonialism. Bridging knowledge bases and being accountable to serve and support communities and their intersectional identities are essential to making deep, scalable changes in education that promote social justice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-18-2022 07:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221138837?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledgments</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/jebb/47/6&quot;&gt;Volume 47, Issue 6&lt;/a&gt;, Page 777-780, December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 12:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221138055?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Indigenous Students and English Learner Identification: A Fifty-State Policy Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;English learner (EL) education is widely conceived as services for immigrant-origin students, however nearly one in ten American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian students are classified in school as EL. Title III of the Every Student Succeeds Act (2015) defines EL eligibility differently for Indigenous, compared to non-Indigenous, students with implications for who is identified as an EL and how best to serve their academic and linguistic interests. This study presents findings from a 50-state review of Indigenous EL identification policy. We find that states fall into four categories ranging from no differentiation in Indigenous EL identification to clear differentiation. We describe each of these four categories and conclude with reflections on how this wide variation in state policies has implications for Indigenous students’ educational resources and experiences.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134697?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Designing for a Productive Politics of Participation in Research Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article considers contested conceptions of community and trajectories toward full participation in research-practice partnerships (RPPs) as key analytical aspects for studying a productive politics of participation. RPPs, as methodology and infrastructure for community participation, frequently surface the character of participation in intersecting communities of practice—making them visible and actionable. I examine two youth-serving RPPs. This analysis considers youth digital media projects as strategies for increasing participation and renegotiating power relations. Findings signal RPPs can help discern the degree to which young people are held on the periphery in communities of practice where marginalizing relations can be reinforced.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:35</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134586?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Research-Practice Partnerships Responsive to Partners’ Needs? Exploring Research Activities During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Despite everyone’s best intentions, RPP-produced research may still fall short of being responsive to the needs of practice partners. The COVID-19 pandemic arguably magnified the demand for research to help education leaders make informed decisions in unprecedented ways. Were RPPs able to be responsive to practice-side partners in their time of need? We draw upon data collected as part of the 2019, 2020, and 2021 National Network of Education Research-Practice Partnerships’ (NNERPP) annual reports to explore this question. Our findings suggest an increase in design-based projects, in addition to increases in quick-turnaround research syntheses in order to accommodate partner needs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134584?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effects of School Choice Competition on an Underserved Neighborhood Public School</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This critical ethnography utilizes critical policy analysis and a theoretical understanding of neoliberal racism to examine the practiced reality of school choice in a public, under-resourced, and historically underperforming neighborhood elementary school attended predominantly by Latina/o/x students. Despite improvement initiatives that resulted in performance distinctions, the school under study experienced substantial enrollment decline amidst the poaching of students by charter schools within the attendance zone. Moreover, the competitive school choice market within the school’s district resulted in the reshuffling of teachers, reinforcement of neoliberal improvement discourses, and even the exploitation of dual language students to raise the school’s market profile. The study provides a unique, up-close representation of marketization in public schools and the residualizing effects that school choice policies can have on public education writ large.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134583?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Political Considerations for Establishing Research-Practice Partnerships in Pursuit of Equity: Organizations, Projects, and Relationships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;If the RPP field is to bring our stated commitments to equity to life, it will require engagement with the political dimensions of RPP work, starting at the outset when a partnership is being established. In particular, prospective members must consider how the research process and products might (or might not) lead to more equitable systems. Recognizing that RPP work centering equity sits at the intersection of distinct intellectual genealogies, I argue that research and activist traditions drawing on critical and decolonial traditions—often overlooked in RPP literature—provide particularly relevant insights. Working through questions relevant to the establishment of an RPP on organizational, project-level, and relational dimensions, analyses and examples drawn from scholars, as well as journalists, organizers, educators, and young people illustrate the political considerations inherent in each. I close with implications for new and existing RPPs and directions for future research on RPPs as a methodology.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 10:15</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221130993?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Math cleverly disguised as/with string”: experienced weavers’ engagement with mathematics</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-17-2022 03:26</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2133005?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“What Do You Think She’s Going to Do Next?” Irresolution and Ambiguity as Resources for Collective Engagement</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2022 10:08</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07370008.2022.2129641?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Topic specificity of students’ conceptual and procedural fraction knowledge and its impact on errors</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2022 07:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2135132?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Personal elaborated feedback design in support of students’ conjecturing processes</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2022 01:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2137571?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the interplay between targeted motivation interventions and motivational teaching practices in mathematics classrooms</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Prior research has shown that brief motivation interventions, such as interventions targeting students’ perceptions concerning relevance of the learning material, can have long-lasting effects on students’ motivation and performance. However, the educational contexts in which these interventions have been implemented have their own motivational affordances, such as the extent to which teachers support students’ perceptions of relevance in regular classes. According to the seed-and-soil hypothesis for the effectiveness of psychological interventions, such interventions can be seen like a “seed” that needs to be implemented in a supportive educational context (i.e., the “soil”) in order to work. Therefore, in this study we examined the interplay between a one-time relevance intervention implemented in mathematics classrooms and the mathematics teacher’s relevance support as perceived by the students before and after the intervention. Data stemmed from a cluster-randomized controlled trial with 79 ninth-grade mathematics classes (&lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; = 1744 students) in which the intervention was implemented by the mathematics teacher or a master’s student, both trained for this purpose. Multilevel moderation models showed that both intervention conditions had larger effects when students perceived higher relevance support before or after the intervention, thus providing support for the seed-and-soil hypothesis. Furthermore, multilevel mediation models indicated a positive effect of the teacher condition on perceived relevance support at posttest compared with the control condition, which partly explained the positive effect of this intervention condition on utility value at follow-up. The results shed light on the contexts in which these interventions are most effective and the mechanisms through which they work.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-16-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01446-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teachers’ Mental Health During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;With an emergence of research investigating the educational impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic, empirical studies assessing teachers’ mental health throughout the pandemic have been scarce. Using a large national data set, the current study compares mental health outcomes during the pandemic between pre-K–12 teachers and professionals in other occupations. Further, we compare the prevalence of mental health outcomes between in-person and remote teachers (N = 134,693). Findings indicate that teachers reported a greater prevalence of anxiety symptoms than did those in other professions and that remote teachers reported significantly higher levels of distress than did those teaching in person. We summarize the policy implications of these results.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-15-2022 12:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221134281?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
