<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>School Inclusion of Refugee Students: Recent Trends From International Data</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;As children with refugee backgrounds continue to enroll in schools worldwide, attention to their educational needs and experiences has increased. In this study, we analyze the extent that schools and classrooms provide refugee students with equitable educational opportunities compared to students who are not refugees, and whether their teachers feel prepared for and engaged in culturally responsive instructional practices. Using survey data on 130,803 teachers and 8,054 schools sampled from 41 predominantly distant resettlement host countries in the 2018 Teaching and Learning International Survey, we find lower levels of resources, safety, and social inclusion for refugee students but higher levels of preparation and instructional practices in multicultural education among their teachers. The results have policy implications for supporting students with refugee backgrounds in different school contexts.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-13-2023 12:36</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221149396?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of Performance Funding Policy Design on College Access and Selectivity</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study draws on a comprehensive performance-based funding (PBF) dataset and up-to-date difference-in-differences econometrics to examine the impacts of specific policy features (e.g., share of institutional revenue at stake and equity metrics) on college access and selectivity. We find suggestive evidence that increases in the share of revenue at stake are associated with decreases in racially minoritized student enrollment. Meanwhile, equity metrics may not be enough to boost enrollment among underserved students. Ultimately, however, our conclusions are limited due to various potential sources of bias, unconvincing pre-trends, and wide confidence intervals. While findings offer limited insight into the impacts of specific design features, they point to limitations of PBF—regardless of design—in expanding access and reducing inequities at 4-year colleges.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-13-2023 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221147905?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engaging a Kanaka ʻŌiwi Literature Review Methodology Through Research on Native Hawaiian Culture-Based Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although research shows that critical outcomes occur for Native students when culture-based education (CBE) centers self-determination, sovereignty, and Indigeneity, Kanaka ʻŌiwi (Native Hawaiian) students rarely learn about these concepts. This review thus seeks to understand how scholars operationalize self-determination and Ea (sovereignty, life) in research on Native Hawaiian CBE and the extent to which this operationalization provides pathways for students to internalize the two concepts, self-identify as Indigenous, and enact praxis. By foregrounding Kānaka ways of knowing and being, a Kanaka ʻŌiwi literature review methodology (KanakaʻŌiwiLRM) is conceptualized and engaged to analyze 20 literature sources. Findings indicate that self-determination and Ea are positioned as the foundations and outcomes of CBE, yet disregarded as a basis for Indigenous self-identification. This results in a call for a purposeful decolonial Native Hawaiian CBE approach that nourishes Indigenous unity and supports self-determination, Ea, and pathways toward praxis.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-11-2023 06:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221149004?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Well Do High-Achieving Undergraduate Students Understand School Algebra?</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of this research is to investigate how well high-achieving students entering tertiary-level education in Ireland understand school algebra. As part of a larger project, a 31-item test was developed to assess first-year undergraduate students’ understanding of basic algebraic concepts. The test was administered online to students studying at least one mathematics module at tertiary level and received 327 responses. In this article, we study how the subset of high-achieving undergraduates in our sample performed on the test. The results demonstrated a very high level of understanding among students, as befits their level of study and prior achievement relative to the difficulty of the test. However, one subsection of the test stood out as being disproportionately difficult for these students. The section focused on valid solutions of equations and inequalities. The items in question are described in detail in this article as is the associated data. Our analysis shows that this topic is an area of concern even for high-achieving undergraduates and so deserves further attention. We conclude with a discussion of the implications of this research and details of the larger project.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-11-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00256-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Causal Latent Transition Model With Multivariate Outcomes and Unobserved Heterogeneity: Application to Human Capital Development</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In order to evaluate the effect of a policy or treatment with pre- and post-treatment outcomes, we propose an approach based on a transition model, which may be applied with multivariate outcomes and accounts for unobserved heterogeneity. This model is based on potential versions of discrete latent variables representing the individual characteristic of interest and may be cast in the hidden (latent) Markov literature for panel data. Therefore, it can be estimated by maximum likelihood in a relatively simple way. The approach extends the difference-in-difference method as it is possible to deal with multivariate outcomes. Moreover, causal effects may be expressed with respect to transition probabilities. The proposal is validated through a simulation study, and it is applied to evaluate educational programs administered to pupils in the sixth and seventh grades during their middle school period. These programs are carried out in an Italian region to improve non-cognitive skills (CSs). We study if they impact also on students’ CSs in Italian and Mathematics in the eighth grade, exploiting the pretreatment test scores available in the fifth grade. The main conclusion is that the educational programs aimed to develop noncognitive abilities help the best students to maintain their higher cognitive abilities over time.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2023 07:21</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221150033?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Assessing Inter-rater Reliability With Heterogeneous Variance Components Models: Flexible Approach Accounting for Contextual Variables</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Inter-rater reliability (IRR), which is a prerequisite of high-quality ratings and assessments, may be affected by contextual variables, such as the rater’s or ratee’s gender, major, or experience. Identification of such heterogeneity sources in IRR is important for the implementation of policies with the potential to decrease measurement error and to increase IRR by focusing on the most relevant subgroups. In this study, we propose a flexible approach for assessing IRR in cases of heterogeneity due to covariates by directly modeling differences in variance components. We use Bayes factors (BFs) to select the best performing model, and we suggest using Bayesian model averaging as an alternative approach for obtaining IRR and variance component estimates, allowing us to account for model uncertainty. We use inclusion BFs considering the whole model space to provide evidence for or against differences in variance components due to covariates. The proposed method is compared with other Bayesian and frequentist approaches in a simulation study, and we demonstrate its superiority in some situations. Finally, we provide real data examples from grant proposal peer review, demonstrating the usefulness of this method and its flexibility in the generalization of more complex designs.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2023 07:16</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221150517?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Special Education and Meritocratic Inclusion</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this theoretical article we present our hypothesis on the incompatibility of the inclusive education policy toward students with special educational needs with the meritocratic principle of education. If considering and recognizing the needs of these students is necessary to achieve a successful inclusive environment, we propose that this goal cannot be achieved within current educational systems driven by a meritocratic ideology. We base our rationale on social psychology theories such as system justification and backlash to argue that such incompatibility is particularly visible during the evaluation process. Finally, if we provide some incentives toward greater inclusion while considering the diverse contradictions such inclusivity generates, we also invite researchers to further empirically examine these contradictions in order to guide policy makers within their choices.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2023 05:18</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048231153606?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Does It Matter Who Evaluates Teachers? Principal Versus Teacher-Led Evaluation and Teacher Motivation</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Increasing job demands and continuing struggles to improve teacher evaluation practice raise the question of how peers might assist principals with teacher evaluation. Using a robust international sample (TALIS2013) of 36,411 teachers from 2,759 schools in 11 countries, we tested the hypothesis that teacher-led evaluation practices are associated with more teacher-reported positive changes in classroom practice, confidence, and motivation than principal-led evaluation practices in three areas evaluation: (1) classroom observations, (2) assessments of teacher content knowledge, and (3) analysis of student test score data. We found that teacher-led evaluation is associated with more positive feelings of motivation and change in practice for all three evaluation areas, but particularly for assessments of teacher content knowledge and test score data analysis. Further, principals’ reported use of extrinsic motivational tools to reward or punish teachers based upon their evaluation was also negatively associated with teachers’ motivation and reports of positive change in practice.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-10-2023 05:12</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221103796?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Handling Missing Data in Growth Mixture Models</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;A Monte Carlo simulation was performed to compare methods for handling missing data in growth mixture models. The methods considered in the current study were (a) a fully Bayesian approach using a Gibbs sampler, (b) full information maximum likelihood using the expectation–maximization algorithm, (c) multiple imputation, (d) a two-stage multiple imputation method, and (e) listwise deletion. Of the five methods, it was found that the Bayesian approach and two-stage multiple imputation methods generally produce less biased parameter estimates compared to maximum likelihood or single imputation methods, although key differences were observed. Similarities and disparities among methods are highlighted and general recommendations articulated.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2023 07:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221149140?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Connecting mathematics and mathematics education: collected papers on mathematics education as a design science</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2023 05:24</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2173640?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Practicum experience: the role of practicum demands and resources in first and second career preservice teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2023 01:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2175662?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Emergence of Collective Mathematical Creativity Through Students’ Productive Struggle</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this article, we show how students’ productive struggle on a mathematical task can lead to collective mathematical creativity. We use observable (co)actions and interactions from a video record that features three Grade 6 students in a problem-solving session to document the emergence of collective creativity leading to a mathematical solution. We discuss some key features of the mathematics task and other elements of the learning environment and present implications for classroom practices aimed at helping students to capitalize on their mathematical struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-09-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-023-00259-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Epistemic and Deontic Authority in Parent–Teacher Conference: Referring to the Expert as a Discursive Practice to (Jointly) Undermine the Teacher’s Expertise</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Teacher Education, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article investigates the interactional constitution of a phenomenon recurrently reported by teachers who complain about a loss of authority, a systematic delegitimization of their role. Adopting a conversation analysis informed approach to a single-case study from a corpus of parent–teacher conferences, we illustrate how challenging the teachers’ expertise is accomplished by participants as an outcome of some identifiable communicative practices. Particularly, we analyze the practices of “quoting” and “referring to the expert” as interactional resources differently exploited by participants: While parents challenge the teachers’ epistemic authority and lay the foundation for claiming the right to decide what do to with their son in the classroom, teachers contribute to this epistemic positioning and cede their expert knowledge-based deontic rights, that is, the right to decide the best practices to adopt in the classroom. In the discussion, we advance that the participants’ interactive competence in navigating the complex epistemic landscape of the encounter profoundly impacts on the local definition of reciprocal epistemic and deontic rights and responsibilities. Indications for teachers’ education are provided in the conclusion.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2023 10:31</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/00224871231153088?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Toward a Class-Conscious Approach to Cultural Responsiveness</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Researcher, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The last several decades have seen a growth in scholarship and application of culturally responsive and sustaining educational (CRSE) approaches in schools serving youth of color. A growing body of research has shown how CRSE serves as an effective strategy to engage students of color, combat pernicious stereotypes, and improve academic outcomes. Notwithstanding these important contributions, CRSE scholarship and practice have not fully explored the significance of social class, despite its long-standing correlation with academic performance, deep connections to identity, and relationship to race and racialization. Drawing on lessons gleaned from ethnographic research, which has demonstrated the importance of social-class analyses, this essay calls for a greater emphasis on and recognition of class in CRSE methods and application. As one of the most prominent and useful sets of pedagogical strategies used in education today, CRSE stands to benefit from a wider inclusion of social class, an addition that would have important ramifications for practitioners and scholars seeking to effectively educate historically marginalized populations. A deeper understanding of the significance of class could also help educators and scholars avoid perpetuating pernicious cultural stereotypes, such as the model minority myth and the culture of poverty. However, a class-conscious addition to CRSE must also maintain its anti-deficit perspective to avoid essentialist views about working-class youth.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2023 03:02</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X221149975?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Deciphering the cognitive and non-cognitive competencies of Chinese students’ mathematics through a critical lens of PISA</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-023-10210-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptualising critical mathematical thinking in young students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract
      &lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;International curriculum and policy directions have called to embed critical thinking across discipline areas including mathematics; however, conceptually, this is under-theorised and under-researched in the field of mathematics education. This paper presents the conceptualisation of critical mathematical thinking (CMT) and the application of a literature informed conceptual framework; in particular, it examines what CMT capabilities young students exhibit as they enter formal schooling. We present the findings from one-on-one task-based interviews, undertaken with 16 young students (aged 5–6) as a means to investigate their CMT capabilities and refine the CMT framework. The interview data were analysed using the new critical mathematical thinking conceptual framework. The data confirms the definition and understanding of CMT in young students, indicating a need for curriculum refinement, improved teaching practices, and further research in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-08-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-023-00445-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Motives for becoming a teacher, coping strategies and teacher efficacy among Swedish student teachers</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2023 12:34</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2175665?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating authenticity in simulation-based learning scenarios in teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2023 12:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2023.2175664?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Being (Asian) American children: children’s exploration of racial/cultural identity and racism</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2023 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13613324.2023.2170434?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reducing Excellence Gaps: A Systematic Review of Research on Equity in Advanced Education</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Unequal access to advanced learning opportunities is among the most complex and controversial issues in American K–12 schools. Interventions that address policy, programming, and instruction can provide opportunities for students with advanced learning needs in school systems that prioritize minimum grade-level standards. Excellence gaps are differences in advanced performance among student subgroups that result from inequities in education and society. In this systematic review of the literature, the authors identified 80 empirical research studies on strategies for reducing excellence gaps published between 2010 and 2021 and identified themes related to the seven facets of the Excellence Gap Intervention Model (K–12 school accountability support, teacher professional learning, expanded advanced learning opportunities, universal screening with local norms, frontloading, flexible ability grouping, psychosocial interventions). This analysis revealed substantial evidence of intervention development over the past decade and suggests a revised approach to equitable, advanced education that begins with preparation (e.g., teacher professional learning, student frontloading) and is followed by placement, evaluation, and adjustment as students’ learning needs change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-07-2023 01:14</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221148461?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Exploration of the Experiences of Substitute Teachers: A Systematic Review</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This article reports on a systematic review of literature on the experiences of substitute teachers, also known as casual or relief teachers. This occupational group are an essential part of school improvement efforts, allowing release time for other teachers to participate in professional learning, complete administrative duties, and attend to personal matters. Although a ubiquitous component of the teaching workforce, little is known about their work conditions, motivations, experiences, and support. This study involved a mixed-methods research synthesis approach. Peer-reviewed studies and dissertations that examined the experiences and needs of substitute teachers in primary/elementary, middle, and secondary/high schools were examined. The study found that, although substitute teachers are a heterogeneous group, their conditions and experiences are less than satisfactory, exacerbated by a lack of targeted support. Education systems need to consider professionalizing this occupational group further. In addition, systems need to develop policies and practices that improve substitute teachers’ work.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2023 11:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221149418?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Leveraging What Students Know to Make Sense of Texts: What the Research Says About Prior Knowledge Activation</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This systematic literature review examined the research on prior knowledge and its activation to ascertain how these terms are defined, what specific techniques have been empirically investigated, and the conditions under which prior knowledge activation facilitated students’ comprehension. Fifty-four articles met the inclusion criteria and revealed that the terms prior knowledge and prior knowledge activation were often vaguely defined. Further, 30 unique techniques for activating readers’ prior knowledge representing eight different categories were identified. Those categories were open-ended prompts, procedural or strategic supports during reading, visual representations, analogical reasoning, text alteration, augmented activation, extratextual activities, and spontaneous activation. Techniques meant to facilitate knowledge activation prior to reading were most common, although the prompting of students’ existing knowledge was beneficial during and after reading as well. Variability in the effectiveness of activation techniques was related, in part, to the amount, accuracy, and specificity of students’ knowledge. Based on the key findings identified in this review, recommendations for future inquiry are forwarded, including suggested definitions of prior knowledge and prior knowledge activation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2023 11:20</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221148478?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Thematic Review of STEM Education for Disadvantaged Students</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The present study proposed to thematically examine the studies on STEM education for disadvantaged students. International and national well-known databases (e.g., ERIC, PROQUEST Dissertations and Theses Global, ULAKBIM, Scopus, YOK-National Theses Center, and Google Scholar) were searched by means of keyword patterns (pattern 1: STEM education and disadvantaged students; pattern 2: STEM education and nondominant students; pattern 3: STEM education and underrepresented students). Then, the inclusion (e.g., STEM education for disadvantaged students, STEM careers/plans and their reasons) and exclusion (e.g., racial microaggressions in STEM education) criteria were applied. Thus, a total of 37 studies were appearant for the thematic review. Afterwards, the studies were analyzed in regard to the matrix (i.e., aims, methodologies, disadvantaged groups, intervention programmes, conclusions, and implications). The findings showed that such factors as socio-economic status, gender, ethnic/racial minority, and learning gap/disability influenced the disadvantaged students’ STEM careers. Therefore, future studies should cultivate these factors as moderator variables to drive disadvantaged students to the STEM careers and develop their potential competencies of STEM fields.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-06-2023 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00247-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptions and consequences of mathematical argumentation, justification, and proof</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>02-04-2023 03:19</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2023.2165537?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
