<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>BSRLM day conference proceedings</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2022 07:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14794802.2022.2126385?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sustaining at Scale: District Mathematics Specialists’ Adaptations to a Teacher Leadership Preparation Program</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2022 06:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2140553?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The interplay between the guidance from the digital learning environment and the teacher in supporting folding back</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Previous studies have proposed that students’ mathematical understanding develops dynamically through the process known as folding back, in which learners revisit earlier forms of understanding and use them to build even deeper levels of mathematical understanding. Digital learning environments, where students can manipulate representations, are often used to enable students to notice properties, patterns, or rules. When working in such an environment, students usually receive support from the environment and the teacher. The interplay between these different sources of support is important according to previous studies. In this study, we examine this interplay in the case of folding back. The study aims to understand how the teacher, together with the learning environment, can support the process of folding back. We collected data from second, fourth, and sixth grade students as they worked in groups to develop a rule for balancing a balance beam in a digital learning environment designed to support folding back. One pre-service teacher guided each three-student group. Data were analyzed by identifying occasions for folding back and characterizing different ways in which the interplay between the teacher and the environment supported students’ folding back. We found different kinds of synergy between the two sources of support. The teachers followed up on and augmented the support from the environment, initiated supplementary folding back, and reinforced the support from the environment. We also found non-synergy between the two sources of support, when the teachers’ support was not aligned with support from the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10193-x</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Analysis of the Observable Behaviors of Undergraduate drop-in Mathematics Tutors</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Despite the prevalence of undergraduate drop-in mathematics tutoring, little is known about the behaviors of this specific group of tutors. This study serves as a starting place for identifying their behaviors by addressing the research question: what observable behaviors do undergraduate drop-in mathematics tutors exhibit as they interact with students? We analyzed 31 transcripts of tutoring sessions using inductive coding, finding 83 observable behaviors. We discovered that tutors used behaviors aimed at engaging students, while primarily retaining control of the decision making and problem-solving process. Although tutors asked students to contribute to the mathematics, they often asked a less demanding question before the student had a chance to respond to the initial question. Our findings reveal the existence of opportunities for student learning in tutoring sessions as well as potential areas of growth for tutors. We present questions for future research that arose from analysis of the data and discuss how our results may be used in tutor training.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-12-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00197-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Images and indicators: mixing participatory methods to build inclusive rigour</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Participatory methods seek to counter the extractive nature of mainstream research methods by putting control into the hands of research subjects. But participation itself does not guarantee against extraction. There is a tension between the desire for researcher-control and the prerogative of community action in participatory methods. How can researchers committed to participation manage this tension? In this paper, we draw on the concepts of “collaborative” and “action-oriented” participatory research to describe how integrating mixed-methodologies can help different research stakeholders attain desirable, fruitful and meaningful levels of ownership and build inclusive rigour. Drawing on our work with participatory indicators and photovoice with conflict affected communities in rural Colombia, we demonstrate how combining different kinds of participatory research methods—in this case, non-visual and visual research—creates opportunities to attend to the sometimes conflicting goals of robust research, policy change and community action. Under the broad umbrella of participatory research, collaborative approaches like participatory indicators and action-oriented approaches like photovoice complement and amplify each other in such settings, embracing complexity and catalyzing multiple ways of ‘knowing-for-action’. The result is participatory research that is attuned to the complexities of conflict-affected settings, inclusively rigorous and potentially transformative.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-11-2022 02:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221137851?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A structuralist view for interpreting the role of mathematics in physics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The effectiveness of mathematics in physics makes people take for granted the intimate connection between both disciplines. However, history shows that this is not always the case, because mathematics has played a minor role, not only in Aristotelian physics in ancient Greece, but also in Confucian and neo-Confucian science in ancient China. The objective of this study is to discuss the role of mathematics in physics and propose a structuralistic view as an epistemological stance to interpret this role. This paper opens with a brief historical overview on the relationship between mathematics and physics, followed by a report on Taiwanese college students’ work on and responses to an activity simulating Galileo’s inclined plane experiment, in order to investigate in what way they analyzed the data and to what extent this activity enriched the affective, knowledge-oriented, and historical aspects of their thinking. Additionally, an investigation of a mathematician’s and a physicist’s beliefs was conducted to search for an epistemological stance that reveals the relationship between mathematics and physics. The study suggests that a structuralist view may be appropriate for promoting students’ learning and their epistemological interpretations of mathematics and physics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-11-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01438-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The transition from school to university in mathematics education research: new trends and ideas from a systematic literature review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Investigating the transition between educational levels is one of the main themes for the future of mathematics education. In particular, the transition from secondary school to STEM degrees is problematic for the widespread students’ difficulties and significant for the implications that it has on students’ futures. Knowing and understanding the past is key to imagine the future of a research field. For this reason, this paper reports a systematic review of the literature on the secondary-tertiary transition in Mathematics Education from 2008 to 2021. We constructed two corpuses: one from the proceedings of three international conferences in mathematics education (PME, ICME, and INDRUM) and the other from peer reviewed research papers and book chapters returned by the databases ERIC and Google Scholar. A clear evolution in perspectives since 2008 emerges from the analysis of the two corpuses: the research focus changed from a purely cognitive to a more holistic one, including socio-cultural and — to a lesser extent — affective issues. To this end, a variety of research methods were used, and specific theoretical models were developed in the considered papers. The analysis also highlights a worrisome trend of underrepresentation: very little research comes from large geographical areas such as South America or Africa. We argue that this gap in representation is problematic as research on secondary tertiary transition concerns also consideration of socio-cultural and contextual factors.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-11-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10194-w</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring the negotiation processes when developing a mathematical model to solve a Fermi problem in groups</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Previous research has highlighted the importance of social relationships in mathematical group work while working on modelling activities. This study analyses the interaction of sixth-grade students in Primary Education (11 to 12 years old) carrying out a modelling task in groups with a Fermi problem used as the modelling activity. The focus of the study was to explore how students develop a mathematical model to solve a Fermi problem in groups. The data collected mainly came from the group discussions, although the students’ productions were also considered. The results show that a variety of factors can influence group work and that model development is based on one student introducing an initial model and then, through social interaction with the other group members, the model is improved to develop a solid strategy that may be useful for solving the problem at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-11-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s13394-022-00435-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Analysing the citizenship agenda in Mathematical Literacy school exit assessments</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Assessments, in particular high stakes assessments, impact the nature of teaching and learning. Given this, the goal of citizenship if seen as important needs to feature within high stakes school exit assessments rather than only as part of curriculum and assessment policy rhetoric. South Africa’s Mathematical Literacy (ML) curriculum foregrounds critical democratic citizenship. We analyse the ML Grade 12 exit assessments from their start in 2008 to 2020 to understand the emphasis placed on critical citizenship and how this emphasis has shifted over time. The literature base links critical citizenship orientations with reasoning and reflecting questions, so we focused on examination questions in this category. Our findings show shifts away from critical citizenship related agendas towards foregrounding a life preparation orientation for the self-managing person. Linked with this shift, we note a move away from general societal contexts towards more personal/individual contexts and moves from almost entirely national contexts to inclusion of global contexts. We noted movement from more open-phrased questions towards closed ‘check figure calculated is valid’-type questions. Assessment memoranda suggest assessors view these questions as reasoning items, eroding the critical citizenship agenda. While increasing numbers of students are taking ML rather than Mathematics, average performance stands at around 40%. This points to limited and diminishing access to mathematical reasoning and reflecting for critical democratic citizenship. The paper highlights ways in which analysis of examinations over time can provide a window into the presence or absence of the citizenship agenda in mathematics education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-10-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01448-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tracing mathematics engagement in the first year of high school: relationships between prior experience, observed support, and task-level emotion and motivation</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;We examined the relationships between different aspects of mathematics engagement for 285 students in their first year of high school in the United States. Path Analyses were used to trace the relationships between students’ self-reported prior motivation and appraisals of control and value of mathematics, perceptions of teacher support and peer support. These variables and observed teacher and peer support as coded from video by researchers, were examined as potentially impacting students’ self-reported in-the moment affect and task-level control and value appraisals Our results showed three key contributions. First, significant paths corresponded to relationships predicted by Control Value Theory (CVT) across a particularly robust set of variables and over the course of their first semester in high school. Second, results added further nuance by considering the objects that students’ in-the-moment emotions were directed toward, showing distinctions between positive and negative emotions directed at the mathematics task, students’ teachers and peers, and selves. Third, results more closely considered the impact of both observed and perceived aspect of support from peers and teachers in the classroom, in both its academic and social forms. Implications are discussed for theory and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-10-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01432-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>History of mathematics in mathematics education: Recent developments in the field</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Over the last 40 years, exploring the possible interrelations between the history of mathematics and mathematics education has gradually emerged as an interdisciplinary domain of educational research and practice, and entered a maturity stage during the last two decades. This development calls for an account of the general issues concerning the rationale and main themes underlying research and applications in its context, and the foundational issues addressed as a result of its interdisciplinary character. Therefore, after explaining the perspective characterizing work in this domain (what has been called the HPM perspective), we present the main themes along which current research is conducted and we analyze the main issues and concerns raised by current research in this domain, with due reference to recent publications. Papers in this issue further develop the key research strands shaped by these main issues and concerns from a variety of perspectives; in particular, papers address the theoretical points related to the interdisciplinary character of this domain (e.g., the role of history in promoting and developing STEM education more profoundly), and the design of innovative teaching approaches based on original sources (e.g., how non-didacticized resource material can motivate mathematically rich tasks without requiring too specialized knowledge in the history of mathematics). These papers also suggest fresh avenues for research, some bearing on potential methodological connections between mathematics, education, and history (e.g., the possibility of different readings of original sources that reveal the complex interrelations among historical knowledge, teaching objectives, and pedagogical practices), and some bearing on the implementation, evaluation, and dissemination of designs connected to the history of mathematics, in teaching at all levels of education (e.g., development of curricular material based on original texts, offering new learning opportunities in relation to core topics in university mathematics). We conclude with a brief description of each contributed paper.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-10-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01442-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are Observed Classroom Practices Related to Student Language/Literacy Achievement?</title>
        <description>
          
            Review of Educational Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this study, we examined the relation of observed classroom practices to language and literacy achievement and the moderation of this relation for students from pre-K to sixth grade. A total of 136 studies (N = 107,882 participants) met the inclusion criteria, of which 108 studies were included for meta-analysis and the other 28 studies were narratively synthesized. The average zero-order (r = .12) and partial correlations (rp = .04) were statistically significant but weak in magnitude. The relation was slightly weaker in upper than in lower grade levels, and stronger for observations capturing macro quality and instructional dimension than those capturing micro measurement and emotional or structural dimension, respectively. The relation did not vary by observation duration, frequency, adopted statistical approach, or type of covariates. Taken together with the narrative synthesis, the results highlight the complex nature of classroom observation and a need for more classroom research, particularly on higher grade levels.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00346543221130687?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conceptions and Practices of Equity in Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This framework explores the plurality of ways that research-practice partnerships (RPPs) conceptualize issues of equity, and with what consequences for what gets studied, whose voices are included in inquiry, and what knowledge is foregrounded in partnership activity. We draw on institutional theory and the perspectives of members from diverse partnerships to create a framework on the beliefs and practices of equity in RPPs. In terms of their missions, RPPs’ conceptions of equity ranged from a focus on individualism and standardization, to advancing goals of identity, culture, and belonging and attending to power, justice, and anti-racism. Equity was reflected within processes for working together, varying across coordination, collaboration, or transformation of roles and power dynamics. For RPPs, the framework can help develop a common language and shared meanings. For future research, it can serve as an analytic lens to understand when and how RPPs work in service of educational transformation and change.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 02:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221131566?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Seeing the continuity behind “double discontinuity”: investigating Hong Kong prospective mathematics teachers’ secondary–tertiary transition</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Felix Klein’s notion of “double discontinuity” between university mathematics and secondary school mathematics has persisted in mathematics teacher education. Situating this study in Hong Kong, we investigated three prospective secondary teachers’ experiences in higher education and secondary mathematics classrooms, including their figured worlds, identities, and mathematical knowledge constructed through those experiences. Our analysis revealed their contrasting experiences in these two contexts, adding to our understanding of the phenomenon of “double discontinuity” in terms of not only how it is relevant to Hong Kong but also how it may manifest in the specific cultural context. Moreover, we found coherency and continuity during the prospective teachers’ secondary–tertiary transition; their learning experiences in both environments served as critical resources upon which they reflected to envision their future mathematics teaching. We conclude with implications and suggestions for mathematics teacher education to support prospective teachers’ (and their future students’) transitions between high school and university mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10649-022-10197-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Students’ Strategic Usage of Formative Quizzes in an Undergraduate Course in Abstract Algebra</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Besides homework assignments, optional quizzes are a commonly used means for formative assessment in tertiary mathematics education. Instructors, for example, implement these to help students detect gaps in their understanding, or to foster a continuous and active engagement with the content. The extent to which these goals are reached, however, strongly depends on how students actually use such quizzes, which is currently an underexplored topic. We investigated this issue in an undergraduate abstract algebra course with a study using a mixed-methods design. Unlike previous research suggesting that students use optional quizzes in tertiary mathematics courses mainly for rehearsal or for a final self-check of their own performance, our study indicates that students also use such quizzes in many other ways, for example for planning their further learning, or for deepening their understanding of the content of the course. Furthermore, our study shows differences regarding students’ quiz usage during the semester and when preparing for the final exam. Finally, the data propose factors that influence the way students use optional quizzes, for example time constraints due to other obligations during the semester, the perceived difficulty of the questions, or the opportunity to discuss these with peers. This leads to several suggestions regarding the implementation of optional quizzes into tertiary mathematics courses.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00194-9</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Mathematical Work of Chilean Secondary Teachers in the Domain of Probability</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The objective of this qualitative research is to study the mathematical work when solving a mathematical task in the domain of probability presented by Chilean high school mathematics teachers in pre-service and in-service training. We consider as theoretical support the Mathematical Working Space model and methodological design of a collective case study, comprising of five teachers in pre-service training and eight teachers in in-service training. This research design allows us to analyze mathematical objects under semiotic, instrumental, and discursive dimensions, identifying privileged vertical planes, the paradigm applied, and the different strategies used by teachers. The task presented to the participants allows two different correct answers depending on the interpretation of the random experiment in question. Since the definition of the random experiment involved in the task is of utmost importance, according to our results, this notion was not evident in all the productions analyzed, which issue poses a challenge for the teaching and learning of probability.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-09-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s42330-022-00235-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selecting Districts and Schools for Impact Studies in Education: A Simulation Study of Different Strategies</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2022 08:28</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2128952?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Explaining the Racial School Climate Gap: Evidence From Georgia</title>
        <description>
          
            AERA Open, &lt;a href=&quot;journals.sagepub.com/toc/eroa/8&quot;&gt;Volume 8, Issue &lt;/a&gt;, January-December 2022. &lt;br/&gt;Research documents positive associations between school climate and student outcomes, and, as such, many policymakers have positioned it among their chief priorities for school improvement. Despite this increased focus, extant research has offered mixed findings on the presence and magnitude of racial school climate disparities. The present study uses administrative data of middle and high schools in Georgia to examine disparities in school-climate perceptions and factors predicting them. I find that Black and “Other” students consistently report worse perceptions on nearly all measures of school climate compared to White students and that these disparities persist within school. Furthermore, Black teachers moderate Black students’ climate perceptions and are critical protective factors against the risks they face in school. Implications suggest that an increased focus on school climate is unlikely to yield equitable returns absent ancillary policy and practices that improve schooling conditions influencing disparities in students’ school climate perceptions.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2022 05:07</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/23328584221131529?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Collegiate Mathematics Observation Protocols: Current Characteristics and Desired Foci</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Typically, departments and universities evaluate and/or provide feedback to college mathematics instructors on their teaching by conducting classroom observations. When these observations are guided by an observation protocol, the protocol provides a particular lens that focuses the observer’s attention on certain aspects of instruction. To understand the way in which mathematics departments are currently evaluating teaching and investigate whether they align with inquiry-based mathematics education practices, we evaluated 24 observation protocols from universities around the United States. Through our analysis we found that protocols mainly include closed-response items that are evaluative, focus more on the instructor than the students or the content, and rarely attend to inquiry-based mathematics education practices. These results suggest that where we aspire the field to go and where it is currently at requires significant and targeted work to achieve. Moreover, our findings provide suggestions and have implications for both those who develop observation protocols and those who use observation protocols as a measure of teaching practices. Our study highlights the need for careful explicit and clear purposes when observations are used for performance measures.
      &lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-08-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40753-022-00199-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Unpacking the Power Dynamics of Funding Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this paper two foundation program officers describe their experiences as funders engaged in supporting research practice partnerships in two very distinct settings. The authors set the context for their experiences and walk through the challenges and opportunities in supporting research practice partnerships. They also discuss how supporting these efforts create power dynamics between the strategic initiatives at foundations and the need for researchers to have independence in crafting research agendas for research practice partnerships. The authors provide some lessons learned and prospect how future engagements with research practice partnerships can be set up for success.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:45</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134585?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whose Agenda is It? Navigating the Politics of Setting the Research Agenda in Education Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;In this article, we provide insight into sharing power and balancing practitioner and researcher priorities during the process of establishing a research agenda for a research-practice partnership (RPP). We draw on the literature about effective collaboration within RPPs to identify concepts and factors that can help or hinder the research agenda-setting process. Concepts include boundary spanning, spheres of interest and action, and strategic knowledge leadership. Factors include early and ongoing engagement of partners, adequate representation of diverse perspectives, funder priorities, and the presence of trusting relationships. The authors then use examples from our own experiences in RPPs to illustrate how these concepts and factors play out in the agenda-setting process.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:40</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221131567?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Equity and Early Implementation of the Every Student Succeeds Act in State-Designed Plans During COVID</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) reverses a trend toward centralization of education policy and instead provides greater authority to the states. This study explores states’ interpretation and early implementation of ESSA’s equity-related provisions. Using a qualitative case study approach, we find wide variation in the design and implementation of equity-related provisions. We provide an overview of implementation efforts and highlight states that are making significant strides and those that are lagging behind. Our findings highlight the need to build capacity at the state and district levels and to better understand the role of state education agencies in implementing ESSA.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:38</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221130994?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>It’s Complicated: Examining Political Realities and Challenges in the Context of Research-Practice Partnerships From the School District Leader’s Perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Growing interest in the potential of education research-practice partnerships (RPPs) as a promising strategy for increasing the relevance and use of research has led the field to create an expanding body of literature documenting both the promise and the potential perils of RPPs. Insightful frameworks abound, outlining the structural and organizational considerations for forming and maintaining a successful RPP. Yet, less is known about how political realities within practice side organizations influence these partnerships. Drawing on Farrell et al.s’ framework describing RPPs as learning at the boundaries, I examine several examples of political challenges confronted by RPPs involving school districts and the degree to which school district leaders’ actions were able to mitigate the political challenges. Power imbalance exacerbated by funder priorities, the ripple effect of leadership change, and school board member priorities will be explored, along with discussions of implications.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:29</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221130352?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Breaking Our Silence on Factor Score Indeterminacy</title>
        <description>
          
            Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Although many textbooks on multivariate statistics discuss the common factor analysis model, few of these books mention the problem of factor score indeterminacy (FSI). Thus, many students and contemporary researchers are unaware of an important fact. Namely, for any common factor model with known (or estimated) model parameters, infinite sets of factor scores can be constructed to fit the model. Because all sets are mathematically exchangeable, factor scores are indeterminate. Our professional silence on this topic is difficult to explain given that FSI was first noted almost 100 years ago by E. B. Wilson, the 24th president (1929) of the American Statistical Association. To help disseminate Wilson’s insights, we demonstrate the underlying mathematics of FSI using the language of finite-dimensional vector spaces and well-known ideas of regression theory. We then illustrate the numerical implications of FSI by describing new and easily implemented methods for transforming factor scores into alternative sets of factor scores. An online supplement (and the fungible R library) includes R functions for illustrating FSI.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>11-07-2022 11:06</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/10769986221128810?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
