<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
   xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest Publications in Education</title>
    <link>https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ebardelli.com/ed-news/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Recent articles published in education journals</description>
      
      <item>
        <title>Combining a Local Comparison Group, a Pretest Measure, and Rich Covariates: How Well Do They Collectively Reduce Bias in Nonequivalent Comparison Group Designs?</title>
        <description>
          
            American Educational Research Journal, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study examined bias reduction in the eight nonequivalent comparison group designs (NECGDs) that result from combining (a) choice of a local versus non-local comparison group, and analytic use or not of (b) a pretest measure of the study outcome and (c) a rich set of other covariates. Bias was estimated as the difference in causal estimate between each NECGD and a carefully appraised randomized experiment with the same intervention, outcome, and estimand. Results indicated that bias generally declined with the number of design elements in an NECGD, that combining all three sufficed to eliminate bias but was not necessary for it, and that this pattern of results was largely replicated across five different replication factors.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2022 12:32</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/00028312221136565?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Organisational Learning and Resilience in Hungarian Schools During COVID-19 Distance Education – Study of Two Cases</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2022 07:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2154205?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional Development at Scale: The Causal Effect of Obtaining an SEI Endorsement Under Massachusetts’s RETELL Initiative</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;We apply a difference-in-difference design to measure the causal effect of a teacher obtaining an endorsement in Sheltered English Immersion under Massachusetts’s Rethinking Equity in the Teaching of English Language Learners initiative on student’s learning outcomes. More than 35,000 in-service public school teachers completed the semester-long course. We find no effect on English learners’ (ELs) average test scores, but modest positive spillovers for students with disabilities and other non-EL students. Training benefited teachers recently hired by their district but had no effect on longer serving teachers.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-05-2022 05:00</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/01623737221136101?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Politics at the Boundary: Exploring Politics in Education Research-Practice Partnerships</title>
        <description>
          
            Educational Policy, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The challenges of transforming our educational systems to fulfill enduring needs for equity, justice, and responsiveness will take a multitude of partners. Research-practice partnerships (RPPs) arrange collaboration and engagement with research to bring about shared commitments and resources to tackle these challenges. Just as sociocultural and political dynamics can shape educational politics generally, without close and intentional attention to the politics of starting, operating, and sustaining RPPs, those political dynamics can potentially derail a partnership. In this article, we consider the emerging research on the politics in and around RPPs pursuing educational transformation and propose a framework to reflect these dynamics. To introduce this special issue, we also deconstruct RPP politics into four major phases of RPP work, and describe the articles addressing each phase. This compilation of articles contributes a wealth of expertise and evidence illuminating how politics can shape both RPPs and their goals of equity and transformation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2022 07:44</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/08959048221134916?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mindfulness for in-service and preservice teachers: an empirical map of the discourse from 2000 to 2020</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2022 05:48</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02619768.2022.2153669?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Government Bonds and COVID-19. An International Evaluation Under Different Market States</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;This study evaluates the sensitivity of government bond yields from the countries most affected by the COVID-19 pandemic to variations in some international risk factors during the period between January 2020 and April 2021. This sample period allows us to focus the study on the first, and the subsequent waves of the COVID-19 pandemic. Specifically, we propose an extended risk factor model estimated using the quantile regression approach. In addition, this study compares the COVID-19 pandemic period with a pre-pandemic and a post-vaccination period. Interesting differences among them are observed, remarking that gold is the key risk factor during the pandemic, whereas VIX and crude oil play that role in the pre-pandemic and the post-vaccination periods, respectively, mainly for bearish states. As expected, the explanatory power of the model is better at extreme quantiles, showing relevant differences between sensitivities, because the found effects are quantile-, country- and risk factor-dependent. The results during the pandemic are robust to the inclusion of a country-specific factor and a factor accounting for the mutual influence of the government bonds.JEL classificationC22, C51, F21, G12, G32, H12
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-03-2022 02:30</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221143680?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“In accordance with age and maturity”: Children’s perspectives, conceptions and insights regarding their capacities and meaningful participation</title>
        <description>
          
            Action Research, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;Embedded within family law proceedings and the United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child (UNCRC, 1989) there is ambiguity surrounding the terms rights, participation, best interests, and capacity. Research furthering the rights of children is necessitated across academic literature and practice. Across research, literature and practice there is an evident reliance upon age in relation to the participation of children in family law settings. There is considerably limited research regarding strong characterisations of such concepts, and significantly less literature involving the voices of children and their perspectives regarding the topic. This qualitative action research aimed to gather the perspectives of children aged 6–12 regarding concepts relating to their capacity to participate using child-friendly methods of assessment, specifically the use of play, art, and narrative activities. This research aim to explore the research questions, how do children aged 6–12 demonstrate, understand and describe participation capacities, what does capacity, rights and participation mean to them? How can children demonstrate and increase their understanding of complex concepts through the use of child-friendly methods such as narrative, play, and drawing? This research allowed children to meaningfully share their unique perspectives, educated the participants, and provided one further step in actualizing the rights of children. Further, this research has offered recommended various methodologies for future endeavours involving children’s participation.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2022 09:23</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/14767503221143877?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Relevant mathematical modelling efforts for understanding COVID-19 dynamics: an educational challenge</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                  &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The purpose of the work described in this paper is to emphasize the importance of using mathematical models and mathematical modelling in order to be able to understand and to learn possible behaviours in epidemic situations such as that of the COVID-19 pandemic, besides suggesting modelling techniques with which to evaluate certain sanitary decisions and policies which do, in fact, affect society as a whole. The mathematical tools that are used derive from nonlinear systems of difference equations (possibly viable at a high school level, using spreadsheets or adequate software) as well as nonlinear systems of ordinary differential equations (therefore using mathematical tools and software well within the reach of undergraduate students of many courses). This purpose is accomplished by motivating students and learners to study existing SIR-type models and modifying them in order to have a fully understandable translation of dynamics for infectious diseases such as COVID-19 in several different realistic scenarios, that is to say, situations that consider social distancing policies, widespread vaccination programmes, as well as possible and even probable results when in the presence of negationist postures and attitudes. Several modelling choices referring to real-life situations are shown and explored. These models are analysed and discussed, implicitly proposing similar attitudes and evaluations in learning environments. Conclusions are drawn, stimulating further work using the described mathematical tools and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-02-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01447-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating the Safe-Haven Abilities of Bitcoin and Gold for Crude Oil Market: Evidence During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
        <description>
          
            Evaluation Review, Ahead of Print. &lt;br/&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic poses a serious threat to investors in the crude oil market. Furthermore, investors have an increasing need to find a safe haven in their investment portfolios when facing unprecedented risks in crude oil markets during the COVID-19 pandemic. According to a review of the literature, there are contradictory findings on which investment is the safer haven for the oil market. Therefore, this paper aims to evaluate whether bitcoin is a safer haven for the crude oil market than the commonly used gold during the COVID-19 pandemic. Three spillover measurements based on the time, and frequency domains, and a network framework are employed to quantify the return spillover effects among bitcoin, gold and three major crude oil futures markets. We divide the sample into two periods, pre-COVID-19 and post-COVID-19. The results show that bitcoin has a weak safe-haven effect on the crude oil market only over a short period, while gold maintains a good safe-haven ability for crude oil futures across various time horizons (frequencies), both before and after the outbreak of the COVID-19 pandemic. The findings of this study have important implications for policy-makers, crude oil producers and global investors. In particularly, investors cannot ignore the importance of bitcoin and gold in selecting more profitable portfolio policies when searching for safe-haven assets.
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 12:59</pubDate>
        <link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0193841X221141812?ai=2b4&mi=ehikzz&af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evidence Gap Maps in Education Research</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 06:46</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19345747.2022.2139312?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Planning Framework Foregrounding Equity in Mathematics Teaching and Learning</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 06:03</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19477503.2022.2150462?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Editorial</title>
        <description>
          
            . &lt;br/&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 03:51</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10986065.2022.2153970?af=R</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Desire of teachers and realities in textbooks: dealing with history of mathematics in the new French curriculum and its impact on teacher training</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Many international studies focus empirically on integrating the history of mathematics in mathematics education. Over the last 2 decades, some studies also revealed theoretical elements concerning the implementation of learning sessions and/or their didactical analysis and effectiveness. This paper has the aim of complementing these empirical studies with a more systematic approach in the French context. Defended for decades within the IREM (Institut de recherche sur l’enseignement des mathématiques), the history of mathematics is now officially introduced in the French curriculum. Nevertheless, is it really sufficient for teachers to change their habits by implementing the history of mathematics in their practices? To answer this question, I first present an unpublished survey with secondary school mathematics teachers (pupils from 10- to 18 years old) about the introduction of the history of mathematics in their classes. This survey allows the comparison of teachers’ desires (‘history of mathematics &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;in potentiality&lt;/em&gt;’) and realities in classrooms (‘history of mathematics &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;in actuality&lt;/em&gt;’). Then I focus on French mathematics textbooks (for pupils from 15- to 18 years old) in order to question their effectiveness as tools for the introduction of a historical perspective. I describe the historical/mathematical tasks available in these textbooks focusing on their reference to Fibonacci. Finally, I present a proposition to implement the history of mathematics in mathematics education starting from the textbooks, aiming to help mathematics teachers to redesign the tasks of their textbooks so as to be more relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01427-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>History of mathematics in the context of mathematics teachers’ education: a dialogical/ethical perspective</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This paper deals with the use of original sources in mathematics education, with emphasis on preservice teachers’ education and the exploration of historical texts. In this context, there is a real challenge, for both teachers and learners, to conduct both ‘synchronic’ and ‘diachronic’ reading. As reported extensively in research, learners seem to have a strong propensity to focus on and to ‘translate’ the texts into modern mathematics, which makes it difficult to deepen both their understanding of history and their own set of conceptualizations. Rather than propose practical solutions, in the paper we explore a theoretical positioning that may help us think differently about these difficulties and, ultimately, provide articulated and different avenues for interventions. Drawing on the philosophy of language of Mikhaïl Bakhtin and Valentin Voloshinov, the idea is to question the Saussurean perspective that underpins the notions of synchrony and diachrony. From this theoretical perspective, we propose to think about the challenges associated with the reading of historical texts in terms of the ethical stance of answerability and engagement in the context of preservice mathematics teachers’ education, and we suggest envisioning a third possible reading, namely, that of the educator.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01437-4</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>From the historical text to the classroom session: analysing the work of teachers-as-designers</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;While classical studies have highlighted the many potential benefits of using original historical sources in the classroom, few studies have documented actual classroom practices outside of research contexts. In this case study, I aim to describe and explain how five French high school teachers autonomously designed and implemented classroom sessions starting from the same document, namely an excerpt from Euler’s &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Elements of Algebra&lt;/em&gt; presenting an algorithm for square root approximation. From a methodological viewpoint, it enables me show how two general frameworks for the study of teachers’ professional practices—the Documentational Approach to Didactics and the Didactic and Ergonomic Double Approach—can be tailored to fit the specific challenges of using historical sources. The empirical results provide fresh insights into the conditions for a mathematically rich use of historical sources in the classroom, and on the connections between this use and the integration of a historical perspective in the teaching of mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01434-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>ZIZO: a history-based approach to mathematics teacher education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, we discuss the zoom in and zoom out approach to mathematics teacher education (ZIZO), which is intentionally designed to foster commognitive conflicts through the exploration of historical sources and the engagement with collective discussions. ZIZO is structured in three interconnected moments: firstly, participants are invited to immerse in primary sources, as a means of shaking their comfort zones regarding legitimate mathematical procedures and criteria; secondly, they engage in plenary discussions on the historical contextualisation of mathematical ideas, supported by the study of secondary sources; finally, they return to the source to unveil specific aspects of historical practices. This approach is part of a broader proposal, which builds upon participants’ collective experiences to stimulate the development of a problematising stance toward knowledge production and teaching of mathematics. We exemplify ZIZO by a case in which the study of books I and II of Euclid’s &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/em&gt; was used to problematise usual approaches to the teaching of Pythagoras’ theorem and areas in Brazilian secondary school. Our findings suggest that the engagement with Euclidean practices led teachers to problematise their views on the teaching of areas as geometrical magnitudes and as measurements, as well as the pedagogical uses of manipulable materials. These results highlight ZIZO’s potential for teacher education, especially regarding the problematisation of views on what mathematics is and how it is learned and taught.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01439-2</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledgements to reviewers 2022</title>
        <description>
          
            
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01443-6</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Series of problems in Clairaut’s Elements of Geometry: interaction between historical analysis and mathematics education research</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this paper, I propose an analysis of the structure of Clairaut’s &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Éléments de Géométrie&lt;/em&gt; (1741), a book presenting geometrical knowledge organized around problems, with rich metadiscourse connecting problems and other elements of mathematical content. This analysis is inspired both by the “Series of problems at the crossroad of cultures” interdisciplinary history of sciences project, in which texts from various cultures structured around problems were analysed, and by ongoing mathematics educational research on the Hungarian &lt;em class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Guided Discovery&lt;/em&gt; approach, where “series of problems” play a central role in the planning and implementation of teaching trajectories. I show how a dialog between the analysis of Clairaut’s historical text and mathematics educational research contributes to the reflection on the construction and analysis of inquiry based teaching trajectories in mathematics education.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01441-8</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Impact of a sequence on the history of ancient mathematics informed by student experiences and teacher practices</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;In this study we examined the impact of four teaching sessions on the history of ancient Mesopotamian mathematics, in a 10th -grade classroom. The sessions were taught primarily with historical objectives by researchers in the history of ancient mathematics. We reconstructed historians’ practices and ethos. The presence of the researchers provided the opportunity to study a sequence in which history was taught ‘as a goal’. Moreover, there was no intermediary between the historians and the teaching given to the students, which allowed us to study directly the transposition choices that interested the researchers. We cross-referenced the qualitative and quantitative results of some of the previous findings with the researchers’ task design and discourse. We focused on two aspects, namely, students’ relationship to mathematics as a scientific activity, and the effects of the students’ encounters with the tools and ethics of the history researcher. We found evidence suggesting that students may have made progress in their perception of mathematics ‘as an activity’ and that a certain ‘dépaysement’ emerged. Further, the emergence of debates on the nature of historical sources suggests that the teaching of history ‘as an endeavor’ also seemed to have affected the students. We conclude by proposing some methodological guidelines for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01436-5</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A structuralist view for interpreting the role of mathematics in physics</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The effectiveness of mathematics in physics makes people take for granted the intimate connection between both disciplines. However, history shows that this is not always the case, because mathematics has played a minor role, not only in Aristotelian physics in ancient Greece, but also in Confucian and neo-Confucian science in ancient China. The objective of this study is to discuss the role of mathematics in physics and propose a structuralistic view as an epistemological stance to interpret this role. This paper opens with a brief historical overview on the relationship between mathematics and physics, followed by a report on Taiwanese college students’ work on and responses to an activity simulating Galileo’s inclined plane experiment, in order to investigate in what way they analyzed the data and to what extent this activity enriched the affective, knowledge-oriented, and historical aspects of their thinking. Additionally, an investigation of a mathematician’s and a physicist’s beliefs was conducted to search for an epistemological stance that reveals the relationship between mathematics and physics. The study suggests that a structuralist view may be appropriate for promoting students’ learning and their epistemological interpretations of mathematics and physics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01438-3</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>History of mathematics in mathematics education: Recent developments in the field</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Over the last 40 years, exploring the possible interrelations between the history of mathematics and mathematics education has gradually emerged as an interdisciplinary domain of educational research and practice, and entered a maturity stage during the last two decades. This development calls for an account of the general issues concerning the rationale and main themes underlying research and applications in its context, and the foundational issues addressed as a result of its interdisciplinary character. Therefore, after explaining the perspective characterizing work in this domain (what has been called the HPM perspective), we present the main themes along which current research is conducted and we analyze the main issues and concerns raised by current research in this domain, with due reference to recent publications. Papers in this issue further develop the key research strands shaped by these main issues and concerns from a variety of perspectives; in particular, papers address the theoretical points related to the interdisciplinary character of this domain (e.g., the role of history in promoting and developing STEM education more profoundly), and the design of innovative teaching approaches based on original sources (e.g., how non-didacticized resource material can motivate mathematically rich tasks without requiring too specialized knowledge in the history of mathematics). These papers also suggest fresh avenues for research, some bearing on potential methodological connections between mathematics, education, and history (e.g., the possibility of different readings of original sources that reveal the complex interrelations among historical knowledge, teaching objectives, and pedagogical practices), and some bearing on the implementation, evaluation, and dissemination of designs connected to the history of mathematics, in teaching at all levels of education (e.g., development of curricular material based on original texts, offering new learning opportunities in relation to core topics in university mathematics). We conclude with a brief description of each contributed paper.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01442-7</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The interplay between history of Mathematics and Digital Technologies: a review</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;This article is a review of the literature on the use of history of mathematics in combination with use of digital technologies in the teaching and learning of mathematics. The review identifies 33 peer-reviewed publications (book chapters, journal articles, and papers in conference proceedings) that address an actual interplay between use of history and digital technologies. Of these, 24 concern the use of primary historical source material, i.e., mathematical texts produced by past (historical) mathematicians. Besides asking the questions of which publications actually incorporate this interplay and what purposes the use of history and digital technology serve, we also address the question of the role of mathematics education theoretical perspectives (or the lack thereof) in the identified publications. A reading of the identified publications shows that the ones involving use of primary historical source material often have a clearer connection to theoretical constructs from mathematics education research (outside the area of History and Pedagogy of Mathematics, or HPM). Still, only a small number of the identified publications make use of mathematics education theoretical constructs specifically addressing the use of digital technology.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01368-0</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The role of M (mathematical worlds) in HPM (history and pedagogy of Mathematics) and in STEM (science, technology, engineering, mathematics)</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;It is commonly known that the letter M in the two acronyms HPM and STEM stands for mathematics, and it is natural to regard mathematics as playing a significant role in science education. However, it seems that appropriate attention is not usually accorded to the role of M in the area of STEM where mathematics tends to be marginalized. In fact, throughout history one witnesses STEM at work so that the discussion of HPM and STEM in parallel will be beneficial to both. In both the historical and pedagogical aspects, it may be worthwhile to note that history of mathematics affords some means to mirror several different mathematical worlds in the context of HPM in a pluralistic way in order to offer a fuller view of the subject. In this paper I examine this issue through sampling many examples gleaned from the history of mathematics, particularly the role of M in the world of science and technology.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01375-1</link>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>On the role and scope of historical knowledge in using the history of mathematics in education</title>
        <description>
          
            &lt;h3 class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;a-plus-plus&quot;&gt;The aim of this paper is to gain a better understanding of the role and scope of historical knowledge in work on using history of mathematics in education. This work can come from three types of actors, namely, teachers, teacher trainers, and educational researchers. The texts written by these actors show that their objectives and practices can be different, as is the historical knowledge they deploy. We can read writings of teachers who seek to ‘give meaning’ to school knowledge, by integrating original texts into their teaching progression. We also can read writings of educational researchers who prepare ‘history capsules’ for teachers, which can be introduced into teaching from time to time. To carry out this research, I focus on analyzing the complex relationships between the following three poles: objectives, pedagogical practices, and historical knowledge. To this end, I use the notion of ideal types introduced and developed by the sociologist Max Weber. Section 1 is devoted to the construction of ideal types corresponding to my aim. Based on these ideal types, in Sect. 2, I elaborate on the role and scope of historical knowledge in concrete situations where the history of mathematics is used; specifically, on the one hand during the reading of original texts in an educational context, and on the other hand, in the particular context of teachers education. Some further comments are made in the third and last section.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        </description>
        <pubDate>12-01-2022 00:00</pubDate>
        <link>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s11858-022-01410-1</link>
      </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
